<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2435204</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130602</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>Odour of Chrysanthemums</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><Volume>8</Volume><AlphaPubDate>Jun 1911</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19110601</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Lawrence</LastName><MiddleName>H</MiddleName><FirstName>D</FirstName><PersonName>D H Lawrence</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lawrence, D H</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Austin</FirstName><PersonName>Austin Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Austin</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>415</StartPage><EndPage>433</EndPage><Pagination>415-433</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2435204/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>Odour of Chrysanthemums By D. H. Lawrence THE small locomotive engine, Number 4, came clanking, stumbling down from Selston with seven full waggons. It appeared round the corner with loud threats of speed, but the colt that it startled from among the gorse, which still flickered indistinctly in the raw afternoon, outdistanced it at a canter. A woman, walking up the railway line to Underwood, drew back into the hedge, held her basket aside, and watched the footplate of the engine advancing. The trucks thumped heavily past, one by one, with slow inevitable movement, as she stood insignificantly trapped between the jolting black waggons and the hedge; then they curved away towards the coppice where the withered oak-leaves dropped noiselessly, while the birds, pulling at the scarlet hips beside the track, made off into the dusk that had already crept into the spinney. In the open, the smoke from the engine sank and cleaved to the rough grass. The fields were dreary and forsaken, and in the marshy strip that led to the whimsey, a reedy pit-pond, the fowls had already abandoned their run among the alders, to roost in the tarred fowlhouse. The pit-bank loomed up beyond the pond, flames like red sores licking its ashy sides, in the afternoon&amp;apos;s stagnant light. Just beyond rose the tapering chimneys and the clumsy black headstocks of Brinsley Colliery. The two wheels were spinning fast up against the sky, and the winding-engine rapped out its little spasms. The miners were being turned up. The engine whistled as it came into the wide bay of railway lines beside the colliery, where rows of trucks stood in harbour. Miners, single, trailing and in groups, passed like shadows diverging home. At the edge of the ribbed level of sidings squat a low cottage, three steps down from the cinder track. Aiarge bony vine scrambled over the house, as if to claw down the tiled roof. Round the bricked yard grew a few primroses. Beyond, the long garden sloped down to a bush-covered brook course. There were many twiggy apple-trees, winter-crack trees, sinister looking bushes, and ragged cabbages. Beside the path hung torn and scattered groups of dishevelled pink chrysanthemums, like pink cloths hung on bushes. A woman came bending out of the felt-covered fowl-house half-way down the garden. She closed and padlocked the door, then drew herself erect, having brushed some bits from her white apron. She was a tall woman of imperious mien, handsome, with definite black eyebrows. Her smooth black hair was parted exactly. For a few moments she stood steadily watching the miners as they passed along the railway: then she turned towards the brook course. There was no quickness, no lightness in her movements. Her face was calm and proud with defiance, her mouth was closed with disillusionment. After a moment she called: &amp;quot;John! &amp;quot; There was no answer. She waited, and then said distinctly: &amp;quot; Where are you ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Here! &amp;quot; replied a child&amp;apos;s sulky voice from among the bushes. The woman looked piercingly through the dusk. &amp;quot; Are you at that brook ? &amp;quot; she asked sternly. For answer the child showed himself before the raspberrycanes that rose like whips. He was a small, sturdy boy of five. He stood quite still, defiantly. &amp;quot; Oh! &amp;quot; said the mother, conciliated. &amp;quot; I thought you were down at that wet brook-and you remember what I told you-&amp;quot; The boy did not move or answer. &amp;quot; Come, come on in,&amp;quot; she said more gently, &amp;quot; it&amp;apos;s getting dark and cold-and listen, there&amp;apos;s your grandfather&amp;apos;s engine coming down the line!&amp;quot; The lad advanced slowly, with resentful, taciturn movement. He was dressed in trousers and waistcoat of cloth that was too thick and hard for the size of the garments. They were evidently cut down from a man&amp;apos;s clothes. As they went slowly towards the house he tore at the ragged wisps of pale chrysanthemums and dropped the petals in handfuls along the path. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t do that-it does look nasty,&amp;quot; said his mother. He refrained, and she, suddenly pitiful, broke off a twig with three or four wan flowers and held them against her face. When mother and son reached the yard her hand hesitated, and instead of throwing the flower away, she pushed it in her apronband. The pair stood at the foot of the three steps looking across the bay of lines at the passing home of the miners. The trundle of the small train was imminent. Suddenly the engine loomed past the house and came to a stop opposite the gate. The engine-driver, a short man with round grey beard, leaned out of the cab high above the woman. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve just come right for a cup of tea,&amp;quot; he said in a merry little fashion. It was her father. She went in, saying she would mash for him. Directly, she returned. &amp;quot; I didn&amp;apos;t come and see you on Sunday,&amp;quot; began the little grey-bearded man. &amp;quot; Because &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I didn&amp;apos;t expect you,&amp;quot; said his daughter coldly. The engine-driver winced; then, trying to resume his merry, airy manner, he said: &amp;quot; Oh, have you heard then ? Well, and what do you think-? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think it is soon enough,&amp;quot; she replied. At her brief censure the little man made an impatient gesture, and said coaxingly, excusing himself: &amp;quot; Well, what&amp;apos;s a man to do ? It&amp;apos;s no sort of life living with strangers, a man of my years. I&amp;apos;m used to sitting on my own hearth with my own woman. And if I&amp;apos;m going to marry again it may as well be soon as late-a few months make no difference.&amp;quot; The woman did not reply, but turned and went into the house. The man in the engine-cab stared about in much discomfort, till she returned with a cup of tea and a piece of bread and butter on a plate. She went up the steps and stood near the footplate of the hissing engine. &amp;quot; You needn&amp;apos;t &amp;apos;a brought me bread an&amp;apos; butter as well,&amp;quot; said her father. &amp;quot; But a cup of tea &amp;quot;-he sipped appreciatively&amp;quot; it&amp;apos;s very nice.&amp;quot; He sipped for a moment or two, then: &amp;quot; I hear as Walter&amp;apos;s got another bout on,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;1 don&amp;apos;t know when he hasn&amp;apos;t,&amp;quot; said the woman bitterly. &amp;quot;I heered tell of him in the &amp;apos; Lord Nelson&amp;apos; braggin&amp;apos; as he was going to spend that b- afore he went: half a sovereign that was.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; When?&amp;quot; asked the woman. &amp;quot; A&amp;apos; Sat&amp;apos;day night-an&amp;apos; I know it&amp;apos;s true.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Very likely,&amp;quot; she laughed bitterly. &amp;quot; He is doing wellan&amp;apos; gives me twenty-th.ee shillings. I&amp;apos;d rather have bad times than good, he hasn&amp;apos;t so much to spend.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s a crying shame, he wants horsewhipping!&amp;quot; said the little man. The woman turned her head with weary impatience. Her father swallowed the last of his tea and handed her the cup. &amp;quot; Ay,&amp;quot; he sighed, wiping his mouth. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve repented the day I ever let you have him.&amp;quot; He put his hand on the lever. The little engine strained and groaned, and the train rumbled towards the crossing. The woman again looked across the metals. Darkness was settling over the spaces of the railway, and the trucks: the miners, in grey sombre groups, were still passing home. The windingengine pulsed hurriedly, with brief pauses. Elizabeth Bates looked at the dreary flow of men, then she went indoors. Her husband did not come. The kitchen was small and full of firelight; red coals piled glowing up the chimney mouth. All the life of the room seemed in the white, warm hearth and the steel fender reflecting the red fire. The cloth was laid for tea; cups glinted in the shadows. At the back, where the lowest stairs protruded into the room, the boy sat struggling with a knife and a piece of white wood. He was almost hidden in the shadow. It was half-past four. They had but to await the father&amp;apos;s coming to begin tea. As the mother watched her son&amp;apos;s sullen little struggle with the wood, she saw herself in his silence and pertinacity; she saw the father in her child&amp;apos;s indifference to all but himself. Walter Bates counted nothing but his own pleasure and interest. Even now he had probably gone past his home, slouched past his own door, to drink before he came in, while his dinner spoiled and wasted in waiting. She glanced at the clock, then took the potatoes to strain them in the yard. The garden and fields beyond the brook were closed in uncertain darkness. When she rose with the saucepan, leaving the drain steaming into the night behind her, she saw the yellow lamps were lit along the high road that went up the hill away beyond the space of the railway lines and the field. Then again she watched the men trooping home, fewer now and fewer. Indoors the fire was sinking and the room was dark red. The woman put her saucepan on the hob, and set a batter pudding near the mouth of the oven. Then she stood unmoving. Directly, gratefully, came quick young steps to the door. A child hung on the latch a moment, then a little girl entered and began pulling off her clothes, dragging a mass of curls, just ripening from gold to brown, over her eyes with her hat. Her mother chid her for coming late from school, and said she would have to keep her at home the dark winter days. &amp;quot; Why, mother, it&amp;apos;s hardly a bit dark yet. The lamp&amp;apos;s not lighted, and my father&amp;apos;s not home.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No, he isn&amp;apos;t. But it&amp;apos;s a quarter to five! Did you see anything of him ? &amp;quot; The child became serious. She looked at her mother with large, wistful blue eyes. &amp;quot; No, mother, I&amp;apos;ve never seen him. Why ? Has he come up an&amp;apos; gone past, to Old Brinsley ? He hasn&amp;apos;t, mother, &amp;apos;cos I never saw him.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;d watch that,&amp;quot; said the mother bitterly, &amp;quot; he&amp;apos;d take care as you didn&amp;apos;t see him, child. But you may depend upon it, he&amp;apos;s seated in the &amp;apos;Prince o&amp;apos; Wales.&amp;apos; He wouldn&amp;apos;t be this late.&amp;quot; The girl looked at her mother piteously. &amp;quot; Let&amp;apos;s have our teas, mother, should we?&amp;quot; said she. The mother called John to table. She opened the door once more and looked out across the darkness of the lines. All was deserted: she could not hear the windingengines. &amp;quot; Perhaps,&amp;quot; she said to herself, &amp;quot; he&amp;apos;s stopped to get some ripping done.&amp;quot; They sat down to tea. John, at the end of the table near the door, was almost lost in the darkness. Their faces were hidden from each other. The girl crouched against the fender slowly moving a thick piece of bread before the fire. The lad, his face a dusky mark on the shadow, sat watching her, transfigured as she was in the red glow. &amp;quot; I do think it&amp;apos;s beautiful to look in the fire,&amp;quot; said the child. &amp;quot; Do you?&amp;quot; said her mother. &amp;quot; Why?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s so red, and full of little hot caves-and it feels so nice, and you can fair smell it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;ll want mending directly,&amp;quot; replied her mother, &amp;quot; and then if your father comes he&amp;apos;ll carry on and say there never is a fire when a man comes home sweating from the pit. A publichouse is always warm enough.&amp;quot; There was silence till the boy said complainingly: &amp;quot; Make haste, our Annie.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well, I am! I can&amp;apos;t make the fire do it no faster, can I ?&amp;quot; . She keeps waffin it about so&amp;apos;s to make &amp;apos;er slow,&amp;quot; grumbled the boy. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t have such an evil imagination, child,&amp;quot; replied the mother. Soon the room was busy in the darkness with the crisp sound of crunching. The mother ate very little. She drank her tea determinedly, and sat thinking. When she rose her anger was evident in the stern unbending of her head. She looked at the pudding in the fender, and broke out: &amp;quot; It is a scandalous thing as a man can&amp;apos;t even come home to his dinner! If it&amp;apos;s crozzled up to a cinder I don&amp;apos;t see why I should care. Past his very door he goes to get to a publichouse, and here I sit with his dinner waiting for him-&amp;quot; She went out. As she dropped piece after piece of coal on the red fire, the shadows fell on the walls, till the room was almost in total darkness. &amp;quot; I canna see,&amp;quot; grumbled the invisible John. In spite of herself, the mother laughed. &amp;quot; You know the way to your mouth,&amp;quot; she said. She set the dustpan outside the door. When she came again like a tall shadow on the hearth, the lad repeated, complaining sulkily: &amp;quot;I canna see.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Good gracious!&amp;quot; cried the mother irritably, &amp;quot; you&amp;apos;re as bad as your father if it&amp;apos;s a bit dusk! &amp;quot; Nevertheless she took a paper spill from a sheaf on the mantelpiece and proceeded to light the lamp that hung from the ceiling in the middle of the room. As she reached up, her figure displayed itself just rounding with maternity. &amp;quot; Oh mother -! &amp;quot; exclaimed the girl. &amp;quot; What ? &amp;quot; said the woman, suspended in the act of putting the lampglass over the flame. The copper reflector shone handsomely on her, as she stood with uplifted arm, turning to face her daughter. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ve got a flower in your apron!&amp;quot; said the child, in a little rapture at this unusual event. &amp;quot;Goodness me!&amp;quot; exclaimed the woman, relieved. &amp;quot; One would think the house was afire.&amp;quot; She replaced the glass and waited a moment before turning up the wick. A pale shadow was seen floating vaguely on the floor. &amp;quot; Let me smell ! &amp;quot; said the child, still rapturously, coming forward and putting her face to her mother&amp;apos;s waist. &amp;quot; Go along, silly! &amp;quot; said the mother, turning up the lamp. The light revealed their suspense so that the woman felt it almost unbearable. Annie was still bending at her waist. Irritably, the mother took the flowers out from her apron-band. &amp;quot; Oh mother-don&amp;apos;t take them out! &amp;quot; Annie cried, catching her hand and trying to replace the sprig. &amp;quot;Such nonsense!&amp;quot; said the mother, turning away. The child put the pale chrysanthemums to her lips, murmuring: &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t they smell beautiful ! &amp;quot; Her mother gave a short laugh. &amp;quot;No,&amp;quot; she said, &amp;quot;not to me. It was chrysanthemums when I married him, and chrysanthemums when you were born, and the first time they ever brought him home drunk, he&amp;apos;d got brown chrysanthemums in his coat. When I smell them I could always think of that, me dragging at him to get his coat off.&amp;quot; She looked at the children. Their eyes and their parted lips were piteous. The mother sat rocking in silence for some time. Then she looked at the clock. &amp;quot; Twenty minutes to six! &amp;quot; In a tone of fine bitter carelessness she continued: &amp;quot; Eh, he&amp;apos;ll not come now till they bring him. There he&amp;apos;ll stick! He needn&amp;apos;t come rolling in here in his pit-dirt, for I won&amp;apos;t wash him. He can lie on the floorEh, what a fool I&amp;apos;ve been, what a fool ! And this is what I came here for, to this dirty hole, rats and all, for him to slink past his very door. Twice last week-he&amp;apos;s begun now &amp;quot; She silenced herself, and rose to clear the table. While for an hour or more the children played, subduedly intent, fertile of imagination, united in fear of the mother&amp;apos;s wrath, and in dread of their father&amp;apos;s homecoming, Mrs. Bates sat in her rocking-chair making a &amp;quot; singlet &amp;quot; of thick creamcolourd flannel, which gave a dull wounded sound as she tore off the grey edge. She worked at her sewing with energy, listening to the children, and her Anger wearied Itself, lay down to rest, opening Its eyes from time to time and steadily watching, Its ears raised to listen. Sometimes even her Anger quailed and shrank, and the mother suspended her sewing, tracing the footsteps that thudded along the sleepers outside; she would lift her head sharply to bid the children &amp;quot; hush,&amp;quot; but she recovered herself in time, and the footsteps went past the gate, and the children were not flung out of their play-world. But at last Annie sighed, and gave in. She glanced at her waggon of slippers, and loathed the game. She turned plaintively to her mother. &amp;quot; Mother ! &amp;quot;-but she was inarticulate. John crept out like a frog from under the sofa. His mother glanced up. &amp;quot; Yes,&amp;quot; she said, &amp;quot; just look at those shirt-sleeves!&amp;quot; The boy held them out to survey them, saying nothing. Then somebody called in a hoarse voice away down the line, and suspense bristled in the room, till two people had gone by outside, talking. &amp;quot; It is time for bed,&amp;quot; said the mother. &amp;quot; My father hasn&amp;apos;t come,&amp;quot; wailed Annie plaintively. But her mother was primed with courage. &amp;quot; Never mind. They&amp;apos;ll bring him when he does comelike a log.&amp;quot; She meant there would be no scene. &amp;quot; And he may sleep on the floor till he wakes himself. I know he&amp;apos;ll not go to work to-morrow after this ! &amp;quot; The children had their hands and faces wiped with a flannel. They were very quiet. When they had put on their nightdresses, they said their prayers, the boy mumbling. The mother looked down at them, at the brown silken bush of intertwining curls in the nape of the girl&amp;apos;s neck, at the little black head of the lad, and her heart burst with anger at their father who caused all three such distress. The children hid their faces in her skirts for comfort. When Mrs. Bates came down, the room was strangely empty, with a tension of expectancy. She took up her sewing and stitched for some time without raising her head. Meantime her anger tinged with fear. The clock struck eight and she rose suddenly, dropping her sewing on her chair. She went to the stairfoot oor, opened it, listening. Then she went out, locking the door behind her. Something scuffled in the yard, and she started, though she knew it was only the rats with which the place was overrun. The night was very dark. In the great bay of railway lines, bulked with trucks, there was no trace of light, only away back she could see a few yellow lamps at the pit-top, and the red smear of the burning pit-bank on the night. She hurried along the edge of the track, then, crossing the converging lines, came to the stile by the white gates, whence she emerged on the road. Then the fear which had led her shrank. People were walking up to New Brinsley; she saw the lights in the houses; twenty yards further on were the broad windows of the &amp;quot; Prince of Wales,&amp;quot; very warm and bright, and the loud voices of men could be heard distinctly. What a fool she had been to imagine that anything had happened to him! He was merely drinking over there at the &amp;quot;Prince of Wales.&amp;quot; She faltered. She had never yet been to fetch him, and she never would go. So she continued her walk towards the long straggling line of houses, standing blank on the highway. She entered a passage between the dwellings. &amp;quot; Mr. Rigley ?-Yes! Did you want him ? No, he&amp;apos;s not in at this minute.&amp;quot; The raw-boned woman leaned forward from her dark scullery and peered at the other, upon whom fell a dim light through the blind of the kitchen window. &amp;quot; Is it Mrs. Bates ? &amp;quot; she asked in a tone tinged with respect. &amp;quot;Yes. I wondered if your Master was at home. Mine hasn&amp;apos;t come yet.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; &amp;apos;Asn&amp;apos;t &amp;apos;e ! Oh, Jack&amp;apos;s been &amp;apos;ome an &amp;apos;ad &amp;apos;is dinner long since. E&amp;apos;s just gone for &amp;apos;alf an hour afore bedtime, but &amp;apos;e won&amp;apos;t be long. Did you call at the &amp;apos;Prince of Wales&amp;apos;?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No &amp;quot;~ &amp;quot;No, you didn&amp;apos;t like-! It&amp;apos;s not very nice.&amp;quot; The other woman was indulgent. There was an awkward pause. &amp;quot;Jack never said nothink about-about your Mester,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; No !-I expect he&amp;apos;s stuck in there!&amp;quot; Elizabeth Bates said this bitterly, and with recklessness. She knew that the woman across the yard was standing at her door listening, but she did not care. As she turned: &amp;quot; Stop a minute ! I&amp;apos;ll just go an&amp;apos; ask Jack if &amp;apos;e knows anythink,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Rigley. &amp;quot; Oh, no-I wouldn&amp;apos;t like to put-!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I will, if you&amp;apos;ll just step inside an&amp;apos; see as th&amp;apos; childer doesn&amp;apos;t come downstairs and set theirselves afire.&amp;quot; Elizabeth Bates, murmuring a remonstrance, stepped inside. The other woman apologised for the state of the room. The kitchen needed apology. There were little frocks and trousers and childish undergarments on the squab and on the floor, and a litter of playthings everywhere. On the black American cloth of the table were pieces of bread and cake, crusts, and a teapot with cold tea. &amp;quot; Eh, ours is just as bad,&amp;quot; said Elizabeth Bates, looking at the woman, not at the house. Mrs. Rigley put a shawl over her head and hurried out, saying: &amp;quot; I shanna be a minute.&amp;quot; The other sat, noting with faint disapproval the general untidiness of the room. Then she fell to counting the shoes of various sizes scattered over the floor. There were twelve. She sighed and said to herself, &amp;quot;No wonder ! &amp;quot;-glancing at the litter. There came the scratching of two pairs of feet on the yard, and the Rigleys entered. Elizabeth Bates rose. Rigley was a big man, with very large bones. His head looked particularly bony. Across his temple was a large blue scar, caused by a wound got in the pit, a wound in which the coaldust remained blue like tattooing. &amp;quot; &amp;apos;Asna &amp;apos;e come whoam yit I &amp;quot; asked the man, without any form of greeting, but with a fine rough deference and sympathy. &amp;quot; I dunna think there&amp;apos;s owt amiss-&amp;apos;e&amp;apos;s non ower theer, though ! &amp;quot;-he jerked his head to signify the &amp;quot;Prince of Wales.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; E&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;appen gone up to th&amp;apos; &amp;apos; Yew,&amp;apos; &amp;quot; said Mrs. Rigley, as if trying to make the best of it. &amp;quot; I bet that&amp;apos;s wheer he is !&amp;quot; declared the husband. There was another pause. Rigley had evidently something to get off his mind: &amp;quot; Ah left &amp;apos;im finishin&amp;apos; a stint,&amp;quot; he began. &amp;quot; Loose-all &amp;apos;ad bin gone about ten minutes when we com&amp;apos;n away, an&amp;apos; I shouted, &amp;apos; Are ter comin&amp;apos;, Walt ? &amp;apos; an&amp;apos; &amp;apos;e said, &amp;apos; Go on, Ah shanna be but a&amp;apos;ef a minnit,&amp;apos; so we com&amp;apos;n ter th&amp;apos; bottom, me an&amp;apos; Bowers, thinkin&amp;apos; as &amp;apos;e wor just behint, an&amp;apos; &amp;apos;ud come up i&amp;apos; th&amp;apos; next bantle-&amp;quot; He stood perplexed, as if answering a charge of deserting his mate. Elizabeth Bates, now again certain of disaster, hastened to reassure him: &amp;quot;I expect &amp;apos;e&amp;apos;s gone up to th&amp;apos; &amp;apos;Yew Tree,&amp;apos; as you say. It&amp;apos;s not the first time. I&amp;apos;ve fretted myself into a fever before now. He&amp;apos;ll come home when they carry him.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ay, isn&amp;apos;t it too bad! &amp;quot; deplored the other woman. &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ll just step up to Dick&amp;apos;s an&amp;apos; see if &amp;apos;e is theer,&amp;quot; offered the man, afraid of appearing alarmed, afraid of taking liberties. &amp;quot;Oh, I wouldn&amp;apos;t think of bothering you that far,&amp;quot; said Elizabeth Bates, with emphasis, but he knew she was glad of his offer. As they stumbled up the entry, Elizabeth Bates heard Rigley&amp;apos;s wife run across the yard and open her neighbour&amp;apos;s door. At this, suddenly all the blood in her body seemed to switch away from her heart. &amp;quot; Mind!&amp;quot; warned Rigley. &amp;quot;Ah&amp;apos;ve said many a time as Ah&amp;apos;d fill up them ruts in this entry, sumb&amp;apos;dy &amp;apos;11 be breakin&amp;apos; their legs yit.&amp;quot; She recovered herself and walked quickly along with the miner. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t like leaving the children in bed, and nobody in the house,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;No, you dunna!&amp;quot; he replied courteously. They were soon at the gate of the cottage. &amp;quot; Well, I shanna be many minutes. Dunna thee be frettin&amp;apos; now, &amp;apos;e&amp;apos;ll be all right,&amp;quot; said the butty. &amp;quot; Thank you very much, Mr. Rigley,&amp;quot; she replied. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s a&amp;apos; right-dunna mention it-you quite welcome!&amp;quot; he stammered, moving away. &amp;quot;I shanna be many minnits.&amp;quot; The house was quiet. Elizabeth Bates took off her hat and shawl, and rolled back the rug. When she had finished, she sat down. It was a few minutes past nine. She was startled by the rapid chuff of the winding-engine at the pit, and the sharp whir of the brakes on the rope as it descended. Again she felt the painful sweep of her blood, and she put her hand to her side, saying aloud, &amp;quot;Good gracious !-it&amp;apos;s only the nine o&amp;apos;clock deputy going down,&amp;quot; rebuking herself. She sat still, listening. Half an hour of this, and she was wearied out. &amp;quot; What am I working myself up like this for?&amp;quot; she said pitiably to herself, &amp;quot; I s&amp;apos;ll only be doing myself some damage.&amp;quot; She took out her sewing again. At a quarter to ten there were footsteps. One person! She watched for the door to open. It was an elderly woman, in a black bonnet and a black woollen shawl-his mother. This was a short woman of sixty or thereabouts, pale, with blue eyes, and her face all shapen to lines of old lament and selfpity. She shut the door and came straight to her daughter, putting her old hand on the other&amp;apos;s strong, capable hands. &amp;quot; h, Lizzie, whatever shall we do, whatever shall we do!&amp;quot; she wailed. Elizabeth drew back a little, sharply. &amp;quot; What is it, mother I &amp;quot; she said. The elder woman went and seated herself on the sofa. The tears were running down the furrows which her old laments had left. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know, child, I can&amp;apos;t tell you ! &amp;quot;-she shook her head slowly and with despair. Elizabeth sat watching her, anxious and vexed. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know,&amp;quot; replied the grandmother, sighing very deeply. &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s no end to my troubles, there isn&amp;apos;t. The things I&amp;apos;ve gone through, and now this-!&amp;quot; She wept without wiping her eyes, the tears running freely. &amp;quot; But mother,&amp;quot; interrupted Elizabeth decisively. &amp;quot; What have you come to tell me ? Let me know! &amp;quot; The grandmother slowly wiped her eyes. The loose fountains of her tears were stopped by Elizabeth&amp;apos;s sharpness. She wiped her eyes slowly. &amp;quot;Poor child ! Eh, you poor thing!&amp;quot; she wailed. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know what we&amp;apos;re going to do, I don&amp;apos;t-and you as you areit&amp;apos;s an awful thing, it is indeed an awful thing!&amp;quot; Elizabeth waited. &amp;quot; Is he dead ? &amp;quot; she asked, and at the words her heart swung violently, though she felt a slight flush of shame at the ultimate extravagance of the question. Her words sufficiently startled the old lady. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t say so, Elizabeth ! We&amp;apos;ll hope it&amp;apos;s not as bad as that; no, the Lord will spare us that, Elizabeth. Jack Rigley came just as I was sittin&amp;apos; down to a glass afore going to bed, an&amp;apos; &amp;apos;e said, &amp;quot;Appen you&amp;apos;ll go down th&amp;apos; line, Mrs. Bates. Walt&amp;apos;s had an accident. &amp;apos;Appen you&amp;apos;ll go an&amp;apos; sit wi&amp;apos; &amp;apos;er till we can get him home.&amp;apos; I had&amp;apos;t time to ask him a word afore he was gone. An&amp;apos; I put my bonnet on an&amp;apos; come straight down to you, Lizzie. I thought to myself, &amp;apos; Eh, that poor blessed child, if anybody should come an&amp;apos; tell her of a sudden, there&amp;apos;s no knowin&amp;apos; what&amp;apos;ll &amp;apos;appen to &amp;apos;er.&amp;apos; You mustn&amp;apos;t let it upset you, Lizzie-you mustn&amp;apos;t, child. Think of that poor little thing as isn&amp;apos;t here by six months-or is it five, Lizzie ? Ay! &amp;quot;-the old woman shook her head-&amp;quot; time slips on, it slips on ! Ay ! &amp;quot; Elizabeth&amp;apos;s thoughts were busy elsewhere. If he was killed -would she be able to manage on the little pension and what she could earn ?-she counted up rapidly. If he was hurtthey wouldn&amp;apos;t take him to the hospital-how tiresome he would be to nurse !-but perhaps she&amp;apos;d be able to get him away from the drink and his hateful ways. She would-while he was ill. The tears came to her eyes at the picture. Then in thought she arose once more-he had killed her &amp;quot; sentiment &amp;quot;-and began to consider the children. At any rate she was absolutely necessary for them. She clung to the thought of the children. &amp;quot; Ay ! &amp;quot; repeated the old woman, &amp;quot; it seems but a week or two since he brought me his first wages. Ay-he was a good lad, Elizabeth, he was a good lad. I don&amp;apos;t know-I don&amp;apos;t know why he got to be such a trouble, I don&amp;apos;t. He was a good lad at home, a dear lad. But there&amp;apos;s no mistake he&amp;apos;s been a handful of trouble, he has ! I hope the Lord&amp;apos;ll spare him to mend his ways. I hope so, I hope so. You&amp;apos;ve had a sight o&amp;apos; trouble with him, Elizabeth, you have indeed. But he was a good lad wi&amp;apos; me, he was, there&amp;apos;s no denying. I don&amp;apos;t know how it is . . . The old woman continued to muse aloud, a monotonous plaintive sound, while Elizabeth thought concentratedly, startled once, when she heard the winding-engine chuff quickly, and the brakes skirr with a shriek. Then she heard the engine more slowly, and the brakes made no sound. The old woman did not notice. Elizabeth waited in suspense. The motherin-law talked, with lapses into silence. &amp;quot; But he wasn&amp;apos;t your son, Lizzie, an&amp;apos; it makes a difference. Whatever he was, I remember him when he was little, a dear little lad as ever you could wish to set eyes on.&amp;quot; It was half-past ten, and the old woman was saying: &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ve nothing left-but trouble; and you&amp;apos;re never too old for trouble, never too old for that &amp;quot; when the gate banged back, and there were heavy feet on the steps. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll go, Lizzie, let me go,&amp;quot; cried the old woman, rising. But Elizabeth was at the door. It was a man in pit-clothes. &amp;quot; They&amp;apos;re bringin&amp;apos; &amp;apos;im in, Missis,&amp;quot; he said, simply. Elizabeth&amp;apos;s heart halted a moment. Then it surged on again, almost suffocating her. &amp;quot; Is he-is it bad ? &amp;quot; she asked. The man nodded and turned away, looking at the garden: &amp;quot; The doctor says &amp;apos;e&amp;apos;d been dead hours. &amp;apos;E saw &amp;apos;im i&amp;apos; th&amp;apos; lamp-cabin.&amp;quot; The old woman, who stood just behind Elizabeth, dropped into a chair, and folded her hands, crying: &amp;quot;Oh, my boy, my boy! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Hush! &amp;quot; said Elizabeth, with a sharp twitch of a frown. &amp;quot;Be still, mother, don&amp;apos;t waken th&amp;apos; children: I wouldn&amp;apos;t have them down for anything! &amp;quot; The old woman moaned softly, rocking herself. The man was turning away. Elizabeth took a step forward. &amp;quot;How was it ? &amp;quot; she asked. &amp;quot;Well, it wor like this,&amp;quot; the man replied, very ill at ease. &amp;quot;&amp;apos;E wor finishin&amp;apos; a stint, an&amp;apos; th&amp;apos; butties &amp;apos;ad gone, an&amp;apos; a lot o&amp;apos; stuff come down atop &amp;apos;n &amp;apos;im.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And is he much-has it made a mess of him ?&amp;quot; asked the widow, with a shudder. &amp;quot; No,&amp;quot; said the man, &amp;quot; it fell at th&amp;apos; back of &amp;apos;im. &amp;apos;E wor under th&amp;apos; face, tha sees, an&amp;apos; it niver touched &amp;apos;im. It shut &amp;apos;im in. &amp;apos;E wor smothered.&amp;quot; Elizabeth shrank back. She heard the old woman behind her cry: &amp;quot;What ?-did &amp;apos;e say &amp;apos;e was suffocated?&amp;quot; The man replied, more loudly: &amp;quot; Yes-that&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;ow it wor!&amp;quot; Then the old woman wailed aloud, and this relieved Elizabeth. &amp;quot; Oh, mother,&amp;quot; she said, putting her arms round the old woman, &amp;quot; don&amp;apos;t waken th&amp;apos; children, don&amp;apos;t waken th&amp;apos; children.&amp;quot; She wept a little, while the old mother rocked herself and moaned. Elizabeth remembered that they were bringing him home, and she must be ready. &amp;quot;They&amp;apos;ll lay him in the parlour,&amp;quot; she said to herself, standing a moment pale and perplexed. Then she lighted a candle and went into the tiny room. The air was cold and damp, but she could not make a fire, there was no fireplace. She set down the candle and looked round. The candlelight glittered on the lustre-glasses, on the two vases that held some of the pink chrysanthemums, and on the dark mahogany. There was a cold, deathly smell of chrysanthemums in the room. Elizabeth stood looking at the flowers. She turned away, and calculated whether there would be room to lay him on the floor, between the couch and the chiffonier. She pushed the chairs aside. There would be room to lay him down and to step round him. Then she fetched the old red tablecloth, and another old cloth, spreading them down to save her bit of carpet. She shivered on leaving the parlour; so, from the dresser-drawer she took a clean shirt and put it at the fire to air. All the time her mother-in-law was rocking herself in the chair and moaning. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ll have to move from there, mother,&amp;quot; said Elizabeth. &amp;quot;They&amp;apos;ll be bringing him in. Come in the rocker.&amp;quot; The old mother rose mechanically, and seated herself by the fire, continuing to lament. Elizabeth went into the pantry for another candle, and there, in the little penthouse under the naked tiles, she heard them coming. She stood still in the pantry doorway, listening. She heard them pass the end of the house, and come awkwardly down the three steps, a jumble of shuffling footsteps and muttering voices. The old woman was silent. The men were in the yard. Then Elizabeth heard Matthews, the manager of the pit, say: &amp;quot; You go in first, Jim. Mind ! &amp;quot; The door came open, and the two women saw a collier backing into the room, holding one end of a stretcher, on which they could see the nailed pit-boots of the dead man. The two carriers halted, the man at the head stooping at the lintel of the door. &amp;quot; Wheer will you have him?&amp;quot; asked the manager, a short, white-bearded old man. Elizabeth roused herself and came from the pantry carrying the unlighted candle. &amp;quot; In the parlour,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; In there, Jim! &amp;quot; pointed the manager, and the carriers backed round into the tiny room. The coat with which they had covered the body fell off as they awkwardly turned through the two doorways, and the women saw their man, naked to the waist, lying stripped for work. Immediately the old woman began to moan in a low voice, &amp;quot; My boy ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Lay th&amp;apos; stretcher at th&amp;apos; side,&amp;quot; snapped the manager, an&amp;apos; put &amp;apos;im on th&amp;apos; cloths. Mind now, mind! Look you now-! &amp;quot; One of the men had knocked off a vase of chrysanthemums. He stared awkwardly, then they set down the stretcher. Elizabeth did not look at her husband. As soon as she could get in the room, she went and picked up the broken vase and the flowers. &amp;quot; Wait a minute! &amp;quot; she said. The three men waited in silence while she mopped up the water with a duster. &amp;quot; Eh, what a job, what a job, to be sure! &amp;quot; the manager was saying, rubbing his brow with trouble and perplexity. &amp;quot;Never knew such a thing in my life, never! They&amp;apos;d no business to ha&amp;apos; left &amp;apos;im. I never knew such a thing in my life ! Fell over him clean as a whistle, an&amp;apos; shut him in. Not ten feet of space, there wasn&amp;apos;t-yet it never bruised him.&amp;quot; He looked down at the dead man, lying serene, half naked, all grimed with coal-dust. &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Sphyxiated,&amp;apos; the doctor said. &amp;quot;I never knew anything like it. It seems as if it was done o&amp;apos; purpose. Clean over him, an&amp;apos; shut &amp;apos;im in, like a vault &amp;quot;-he made a sweeping gesture with his hand. &amp;quot; It woer that!&amp;quot; corroborated one of the men. They forced the horror of the thing upon the woman&amp;apos;s imagination. &amp;quot;Steady, Missis!&amp;quot; said the manager. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s a bad job, I know it is, but &amp;quot; Then they heard the girl&amp;apos;s voice upstairs calling shrilly: &amp;quot;Mother, mother-who is it ? Mother, who is it ? &amp;quot; Elizabeth hurried to the foot of the stairs and opened the door: &amp;quot; Go to sleep! &amp;quot; she commanded sharply. &amp;quot; What are you shouting about ? Go to sleep at once-there&amp;apos;s nothing-&amp;quot; Then she began to mount the stairs. They could hear her on the boards, and on the plaster floor of the little bedroom. They could hear her distinctly: &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s the matter now ?-what&amp;apos;s the matter with you, silly thing ? &amp;quot;-her voice was much gentler than when she had called at the foot of the stairs. &amp;quot; I thought it was some men come,&amp;quot; said the plaintive voice of the child. &amp;quot; They only brought your father home. There&amp;apos;s nothing to make a fuss about. Go to sleep now, like a good child.&amp;quot; They could imagine her smoothing the bedclothes over the shoulders of the soothed children. &amp;quot; Is he drunk ? &amp;quot; asked the girl, timidly, faintly. &amp;quot;No! Don&amp;apos;t be silly. He-he&amp;apos;s asleep.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is he asleep downstairs?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes-and don&amp;apos;t wake him.&amp;quot; There was silence for a moment, then the men heard the frightened child again: &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s that noise ? Is it him asleep ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes! He&amp;apos;s all right, what are you bothering for?&amp;quot; The noise was the grandmother moaning. She was quite oblivious of everything, sitting on her chair rocking and moaning. The manager put his hand on her arm and bade her &amp;quot; Sh-sh ! ! &amp;quot; The old woman opened her eyes and looked at him. She was shocked by this interruption, so she became quiet. &amp;quot;What time is it ? &amp;quot;-the plaintive thin voice of the child, sinking back into sleep, asked this last question. &amp;quot; Ten o&amp;apos;clock,&amp;quot; answered the mother softly. Then she must have bent down and kissed the children. Matthews beckoned to the men to come away. They put on their caps and took up the stretcher. Stepping over the body, they tiptoed out of the house. None of them spoke till they were far from the wakeful children. When Elizabeth came down she found her mother alone on the parlour floor, with the face of her son between her hands, the tears dropping on him. &amp;quot; We must lay him out,&amp;quot; the wife whispered softly. She ut on the kettle, then returning knelt at the feet, and uegan to unfasten the knotted leather laces. The room was very dim with only one candle, so that she had to bend her face almost to the floor. At last she got off the heavy boots and put them away. She pulled off his stockings, vexed by the knot of the dirty tape garter. Like most miners, he was fairly clean in his person, so that she was not ashamed for him. Elizabeth unfastened the leathern belt from round his waist. &amp;quot;You must help me now,&amp;quot; she whispered reverently to the old woman. Together they stripped the man. When they arose, saw him lying in the reckless dignity of death, both women bowed in primeval awe, while the tears of motherhood rose in each. For a few moments they stood religiously silent. Then the mother-feeling prevailed. Elizabeth knelt down, put her arms round him, laid her cheek on his breast. He was still warm, for the mine was hot where he had died. His mother had his face between her hands, and was murmuring incoherently. The old tears fell in succession as drops from wet leaves; the woman was not weeping, merely her tears flowed. Elizabeth embraced the body of her husband, with cheek and lips. Suddenly she felt jealous that the mother held his head. She rose, went into the kitchen, where she poured warm water into a bowl, brought soap and flannel and a soft towel. &amp;quot; I must wash him,&amp;quot; she said decisively. Then the old mother rose stiffly, and watched Elizabeth as she gently washed his face, tenderly, as if he were a child, brushing the big blonde moustache from his mouth with the flannel. The old woman, jealous, said: &amp;quot; Let me wipe him! &amp;quot;-and she kneeled on the other side drying slowly as Elizabeth washed, her big black bonnet sometimes brushing the dark head of her daughter. They worked thus in silence for a long time. Sometimes they forgot it was death, and the touch of the man&amp;apos;s body gave them strange thrills, different in each of the women; secret thrills that made them turn one from the other, and left them with a keen sadness. At last it was finished. He was a man of handsome figure and genial face, which showed no traces of the disfigurement of drink. He was blonde, full-fleshed, with fine round limbs. &amp;quot; Bless him,&amp;quot; whispered his mother, looking always at his face, &amp;quot; he looks as if he was just waking up. Dear lad-bless him!&amp;quot; She spoke in a faint, sibilant rapture. Elizabeth sank down again to the floor, and put her face against his neck, and trembled and shuddered till she was tired. The old woman wept slow, noiseless tears, touching him, regarding him with endless fondness and unwearying interest. &amp;quot; White as milk he is, clear as a twelve-month baby, bless him, the darling ! &amp;quot; she whispered to herself. &amp;quot; Not a mark on him, clear and clean and white, beautiful as ever a child was made,&amp;quot; she murmured with pride. Elizabeth kept her face hidden. &amp;quot; He went peaceful, Lizzie-peaceful as sleep. Isn&amp;apos;t it wonderful ? You&amp;apos;d think he was smiling a bit. &amp;apos;Appen he made it all right, Lizzie, shut in there. He&amp;apos;d have time. He wouldn&amp;apos;t look like this if he hadn&amp;apos;t made his peace. He&amp;apos;s smiling a bit. Eh, but he used to have a hearty laugh. I loved to hear it. He&amp;apos;s like he was when 1 had him, Lizzie. The heartiest laugh he had-&amp;quot; Elizabeth looked up. The man&amp;apos;s mouth was fallen back, slightly open under the cover of the moustache. The eyes, half shut, did not show glazed by the small candlelight. His wife looked at him. He seemed to be dreaming back, half awake. Life with its smoky burning gone from him, had left a purity and a candour like an adolescent&amp;apos;s moulded upon his reverie. His intrinsic beauty was evident now. She had not been mistaken in him, as often she had bitterly confessed to herself she was. The beauty of his youth, of his eighteen years, of the time when life had settled on him, as in adolescence it settles on youth, bringing a mission to fulfil and equipment therefor, this beauty shone almost unstained again. It was this adolescent &amp;quot;he,&amp;quot; the young man looking round to see which way, that Elizabeth had loved. He had come from the discipleship of youth, through the Pentecost of adolescence, pledged to keep with honour his own individuality, to be steadily and unquenchably himself, electing his own masters and serving them till the wages were won. He betrayed himself in his search for amusement. Let Education teach us to amuse ourselves, necessity will train us to work. Once out of the pit, there was nothing to interest this man. He sought the public-house, where, by paying the price of his own integrity, he found amusement; destroying the clamours for activity, because he knew not what form the activities might take. The miner turned miscreant to himself, easing the ache of dissatisfaction by destroying the part of him which ached. Little by little the recreant maimed and destroyed himself. It was this recreant his wife had hated so bitterly, had fought against so strenuously. She had strove, all the years of his falling off, had strove with all her force to save the man she had known new-bucklered with beauty and strength. In a wild and bloody passion she fought the recreant. Now this lay killed, the clean young knight was brought home to her. Elizabeth bowed her head upon the body and wept. She put her arms round him, kissed the smooth ripples below his breasts, bowed her forehead on him in submission. Faithful to her deeper sense of honour, she uttered no word of sorrow in her heart. Upright in soul are women, however they bow the swerving body. She owned the beauty of the blow. And all the while her heart was bursting with grief and pity for him. What had he suffered ? What stretch of horror for this helpless man! She wept herself almost in agony. She had not been able to help him. Never again would she be able to help him. It was grief unutterable to think that now all was over between them. Even if it were a case of meeting in the next world, he would not need her there; it would be different. She saw the great episode of her life closed with him, and grief was a passion. The old mother was hushed in awe. She, the elder, less honourable woman, had said: &amp;quot; She drives him to it, she makes him ten thousand times worse.&amp;quot; But now the old mother bowed down in respect for the wife. As the passion of Elizabeth&amp;apos;s grief grew more, the old woman shrank and tried to avoid it. &amp;quot; Have you got his shirt, &amp;apos;Lizabeth I&amp;quot; Flizabeth wept without answering, though she strove to lull and recover. At last she rose and went into the kitchen. Returning: &amp;quot; It is aired,&amp;quot; she said, grasping the cotton shirt here and there to try. She was sorry to disturb him, but he could not lie naked. It was hard work to clothe him. He was so heavy and helpless, more helpless than a baby fallen heavily asleep. They had to struggle with him as if he were a rebellious child. This made Elizabeth&amp;apos;s heart weep again. Yet more joy was mixed in her emotion than she knew. He might have come home ugly, befouled, so that she would have had a loathly, strange creature to combat. Ah! how she had fought that him, the disfigured coward, which gradually replaced her man! How wise of death to be so silent! Even now her fear could not trust him to speak. Yet he was restored to her fair, unblemished, fresh as for the splendour of a fight.</FullText></Record>