<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2436814</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130955</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>My Visit to Auber</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Sep 1914</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19140901</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Grierson</LastName><FirstName>Francis</FirstName><PersonName>Francis Grierson</PersonName><OriginalForm>Grierson, Francis</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Austin</FirstName><PersonName>Austin Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Austin</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>173</StartPage><EndPage>186</EndPage><Pagination>173-186</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2436814/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>My Visit to Auber By Francis Grierson AT the appointed time for my visit to Auber, Samuel David called for me at the Grand Hotel. A short walk brought us to the rue Bergere and the Conservatoire. On learning that the Director could not receive us for some twenty minutes or more, David conducted me into the court. It was rectangular, as if in keeping with some strange combination of music and mathematics. My guide looked at me with that air of mingled selfcomplacency and bland cynicism peculiar to his temperament, and began to prepare me for the presence of the most feared and most respected musical celebrity of Paris, the octogenarian Auber, whose jokes, bows mots, and persiflage were almost as famous as his operas, and whose compositions had for upwards of sixty years represented the national spirit of French music. I was informed that Auber had been Director of the Conservatoire for the extraordinary period of twenty-nine years; that, besides being the most celebrated French composer living, his wit and humour were as spontaneous and perennial as his music; and that, all things considered, he was a very wonderful man. And I found it all true; for now if I were asked to name the most typical Frenchman I ever met I should not hesitate to name Auber. He was the embodiment of the spontaneity, the vivacity, and the genius of the French character of that epoch. He put into his music what Beranger had put into French poetry. Samuel David, after a good deal of talk about the Conservatoire, said: &amp;quot; This courtyard is not gay.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No,&amp;quot; I remarked; &amp;quot; it is enough to put a damper on the aspirations of any novice coming here in search of harmony and inspiration.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ah,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot;the Conservatoire itself is one of the gayest and most amusing places in Paris. No one dies of ennui here, although one or two have had endings that were tragic enough.&amp;quot; Just then I heard sounds of the tuning of stringed instruments, and David remarked: &amp;quot;At present you will hear a curious confusion of noises which you will find the reverse of musical; it is about this time the ckarivari begins.&amp;quot; And, effectively, it was beginning. From a window at our right the sounds of viols sent forth gruntings that were answered by high squeaks from fiddles in another room; here and there could be heard the quacking of clarionets, the piping of flutes, the rumbling of the violoncello, the bleating of the hautbois, and over all the high note of an incipient prima donna, or a young man with a cold trying to reach an impossible pitch. It required no great powers of imagination to form a mental picture of all the lunatics in Paris assembled here for a grand operatic rehearsal. Samuel David, seeing my surprise, recounted a joke uttered by Auber in this same courtyard not long before. The Director was escorting a distinguished visitor through the surprises of the Conservatoire, and when they had got to the middle of this court the visitor halted to listen, bewildered with the bedlam of conflicting sounds, when all at once a terrible cry came from one of the windows in front of them. Auber, always on the alert for a jest, tapped his visitor on the shoulder with the reassuring remark: &amp;quot;Don&amp;apos;t be alarmed, it&amp;apos;s the bleeding hour; they are only taking a few ounces from a tenor. It will be the turn of the basso next; he was at a banquet last night, and they will take at least half a pint from him&amp;quot;; at which the visitor, more bewildered than ever, looked what he could not speak. Then he added, with a malicious twinkle in his brown eyes: &amp;quot;No, this is not a slaughter-house; we only tame them here. The slaughtering occurs when they make their debut.&amp;quot; At last, after waiting for more than half an hour, we went upstairs and were shown into the Director&amp;apos;s receptionroom. I found myself in the presence of the greatest little man I ever encountered. Not that he looked distinguished. He might have passed for an old-clothes man had he been dressed somewhat differently. He was in his eighty-sixth year, and looked about sixty. His face had that look of calm contentment that only comes with years of success and established authority. He received me with mingled affability and indifference. His questions were abrupt, matter-of-fact, much as if I had come to take his measure for a suit of clothes or to talk about the price of stocks. I had not been in the room more than two or three minutes when he asked me to take my seat at the piano and improvise. Had he asked me to stand on my head it would have been just the same. The small upright instrument looked about as old as the little nonchalant don&amp;apos;t-care-a-fiddlestick Director, and I pictured to myself an auction mart, with the piano-stool a weighing machine, with an indicator pointing now to fair, now to middling, now to good, or very good, and I could only think of the words: &amp;quot;This pig weighs so many pounds, so many ounces&amp;quot;; or, &amp;quot; This gift horse has had his mouth examined; I have seen worse horses given away and end by winning the Grand Prix.&amp;quot; I was so filled with the humour of the situation that I ceased playing and asked to be excused from further effort. I became absorbed in the personality of the Director, who seemed greatly puzzled. &amp;quot; What can I say? &amp;quot; he remarked to David. I did not shrink from hearing his judgment; on this question my mind was a blank. After some moments&amp;apos; reflection he added: &amp;quot; You see, this is a special talent. You remember that young man, Jules Guerin, from Marseilles? No, you don&amp;apos;t remember him; it was during Cherubini&amp;apos;s directorship. Well, young Guerin could only play by ear, but this young man -alluding to me-&amp;quot; does not imitate, he improvises; and you tell me he has never been able to learn music. It is very curious. We have never had such a pupil here. With him, music must be altogether intuitional. You know yourself, as an old pupil of the Conservatoire, that we have no rules here for intuition.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Precisely,&amp;quot; said David; &amp;quot; I only desire to have your opinion. His place in the musical world is quite exceptional; he not only cannot master the rules of harmony, but he cannot even read music at sight, and he tells me he has given up trying to learn.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Ah! &amp;quot; exclaimed Auber, &amp;quot; c&amp;apos;est tout a fait extraordinaire ! &amp;quot;-and he looked at me as if in the short interval I had grown horns and might become formidable. But when David said: &amp;quot;What is still more curious, he comes of an unmusical family,&amp;quot; the good Director simply sat down and looked at me, while he muttered to himself: &amp;quot;C&amp;apos;est incroyable ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What he has played here to-day is insignificant compared to what I have heard him play elsewhere.&amp;quot; This remark brought Auber out of his reverie. &amp;quot; I know very well,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot; this is not the place for the full expression of a talent like that. Come to dejeuner with me to-morrow; then the young man will feel more at ease, and his music, I am certain, will be very different.&amp;quot; Auber lived in his own house, 24 rue Saint-Georges. When we arrived there on the following day an octogenarian concierge directed us to the floor above, where we were told a valet de chambre would usher us into the presence of the great man. Samuel David rang, and the door was opened by a wrinkled and frigid valet with the air of a mannikin and as old as the concierge. He gave us an icy reception. He did not take the trouble to announce our names, but told us to go ahead unannounced as if we were on our way to commit suicide; but, in spite of our frigid reception at the door, we found Auber awaiting us and in the best of humour. We were soon seated at table, and another servant made his appearance-older, if possible, than any we had yet seen, and I became aware that I was in a habitation of walking shadows. Auber had five domestics, the youngest, whom he called the baby, being the coachman, who was seventy-five, and the Director told us this coachman had only been thirty-five years in his service. Auber must have guessed what our thoughts were, for he playfully alluded to his domestics several times during the meal. &amp;quot; You eat very little, cher mailtre,&amp;quot; remarked David. &amp;quot; I find one meal a day sufficient,&amp;quot; was Aubers reply; and I thought to myself, &amp;quot;That is all that is necessary to keep so contented a spirit in so small a body.&amp;quot; While sitting at the table I began to get away from the Paris of the last days of the Second Empire. My imagination went back to the time when the old young man with the placid wrinkles and brown eyes must have heard people talk of the tragic ending of Louis XVI. and the passing of Robespierre, Auber being about ten years of age at the time of the latter occurrence. He had a vivid recollection of the advent of Bonaparte, the scenes following the battle of Waterloo, the return of the Bouruons, and the Revolution of i830. He had lived under two emperors, four kings, and two presidents; had been an eye-witness of the entrance of the Allied Armies into Paris; had experienced the joys, pageants, thrills, illusions, and disillusions of four social epochs; and there he sat as full of life as ever, a living embodiment of the romance and vitality of a typical Parisian, for he refused to leave Paris even for a day. There he sat, this man who was used to all the luxuries of the table, eating a plain omelet, waited on by servants who might have been phantoms from the past, he the only one there with a young heart and a fertile imagination. But he was not master in his own house. The forbidding old valet was his master. &amp;quot;Let them come the day after to-morrow,&amp;quot; he would say in a surly tone; &amp;quot;we cannot receive them to-morrow.&amp;quot; To which Auber would reply, without a tinge of illhumour: &amp;quot;Very well, let it be after to-morrow.&amp;quot; This valet stood behind Auber during the dejeuxer like some apparition at a banquet, as if to remind the composer of his age and compel him to direct his wits to the irreparable past and his imagination to the inevitable future. But nothing could mar the placid live-by-the-day existence of this wonderful man. Auber and Rossini had been great friends. The Director had-much to say about the composer of &amp;quot; William Tell,&amp;quot; whose funeral he had witnessed in the company of Samuel David the previous November. &amp;quot;Alas! they are all passing away,&amp;quot; he said to David at the funeral; &amp;quot; after Meyerbeer it is Rossini, next it will be the turn of poor Thomas.&amp;quot; The amusing part of this remark consisted in the fact that Auber was twenty-nine years older than Ambroise Thomas, who was at that moment enjoying the best of health. On another occasion someone remarked that the composer of &amp;quot;Mignon&amp;quot; seemed much changed of late, when Auber replied: &amp;quot; Thomas never changes; he was born changed.&amp;quot; The conversation turned on Rossini and his superstitions. &amp;quot; Do you know,&amp;quot; said Auber, &amp;quot; when I was in Rossini&amp;apos;s company I always felt the influence of his superstitions. This Italian could do nothing without the aid of his charms to avert the influence of the Evil-eye. A few days before the representation of my opera, &amp;apos;Le Premier Jour de Bonheur,&amp;apos; I found myself in the company of Rossini, looking at the crowd skating on the lake of the Bois de Boulogne. I asked one of my lady friends who was there why she was not skating. She jokingly replied that she would not consent to run such a risk unless I accompanied her on the ice. I was just putting on my skates, when Rossini took me by the arm and cried: &amp;quot;&amp;apos; Unfortunate man! What if you have a fall just on the eve of the first night of your new opera? &amp;apos; &amp;quot;&amp;apos;You are right,&amp;apos; I replied. &amp;apos;I shall take no risks on the ice until after the premiere.&amp;apos; &amp;quot;Rossini then began to tell us strange stories about the Comte de G . . . and his Evil-eye, and some of the curious incidents brought about by this, when we suddenly discovered the Comte walking towards the lake, accompanied by the Duc d&amp;apos;A . . ., who was another jettatura. &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Heaven preserve us!&amp;apos; cried Rossini, &amp;apos;let no one venture on the ice now,&amp;apos; at the same time clutching the coral horns that hung on his watch-chain. &amp;quot; Hardly had he finished the words when we heard a loud cracking of the ice in the middle of the lake, where hundreds of people were skating. Several persons sank to the bottom. . . . My lady friend fainted, and Rossini assisted me in getting her into my coupd, when we drove away. As for Rossini, he found it impossible to quit the place fast enough. This same lady was invited to dine with him some days later, and all through the dinner he talked of nothing but the Evil-eye, his horror of Friday, and the number thirteen. Nothing could induce him to invite anyone to luncheon or dinner on a Friday. You know Saturday was his day. He then had company at both meals.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But his miserable wife, Olympe, spoiled everything,&amp;quot; remarked David. &amp;quot;The last time I dined there the macaroni was so good that I asked for more, when she cried out, &amp;apos;Why, I thought you had been served.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; &amp;quot;Ah,&amp;quot; said Auber, the expression on his face being impossible to describe, &amp;quot;you didn&amp;apos;t know the trick.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;What was it?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;To dine before the dinner.&amp;quot; David listened attentively. &amp;quot;Once, at a time when I ate much more than I do now,&amp;quot; continued Auber, &amp;quot; I was invited to a big dinnerparty at Rossini&amp;apos;s, and I knew from experience the larger the company the less one would get to eat. What did I do? I stepped into Bignon&amp;apos;s about six o&amp;apos;clock and ordered a consomme velours, to be followed by a succulent bi//ek. Just as I arrived at Bignon&amp;apos;s I saw someone enter the establishment whose figure seemed familiar. It was Ambroise Thomas. He gave me a look of despair. &amp;apos;What,&amp;apos; I cried, &amp;apos;you are due at Rossini&amp;apos;s for dinner at seven, and here you are in a restaurant! &amp;apos; Poor Thomas was the picture of a comedian when he hears some grave news, his face full of unutterable woe. I came to his relief by saying, &amp;apos;I, too, am on my way to Rossini&amp;apos;s for dinner, so we&amp;apos;ll dine here together before we give Olympe the satisfaction of starving us.&amp;apos; Even then Thomas hardly knew what to say. I burst out laughing. You know his habitual melancholy. &amp;apos;Ah, ah,&amp;apos; he stammered at last, &amp;apos;but what will Rossini say, what will everyone say, if this gets out?&amp;apos; &amp;quot; When we had eaten sufficient at Bignon&amp;apos;s we went to Rossini&amp;apos;s, where all was ready for dinner. I noticed among the guests more than one big eater, and you know how Olympe detested such people. She took a delight in giving them bones. When the pheasant was passed round, I had my eye on a guest who I knew had a horror of bones. Olympe had placed him exactly where he would be most likely to get the pickings of any game there might be. Now, if he disliked one thing more than wings it was legs, and he was offered a leg. &amp;quot;One day four of us determined to play her a trick which would, perhaps, serve her as a lesson. We arranged to dine well at Bignon&amp;apos;s, so as to leave us all without the possibility of an appetite for dinner at Rossini&amp;apos;s. Seven o&amp;apos;clock found us seated in Rossini&amp;apos;s dining-room in the best of spirits, certain of one evening&amp;apos;s amusement at the expense of the amiable Olympe. We made a pretence of eating. We talked while some of the others were trying in vain to appease good appetites, and it was not long before the watchful hostess began to suspect something was wrong. Seeing how intrigued she was, we became gayer and gayer, and with the aid of some of Rossini&amp;apos;s wine we ended by having one of the most amusing evenings we ever spent in the whole course of our lives. Olympe could not account for our gaiety, considering that we had eaten so little, but at last she must have suspected the truth, for during the next few weeks she gave her guests more to eat; but she soon returned to the old tricks, and the mot d&amp;apos;ordre became general among the knowing ones: always dine before dining with Rossini. &amp;quot; One of our professors used to send Rossini a present of royans, those delicious sardines that come from Bordeaux; you know they cannot be had here. Rossini requested him not to send the royans on a Saturday, as that was the day he had company at both meals, and he preferred eating the sardines alone. He gave one to Olympe, eating the other eleven himself.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He was extraordinary! &amp;quot; exclaimed David. &amp;quot; He was just as amusing as his music was delightful.&amp;quot; During the last years of Rossini&amp;apos;s life it was said in Paris that there were two courts-one presided over by the Empress at the Tuileries, the other by Rossini at his salon. His genius, his wit, his inextinguishable humour were such that nothing could mar the fascination of his soirees, and artists, writers, musicians, and singers forgot or overlooked the proverbial meanness of what people called his harpie. The conversation turned on the inevitable quarrels and jealousies of composers and musicians. Hector Berlioz, that wonderful musician, who died on March 9th, i869, was discussed. For a long time the compositions of Berlioz were regarded by many French composers and critics as the music of a madman. The same thing was said of the symphonies of Beethoven and the music-dramas of Wagner. Composers and critics quarrelled among themselves like so many cats and dogs. Words fail to give an adequate notion of the malice and fury displayed by the different factions. Wagner opposed Meyerbeer, Berlioz opposed Wagner, while Hal6vy and Auber were regarded as the bites noires of Berlioz. Liszt, the only musician among them with a level head and a sort of innate cosmopolitan musical culture, did his best to make the works of Berlioz known in Austria and Germany while trying to make the genius of Wagner familiar to the French. Liszt had the true flair in everything pertaining to musical originality. Auber, continuing the conversation. said: &amp;quot;You know Grillparzer&amp;apos;s mot? &amp;apos;Berlioz is a genius without talent.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; &amp;quot; And I heard Berlioz declare that Rossini had a pretty talent but no genius,&amp;quot; remarked David. &amp;quot; Berlioz expected the Emperor to appoint him director of music at the Tuileries, but I was appointed instead, and he never forgave me,&amp;quot; said Auber. &amp;quot;I think,&amp;quot; he continued, after a moment, &amp;quot; that Paganini helped more than Liszt to make Berlioz known. Paganini, as d&amp;apos;Ortigue says in his book, united in himself all sorts of glory; he was not satisfied with being a great musician and composer, artiste criateur; in presenting Berlioz with twenty thousand francs the prince of virtuosos made his name immortal. He gave Berlioz the means of working in peace and quiet for the space of three years. Paganini, after hearing a fine performance of Berlioz&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Harold&amp;apos; symphony, declared that never in his life had he been so moved. He took Berlioz by the arm and led him forward before the orchestra and on his knees kissed the hands of Berlioz. &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Beethoven is dead,&amp;apos; cried Paganini, &amp;apos;but he lives again in Berlioz! &amp;quot;&amp;apos; After that people began to talk about the music of Berlioz. Speaking to some of the pupils at the Conservatoire, Auber said of a certain young lady whose nose was pointed and long, and who persisted in singing false, &amp;quot;If her hearing was as long as her nose, she would be a great success.&amp;quot; He made the remark that he thought fewer eccentric pupils were to be seen at the Conservatoire than formerly. David having brought up the subject of the tragic end of a young creole named Bartholomeo, who was a pupil in Allard&amp;apos;s class, Auber, who was well acquainted with all the details, said: &amp;quot;There were some years when the Conservatoire seemed to be given over to pupils who refused to be influenced or governed by any rules of classical art. The worst case of the kind was that of the unfortunate creole Bartholomeo. Allard had hopes of making Bartholomeo a great violinist, and began by letting him have his own way in many things, believing that he would settle down to work and imitate only the best examples. However, he was rudely disappointed. Bartholomeo began by astonishing his teacher and all the members of the class by his amazing execution. He did what he pleased with his violin. He played according to his own notions; he created his own rules. He was like so many others who mistake eccentricity for genius. He was stubborn beyond any pupil we ever had. Allard said it was like trying to tame a musical tiger. He got it into his head that he was a second Paganini. He spoiled the most beautiful melodies by his absurd additions, ridiculous variations, the most outri combinations of double chords, an incessant vibrato, a perpetual reaching for the highest notes. He was Allard&amp;apos;s bete noire. The unhappy professor came to me complaining that he was at his wits&amp;apos; end with the incorrigible Bartholomeo. What Allard feared most was that his crazy pupil would leave the Conservatoire one day and announce himself as a graduate. Things got so bad that Allard was kept awake at night trying to devise means to tame his pupil. He asked me to hear him play and judge for myself. Before the creole had played a dozen bars I saw his case was hopeless. &amp;quot;We all liked Bartholomeo; he was a good boy, but, as you see, he refused to learn. Examination day was drawing near, and this is what Bartholomeo decided on doing: he practised his morceau de concours for several weeks, secretly in his own room at his lodgings, not in the way Allard had taught him, but after his own fantastic notions. He changed everything-movement, measure, expression, execution, adding double chords, points d&amp;apos;orgues, and all sorts of tricks and impossible additions until the original morceau was hardly recognisable. &amp;quot;I was in the presidential loge on the day of the concours, and was prepared to hear something bizarre in the way of violin-playing, but I was not prepared for what I heard then. Shortly after Bartholomeo began to play I could hear ominous whispers among the other pupils, and then from time to time ironical applause-all of which served to render the creole more and more exalte&amp;apos;, more and more fantastic. I looked at poor Allard, whose face was that of a martyr. How was it possible for a pupil to play his master such a trick, and in full hearing of all the pupils and professors? &amp;quot; Long before Bartholomeo ceased to play some of the pupils laughed and clapped their hands, while the violinist smiled with delight, thinking he was carrying all before him. When he ceased playing he felt certain he would carry off the premier prix; he had accepted the general hilarity for an expression of unanimous approval. When the time came for the jury to decide, there was an ominous hush. I think I never saw an audience in such a state of suspense and agitation. You know how it is yourself at the Conservatoire at such a time, but you never saw anything like the scene that followed. It seemed as if the jury would never return, but at last I received their verdict. I called Monsieur Lamoureux, and he stepped forward and received the premier prix. The unfortunate Bartholomeo, who was standing among the other pupils feverishly awaiting the verdict, seized the first string of his violin and broke it. I then had to announce the second prix, and no sooner had I done so than he broke another string of his violin. Imagine the state of the pupils by this time! I next had to announce the premier accessit, and hardly had I mentioned the name of Monsieur Gros than snap went the third string of Bartholomeo&amp;apos;s violin. Even now he did not despair. I called out the winner of the second accessit, and snap went the fourth and last string. It was my business to speak for the jury, and I named the third accessit. Amidst a silence too horrible to describe, poor Bartholomeo raised his leg and broke his violin across his knee. &amp;quot; He returned to his lodgings in the rue Notre-Dame de Lorette, and died of brain fever three days later.&amp;quot; We sat a long time at table, and at last Samuel David remarked it was perhaps the time for me to take my seat at the piano, but Auber said: &amp;quot;There is no hurry. You know how artistes dislike playing after eating. Let us go upstairs and look at my costumes, since you have expressed a desire to see them; by that time your protigd will feel in a better mood for music.&amp;quot; David had heard much gossip about Auber&amp;apos;s astounding wardrobe at the top of the house. Everything here was a revelation to me. On the way upstairs my head was filled with thoughts of a past I had not witnessed, of people I had never seen, and it was hard to believe that I was living under the Second Empire and not under the Directoire or the doubly old-fashioned age of Louis XVIII., when some of the customs and manners of the reign of Louis XVI. were revived and kept green till the overthrow of Louis Philippe in i848. Just before we reached the top I noticed a ghost-like figure moving slowly along the corridor like an apparition disturbed in its solitude, so old that it gave me the impression of being older than the house, older than the ancient furniture in the house, older than the First Empire and the reign of all the Louis; for the figure impressed me as belonging to a thousand remote souvenirs too strange and personal for utterance among the living inhabitants of the new Paris. The figure disappeared from view as we arrived at the last step, and without the slightest noise a door closed behind it. It was Auber&amp;apos;s oldest servant. After having seen it, Auber resembled a vivacious pierrot, quite in keeping with Baron Haussmann&amp;apos;s modern boulevards. But I had yet to be initiated into the secrets of the dress department of the composer&amp;apos;s life and work. He opened a door, and we stood in a large, desolate room hung round on all sides with the different costumes he had worn from the year i8o8 to i869. The look on David&amp;apos;s face was one of absolute bewilderment. For some moments I was so absorbed in it that I was on the point of missing some of Auber&amp;apos;s comments. There was nothing in the room but suits of old clothes; there were upwards of one hundred and fifty costumes and hats, including all the fashions from the reign of Napoleon I. down to the last years of Napoleon III. The sight was unique. But far more interesting still were the dates, comments, reflections, contained in a special note pasted on each costume, these reflections reading like the leaves torn from some old chronicle of romantic love and adventure. Had Auber been a literary musician, like Berlioz and Wagner, he would have left us in possession of a series of souvenirs which might have rivalled the Memoirs of Chateaubriand. One thing made this room a room of wonders: it represented the dead past of a man who was very much alive, absolutely contented, full of humour, witty repartee, and irony, a man who had achieved one of his greatest successes when long past his eightieth year, and was even now at work on a new opera. No flattery could turn his head, no success could make him arrogant; seventy years of hard work and good humour had left his heart and mind unchanged-in one word, he presented the extraordinary sight of a man who had spent all his life in the gayest city in the world without having become blase&amp;apos;. Asked by the Empress Eug6nie one evening at the Tuileries if he did not regret never having married, Auber replied: &amp;quot; No, Madame, and less to-day than ever, seeing that Madame Auber would now be in her eightieth year.&amp;quot; Rossini and Auber were the gayest and wittiest of the composers; Cherubini, Berlioz, and Ambroise Thomas were habitually melancholy and often morose. We now went downstairs to the salon where Auber would sit in judgment on my improvisations, and where I felt certain there would be neither flattery on the one hand nor canting criticism on the other. I took my seat at the piano, feeling as much at home as I would among old friends. At last, after having played for more than an hour, with my judge walking about or sitting, as the humour took him, Auber began his comments on my improvisations. &amp;quot;What this young man needs most, like all beginners, is la pondfration. I advise him to proceed slowly. Whoever tries to control his playing will fail; there is no system by which improvisation can be taught. I hope he will control his art, and not let impulse control him. He should never try to learn; if he does, he may become a conventional pianist. Have you warned him about invitations that will pour in from all sorts of people? I know how it was in my case. The great trick will be to invite him to dinner and expect him to pay for it in music. We have all been through that phase. Liszt told an Austrian princess he did not feel disposed to play since he had eaten very little of her dinner, and Chopin had a way of his own in dealing with them; but Vieuxtemps played a good joke on the Duchesse de D . . ., who wrote asking him to dine in strict intimacy with her family, and to be sure to bring his violin. Vieuxtemps replied that he was sorry he could not accept as he had a previous engagement, but he would send his violin instead. &amp;quot; One evening I saw Schulhoff in a rage when asked by Madame Rossini to play after dinner. Paris is a good school.&amp;quot; After this de&amp;apos;jeuner invitations to dinner arrived in such numbers that I had to have the advice of friends in dealing with them. It seemed as if all the brilliant and gifted women of continental Europe resided in Paris under the Second Empire. The salon of the Princess Mathilde Bonaparte was a greater centre of attraction for writers and artists than that of the Tuileries; the Princess Metternich, wife of the Austrian Ambassador, wielded a social power greater than that of many crowned heads; while the beautiful Russian Princess Sophia Troubetskoi became the wife of the Duc de Morny, half-brother of the Emperor. More than twenty years later I again met this grande dame, who had now become the wife of the Spanish Duke de Sesto, with a palace at Madrid that rivalled in splendour and beauty the most romantic scenes in the Arabian Nights. It was at a special recital I gave in honour of the Infanta Eulalia of Spain, and I seemed once more to be passing through some of the wonderful scenes of the Empire.</FullText></Record>