<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2439835</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131356</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>Musical Notes</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Oct 1917</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19171001</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Evans</LastName><FirstName>Edwin</FirstName><PersonName>Edwin Evans</PersonName><OriginalForm>Evans, Edwin</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Austin</FirstName><PersonName>Austin Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Austin</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>338</StartPage><EndPage>340</EndPage><Pagination>338-340</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2439835/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><Abstract>       &lt;AbsText&gt;THE autumn musical season enters with a kind of ritual, the order of which has in most of its details the sanction of established custom. Like most spectacular pageants, it opens with an orchestral introduction, by Sir Henry Wood at the Promenade Concerts. Then, in these later days, Sir Thomas Beecham satisfies our curiosity concerning additions to his repertory for the autumn. Meanwhile, the fashionable virtuosi who imagine that they have some part to play in musical progress announce an autumn recital, or a series of them if they are fashionable enough.&lt;/AbsText&gt;     </Abstract><FullText>Musical Notes By Edwin Evans THE autumn musical season enters with a kind of ritual, the order of which has in most of its details the sanction of established custom. Like most spectacular pageants, it opens with an orchestral introduction, by Sir Henry Wood at the Promenade Concerts. Then, in these later days, Sir Thomas Beecham satisfies our curiosity concerning additions to his repertory for the autumn. Meanwhile, the fashionable virtuosi who imagine that they have some part to play in musical progress announce an autumn recital, or a series of them if thev are fashionable enough. At the same time the directors of the Queen&amp;apos;s Hall Orchestra are examining how many, and those of the London Symphony Orchestra how few, interesting novelties they can contrive to include in their winter programmes, and the Royal Philharmonic Society is keeping us as long as possible in suspense as to whether it will or will not have a season at allthough on that matter the doubts of a year ago have given way to some degree of confidence. All these decisions will be made known within a week or two, and the sequel rests with the public. During the last few seasons the attitude of the latter has assumed much greater interest than it possessed before the war. Then it was disposed to shut its eyes and open its ears indiscriminately to everything that more or less resembled music-a circumstance that the astute gentlemen who used to meet at the German Athenaeum were not slow in turning to the advantage of the then dominant interest. An examination of its list of members would go a long way towards explaining the undoubted German bias of all our musical institutions in those days and the relative facility with which a German artist could make headway as compared with an equally or more talented executant from any other countr, not to speak of our own. Let me cite a case in point. For some years we had a small boom of Elena Gerhardt. I am not denying that she was a good exponent of the German lied, inclined maybe to that excessive sentimentality which Heine would have been the first to resent, but, on the whole, a singer whom one heard with enjoyment. During the same period we had two or three visits of Jane Bathori, the most highly gifted French exponent of the same form of art, musically far more intelligent than Gerhardt, with the additional advantage that the intelligence was her own. Bathori passed almost unnoticed, save by the few independent music-lovers who refused to have their opinion prepared for them by the gentlemen of the German Athenaum, and the Gerhardt boom continued unabated even when she began to deteriorate. It would not be difficult to recall many simnilar instances, and the case of the composer was the most flagrant of all. But signs of change were already apparent. I remember noting, for example, the curiously un-English gathering at the Music Club for the glorification of Richard Strauss on the eve of the outbreak of war, when the clou of the evening was the performance of his Violin Sonata by Lady Speyer, with the composer at the piano. The occasion of his presence in England was the production of that monumental piece of Teutonic vulgarity, &amp;quot;The Legend of Joseph,&amp;quot; in itself almost a justification of war if one has imagination enough to realise what it stood for. No effort was spared to make the reception a success, but the abstentions from participating in it were eloquent. I had recently returned from Paris, where the tactlessness of the German visitors ha-d had somewhat similar consequences, but the London phenomenon, I felt, had deeper causes, which foreshadowed the change that is taking place at present in our musical audiences. We are turning over the page, a little late maybe, but I trust with some decision. The Anglicisation of opera as a rallying-point for our musical life has the great advantage that it appeals, or should appeal, to all classes alike. If the full measure of success is achieved for which the foundation has now been laid, opera will cease to be an aristocratic function in the stalls and an Italian fesfa in the gallery, and draw audiences representative of that new world to which we are all looking forward. It is, however, as Sir Thomas Beecham himself would doubtless admit, chiefly as a means to an end that the present state of development in that direction is of interest. Though excellently adapted, sung, and staged, an opera like Ivan the Terrible or Louise necessarily retains its essential exotic quality, and, whilst such productions will, I hope, always be welcome among us, the time has come when we may speculate on the prospects of something indigenous. By that I do not mean merely an opera composed to an English libretto and signed by English names, but an evolution of the art of the lyric stage that will produce a new characteristic form. French art underwent a similar experience about the time of the guerre des bouffons, when a shrewd manager, Jean Monnet, and three composers, Philidor, Monsigny, and Dalayrac, created a lyric form which, in all essentials, remains to this very day a contribution to the art of the stage, much of whose excellence is derived from its wholly French character. Hitherto nothing of the kind has been possible in England, for our managers had no imagination, and the most competent of our English composers had never seen the business end of a theatre. All that is changed. We have a manager who is not only far-seeing, but a musical genius and an enthusiast to boot, doing by private enterprise what in most Continental countries demands the aid of subsidies from the State, and, by now, the clever young musicians who co-operate with him have learned something of the requirements of the lyric stage. Surely the time has come when we may, without Wellsian detachment, inquire what this is going to mean for us in a few years&amp;apos; time. Sir Thomas has told the Press that he has three or four English operas awaiting production, and there are probably quite as many more on his horizon. Is there among them all one work to which we may look forward as a potential landmark in the evolution of our lyric stage? By that I do not mean a work of stupendous merit. The landmarks from which important developments in musical history are dated are often themselves of debatable quality, surviving only because they contained the initial germ of great things to follow. Even when a failure, such a production is an outstanding event, and there is no reason why one should not be a success, until superseded by something better along the same channel of development. It would be interesting to know whether Sir Thomas is confident that the ne~w audience his enterprise is creating can look forward to a correspondingly new art-form.</FullText></Record>