<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2440784</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131346</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>&amp;quot;Agatha Blount&amp;quot;</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Jun 1909</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19090601</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>D&apos;Arcy</LastName><FirstName>Ella</FirstName><PersonName>Ella D&apos;Arcy</PersonName><OriginalForm>D&apos;Arcy, Ella</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Ford</LastName><MiddleName>Madox</MiddleName><FirstName>Ford</FirstName><PersonName>Ford Madox Ford</PersonName><OriginalForm>Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>435</StartPage><EndPage>470</EndPage><Pagination>435-470</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2440784/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><Abstract>       &lt;AbsText&gt;IT was July 27, &amp;quot;breaking-up day&amp;quot; at the Convent of the Immaculate Conception on Streatham Common. The prizes had been distributed by Dr. Wise, Bishop of South London, and the eighty girls, big and little, had departed to their homes with their parents or friends. Most of the children carried with them piles of incredibly dull books in vile bindings, but every child had received at least one book, although it were only a &amp;quot;consolation&amp;quot; prize.&lt;/AbsText&gt;     </Abstract><FullText>&amp;quot; Agatha Blount &amp;quot; By Ella D&amp;apos;Arcy IT was July 27, &amp;quot; breaking-up day&amp;quot; at the Convent of the Immaculate Conception on Streatham Common. The prizes had been distributed by Dr. Wise, Bishop of South London, and the eighty girls, big and little, had departed to their homes with their parents or friends. Most of the children carried with them piles of incredibly dull books in vile bindings, but every child had received at least one book, although it were only a &amp;quot; consolation &amp;quot; prize. For this pleased the parents, and seemed some small return for the hundred guineas yearly which education at the Immaculate Conception cost. The big class-rooms were empty, windows and doors stood open, the waxed and polished floors were littered with scraps of paper, torn exercise books, pens with broken nibs and nibbled handles, cracked slates and pieces of slate pencil. It was a tradition amongst the girls that the last day of the school year must be feted by all the disorder forbidden in the course of it, and so the rows of battered desks, standing with open lids, showed chaos within, and Sister Marie des Anges, going round her own particular domain-the third-class room-foresaw many midday recreations spent in tidying up these desks and putting things straight again. But she was not sorry for this, as for a long time her recreations with the Community had been hours of trial. For months past the elder nuns had sent her practically to Coventry, while, to the younger ones-her own contemporaries-to the novices, and to the children, she was strictly forbidden to speak of that which lay heavy on her mind. Yet she could not take an interest in anything else, nor could she cease to contrast her present treatment with the kindness shown her in former days. At one time she had been the favourite of the whole house. But this had been while old Reverend Mother was living, and before Sister Therese de la Sainte Croix had been transferred from Streatham to Montmirail. Standing within the semicircle of desks in the big bow- window of the schoolroom, the young nun showed a tall, slight figure whose long limbs and slender hips could be divined beneath the multiple folds of the black serge gown. The wimple, a sort of short circular cape of linen stiffly starched, concealed the bust, while a close linen cap tied beneath the chin was edged with a goffered frill that stood out all round the face two inches deep, and, seen sideways, entirely hid the profile. Below the cap, a linen band covered the forehead down to a quarter of an inch of the brow, and a big square of black veiling pinned to the top of the cap floated thence to hide the shape of the head, the attachment of the throat to the shoulders, the curve of the back, and the line of the waist. Outside the window, on the lawns and flower-beds of the oldfashioned garden, glorious with summer sunshine, lay wonderful pieces of purple lace which shifted their position all day long, from west to east. The garden had been arranged in the days of George III., so that the closely shaven velvet lawns were already more than a century old. But the lace-makers, the mulberry-trees and chestnuts were much older still, and parents visiting the convent for the first time were agreeably impressed by this matured and spacious garden, in which they foresaw their little darlings at play. In reality, the little darlings were never allowed in this part of the grounds at all. They played in a big gravelled yard out of sight of the house. The velvet lawns were sacred to the choir nuns, to Mother Superior, and to her guests. She and Dr. Wise were walking up and down them now. Sister Marie des Anges, glancing timidly out at the two slow-pacing, black figures, wondered whether they might not perhaps be talking of her. The momentous letter might have come from Rome . . . the Bishop might have brought it. There was nothing to be learned from Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s face. It was always the same, perfectly self-controlled, set in pious and suave lines. Habitually she held her head inclined over to the left, laughed rarely, and when she did so displayed yellow, irregular teeth. But the ghost of a smile glimmered perpetually round the corners of her mouth. Her small, dark eyes, set in a sallow face, had looked shrewdly at the world for over fifty years, but this faint ambiguous smile was the only indication of what she thought about it. To speak metaphorically, she never showed her hand, while as a matter of fact both her hands were generally hidden, being as now, crossed over and slipped up the wide sleeves of her habit, which is a conventual fashion. The sunshine played upon the silver cross, fastened with a safety-pin in the centre of the wimple, and upon the snubby toes of her low thick shoes, which came in and out beneath the hem of her gown. A rosary of black wooden beads, big as hazelnuts, hung from her girdle to below the knee, where the brass crucifix in which it terminated swayed slightly with every step. Dr. Wise had been served tea in the guest-parlour, and a luscious kind of sponge and guava cake made in the convent, which he particularly appreciated. He was waiting now for his carriage and listening courteously to the lady&amp;apos;s flow of words. Reverend Mother was French, and spoke always in that language. The Bishop had been partially educated at St. Omer, and would have welcomed the opportunity for removing some of the rust from the extremely untrustworthy lingual weapon he had there acquired. But Reverend Mother gave him no such chance. She talked herself all the time, snatched at his meaning before he had expressed it, and with a &amp;quot; Parfaitement, Monseigneur ! Vous voulez dire que &amp;quot; unfairly possessed herself of both sides of the conversation, and converted what might have been an excellent French exercise for him into a mere exercise of holy patience-a virtue which he found himself practising, of necessity, most hours of the day. Sister Marie des Anges could hear the smooth, fluent voice of Reverend Mother every time their steps brought them near the house, and an occasional stumbling attempt on the Bishop&amp;apos;s part to say his say, instantly quenched by the lady&amp;apos;s, &amp;quot; Mais, parfaitement. Vous voulez dire, n&amp;apos;est-ce pas ? . . . &amp;quot; The first desk on the left-hand side of the window was Rhoda Hammond&amp;apos;s. It had to be entirely cleared out, for Rhoda was not coming back. She had left with great reluctance, she insisted that she wished to become a nun, and she was tremendously &amp;quot; cracked after &amp;quot; Sister Marie des Anges. To be &amp;quot;cracked after &amp;quot; a nun was, in school-girl parlance, to be passionately fond of her, to follow her about with adoring eyes, to get as often as possible into personal contact with her, to treasure up every unconsidered trifle she had touched. It was to lose one&amp;apos;s appetite if she spoke coldly, and to weep oneself sick if she were unkind. There was scarcely a nun in the community who had not at least one &amp;quot; crack &amp;quot; amongst the girls, while the popular nuns had many. Sister Marie des Anges had never been without two or three, but Rhoda Hammond&amp;apos;s was the most pronounced case. All that morning, all through the preceding day, Rhoda with red eyes and a red and swollen nose, had hung upon her tracks, had seized her hand to fondle it surreptitiously, and to water it with her tears, had asserted over and over again her irrevocable intention of coming back to the Immaculate Conception so soon as ever her father would permit her to take the veil, and Sister Marie des Anges had listened in silence, and with extraordinarily mixed feelings. She was under the most stringent injunctions not to speak of what was on her mind, and yet if she must conceal her real sentiments, she did not know what she could say to the child at all. But at least she could express her satisfaction that Mr. Hammond insisted on Rhoda remaining for one whole year &amp;quot; in the world.&amp;quot; She herself had only been there for six weeks. She had been just eighteen years of age when she had gone back to Streatham at the end of the summer holidays to enter the Order as a postulant. Now she had been a nun for twelve years. Two years a novice at Montmirail, ten years a fully professed nun here. A long time-and yet it seemed to her to have flown. To herself she seemed to be always young, to be always the identical Agatha Blount whom she had known so intimately as a child, as the young girl who lived still in her heart beneath wimple and habit, and the puzzle was that she was not the same, that all her hopes, wishes and ideas were diametrically different from those of the Agatha Blount of twelve years ago. Rhoda&amp;apos;s desk was a jumble of the most heterogeneous objects, torn papers, old letters, reels of cotton, empty bonbonnieres, holy pictures, books, and a tangled mass of grimy sky-blue wool. Agatha, glancing casually at each piece of paper she took out before crumpling it up to throw it into the waste-paper basket, read on one, &amp;quot; Dearest, darlingest Sister Marie des Anges, I am sure there can be no angel in Heaven so beautiful, so good, and so adorable as you. Dear Angel &amp;quot;-with three very black lines under the &amp;quot; dear,&amp;quot;-&amp;quot; I love you, and I wish you would not be so cold to me, and that you would always let me carry your Mass-book for you to chapel. Yesterday you gave it to Mary Parker.&amp;quot; Here the letter stopped abruptly, for the writer to try over and over again &amp;quot; Dear darling &amp;quot; and &amp;quot; Angelic Marie &amp;quot; in different hands and with different pens. Agatha was accustomed to finding letters from Rhoda in her place in chapel, in her desk, or in her bed, but these letters were written in a more restrained and decorous style. It was the letters that Rhoda did not send which overflowed thus with sentimentality. She remembered that she herself had been wont to write in much the same style to Sister Thirse de la Sainte Croix. She mused over the silliness of young girls, and wondered why no one taught them wisdom, but reflected that perhaps, as in her own case, those who knew were not allowed to speak. Continuing her investigations in the desk, she came upon a frayed pink silk garter, a broken side-comb, a lump of rockalmond, and one of those circular mirrors in leaden frame and case which the elder girls carried always in their pockets. Agatha was seized with the desire to see herself. It was long since she had deliberately looked in a glass. But glancing towards the garden, she saw the Reverend Mother and Dr. Wise at the edge of the lawn, close under the window. Their eyes were raised to her. Blushing guiltily, she bent her head over the desk, and waited until they should have turned. Then she opened the mirror case and looked in. There was little to be seen. Just a pair of dark brows drawn straight and thin, above dark, liquid, timid eyes that swam on bluish whites, a straight nose, thin sensitive lips, and a smooth skin, which did not seem to have changed in the very least since her eighteenth year. Yet to-day she was thirty-one-thirtyone, three weeks and two days. It was during her twenty-ninth year that her present trouble had begun. One day the thought occurred to her, &amp;quot; In two years I shall be thirty! &amp;quot; and suddenly it had seemed incredible and terrible that she, Agatha Blount, who had been young so long should, in another two years, have lost her youth for ever. For the thirtieth birthday appeared to her an inexorable turningpoint. You were young up to thirty, after that you were young no longer. And thus, when more months had passed, and she said with a strange sinking of the heart, &amp;quot; Next month I shall be thirty! &amp;quot; something not herself had answered her, &amp;quot;Yes, and you have never lived! &amp;quot; So had the trouble begun, but this question of age was not certainly its only cause. It was attached to a thousand intricate filaments, the windings of which she could not trace, it went down to obscure roots, planted perhaps years before, sprung perhaps from seeds sown generations back. And the strange thing was that while she knew herself to be the same Agatha Blount she had always been, nevertheless her whole outlook on life was changed-her whole soul, her whole mind were changed to the minutest particle. It was as if, during all the past years, she had been asleep and dreaming, but now at last was waking up to real life. Shyness and hope, curiosity and surprise gazed back at her from the dark eyes in the little mirror, but she did not know how to read them, she did not understand the face she saw. Between herself and her reflection there floated the web of all her wishes and all her fears. With a sigh over her helplessness, she slipped the mirror into a pocket beneath her gown, and went on tidying up. The purple lace, spread over brilliant flower-bed and velvet lawn, had perceptibly lengthened and shifted far to the east. The crush of carriage wheels over the gravel in front of the house reached the ear. Sister Veronica, the portress, crossed the grass to inform the Bishop his carriage waited. Now the garden was empty and very silent, half the lawn was in shadow, and the school-room was filled with shadow and silence too. The small noise of shutting down the lid of Rhoda&amp;apos;s desk reverberated through the room. Agatha started at the click of the door handle, nervously dropping the books and papers which she held. Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s voice came through the door ajar. &amp;quot; Sister Marie des Anges!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, Mother! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Will you come up to my room, please ? I have something to tell you.&amp;quot; Agatha&amp;apos;s forehead and hands grew wet with emotion and fear. The momentous letter from Rome must have come. She followed, at a respectable distance, the spare black-robed figure up the broad shallow, carpetless stairs-over which, in former days, swords had clanked, and high heels had tapperedinto the big room at the back of the house on the first floor, which once had been the chamber of some gay Georgian beauty, and was now Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s private sanctum. Through the slim doorway of the ancient &amp;quot; powder-closet&amp;quot; you saw her bed and toilet arrangements, in the outer room stood her big table-desk, her books, and her prie-Dieu, with the ebony and silver crucifix hung above it. On a shelf stood a row of japanned and white-lettered boxes, as in a solicitor&amp;apos;s office. In this room all matters of importance were conducted. Here heads of departments were interviewed, reprimands administered, and hither were conducted such heinous sinners among the children as no ordinary puishment might impress, no mere class-mistress terrify. And it was well known that, however haughty and defiant a child might be on entering that room, she would not emerge again until a condition of abasement and convulsive weeping had been reached. What took place between judge and culprit never transpired. It was a curious fact that, once her tears were dried, the delinquent maintained on the subject an impenetrable silence. The room had an uncurtained window of two immense sheets of plate glass, grey distempered walls, and a highly polished floor. There was no carpet. The only carpet in the whole convent was the Aubusson on the altar-steps in the chapel. But a mat, neatly and ingeniously made of cloth snippets, lay in front of every chair. The walls were decorated with two black-framed photographs of the exterior and interior of St. Peter&amp;apos;s, and a highly coloured print of the Sacred Heart. Five cane chairs were ranged severely round the walls, and a sixth one stood out facing the light, and Mother Superior&amp;apos;s desk, which was placed sideways to the window. She motioned Agatha to this chair. Mother Superior sat at this table. She turned round on Agatha&amp;apos;s entrance, and gazed at her in a direct and sapient way. And she continued to look at her thus, in complete silence, until the girl coloured painfully and her eyes wavered and fell. On which, apparently satisfied with this sign of submission, Reverend Mother began to speak. &amp;quot; I have heard from Rome,&amp;quot; she said, and Agatha, looking up involuntarily, uttered an eager little &amp;quot; Oh ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You are very anxious to leave us, dear child ? &amp;quot; inquired Reverend Mother, sarcastic and suave. Agatha&amp;apos;s eyes filled with tears. &amp;quot; No, not that,&amp;quot; she murmured. &amp;quot;But you know how I feel . . . that it is no longer possible . &amp;quot; &amp;quot; We will not go into the question again, Sister; we have discussed it enough. I have told you already that such temptations are not peculiar to you, that you need not flatter yourself that you have an exceptional nature, nor an exceptional trial. Such trials and such temptations come to us all. I don&amp;apos;t suppose there is a nun in religion who has not experienced them. So soon as the first years of ardour have gone by, the Devil suggests to us that we have made a mistake, that our vocation is not real, that the world has need of our life, our work, our abilities. Not a single religieuse who attains thirty years of age but goes through, sooner or later, this period of temptation. Were each weakly to succumb, every convent and monastery in the world would be emptied. It is the hour of Agony in the Garden permitted by God for the ultimate triumph of the soul, since it is only by resisting temptation that the soul acquires strength. Each of the nuns whom you know has found the grace to resist, and so sits secure and happy at the feet of the Bridegroom, having chosen, like Mary, the better part. But you, my poor Sister, do not wish to resist-do you ? You prefer, like Martha, to busy yourself with the things of this world ? &amp;quot; Hopeless tears began to roll down Agatha&amp;apos;s cheeks. The auburn hair and beard of the &amp;quot; Sacred Heart &amp;quot; at which she gazed, the crimson blood-drops, the pink mantle and azure gown, liberally edged with gold, all sprang together into a rainbow blur. It was hopeless to argue with Reverend Mother. Never had she been able to do so. In spite of which inability, right through the last two dreadful years something not herself had driven her to repeat to her confessor, to her family, to each who questioned her that she was no longer happy, that she had mistaken her vocation, that she must go. To this resolution she had clung with the desperate courage of a gentle nature, and no one was more surprised than she at the tenacity with which she had held her own during the mortifications and browbeatings of the last two years. Finally, because of her persistency it had become impossible to refuse her request for an appeal to the Holy Father to release her from her vows, and it was the result of this appeal that she was waiting now to hear. After a pause, made rather for its dramatic effect than because she desired a reply, Reverend Mother continued: &amp;quot; But what sort of a life awaits you in the world ? What place have you there ? What work ? Who wants you f In your own home there is nothing for you to do. Your parents are wealthy, and don&amp;apos;t need any help from their daughters, except in certain social duties for which your sisters are far better suited than you. You have five younger sisters; two grown up and &amp;apos;bout,&amp;apos; three more growing up. Without any sin against holy charity on my part, or any lack of natural affection on theirs, I think we may take it for granted they have no very enthusiastic desire to have you home again. For twelve years now your sister Katie has been the eldest Miss Blount, and I suppose she is not eager to cede her place to you ? It is true she is about to be married, but there is Carrie, already twentythree or twenty-four, is she not ? and so quite ready to step into Katie&amp;apos;s shoes. Besides, how are you going to mix in society, to which you are so unaccustomed ? How are you going to make yourself happy in it ? I fear, my poor child, some very bitter deceptions await you. People are naturally shy of a professed nun who has had to get released from her vows. The position speaks for itself of lightness of character, inconstancy and caprice. Who could repose any confidence in a woman who, after twelve years&amp;apos; service in the House of God, goes out to serve-I do not say the Devil and the Flesh, God forbid !but at least the World, and who, after being the affianced Bride of Christ, puts off her ring and lays aside her marriage garments to take up with the poor rags and baubles of a worldly life ? You will be looked on with suspicion by those who know your story, and when your name is mentioned to strangers, there will follow the explanatory word. For you may believe me, wherever we go, there our past goes with us. We can no more escape it than we can our shadows. It is projected from us as inevitably as our shadow is projected in the sunshine.&amp;quot; Agatha&amp;apos;s tears now fell so fast that the starched and goffered frill beneath her chin was getting limp and out of shape. She fumbled for her handkerchief, found it at last-large and coarse as a dish-cloth-and, hiding her face in it, wept miserably. There was silence. Reverend Mother was perhaps placated by this bending of the neck beneath the yoke of tears. Agatha, in spite of her distress, heard the opening of a drawer and the rustle of note-paper taken from an envelope. Resolutely she wiped her eyes, squeezing her handkerchief up into a tight pad between her trembling hands. &amp;quot; I think it only right to put these considerations again before you, Sister, because the answer from Rome has come. I have it here.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Dr. Wise brought it to-day ? I guessed he had done so,&amp;quot; Agatha murmured. &amp;quot; You guessed wrong, then. I have had it over ten days, but with the examinations taking place, I thought it best to say nothing that might distract your mind.&amp;quot; At this, Agatha was revolted. It seemed to her cruel beyond measure of Reverend Mother to have concealed this news from her for ten whole days, after the long weeks and months that she had waited for it in the tortures of suspense. Her thoughts were reflected as in a mirror upon her child-like face. Reverend Mother smiled that evanescent, ungenial smile of hers, which always left a permanent ghost of itself hovering round the corners of her mouth. &amp;quot; You are very eager to leave us,&amp;quot; she repeated, &amp;quot; though perhaps the day will come when you will be as eager to return. Our Blessed Lord deals with us always far better than we deserve. However, what I have now to say to you is this.&amp;quot; She glanced over the letter she held in her hand. Then: &amp;quot; The Holy Father, while deploring as much as does our dear Bishop, as does your Director, and as do we all, your unhappy desire to go back into the world, nevertheless permits it for the prevention of a worse scandal.&amp;quot; Agatha gave a little cry, scandalised at the word. &amp;quot; Would it not be a worse scandal to have you here against your will ? We no longer live in the Middle Ages, unfortunately -those holy, happy centuries of discipline and faith-and you would be pining and planning to get away all the time. But the Holy Father, in his wisdom and kindness, has determined not to release you entirely and irrevocably from your vows for the present. He grants you instead a year&amp;apos;s dispensation, during which period you may leave the convent, lay aside your habit, and live in the world exactly as worldlings do. At the year&amp;apos;s end, if you still persist in being of the same mind, you must make another application to Rome to have your vows cancelled.&amp;quot; Reverend Mother broke off abruptly, to say in tones of compassionate condescension: &amp;quot; I see you are already, my poor child, making that application in spirit ? &amp;quot; Agatha, confounded by such prescience, and unable to deny its truth, blushed to the forehead-band, felt the heat creeping up to the roots of her hair, and down her throat and neck. Reverend Mother watched her with pleasure, savouring the spectacle a long moment, before speaking again. &amp;quot; However, the future is in God&amp;apos;s hands, and we-poor, frail creatures-have not to concern ourselves with it, but simply to do our duty in the present. In this particular instance the duty of us all is to keep your departure as quiet as possible. The children on their return will be told nothing about you, and your sister, Lucy, will not come back here, but is to go to the Assumption Convent in Kensington Square. You are to leave the day after to-morrow. Lady Blount cannot spare the carriage before then. You must be ready by three o&amp;apos;clock on Friday afternoon, and I wish you to go up to your cell immediately after dinner, and to wait there until you are sent for. You are not to say any good-byes to your companions. Those who know of the affair could hardly wish you well, and those who do not know of it are best left in ignorance. I myself, Sister, will say good-bye to you here and now, and I will pray that the Holy Spirit may restore you to the light.&amp;quot; She rose and stood prepared to bestow the perfunctory kiss of religion upon Agatha&amp;apos;s cheeks. Agatha rose too, her mind whirling. So her mother had known ! Yet she had parted from her mother, who had driven down from town to assist at the prize-giving and take Lucy home, hardly two hours before, and Lady Blount had not said one kind, encouraging word to her concerning her home-coming, had treated her as she had always treated her since this tribulation had begun, with a detached coolness, suggestive of an inimical point of view. She felt it was extraordinarily unkind of her mother to have said nothing at all. Then another idea occurred to her. How could she go away in her habit ? And she had no other clothes. She timidly made the objection, but Reverend Mother met it at once. &amp;quot; Everything has been arranged. Some clothes of your sisters&amp;apos; were sent for you some days ago. The box will be put in your cell on Friday, and no one need see you after you have put aside the habit. The hour has been purposely arranged when the Community will be at Compline. You will leave everything in your cell, including your rosary, cross &amp;quot;-the speaker lightly touched the silver cross on Agatha&amp;apos;s bosom with a long and polished forefinger nail-&amp;quot; and ring. All you may take with you is your Mass-book and Book of Office. You will probably wish to say your Office every day, although you understand you are under no obligation to do so. You are perfectly free. And now, there is the bell for Vespers. We will go down. Be so good as to keep yourself under perfect control between now and Friday. Let there be no tears, and, above all, no confidences.. Adieu, ma bonne enfant. Que la Sainte Vierge vous garde et vous nous ramene.&amp;quot; The cold kisses were given and received, and Agatha followed Reverend Mother to the chapel, seeing nothing, hearing nothing, finding her way automatically as a somnambulist walks in a dream. Sister Marie des Anges entered her cell for the last time, a small, square room, one of many, opening upon a stone corridor. Corridor and cells were built in the new wing of the house above the Chapel, and the corridor windows looked over to the opposite wing, which consisted of the children&amp;apos;s refectories and dormitories. But the cell windows, turned the other way, gave only upon the wood-yard, some out-buildings, and some elm-trees. Every cell was furnished exactly alike with a narrow bed, an iron tripod washstand, a deal table, deal prie-Dieu, and deal chair. A holy-water stoup hung just within the door, a crucifix and piece of blessed palm above the bed&amp;apos;s head. The only individual touch permitted was in the choice and arrangement of &amp;quot; Holy Pictures,&amp;quot; which the nuns fastened to the wall above the prie-Ditu by means of drawing-pins. A reasonable number was allowed, and seven, or at most nine, reached the limit of reason. But the novice who papered one entire wall with seventy-five of these lace-edged inanities saw them all confiscated, and herself condemned to a week&amp;apos;s discipline. When Agatha entered her cell on that Friday afternoon, she found a big cardboard box on the table, and she opened it with strange trepidation. It contained the clothes she was to put on to go home in, and she took out the articles one by one, and examined them anxiously. First, there was a petticoat of bright green silk, with little frills up to the knee. Then a soft unlined grey woollen gown, with a blouse bodice of the same stuff. It was open at the neck like a man&amp;apos;s coat, with a roll collar and lapels, and so there was a separate little chemisette affair of white lace to be worn inside. A three-cornered hat of black and white grenadine had a pair of bright green wings fixed across the back. She remembered that Katie had come to the Convent one Sunday in this hat and the grey frock more than a year ago, and she was conscious that the sleeves were out of fashion. Women have an extraordinary and apparently intuitive knowledge of the vagaries of fashion, even although they be immured in a convent or prison. Agatha knew that sleeves were no longer worn full at the wrist. She was impatient to see how she looked in the hat, and removed her veil, cap and forehead band. But she found it impossible to hold the hat on with one hand and see comfortably in the tiny circular glass which she held in the other. She must manage in some way to fix the glass up against the wall. Her gaze fell on her &amp;quot; Holy Pictures,&amp;quot; on her Saint Louis Gonzague, her St. Stanislas, her Saint Sebastian, her womanish Christs, with, in one instance, a Beloved Disciple, long-haired and girlish, lying on the Master&amp;apos;s bosom. She unpinned them all, and with the strongest pin fixed up the little three-inch mirror in their place. But still the hat refused to sit at the right angle, nor would it stay where she placed it. Katie had forgotten to send hatpins, or perhaps had remembered that with no hair, hat-pins would be superfluous. She wondered what she should do, and looking round her perplexedly, caught sight of the piece of black elastic which went twice round her Missal, sewn to the neat black cashmere cover, with which nuns protect the bindings of their books. She ripped it, with a sense of sacrilege, and sewed it in her hat. Now she looked at herself again in the glass, and blushed at the brazen, &amp;apos;shameless face she saw. Where the goffered cap had been tied beneath the chin appeared a white and naked throat. Where the coif had hidden everything down to the brows was naked forehead and dark hair, three-quarters of an inch long, curling prettily. On her head, in place of the veil, was poised the jaunty black and white hat. The tips of the green wings stuck out on either side. But her watch, lying on the table, showed the long hand already at eight, the short hand close on three. It was more than an hour since she had come up from the Refectory, she had not yet begun to dress, and in another twenty minutes the carriage was to come. She again removed the hat, and set to work more methodically. Taking off wimple and habit, she folded the latter, laid both upon the bed, and prepared to re-dress herself completely. But neither shoes nor stockings had been sent. She must go away, therefore, in the thick woollen stockings and stout shoes of the convent. Their much worn, rounded toes, appearing beneath the edge of her smart gown, looked absurd, and seemed to speak loudly of her treachery to Christ and her repudiated vows. While she contemplated them there came a warning knock at the door. It was opened two inches and the voice of Sister Rose was heard reciting the first part of the &amp;quot; Hail Mary! &amp;quot; When Agatha had responded with the second part, the lay sister came in, and seeing Sister Marie des Anges so strangely apparelled, began to giggle. She was a red-cheeked, country girl, wearing goffered cap, coif and wimple like the choir nuns, but with no veil, and her habit was of coarse grey homespun, instead of fine black serge. She stared at Agatha from round eyes, half shocked and wholly delighted, was on the point of bursting into laughter, caught herself up, and clapped a big red hand over her mouth. Then she seemed to remember that the woman before her had forfeited all respect, for she said with familiarity: &amp;quot; Lor&amp;apos;, I should never have known you ! You do look worldly, to be sure ! Don&amp;apos;t you feel funny in them fal-lals ? And feathers and all in your hat! Well, I should die of shame! &amp;quot; She circled round Agatha, a prey to fascination and horror, and forgot what she had come for. Agatha was ready to sink through the ground with humiliation. She was conscious she looked ridiculous. Her neck, her face, her head felt bare. She missed every instant the comfortable pressure of the concealing linen, the flow of the veil, the wide sleeves in which she could hide her hands, the warmth of the pleated habit round her waist. She felt thin, cold and indecent in this clinging grey skirt, and shrank from the idea of having to go out of her cell, of being seen thus by others as well as by Sister Rose. The girl now remembered her errand. &amp;quot; Lady Blount&amp;apos;s carriage is here,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;You&amp;apos;re to come down at&amp;apos;once, please.&amp;quot; Agatha gave a last look round the familiar cell. It was unfamiliar already, strangely changed. The cardboard box and its lid lay upon the floor, the holy pictures were gone from the wall, her convent clothes strewed the blue bed-quilt. Heaped together on the table were girdle, rosary, silver cross and silver ring, the insignia of her past dignity and happiness. Her big white-faced silver watch ticked beside them. The Christ from the crucifix over the bed seemed to regard her with mournful eyes. She was suddenly filled with wild regret, and if by a wish she could again have found herself in the habit, it would have been accomplished, and she would have slipped down to join the Community at Compline with immense relief and joy. But with her own hand she had put away such gracious joys for ever. Now she must walk forward along her self-elected road. For the last time she dipped her fingers into the stoup of holy water, crossed herself and followed Sister Rose along the vacant corridors, which smelt strongly of beeswax and cleanliness, down the polished staircase, and into the great hall paved with black and white marble where Sister Veronica, the portress, stood waiting with the keys. On Sister Veronica&amp;apos;s withered face, which was small and brown, and shrivelled like a russet apple in the spring, there was nothing but disapproval. She had been fifty years in religion, and this was the first time she had been required to unlock the convent doors to permit a professed nun to go back into the world. No doubt she too, like Reverend Mother, regretted the Middle Ages when her services might have been required for a ceremony of a very different kind. Through the plate-glass panels Agatha saw the brougham with the wooden-faced coachman, a monument of patience, on the box, and Bessie, the foam-flecked, pawing brown horse, fretted into a simulation of mettle and long pedigree by a bearing-rein tightly braced back. Behind the carriage waved the silver birch-trees, the lilac and laburnum bushes of the shallow, semicircular drive, at either end of which open gates gave flashes of that world on whose brink Agatha stood frightened yet allured, as a timid bather stands on the rocks of safety and considers the sea. The convent hall was very silent. At the end of it the garden door, of glass too, showed nothing but a green shade. A tiny flame burned in a red glass before the statue of the Blessed Virgin, which stood on a pedestal half-way down the hall. A bowl of freshly gathered roses, placed at the Virgin&amp;apos;s feet, scented the whole air. Agatha and the two nuns looked at one another in silence. She felt lonely and abandoned, and it seemed to her ignominious to steal away in this furtive fashion. Had the whole Community been there, were it only to condemn her, it would have been less disconcerting and strange. She offered Sister Rose, with timidity, the conventual salute. Choir nuns do not kiss the lay sisters except on great occasions, such as when they are received into religion . . . and perhaps when they leave it again. But when she turned to do the same by Sister Veronica, the old nun was ostentatiously busy with her keys. Agatha was too shy to make further advances, and the other, having unlocked the door, stood back. &amp;quot; Good-bye, Sister!&amp;quot; was all Agatha ventured to say, and Sister Veronica answered, &amp;quot; May the Blessed Virgin, whom you have abandoned, Sister, never abandon you ! I shall remember you in my prayers for all poor strayed and troubled souls! &amp;quot; Agatha had not taken her seat in the brougham before the convent door was shut and locked behind her, and when she looked back both Sisters Veronica and Rose had vanished. There was no sign of life within the convent, there was no one to be seen. She glanced right along the hall and out into the garden beyond, and both appeared empty and desolate, and all the desolation was centred in her own soul. When the carriage drew up in Cromwell Road she got out, trembling with nervousness, and forgot to shut the brougham door. The coachman reminded her of it. More nervous than ever, she stood absolutely tongue-tied when the smart parlourmaid appeared, in answer to her bell. But the well-trained servant, after waiting the regulation half-second for the lady to speak, came to her aid. &amp;quot; Lady Blount wishes me to say that it is her At Home day, and she is engaged with visitors upstairs, but if you&amp;apos;ll come this way, miss, I&amp;apos;ll show you your room.&amp;quot; She led Agatha to a small room at the end of the hall, that had been hastily arranged for her reception. A bed stood behind the door. The requisite bedroom furniture overcrowded the rest of the space. Thick festoons of virginia creeper darkened the French window, which opened upon a flight of stone steps and a London back garden, given over to sooty sparrows and predatory cats. The maid, offering to return with a cup of tea, went away, and Agatha was left alone. A can of warm water, covered with a folded towel, lay in the basin. She washed her hands for the sake of something to do. She had unpacked her little parcel of toilet necessaries, and had laid out upon the dressing-table her Missal and Book of Office. Now, sitting down with her back to the looking-glass, she tried to read over her Office, to pass the time. But she could not fix her attention. She felt restless and unsettled. She got up, opened the door, and strained her ears for some encouraging sound of life. She heard voices on the drawing-room floor, the rustle of silk petticoats descending the stairs, steps along the hall, and the noise of the street door shutting, as the visitors left the house. She went back to her seat, leaving the door ajar. The maid had evidently forgotten the tea, and presently it seemed to Agatha that she had been sitting there for hours. Then she went out to stand upon the garden steps, and watch the sky redden above the roofs of the mews. In the convent garden at Streatham the sun would be setting more beautifully behind the trees. . . . A key turned in the hall door. She heard her father&amp;apos;s heavy step and cheery voice. &amp;quot; Hullo, Fletcher! What&amp;apos;s the meaning of all these books and coats and things littering the hall ? Given Miss Blount the cloak-room, have you ? Where is she ? &amp;quot; Agatha came to greet her father, who took her cordially in his arms and warmly kissed her cheeks. &amp;quot; So I&amp;apos;ve got my eldest daughter back again ? Very glad, my dear, I&amp;apos;m sure. Seen your mother and the girls ? Visitors ? At this hour ? Fletcher, who&amp;apos;s in the drawing-room ? Mrs. Trevor. Oh, only your Aunt Carrie. Come up and see your aunt ! &amp;quot; The drawing-room door was wide open, and over the thick stair-carpets their footsteps fell unheard. Lady Blount stood exchanging last words with her sister. Agatha heard her say with bitterness, &amp;quot; I call it a disgrace! &amp;quot; Mrs. Trevor demurred. &amp;quot;Well, hardly a disgrace, but certainly a misfortune.&amp;quot; The listener blushed miserably, as Mrs. Trevor caught sight of her. &amp;quot; Why, here is Agatha! How d&amp;apos;y do, Charlie?&amp;quot; She gave a hand to her brother-in-law, kissed her niece, and holding her at arm&amp;apos;s-length, examined her with kindly curiosity. &amp;quot; How strange the child looks, to be sure! That cropped head! &amp;quot; she laughed. &amp;quot; Unrecognisable ! But &amp;quot;-with an amiable envy-&amp;quot; absurdly young-she looks younger than Carrie, I declare! She might be Ted in girl&amp;apos;s clothes! Ah, you won&amp;apos;t keep that freshness long, now you&amp;apos;re back in the world, my dear. And what was it, I wonder, that made you first wish to come out ? &amp;quot; She released her to pass her on to Lady Blount, who kissed her coldly. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ll have to do something with your head-wear a wig, I suppose. I couldn&amp;apos;t possibly have you going about like that. You look as if you had just come out of hospital, or prison. Besides, we don&amp;apos;t want to advertise our shame ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Pooh ! Shame ! &amp;quot; repeated Sir Charles. &amp;quot; What nonsense. Do be reasonable, Polly ! You&amp;apos;re not going to set yourself up as being wiser than the Pope ? Agatha has his permission to come out, and there&amp;apos;s nothing more to be said.&amp;quot; He patted her kindly on the back, and again assured her he was very glad to have her home. Lady Blount shrugged silk-clad shoulders. She was a handsome woman, handsomely dressed. Her faded light brown hair, arranged in loose bandeaux, was much crimped, to make up for its lost luxuriance. She had the straight Gerard features and thin mouth which she had given to most of her daughters. Alluding to them, and commenting on her husband&amp;apos;s last words, she said witheringly: &amp;quot; With five on your hands already!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, well, Agatha won&amp;apos;t compete with them, anyway!&amp;quot; Mrs. Trevor understood both points of view, and desired to administer consolation all round. &amp;quot; She&amp;apos;ll be a help, a great help, I&amp;apos;m sure! She&amp;apos;ll be as good as and better than a governess for the younger ones. I expect by the time you&amp;apos;re back from Folkestone I shan&amp;apos;t know that unruly younger crew. Sister Marie des Anges will have turned them all into model children. Well, Polly, I must go, and I don&amp;apos;t see you again until October. Fred and I start to-morrow. Good-bye, young people ! &amp;quot; She threw her voice into the recesses of the back drawingroom, where the tea-table still displayed its crumpled pieces of cake and last slice of bread and butter. Two tall young ladies, with a lanky, smiling youth, came forward, and these also kissed Agatha in the perfunctory way of families, where kisses are an obligatory rite, to be got over as lightly and quickly as possible. The elder of the two girls, Carrie, put even less warmth into her kiss than she might have done, had she not overheard her aunt&amp;apos;s remark on the youthfulness of Agatha&amp;apos;s appearance. But that Agatha, who was eight years her senior, should be said to look younger than she did, constituted a crime on her sister&amp;apos;s part difficult to forgive. The smiling youth, whose name was Edward, had likewise been solely struck by Mrs. Trevor&amp;apos;s reference to himself. &amp;quot; I should hope I don&amp;apos;t look like Aggie,&amp;quot; said he, and jingled softly the coins in the pockets of his trousers. &amp;quot; I should look very rummy if I did.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You remember, mother, we&amp;apos;re dining earlier to-night because of the theatre ? &amp;quot; Carrie observed. She gave a complacent glance into a mirror near at hand, and caressing little pats to her hair. &amp;quot; What theatre?&amp;quot; Sir Charles wanted to know. &amp;quot; Bernard Goldney has sent a box at the Haymarket for four, and mother&amp;apos;s going to take me and Katie, and he&amp;apos;s to meet us there,&amp;quot; Carrie explained; and Lady Blount commented: &amp;quot; A very stupid arrangement. He had much better have dined here, and have gone with us. He&amp;apos;s out with Katie now, and must bring her home first, which will give him very little time to get to Cleveland Gardens, and dress and dine.&amp;quot; Man-like, Ted flew to discomfit his mother, and defend his sex. &amp;quot; But how could Goldney dress here ? In the governor&amp;apos;s togs-or in mine, perhaps ? Or, should he have worn dressclothes on the river Or would you like him to go to the theatre in flannels ? He might have continued his interrogatories, but that Mary Frances, the younger girl, broke eagerly in upon him with: &amp;quot; Oh, mother, before you go, do tell Ted he must take me and Moghey round to the Nolans&amp;apos; this evening. Gwen has asked us in after dinner. They&amp;apos;re going to dance.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;re quite capable of taking yourselves,&amp;quot; declared Ted very sweetly. &amp;quot; But they want you to go. Gwen Nolan-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I shouldn&amp;apos;t dance anyway-&amp;quot; An animated wrangle broke out between the two. Ted, still vindicating his liberty of action, made strategic retreat towards the door, and his sister followed, pressing her point. His gentle voice was heard, saying from the stairs: &amp;quot;You may beg, you may pray, you may coax, you may threaten, but you don&amp;apos;t catch me going over to Porchester Terrace to-night.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; By-the-by, Polly,&amp;quot; said Sir Charles, &amp;quot;have you spoken to Hitchen&amp;apos;s yet about the conservatory ? I want that seen to before you leave town, otherwise you&amp;apos;ll never be satisfied. Wait a moment, Carrie; I&amp;apos;m coming down to see you out.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know whether to wear my black and white, or the violet chiffon ? &amp;quot; Lady Blount observed to her daughter Caroline. &amp;quot; The chiffon&amp;apos;s the most suitable, but that owl of a Sparkes has sewn the lace in the wrong way. Instead of the lapels hanging forwards, so, as they ought, she has turned them back. Come up to give me your advice.&amp;quot; Agatha found herself standing in the middle of the room, alone for the second time since her return home. She felt unwanted and forlorn. She had plenty of time that evening and during the days which followed to meditate over her aunt&amp;apos;s question: &amp;quot; What was it that first made you want to come out ? &amp;quot; Mrs. Trevor had not waited for the answer, nor could Agatha have given it. There was the death of the old Superior, and the arrival of the new one, and with the new one Agatha had never felt herself in sympathy. Almost the first thing Reverend Mother did was to get Sister Therese de la Sainte Croix transferred to Montmirail. Agatha&amp;apos;s grief over the separation could not be concealed, and Reverend Mother, while collecting-so to speak -each little bit of evidence of it, would watch the young nun with her enigmatic smile. One day there had been a talk of other changes, and the nuns had expressed their personal hopes and fears. Agatha exclaimed impulsively she wished she might be sent to Montmirail, as then she would again be with Sister Therse. She could have bitten her tongue off next moment when Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s eyes met hers, and she saw in them a flicker of satisfaction, prefacing the pronouncement : &amp;quot; It is not likely, my child, that Mother General will ever put you again under the same roof as Sister Th&amp;amp;rese. She might easily have become for you an occasion of sin. You must be on your guard against attaching yourself overmuch to the creature instead of to the Creator. A good religieuse gives her entire affection to God.&amp;quot; Agatha could still see, as in a picture, the hard face inside the border of immaculate white frill which made the skin look so sallow, and the small eyes, shrewd and sly, in which flickered an unkind satisfaction. She had not realised how little she had liked Reverend Mother until now that she had left her. Perhaps it was as much to escape from her jurisdiction as for any other reason that she had first wished to come out. But no, she knew this was not so. She knew that her action had been inspired less by the evil which she wished to avoid, than by the good which she wished to obtain, the definite and tremendous joy which in secret she coveted. While she sat in the drawing-room of Cromwell Road with a band of needlework in her fingers, while she walked with her sisters in Kensington Gardens, she would gaze in front of her with unseeing eyes, and dreaming of this great joy, she would feel the hot colour travel over her face and neck and arms, for she was not sure that her wish were not a sin. She remembered perfectly how and when it had first come to her, and another picture rose before her, that of an April morning in the convent garden two years ago, a heavenly day, when the scented snows of spring lay thick upon the apple-tree and hawthorn, and white and pink petals lay strewn upon the grass. The tumultuous sparrows filled the air with bird-talk, and the serener blackbird or thrush snatched now and again five minutes from nest-building to enchant his young bride with some jewelled song. A wind of awakened life blew through the garden which had lain asleep for months, and in the air was the fragrance and stimulus of the beauty which intoxicates. Agatha, walking on the outskirts of the little crowd of nuns that hung about Reverend Mother as bees about their queen, felt a stir in her blood that was half pleasure, wholly pain. She had often felt it before, and always on some such exquisite day as this. Her whole nature seemed to open wide to the beauty of the world, and -this constituted\the pleasure-the desire for even greater joy, for something unknown, something which never could be hers; succeeding this moment of ecstasy came the pain, a sharp pain which filled her eyes with tears. On that particular April morning she had walked in silence beside Sister Philomene of the Five Wounds, who herself was divided by another nun from the person of Reverend Mother. To be immediately on the right or left of Reverend Mother was the most eagerly sought privilege of the Community. During the hour of recreation no private talk was allowed. Reverend Mother provided the subject, and the Community was expected to converse on it, or to keep silence. To-day conversation had reached the absorbing topic of miracles, to which there was not a nun but could contribute at least from hearsay some well-authenticated tale. Sister Anastasia, a novice from Bruges, related the case of a child who, prompted by the Devil, secretly removed the Sacred Host from her tongue after Holy Communion, wrapped It in her pocket-handkerchief, and found an opportunity to bury It in the garden. Next morning a rose-tree covered with crimson roses was found growing from the spot. The authorities of the convent naturally suspected that something was wrong, since the month was December, and no rose-tree had ever been known in that part of the garden before. They caused, therefore, the mysterious bush to be pulled up by the roots, whereupon the Blessed Wafer was discovered, sticking to a rootlet, while a sinister chasm opened in the ground, about a yard in diameter, and of unfathomable depth. On the advice of the chaplain every individual of the household, from the Superior down to the youngest child, was invited to jump across this chasm, and all got across in safety until it came to the turn of the sacrilegious communicant, who missed her spring, fell in, and instantly the earth closed above her for ever. Agatha, forced to listen to this story in spite of herself, was filled with irritation at its puerility. She sighed; if only she might go and walk by herself out of hearing. She looked with wistfulness down the solitary glades of the garden. She perceived two women emerge from a side path, and advance towards the group of nuns with evident intention. These were Maggie MacKellar and her mother, Mrs. Ryan, who did some of the dressmaking for the school. All the nuns were interested in Maggie. She had been educated in their middle-class day school, for which there was a special building in another part of the grounds. Assisted by pupil-teachers, the nuns took it in turn to teach there, and pretty Maggie Ryan, with her sunny disposition ,and delightful Irish smile, had been the show-girl of her class. Therefore it had made a great sensation in the community when it had come to be known a year ago that Maggie was marrying MacKellar, the Scotch gardener, a widower, middle-aged, highly respectable. But this sensation was slight compared to the thrill produced ten months later when Maggie&amp;apos;s baby was first presented to the nuns. John MacKellar, junior, had been an object of absorbing interest to them ever since, and now, as first one and then another caught sight of the bundle of lace and cambric in Maggie&amp;apos;s arms, the foolish story was forgotten, the knot of women round Reverend Mother shook loose, and a general movement was made in the direction of the visitors. The proud young mother was encircled by goffered caps and black veils and, for the moment, all the nuns were normal natural women, deeply concerned in the perusal of a small human document. Maggie lifted the bit of net from the baby&amp;apos;s face, and each looked with delight at the wide-open, unwinking dark blue eyes, at the incredibly fine brows and lashes, at the incomparably soft hair. There were ecstatic comments. &amp;quot; Oh, Maggie! How he grows !&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What a perfect darling ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Did you ever see anything so sweet!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, Reverend Mother, do look! He&amp;apos;s holding on to my finger quite tight ! &amp;quot; Every nun claimed to hold the baby in turn, and he with complacency allowed himself to be transferred from one to another, while he clawed ineffectually at the cap frills, blew bubbles and smiled. The last to receive him was Agatha, and for this reason she was able to hold him the longest. Reverend Mother had led her flock from the lawn to the sunny benches of the still leafless rosery, where Mrs. MacKellar was given the place of honour on her right. For the Brides of God, with a natural inconsistency, are always found to pay marked deference to the Brides of Man. The condition of the widow or the virgin finds less favour in their eyes. Presently, as Agatha still held the child, the warmth of the little body began to penetrate through her thick habit, she began to feel it against her, warmer than herself. A sensation, novel, mysterious, undefinable, stirred at her heart, and she was terrified. She leaned her burning face down to the child&amp;apos;s to conceal her emotion, and hungrily kissed the little head and face. Perhaps she pressed him too hard, or merely frightened him, for he set up a vigorous howl, and almost wriggled himself out of her arms. Maggie Ryan flew to take him, rocked him against her bosom, soothed him with lovely nonsense, and Reverend Motherlooking at Agatha with her faint censorious smile-remarked that the baby did not appear to approve of Sister Marie&amp;apos;s amateur nursing. Then she rose, and the party broke up. The nuns dispersed to their different duties, Agatha to take her class. But she realised at last what it was that she desired -she wanted a child, she thirsted for the joy of possessing a child of her own, of laying its scented downy head against her breast. And a chill passed over her soul as she remembered that in less than two years she would be thirty, while Something not herself whispered: &amp;quot; Yes, and then your youth will have gone and you will never have lived.&amp;quot; Agatha, when clothed in her habit and within the convent walls, had been conscious that this wish was a sin. But even now that she was out in the world, with the acquisition of her final freedom depending on herself alone, she was not sure that the wish were permissible. Nor had she the courage to consult a living soul. Long before formulating the wish into words she must have died of shame. But she knew that it lay there at the bottom of her heart, that it was her secret hope of realising it which had driven her out into the world. After the first month of home life Agatha began to discover that Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s prescience had not been at fault. No one seemed to want her. Her father was always busy, her mother unsympathetic, and her sisters, although not unkind, were each one engrossed in her own affairs. When the holidays were over the three younger children were sent off to school, Lucy to begin her first term in Kensington Square, Bob back to Stoneyhurst, and the Babe, who had reached the dignity of an eighth birthday, to taste life&amp;apos;s realities at Hodder. There remained nothing for Agatha to do. She did not know how to employ her days. She missed the set tasks of the convent, the regular hours. Now, when she had heard Mass in the morning at the Oratory, or the Carmelite, when she had recited the Office of the Immaculate Conception, her duties were over, and she had hardly disposed of two hours. Fourteen or fifteen hours remained to kill in futilities, and while thus wearisomely engaged, her thoughts turned continually towards her one aspiration to have a home of her own, to have children, to be married. Of this desire she never spoke to a human being, scarcely even admitting it to herself, but it hid deep in her heart, wherein at the same time the conviction grew that there was no one waiting to marry her, that there were hundreds of girls younger and prettier than she, all keen on getting husbands, and understanding the rules of the game far better than she did. These had developed, had gained some experience, while she had remained, in body and mind, a convent girl of eighteen. Her knowledge of the world was no greater now than then, and at eighteen it had been a nebulous misknowledge made up of sentimentality garnered from the few novels she had been permitted to read, of the stray opinions she had heard from her elders, and of the wrong constructions she had put upon their actions and their attitude towards life. Agatha knew nothing of men, and her ideas concerning them were far-fetched and erroneous. She had generally heard them alluded to as sheep might allude to ravening wolves. How to avoid them, how to guard against them, how to defeat their machinations, these mysterious necessities never openly discussed before her were constantly hinted at in mysterious fashion. And as a deduction from these premises, to have found herself anywhere alone with a man-even for five minutes-would have paralysed Agatha with embarrassment and fear. At the same time, from poetry to fiction, she had derived another set of ideas equally absurd. Thus, she imagined that when a man wished to marry a woman he conducted himself like the knights of old, and welcomed everything at her hands, even affronts and unkindnesses. Indeed, from very maidenliness a really &amp;quot; nice &amp;quot; girl would be compelled to make him suffer. For instance, she must not admit that she cared about him, but must treat him with coldness and scorn, otherwise how could she be sure he was not merely trying to entrap her ? But the real, true knight would return. And after she had probed his constancy and devotion in various ways, she would permit him to kiss her hand. Which would be the only kiss ever permitted. Any other sort came under the heading of &amp;quot; not nice.&amp;quot; Once, as a mere baby, she had attempted to press her little mouth against her mother&amp;apos;s. But her mother had pushed it aside. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s disgusting to touch another person with your mouth! Turn your cheek. There! That&amp;apos;s the nice way to kiss ! &amp;quot; From that day onward Agatha&amp;apos;s kisses had been simply a cheek laid against a cheek, and a kiss given to the air. But when she went, at eight years old, to Streatham Convent, the nuns kissed her on the forehead, and when she, too, found herself a nun, she kissed the children in the same way, touching the centre of their foreheads with her lips. This was all she knew of kissing at the age of thirty-two, and she never imagined anything warmer. The first time she had seen Bernard Goldney kiss Katie she had experienced a disagreeable emotion. He did not kiss his fiancee &amp;quot;nicely &amp;quot; at all, but as though he really enjoyed it. Agatha was scandalised that Katie should take such a kiss as a matter of course. But Carrie&amp;apos;s ill-disguised eagerness to be with any sort of a man, her animation when talking to one, although so moody and taciturn with her own people, her undignified efforts to please him, scandalised Agatha even more. As for Mary Frances, with the shameless candour of sixteen, she blurted out every sentiment that her older sisters hid, and no man crossed the Blounts&amp;apos; orbit whom &amp;quot; M. F.&amp;quot; did not discuss in the light of a possible husband for herself or the others. The two preliminary points to be determined about him were if he were unmarried, and if he were of the true faith. &amp;quot; Is he a bachelor ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is he a Catholic ? &amp;quot; were her invariable inquiries. Should the first question be answered in the negative, she took no further interest in him at all, but if he turned out to be a bachelor, and not a Catholic, she loudly lamented this drawback to eligibility. In the happy event of his being a Catholic and unmarried. she took him metaphorically to her heart. The prettiest of the four was Margaret, who had the straightest features, the largest eyes, a more generous mouth than the others. In character she was placid and serene. Her silence made a striking contrast to Carrie&amp;apos;s volubility when the latter had slipped into her &amp;quot; company manners,&amp;quot; but when the family was alone Margaret&amp;apos;s silence was an amiable silence arising from nothing to say, and Carrie&amp;apos;s was an irritable silence because there was no one worth speaking to. Lady Blount showed more interest in Margaret than in her other daughters, cherishing hopes that the child would make a really good marriage, superintending her choice of frocks, and concerning herself with her amusements and occupations at home. With Agatha, who represented no possible brilliant future, but instead a lamentable present, tarnishing the dignity of the past, the mother&amp;apos;s only direct relations arose when there was some tedious job on hand, which her maid was too lazy or too incompetent to undertake. She would say then: &amp;quot; There is a whole pile of silk stockings, Agatha, lying on my bed to be mended. I wish you would see to them ! Sparkes darns so clumsily, I can never wear a stocking she has touched.&amp;quot; Agatha was humbly pleased that she could darn better than Sparkes, was grateful to her mother for the task, and still more for the faint implication of praise. On a certain evening in November a tall young lady, coming down the staircase in the Blounts&amp;apos; house, met on the half-way landing between two floors a similarly tall young lady in eveningdress, with elaborately waved hair. In one hand the apparition carried gloves and a fan, with the other she lifted her white gown, that the edge might not fray out through sweeping the stairs. A similar thrifty habit had been impressed on Agatha during&amp;apos;the years of her noviciate. Suddenly she realised that she was looking at her own image in the glass. The sight of her bare neck and arms disconcerted her. She considered them indecent, and yet it had been her own wish to have a real evening-frock. Katie had been married at the Oratory that morning, and when a dance had been first proposed and planned as a desirable wind-up to the wedding festivities, Agatha had timidly expressed this wish. Her mother had thrown cold water upon it, but her father had come to the rescue, telling her to order what she wanted and to send the bill to him. Katie had taken her to Madame Elise, who was making the trousseau, and Madame Elise and Katie together had insisted that a low dress must be really a low dress, and that it would be absurd not to show the whole of so plump and pretty a neck. In the garish daylight of Madame Elise&amp;apos;s fitting-room, with that lady making devastating gashes at arm-hole and bosom, a haughty assistant damsel handing pins, and Katie as spectator, Agatha, contemplating her own nakedness in triple glasses, was ready to sink through the floor with shame. Nevertheless, she let them have their will, understanding obscurely that some exhibition of herself was a necessary step to the accomplishment of her heart&amp;apos;s desire. In the big, completely emptied drawing-rooms, under the radiance of all the electric lights, Ted and Carrie whirled round, trying the floor, while at the piano Bob, up from Stoneyhurst for the wedding, strummed a waltz with heavy fingers and the aid of the loud pedal. Lucy Mary, nursing a basket of programmes, leaned against the piano&amp;apos;s tail, watching the musician with adoration, and criticising his performance with candour. The Babe, resplendent in real lace and black velvet, was busy making slides across the bow-window, an accomplishment just acquired on the ice in Lancashire. He muttered to himself choice morsels of his new Hodder vocabulary: &amp;quot; Now then, Toppin, you bloomin&amp;apos; kangaroo, out of my path! &amp;quot; and ignored his fellow men. When Agatha came into the room Robert let his hands crash down upon the keys, and stopped short. &amp;quot;My! ain&amp;apos;t I the cheese! &amp;quot; he said vulgarly, and &amp;quot; Sorry! &amp;quot; cried Ted, who, at that moment, steered his partner straight into her. &amp;quot; Have a programme ? &amp;quot; queried Zulu, and began to disentangle one of the highly glazed white and silver cards from the rest, a work of difficulty, as the slender cords and slim pencils were already inextricably mixed. &amp;quot; I bet you Aggie doesn&amp;apos;t get a dance all the evening!&amp;quot; declared Bob, with schoolboy brutality. Agatha smiled. &amp;quot; I shall get one, anyway, for I&amp;apos;m going to put down your name for the very first waltz, Robert,&amp;quot; and although he protested that the moment dancing began he meant to &amp;quot; bunk &amp;quot; to the refreshment-room, nevertheless he felt flattered and pleased, for, in spite of LucyteMary&amp;apos;s constantly expressed readiness to dance with him, he had not foreseen any chance of a real partner that night. Lady Blount swept into the room, a stately and even a gracious figure, and swept round it, making the most ungracious remarks. There was too much light-not enough flowers. Who had been stupid enough to put all that French chalk upon the floor ? &amp;quot; Just look at my gown, Carrie ! It will be absolutely ruined before the evening&amp;apos;s over ! So that&amp;apos;s your dress, Agatha ? I must say it&amp;apos;s most unsuitable! It&amp;apos;s the coming-out frock of a girl of seventeen. Elise ought to have had more sense.&amp;quot; The sound of the hall-door bell pealed through the house. &amp;quot;Here! People are beginning to arrive, and your father not yet down. He&amp;apos;s the most dilatory man I know. And where are Jack and Gerard, and the other girls ? &amp;quot; There were other bells. Four or five guests reached the drawing-room together. Jerningham entered one of the first. He looked very fresh, very handsome in his evening-clothes. His manner was cordial, charming. Even Lady Blount, smiling back into his good blue eyes, found nothing to censure. &amp;quot; Awfully sorry I couldn&amp;apos;t get to the wedding this morning! Hope it went off all right ? Yes, we only reached home to-day ourselves. Had a splendid time, done everything, been everywhere. I don&amp;apos;t believe there&amp;apos;s a church or a palace in Italy that we haven&amp;apos;t studied and sketched. And didn&amp;apos;t those old Italian chaps know how to build, too ? I&amp;apos;m crazy about Renaissance architecture, and the domes of Brunelleschi and Michael Angelo. Ah! there was Titian! But I mustn&amp;apos;t bore you with my crude enthusiasms-&amp;quot; He turned to Agatha, who stood near her mother. &amp;quot; Do you know, for a moment I hardly recognised you. Ladies&amp;apos; dress makes such a tremendous difference, doesn&amp;apos;t it ? But it&amp;apos;s awfully jolly to meet you again. Will you give me this dance ? It&amp;apos;s the first &amp;apos; extra &amp;apos;-just to set things going ? &amp;quot; The musicians were, by this time, installed in the back room, and a brilliant waltz had struck up. Guests were arriving in an unbroken stream, and light dresses and black coats formed little groups about the floor. He took her hand and they began at once. Agatha had been practising lately in the evening with Ted and Bernard Goldney, and she got round the room creditably. Before he left her he took her programme and wrote down his name for numbers five and eleven. A little giddy, but extremely happy, she danced the next waltz with Robert, and then sat down and looked on. Margaret and Mary Frances were surrounded by a crowd of eager youths. Their cards were completely filled, while many of their girl friends lined the walls, still waiting for introductions. Moghey, with the younger men, was particularly popular because she was so &amp;quot; tremendously pretty,&amp;quot; and because they thought her so intelligent. She always agreed with everything they said. Gerard Blount declared that &amp;quot; Moghey was of your own opinion, even before you had uttered it.&amp;quot; Carrie, with sparkling eyes and brilliant colour, and great animation, did the honours of the house in a spasmodic fashion. When asked for a dance by a man who didn&amp;apos;t please her, she remembered she was bound to look after her guests. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m so sorry, but I&amp;apos;m afraid I shan&amp;apos;t be able to dance this one; you see, there are so many girls sitting out. But you&amp;apos;ll be nice, won&amp;apos;t you, and let me introduce you to Miss Smith ? &amp;quot; And the presentation was made. Strange to say, she never had occasion to introduce Miss Smith to any save the bad dancers and the nonentities. The room was filled now with gyrating couples. It was amusing to watch them. When the music ceased, they streamed out upon the balcony, or downstairs to the conservatory or refreshment-room. Agatha saw that the Trevors were come. Aunt Carrie was over by the window talking to Lady Blount, and Uncle Fred, tall, thin and juvenile, was wandering about with his eye-glass in his eye, examining the decorations. Number five in the programme was reached. It was again a waltz. The first notes brought the most energetic hurrying in. Moghey entered on the arm of young Nolan, M. F. tripped and chattered beside a strange and spotted youth, who, as they danced, sawed her arm up and down like a pump-handle. The whole room twirled. Agatha could no longer follow any separate couple. She watched the dancers in a mass. Her feet tapped to the music. In another moment or so she, too, would be moving amongst them. Uncle Fred strolled up to her. &amp;quot; Have a turn, Aggie ? &amp;quot; he said condescendingly. &amp;quot; Thank you, Uncle Fred, but I&amp;apos;d rather not. I dance so badly.&amp;quot; It was her dance with Jerningham, but he had not come, and she was reluctant to say she still waited for him. &amp;quot;Oh, nonsense! I saw you dancing when I came. You seemed to get along all right. Let&amp;apos;s see your programme.&amp;quot; He took it from her. &amp;quot; Robert &amp;quot;; &amp;quot; C. J.&amp;quot; he read. That&amp;apos;s Jerningham, eh ? And here&amp;apos;s another &amp;quot; C. J.&amp;quot; lower down. But I don&amp;apos;t fancy he&amp;apos;ll come near you again. I&amp;apos;ve just been talking to him. Asked him how you danced, and told him you were an escaped nun. You should have seen his face ! &amp;quot; Agatha coloured deeply with humiliation and pain. &amp;quot; Oh, Uncle Fred! How could you be so unkind! &amp;quot; She stopped, choked with emotion and impending tears. &amp;quot; Well, it&amp;apos;s true, isn&amp;apos;t it ? You can&amp;apos;t expect to keep it dark, and lots of fellows would like you the better for it, it shows your spirit. But Jerningham seems to be one of those strict sort of chaps. I could see he thought he&amp;apos;d been committing a sacrilege to have had his arm round your waist. Yes, look here. He&amp;apos;s chucked you for Carrie! Come along ! &amp;quot; Agatha was obliged to obey, but, swung energetically round in her uncle&amp;apos;s arms, discovered that she hated waltzing and never wished to dance again. As she resolutely declined refreshments, Major Trevor went off alone in search of them. &amp;quot; Well, Miss Blount, you&amp;apos;ve not forgotten me, I hope ?&amp;quot; said a voice at her elbow, and raising her head she saw Alfred Withers, a Folkestone friend of Jack&amp;apos;s, whom she had met when there in the summer. They shook hands. &amp;quot;You&amp;apos;re not dancing ? &amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot;Then I&amp;apos;ll sit down beside you if I may, and we&amp;apos;ll gossip a bit. A very different scene, this, to Folkestone beach, isn&amp;apos;t it ? Not nearly so healthy a one. When I marry I shan&amp;apos;t let my wife dance or keep late hours. They play the dickens with a woman&amp;apos;s health. Besides, a wife&amp;apos;s place is in her home. You agree with me, I&amp;apos;m sure ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, I certainly do,&amp;quot; Agatha answered shyly, and her thoughts flew to Katie, as they had done so often during the evening, to wonder what she was doing, how she was feeling at that very moment. Katie must surely feel horribly strange and embarrassed at finding herself quite alone with a man in a foreign town, even though that man were one whom she knew as well as Bernard. Yet Katie liked to be with Bernard; undoubtedly she would sooner be alone with him at the Paris hotel than here amongst all her family at the dance. Agatha spoke her conclusions out loud. &amp;quot; But I suppose that when a girl marries she gives up society of her own accord ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not a bit of it. Wants to go out all the more. But a man must be a fool who permits it. A sensible man knows how to control his wife and household. Don&amp;apos;t you agree with me?&amp;quot; he asked again, and Agatha murmured that she did agree. Withers kept stroking his beard, while he watched his companion from behind his glasses with intelligent, purposeful eyes. &amp;quot; My wife,&amp;quot; he affirmed, &amp;quot; will find her pleasure at home looking after her husband and children. Suppose we go downstairs into the conservatory ? We shall be more to ourselves.&amp;quot; He led her there without waiting for any reply, and she liked these masterful ways, which relieved her of the difficulty of deciding for herself. His personality did not attract her as Jerningham&amp;apos;s did, although it was true that his pointed auburn beard brought him nearer&amp;apos;to the blonde Christ of her dreams. Besides, Jerningham had deserted her, and evidently condemned her, while Withers either did not know her story or, knowing, was indifferent to it. But Jack had told them that Withers was a Protestant; no doubt for this reason he would not care. And reflecting on this point, she felt a sort of terror as she measured the distance she had fallen since coming back into the world. It seemed monstrous that she, Sister Marie des Anges, should be sitting amicably beside a Protestant, should be listening to his conversation with interest. Were he to die to-night, she knew that he must go straight to Hell for ever. She looked at him with awe-filled and compassionate eyes. Withers laughed, said, &amp;quot; May I ask your thoughts ? &amp;quot; and was amused and flattered by the confusion into which Agatha fell. He told himself she was a malleable little creature, and he didn&amp;apos;t forget that she possessed six thousand pounds. The fact that she had been a nun didn&amp;apos;t perturb him at all, and that she remained a Roman Catholic was a point in her favour. He approved of religion for women in the same way as he approved of blinkers for horses-it kept them straight. And the stricter the religion, the more numerous its rites, so much the less latitude and opportunity to swerve. He even saw no objection to the confessional-box in England, where temperaments-like the climate-are cold. His self-confidence assured him that all priestly influence over any woman of his would drop from her as she left the church. In his house there would be only one master, Alfred Withers: but Agatha Blount appeared to him well fitted to make a dutiful mistress of it. He moved his chair nearer, and, prompt in his decisions and their execution, took her hand. Agatha was filled with an indescribable terror, her whole body began to tremble, she longed to be a thousand miles away. Oh! he was going to kiss her! And then she realised, with a still greater terror, that she wanted to be kissed. The next moment Jack Blount and Gwendoline Nolan came round the clump of palms which masked the inmates of the conservatory from the stairs. Jack exclaimed: &amp;quot; Hullo, old man! So that&amp;apos;s where you were all the time ! Wondered where you had got to. You and Aggie have found a quiet corner, but you won&amp;apos;t mind us, will you ? Now then, Gwen, put yourself here, my child, and I&amp;apos;ll fan you.&amp;quot; Withers gave Agatha a look in which she read annoyance, regret, and his well-defined intention of kissing her on some future occasion. Then he got up and offered her his arm. &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ll leave you the field, Blount,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot; Your sister and I were just going back to the drawing-room.&amp;quot; Throughout that winter Alfred Withers came often to Cromwell Road, where the Blounts were informally at home on Sundays, and he received invitations with Jerningham and others to theatre-parties and Town Hall dances. When May proved an exceptionally warm and brilliant month, and boating began, the Blounts gave their annual river picnic, sixteen young people and two boats from Maidenhead up to Sonning. Withers, who kept a boat of his own at Twickenham, offered a return hospitality by inviting Agatha, Moghey and Ted to spend a day with him there on the river. But the opportunity of the conservatory did not renew itself, and he refrained from forcing the hand of Fate. At the same time Agatha was conscious that he paid her a subtle and particular attention which he did not pay to the other girls. She could not have defined precisely in what it lay, and yet the knowledge of it kept her perfectly happy. She was content, since he was, to let things drift, just as she was content to sit still in the stern of the boat beside Moghey, who steered, and watch him sculling stroke. She would let her hand hang over the edge of the boat, liking to feel the water rush through her open fingers, and she liked, too, to know that his intelligent, short-sighted eyes behind the inevitable glasses were constantly studying her face and person. That day spent on the suburban waters, between Twickenham and Chertsey, was one of the two happiest days of her life-the day of the dance, because of a few moments of expectation, had been the other. Meanwhile, behind the social side of life there arose an agitating question, the question of her dowry. Would the Order of the Immaculate Conception return it, or refuse to return it ? Lady Blount was absolutely convinced of the equity of its return, and Sir Charles would have welcomed it-the family being large and their expenses heavy. Urged thereto by his wife, he had written to Reverend Mother on the subject, before Agatha had been at home many weeks. A voluminous and apparently interminable correspondence ensued. Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s contention was that until Agatha had applied for and obtained final release from her vows, no question of a return of dowry could be entertained; but that, in any case, the Order could only relinquish its right to the thousand pounds given by Sir Charles on her profession. Of the six thousand inherited by her when already professed some years, she had made a free gift in due legal form to the Order, the money had gone to the building of the new chapel and wing and could not be returned. Over this transaction, and the multitudinous minor points attached thereto, there were months of correspondence, scores of letters between the solicitors of the Streatham nuns and Sir Charles and between Sir Charles and his old friend, Nolan, who had been Lady Welford&amp;apos;s solicitor and Agatha&amp;apos;s trustee. Sir Charles was especially annoyed that Nolan had not advised him of Agatha&amp;apos;s so-called &amp;quot; free gift &amp;quot; to the convent, that all had been done behind his back and without asking his consent. To which Nolan replied that Blount&amp;apos;s consent was not needed. Lady Welford&amp;apos;s will gave instructions that should Agatha, on her marriage, or at any other time, require a portion or the whole of the six thousand pounds paid over to her, Nolan, providing that he approved of the purpose for which she required it, was to make this payment. And he produced a letter from Agatha, requesting him tq sell out the whole of her Bank of Australia stock, and to draw up a deed conveying the proceeds to Reverend Mother. Sir Charles spoke of undue influence. It became a pretty quarrel. The lawyers flourished and Agatha suffered, for her mother -highly incensed-never lost an opportunity to reproach her. She was reproached for her selfishness and want of natural affection in signing away her property to strangers, for her weakness of character in changing her vocation, and for the disrepute she had brought upon her family in coming home. If she ever needed any new clothes, or the smallest sum of money, Lady Blount complained. &amp;quot;You should try to manage with what you have, Agatha; that is the least you can do, remembering the heavy expenses your father is put to for the education of the boys, and that you are an extra person to keep, on whom we never reckoned.&amp;quot; Or: &amp;quot; You ought not to write so many letters then! You appear to eat stamps ! I&amp;apos;m sure your correspondence alone must cost your father C20 a year.&amp;quot; Constant recriminations of this sort became so humiliating that Agatha at last would sooner walk any distance than ask for a &amp;apos;bus fare, and she took to using-the free seats at Mass, in order to reserve her few pence for the offertory. By July Reverend Mother&amp;apos;s position was proved to be unassailable, the i6ooo belonged indubitably to the Order, and the figo was only to be returned if Agatha ultimately decided to remain in the world and have her vows cancelled. On the other hand, Reverend Mother pointed out that if Agatha changed her mind, there would always be a home for her in the convent. Sir Charles gave up the contest, weary of it, and of a great many other things as well. But Lady Blount showed the usual feminine inability to accept the inevitable, and merely included him, for his want of energy and determination, under the ban of her displeasure, which lay heavy upon Agatha. Nor could she cease from discussing the subject, and even the visitors who came to the house, including Jerningham and Withers, were invited to listen to her lamentations, and to give their views. Withers&amp;apos; chief view was one which he kept to himself, and he was glad to remember that he had not kissed Agatha in the conservatory. He intended to marry, the marriage status being desirable for a medical man, an asset like a carriage; he liked Agatha, and C6ooo would have decided him for her. But a thousand pounds was not worth considering. Fortunately, no harm was done. He had only to avoid the Blounts for a time. The summer holidays, just at hand, offered a natural break in the intimacy which, after the holidays, need not be resumed. He left town for Colchester, to spend an inexpensive vacation in his sister&amp;apos;s house, and carried with him an agreeable sense of security in his unfailing good luck. The Blounts again went to Folkestone, but this year&amp;apos;s visit did not repeat last year&amp;apos;s success. The party was smaller by Katie and Bernard Goldney, and less gay. Sir Charles sat listless all day in the furnished house he had hired on the Lower Sandgate Road, and stared at the sea. He refused to escort his wife to the band, and seemed tired of everything. Lady Blount told each of her children, separately and many times over: &amp;quot; Your father is the most indolent and annoying man I know! Just look at him ! He does nothing whatever from morning to night! Anybody else would be here, there and everywhere, up on the Leas with me, or over on the Hythe Golf Course. I expect he will soon be too idle to feed himself, and will expect some of us to do it for him.&amp;quot; Agatha remembered this taunt with a pain in her heart when, back in town a few weeks later, she leaned over her father&amp;apos;s bedside, trying to tempt his appetite with jelly or grapes. But he was tired of life, the result of his illness, or perhaps the cause of it, and after years of an apparently enviable success, he let himself succumb to his long latent, but suddenly developed disease with scarcely a struggle. In the first stress of grief over her father&amp;apos;s death, Agatha forgot to think about Alfred Withers, whose card of &amp;quot; sincere sympathy &amp;quot; had reached the family with hundreds of others. And there was also much else to think about, continual discussions as to ways and means, plans for the future. John Blount and Bernard Goldney were the executors of the will, by which a sum of ?500 had been provided for immediate expenses. Everything else had been left to Lady Blount, and on going into accounts it was estimated she might have between 40o and ?500 a year, which seemed a pittance after the lavish expenditure she had been accustomed to. The house in Cromwell Road must be given up, the carriages and horses parted with, expenses cut in every way. But certain expenses could not be cut, such as the schooling of the younger children. It became evident that the elders must fend for themselves, the daughters as well as the sons-unless, indeed, the girls were so fortunate as to marry. The one bright part of the unsuccessful Folkestone summer was the fact that Margaret had got engaged to a certain Tom Bois. &amp;quot;He ought to have chosen M. F.,&amp;quot; Robert remarked, &amp;quot; as then there would have been two tom-boys together.&amp;quot; Talking over their prospects with her eldest son, Jack Blount was of opinion that visitors should now be invited to the house again, of course in the quietest possible way. Jerningham was given to understand that Lady Blount would be pleased to see him on Sunday afternoons, as before. To Mr. Withers a definite invitation was sent, and his immediate reply read so cordially, the excuse given appeared so inevitable, his regret so sincere that Lady Blount, in the course of a week or two, wrote to invite him again. Again, &amp;quot; most unfortunately,&amp;quot; he was prevented accepting. Jack Blount, meeting him by chance, asked him to look them up at home. He promised with effusion to do so, but did not come. Agatha wondered and suffered in silence, and the others forgot him. One day Carrie came flying into the drawing-room, full of news and the desire to impart it. &amp;quot; What do you think I&amp;apos;ve just heard from Cyril Jerningham ? Mr. Withers is going to marry Rhoda Hammond! Isn&amp;apos;t it queer ? Think of that hideous, red-haired, freckled little creature ! &amp;quot; Lady Blount felt deeply injured, the marriage of other people&amp;apos;s daughters always appeared unpardonable to her. She said peevishly. &amp;quot; I credited Mr. Withers with better taste,&amp;quot; and then found a reason for his seeming lack of it. &amp;quot; To be sure, Rhoda must have at least thirty thousand pounds. Her grandfather was &amp;apos; Hammond&amp;apos;s Blood Mixture.&amp;apos; You see the name everywhere still.&amp;quot; Ted was present, getting home from the bank early. He remarked, &amp;quot; I never could bear that chap! He&amp;apos;s as close-fisted as they make &amp;apos;em. The day we went up the river with him, he let me pay all the locks. Another cup of tea, Aggie, please, and rather hotter and stronger than the last.&amp;quot; Katie Goldney, who was calling, said, &amp;quot; I used to think Mr. Withers liked Agatha,&amp;quot; but no one took this up, and Agatha herself kept her head bent low over the tea-tray, ministering to Ted&amp;apos;s wants. This, then, was the reason she had seen nothing of him for so many weeks. He had been making the acquaintance of Rhoda Hammond, had been falling in love, and was now going to marry her. It seemed extraordinary to Agatha. She thought of the dance last November, a year ago; of the kiss he had not given her in the conservatory; and she thought of Rhoda-a mere child-it was but the other day that she wore short frocks, and her thick red hair in a plait with a fuzzy end to it. It seemed incredible she was to be married. Agatha remembered Rhoda&amp;apos;s passion for Sister Marie des Anges, and suddenly understood how these school-girl adorations were just a preparation for the real emotions of life, a &amp;quot; false dawn &amp;quot; before the morning broke. After this, life seemed to Agatha more unsatisfactory than ever. Often now she found herself looking at the clock, and saying, &amp;quot; At Streatham the nuns are just going into chapel for Benediction,&amp;quot; or &amp;quot; they are walking in the garden.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Sister Aloysius is telling tales of the Saints. Every one is happy and amused.&amp;quot; In the evening, when she sat at Aunt Carrie&amp;apos;s, taking a hand at cards, or turning over the leaves of a book at home, she would reflect: &amp;quot; NQw everybody in the convent is asleep.&amp;quot; She forgot the little miseries and boredoms of convent life, its dark hours and days. She remembered only the irresponsible, child-like existence there, in which she had her work, her place, her rairon d&amp;apos;ttre. In the world she had no railon d&amp;apos;etre at all. Worse than that, she was a burden upon her family. She would have liked to find paying employment, but there was nothing which she could do except teach young children, and certainly no Catholic parents would engage her as a governess. Sometimes she wondered whether she ought not to return to the convent, where, as Reverend Mother had written, her future was always assured. She hesitated over the irrevocable step, until there came a trivial word, heard by chance, which decided her. She and Carrie were spending the evening at Aunt Caroline&amp;apos;s, who occupied a flat on the second floor over a shop in the Brompton Road. The rooms were very small, and overflowing with Oriental trumpery picked up in the bazaars of Delhi and Meerut. There was music and cards, and two or three Catholic young men of the usual type. Under cover of a song, she overheard one youth saying to another, &amp;quot; No, that&amp;apos;s not Carrie Blount in black, that&amp;apos;s the old one. Carrie is in white.&amp;quot; With this surprising word &amp;quot; old &amp;quot; still ringing in her ears, Agatha looked at herself next morning long and critically in the glass. She saw that disappointment, late hours, and the change from the regularity of convent life had altered her immensely. She looked not only her age, but more than her age. She was hollow-cheeked, her hair had whitened upon the temples and above the ears. She felt certain that her chances of marriage had gone by, and sitting down she wrote a submissive letter to Reverend Mother, humbly begging to be taken back. In less than a month after the letter&amp;apos;s despatch she lived again within convent walls.</FullText></Record>