<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2443792</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131534</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>The Holy Mountain</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Jun 1909</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19090601</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Reynolds</LastName><FirstName>Stephen</FirstName><PersonName>Stephen Reynolds</PersonName><OriginalForm>Reynolds, Stephen</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Ford</LastName><MiddleName>Madox</MiddleName><FirstName>Ford</FirstName><PersonName>Ford Madox Ford</PersonName><OriginalForm>Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>517</StartPage><EndPage>578</EndPage><Pagination>517-578</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2443792/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>The Holy Mountain By Stephen Reynolds (AuTHoR oF &amp;quot;A PooR MAN&amp;apos;s Hous &amp;quot;&amp;apos;) VII ANOTHER, a far less edifying but much more amusing scene was enacted that Sunday evening. Mr. Ganthorn&amp;apos;s servant spent her time from half-past nine to ten o&amp;apos;clock in bidding a long &amp;quot; So long! &amp;quot; to her sweetheart. Then, as the clock struck, she said: &amp;quot;Bye-bye, &amp;apos;Arry. You must go now. So long.&amp;quot; Whereupon the young man peeped outside the gate, returned to take another kiss from his fair lady, and did go. The front door banged. A light flitted about. Within five minutes the dwelling and its precincts were quite quiet. Such an idyllic little scene could hardly have taken place had Mrs. Ganthorn been at home. She was visiting her unmarried sister, where, indeed, the childless woman stayed during the greater part of the year; for she found that distance lent a very considerable enchantment to her sharp little husband. He, on his side, quickly lived down the gossip which had its origin in an absentee wife. Away, she could not gall his cool sceptical intellect with her sloppy emotionalism; and the arrangement was particularly happy in that it left him a much greater freedom to entertain his friends. Mr. Ganthorn&amp;apos;s back sitting-room was a place outside the meaning of the Acts which have from time to time been passed in the hope of putting a check to drinking and gambling. It was, in fact, an unregistered, uninspected club. When completely sober, he was an objectionable little man; everybody in Trowbury knew that; but when he had taken something to drink he was the best of hosts; hospitable, pungent and amusing, according to the standards of Trowbury; and, above all, when his wife was away he could without let or hindrance invite anybody and everybody to take a glass or glasses at his house at any hour of the day or night. Shortly after the maidservant had gone to bed, he came up the street attended by Messrs. Trotman, Clinch and Borbellthe last-named being a cattle dealer of astonishing dimensions and reputed wealth. The time of night was five minutes past ten; precisely five minutes, that is, after the closing of the Blue Boar bar. The merry party stood outside the gate for a while, looking at the stars, smoking, and waiting for Mr. Ganthorn formally to invite them in. &amp;quot; Young George Potterne&amp;apos;s going it, isn&amp;apos;t he ? &amp;quot; Mr. Clinch was saying. &amp;quot; Ought to have been turned out an hour before closing time to-night,&amp;quot; said Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;d have a law to prevent all young fellows drinking before they&amp;apos;re twenty-five or so.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Did you ? &amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn asked. &amp;quot; I knew when to stop....&amp;quot; &amp;quot; More than you do now, old chap.&amp;quot; There was a hearty laugh, broken into by the husky voice of Mr. Borbell, who said in his hearty fashion: &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s like his grandfather. . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; rou didn&amp;apos;t know his wusshup&amp;apos;s grandfather.&amp;quot; Another laugh. &amp;quot; Young George Potterne, I means. I mind buying scores of beasts from old John James Potterne. I&amp;apos;ve driven many a hard bargain with him when he was sober, but when he was a bit in liquor. . . . Lor&amp;apos; bless you! he always got the top hand o&amp;apos; me then.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Who&amp;apos;s that got the better of you, Borbell ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why, as I was saying, old John James Potterne did-when he&amp;apos;d had a drop. And what&amp;apos;s bred in the bone comes out in the flesh, I say. All they Potterne&amp;apos;s be twice the men drunk to what they be sober.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; So are we all. All! &amp;quot; said Mr. Ganthorn. &amp;quot; Now, gentlemen, what brew of wet damnation is it to-night ? &amp;quot; By this time they were all well inside the house. &amp;quot; Try another chair, Borbell,&amp;quot; said Mr. Ganthorn. The general laugh was increased to a roar of merriment when he added, &amp;quot; My wife bought that little one at the Emporium the last time she visited me.&amp;quot; It is not difficult to understand why Mr. Ganthorn, in spite of his acidity, was accounted the best entertainer in Trowbury. He dug at all his guests impartially, so putting them at ease with one another; and when that can be brought about, of what importance comparatively is the nature of the host ? A violent knocking at the door was heard. &amp;quot; George Potterne himself, I&amp;apos;ll lay five to one-in threepenny bits,&amp;quot; exclaimed Mr. Ganthorn. &amp;quot; Done! &amp;quot; replied Mr. Borbell.-&amp;quot; Damme, &amp;apos;tis! I thought I knew his knock better than that.&amp;quot; George Potterne lurched in. &amp;quot; Thought you&amp;apos;d given me the slip, did you ? &amp;quot; he greeted them. &amp;quot; I was up to your little tricks. Trust me! The three of you won seventeen and tenpence out of me last Thursday. Now you&amp;apos;ve got to give me my revenge.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No cards on Sunday,&amp;quot; said Mr. Trotman, &amp;quot; or I go.&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn took up the cue. &amp;quot; Look here, George, you&amp;apos;re in my house,&amp;apos;and I sha&amp;apos;n&amp;apos;t have card-playing on Sunday.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Course not,&amp;quot; Mr. Borbell added. &amp;quot; You youngsters don&amp;apos;t care for hog, dog, or devil nowadays.&amp;quot; George Potterne was fumbling in his inside breast-pocket. &amp;quot; Look here, you chaps,&amp;quot; he went on with unsober inconsequence, &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve got something to show you &amp;apos;ll make you sit up.&amp;quot; He pulled out a red morocco pocket-book. &amp;quot; Who gave you that, George ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; My sister. Rather nice, ain&amp;apos;t it ? Better&amp;apos;n most women&amp;apos;s presents.-There look ! How d&amp;apos; you like that ? Latest from Paris. Got it when I was up in town.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What were you up in town for?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Never you mind.&amp;quot; A card, shaped like a folded butterfly was handed round. &amp;quot; Pretty toy for boys,&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn remarked. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve seen better.&amp;quot; Mr. Clinch turned it over and over, opened it and shut it two or three times, as if he would have liked to stock it at the Emporium. &amp;quot; Cleverly got up,&amp;quot; he observed. Mr. Borbell said he had done with things of that sort, whilst the Mayor, after a lengthy and rather shamefaced examination, said emphatically: &amp;quot; If I had my way, I&amp;apos;d soon put an end to things of that sort. Disgraceful! &amp;quot;Get out, you old fool!&amp;quot; George Potterne exclaimed. &amp;quot;You&amp;apos;d like one if you could get it quiet-and on the cheap.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You or me had better go, I think,&amp;quot; said his worship with dignity. &amp;quot; If ever you get brought up before me . . . &amp;quot; Dry up!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Look here, George,&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn interposed, &amp;quot;you and your butterfly had better go. Time all young people were in bed. Sunday too.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Sha &amp;apos;n&amp;apos;t ! I want a game o&amp;apos; nap.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Let&amp;apos;s see. . .. How much is it you owe me ? Two five-pound notes, six pounds in gold, ten and six for whisky. . &amp;quot;All right, old chap. You&amp;apos;ve got security-took good care of that. I&amp;apos;m going. You needn&amp;apos;t throw a fellow&amp;apos;s debts in his face.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You try throwing what you owe me into mine.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, shut up . Exit Mr. George Potterne junior. For a few minutes the remaining four men sipped their drinks in silence. Said Mr. Clinch at last: &amp;quot; Who&amp;apos;s going to be mayor next year ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;You, of course. It&amp;apos;s your turn.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I can&amp;apos;t, I tell you. I can&amp;apos;t. Expenses of enlargement and bad debts . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ll have to if we make you, or else pay up the fiftypound fine.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Look here, I can&amp;apos;t; not next year. I can&amp;apos;t really. A bit later-then I&amp;apos;ll be mayor willingly, and do it well.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Who is to be mayor then ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I tell you what, gentlemen,&amp;quot; said Mr. Borbell with mock solemnity. &amp;quot; Mr. Trotman here is always talking about Trowbury, and saying it only wants to be known how progressive and pretty and cetera the town is, for people with money to come and live here, and works and businesses and such-like. Well, his son&amp;apos;s been and got hisself known with a vengeance if the newspapers is true. Why don&amp;apos;t you make Mr. Alec Trotman mayor ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What! &amp;quot; cried Mr. Trotman. But it was evident the idea pleased him. &amp;quot; Make young Trotman mayor,&amp;quot; continued Mr. Borbell. &amp;quot; No reason as I can see why a son shouldn&amp;apos;t follow his father. You were pleased enough when young Paton was mayor just before his father died and only a year after his father too.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The expense . . .&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman began. &amp;quot;Pooh! &amp;quot; exclaimed Mr. Ganthorn. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t tell me you haven&amp;apos;t made anything out of the mayor&amp;apos;s salary. I&amp;apos;d keep the office in the family if I were you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;ll make some money out of this Holy Mountain job, won&amp;apos;t he; or you will?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I can&amp;apos;t say,&amp;quot; replied Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot; And I&amp;apos;m not at liberty to tell you anything about it. You can see all there is to be known in the newspapers.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; In the Half nny Priss ? &amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn jeered. &amp;quot;Let&amp;apos;s have a rubber of whist,&amp;quot; said Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot;Thought you didn&amp;apos;t play cards on Sunday ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Twill be Monday by the time you&amp;apos;ve got the cards out and dealt.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, anyhow, is it settled young Trotman&amp;apos;s to be mayor next year ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, of course &amp;apos;tis. Isn&amp;apos;t it, Trotman &amp;quot; &amp;quot;If the town confers that honour....&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Drat the town and its honour! We&amp;apos;re the honourable town. If we say so, he will be, and then let &amp;apos;em object if they like and how they like. That&amp;apos;s done. Cut for partners. Shilling points Refresh your glasses, gentlemen. Forget yourselves.&amp;quot; With full glasses, free tongues, and a merry pack of cards will we leave the leading burgesses of Trowbury. The game obliterated all discussion about the Holy Mountain. The petrified brains of Trowbury were, indeed, unfitted to deal with anything that had developed to such dimensions and intricacy. London might stir itself; but Trowbury.... It was the centre of the storm and, as such, calm. VIII On Monday morning both Mrs. Trotman and Julia received Sunday letters from Alec. He told his mother shortly that he was enjoying himself awfully in London and that everybody was awfully nice; that Sir Pushcott Bingley was very nice and very busy; that Mr. Fulton took him all about London on a motor-car; that lots of people seemed to know him; that a gramophone thing had spoken for him at the Crystal Palace, where the light had hurt his eyes and he didn&amp;apos;t know whether it was supposed to be minstrels or a service. Finally, he said that he didn&amp;apos;t much like wine and that he had a rather awful stomach-ache. He omitted to say that he was engaged to appear in a patriotic ballet at a music-hall. In fact, he hardly realised it himself. The stomach-ache took up the major part of Mrs. Trotman&amp;apos;s attention. She greatly feared that stomach-ache and would at once have set out for London had not her husband pooh-poohed the idea and called her a silly old hen-the one jibe which always tamed her solicitude for her son. After much worry and more talk, she contented herself with sending to Alec by express post a large-sized bottle of the local chemist&amp;apos;s Electric Stomach Elixir. Julia Jepp&amp;apos;s letter was by far the longer: &amp;quot; DEAR JULIE,-You did not mean what you said when I was leaving Trowbury, did you. I do love you, Julie. Write and say you did not, I cannot think why you did. &amp;quot; Julie, I&amp;apos;m having such an awfully jolly time and everybody is awfully kind and lots of people know me. They are not so stuck up in London as they are in Trowbury. &amp;quot; You never saw such a lot of people as there were at the Crystal Palace to hear me speak. I should think there was nearly a million or at least ioooo, all there to hear your Alec speak and I didn&amp;apos;t make a speech after all, I&amp;apos;ll tell you really only you must not split or else Mr. Fulton says the game will be up if people get to know. Mr. Fulton and a clergyman from the mission made up a speech for me and made me read it out twice for practice. Then I spoke it into a gramophone thing and it was a great big one with four big funnels that spoke it for me at the Crystal Palace, only it wasn&amp;apos;t mine really. I never saw such a lot of people, you could not nearly see to the end of them and their faces were like confletti what they throw at weddings. There were a lot of bishops there and all sorts, when the machine had finished talking they clapped and made such a noise and sang for he&amp;apos;s a jolly good fellow several times and then a man said let us pray through a speaking trumpet and Sir Pushcott Bingley said for God&amp;apos;s sake let&amp;apos;s get out of this and we went. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve got to go to the Neeopolitan Music Hall to-morrow but not speak. Sir P. says speaking is not my strong point, he says it is better for me to be ornamental. He has not asked me to write an article for his paper yet, but I expect he will soon. He says I shall have quite money enough to do what I want to on and perhaps more if things go all right, I wish I could go with you on the Downs to-night. I have been on a motor with Mr. Fulton to see Ramshorn Hill in Acton, it looks miserable and dirty. Hoping this will find you well as it leaves me only I have got a stummycake.-Your loving ever and ever &amp;quot; ALEXANDER TROTMAN.&amp;quot; Nothing but real love could have given Chop-Allie Trotman the energy to make such a prodigious effort in the way of letterwriting. Julia was proud and frightened and softened by turns. But Alec&amp;apos;s success did in the end only strengthen her determination to go on being a martyr. It made her feel a good and disinterested onlooker. It overcame her motherliness. The worst vices of such women as Julia Jepp are virtues out of place. Ix Whilst Mrs. Trotman was suffering from suppressed solicitude for Alexander&amp;apos;s digestion, was taking the servant into her confidence and pouring forth a tale of gastric woe, Mr. Trotman sat over his third cup of tea with the calm air of a philosopher and man of sense, and read the morning&amp;apos;s Hal/penny Press. &amp;quot; If Alec is really ill,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot; you can be quite sure Sir Pushcott will have the best doctors. There&amp;apos;s nothing secondrate about Sir Pushcott Bingley. &amp;quot; No, I know there&amp;apos;s not,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Trotman in tones of unconviction. &amp;quot; Well, then, for goodness&amp;apos; sake be quiet!&amp;quot; The Halfpenny Press was indeed most interesting. It contained a special four-page supplement, filled with pictures of the Crystal Palace Empire Revival Mission and a squib-like account thereof. No less than one whole page was given up to correspondence, From Our Readers.-Two-score donkeys nibbling at a carrot. One busybody of the parasitical world which collects and administers subscriptions said at great length that, in the case of the Wonder Worker being left unrewarded, he was prepared to receive sums of money from a halfpenny (only the price of a newspaper) upwards, towards the cost of purchasing a life annuity for him who had shown mankind that miracles were as possible in this our twentieth century as in the olden days. Such a demonstration, the busybody pointed out, could but infuse courage into the hearts of all those who were fighting the good fight on behalf of the immutable truths of religion. An editorial note, however, while commending the busybody as a truly religious patriot, mentioned that proposals were already afoot in high and influential circles to give the Holy Mountain to Mr. Alexander Trotman, the mover of it; or, at least, to lease it to him from the Crown on very advantageous terms. Ramshorn Hill, now justly called the Holy Mountain, being Crown land, was national property, and, therefore, this brilliant proposal would enable every British man, woman, and child substantially to show their gratitude to Mr. Trotmanwhether they wished to or not. Fox populi, vox Dci ! In such a way the right-minded majority could compel the careless, unpatriotic, irreligious minority to contribute towards that recognition which no Britisher should wish to deny. There could be no shadow of doubt that Mr. Trotman would use the gift in such a way that the best interests of religion and the glory of the British Empire would be equally advanced. So said the Hal/penny Press. Notice was given that the Neapolitan Music Hall would be closed on that (Monday) evening in order to prepare a grand patriotic Church and Empire Ballet in which Mr. Alexander Trotman would take part. The Mountain-Mover would thus be visible to all who were unable or unaccustomed to attend revivals. The Halfpenny Press would book orders for seats by telephone. A letter from the Archbishop of All the Empire&amp;apos;s chaplain ran: &amp;quot; His Grace desires me to say that he considers the Church and Empire Ballet, reverently treated, to be an excellent idea.&amp;quot; On the morrow, the only authorised biography of Mr. Alexander Trotman would commence in the columns of the Halfpenny Press. It would be written, under Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s supervision, by that brilliant journalist and littirateur, Mr. John Fulton. The front page of the newspaper was taken up in its entirety by an advertisement of the Neapolitan Music Hall-refined, mirthful, beautiful, national, fully licensed. Half the back page was devoted to a glowing advertisement of the Times&amp;apos; monumental work on earthquakes. The remaining portions of the paper were occupied by short synopses of foreign affairs and parliamentary proceedings, and accounts of three interesting murders and two peculiarly distressing suicides. Publicity was given an unconfirmed telegram to the effect that an Indian fakir had succeeded in overturning the summit of Mt. Everest. It was very noticeable that the Halfpenny Press, hitherto in frantic opposition to the inefficiency and inertia of the government, was now become a supporter of the ministry and looked forward to a long life of beneficence for it. &amp;quot;That is curious, if you like!&amp;quot; remarked Mr. Trotman judicially. X The Neapolitan, famous even among music-halls for its topicality and its original turns, did not now belie its reputation. There was no precedent in the theatrical world for the energy with which the Church and Empire Ballet was hustled upon the stage nor for the vigour with which it was advertised. The properties of a patriotic ballet were sorted out on the Sunday. Ecclesiastical costumes and apparatus were gathered together on the Monday morning. One or two clergymen, believers in the possibilities of stage influence for good, gave ready help in matters of which the management possessed but little experience. Scene-painters worked day and night with pneumatic paint-brushes, inventing and adapting. Opticians busied themselves with dissolving views and novel effects in stage lighting. The orchestra practised with food and drink on stools beside it. Rehearsals were almost continuous; the stage-manager&amp;apos;s voice filled the hall without intermission. The production of the Church and Empire Ballet was, indeed, a work of concerted genius. One grand dress rehearsal-and that without the central figure of the ballet-took place on Tuesday. Alec, in fact, was the most indispensable and the least necessary personage in the whole affair. Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s stipulation that he should have nothing to say and nothing to do, except be present on the stage, was ridiculed by the manager, who staked his reputation on being able to drill the young man into something that would catch on. Sir Pushcott therefore invited him to meet Mr. Alexander Trotman at lunch. There the manager drew him affably into conversation, and soon became finally convinced that the Wonder-Worker had better remain quite a lay figure. Nevertheless, he kept one small item up his sleeve. Alec was duller than usual. The unwonted stir and excitement had completely dazed him. Besides which, he was in pretty constant pain, and now that the bloom of his visit to London had worn off, he was also rather homesick. He hungered after the ministrations of his mother. The delights of Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s table kept up his spirits somewhat; but his appetite was failing, and at lunch on Tuesday he would take nothing except a little lobster salad. &amp;quot; We shall have to get the doctor to you, young man, I can see,&amp;quot; said Sir Pushcott Bingley. &amp;quot; Dr. Vere M&amp;apos;Lloyd ? &amp;quot; Alec asked. It was the name of his mother&amp;apos;s favourite physician at Trowbury. Most successful men attribute their success to some one virtue that comes easy to them. In Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s case, the fetish was punctuality. Arriving at the Neapolitan rather too early, they were shown into a stage box. &amp;quot; Sit back,&amp;quot; the manager told Alec. &amp;quot; We shan&amp;apos;t want you till the last moment. But you be ready when you&amp;apos;re called. There&amp;apos;ll be a row if we&amp;apos;re too long getting it on. Our house isn&amp;apos;t used to much curtain. Sit back-here.&amp;quot; Alec sat back as requested, and watched a bare-chested woman in black tights showing off her troupe of performing cats. The band played; the woman strutted about the stage, tapping the cats with a beribboned cane, bowing to the music, to the cats and to the audience like a mechanical toy. How much more dignified the snarling cats than the swaggering woman ! Alec was delighted with them, and would have clapped naively had not the Halfpenny Press man touched him on the arm and held up a warning finger. The performer kissed herself and her cats off the stage amid a moderate applause. She was a falling star. The Church and Empire Ballet was to come. For some time the curtain remained down to the music of the orchestra and the stage hammers. The audience began to be impatient. They whistled, they stamped, they boo&amp;apos;d. Somebody flung a ginger-beer bottle at the curtain. It hit a painted languishing Italian lover on the nose so neatly that one of the gallery gods cried out, &amp;quot; Give &amp;apos;em another just there ! &amp;quot; An orange followed. A penny bun, being less weighty, fell short and hit the conductor of the orchestra on the head. The most softly captivating, and the loudest, strains of the orchestra were alike powerless to check the rising enthusiasm for this musichall version of Old Aunt Sally. Turning down the lights only made the musicians&amp;apos; heads into the target, instead of the lovers on the curtain. A flautist had a tooth knocked out and his skilful lip cut. Suddenly Long Willie, the popular comedian of the moment, bounced along the stage before the curtain. He stretched out a ragged skinny arm, made a familiar face, and shouted, &amp;quot; Just you wait a minute. I&amp;apos;ll revive you! &amp;quot; A quick change and he re-entered as a typical revivalistic parson. The audience, at the gleeful sanctimoniousness of his face and walk, burst into a roar of laughter. The painted lovers and the musicians&amp;apos; heads were saved. Long Willie pulled some underclothing out of the end of his trouser-leg and placed it on the ground to imitate a little hill. On the top of it he carefully planted a flower. Then, having retired a few paces, he walked towards the little hill, his eyes cast heavenwards and his finger downwards, saying: &amp;quot; Get thee to the George and Dragon. I am coming.&amp;quot; He tripped, fell backwards on the little hill, squashing it, and rose like a schoolboy after a caning. &amp;quot; How I move mountains! &amp;quot; he said. The audience shrieked with merriment. Alec hid his head. Sir Pushcott Bingley reddened and rang the bell. The manager himself appeared. &amp;quot;Stop that!&amp;quot; Sir Pushcott commanded. &amp;quot;What ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;That travesty. Stop it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I can&amp;apos;t.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;We go at once . . . &amp;quot;Well. . . . Can&amp;apos;t see what there is to object. . . . All right.&amp;quot; Long Willie was called off the stage. Before long the manager returned to the box for Alec. Already the orchestra was playing Rule Britanxia. Alec was led behind the scenes, among a marvellous complexity of girders, beams, ropes and properties-all the hastily prepared paraphernalia of the Church and Empire Ballet. Right at the back of the stage they came to a large mound, an imitation hill, against which there rested a ladder. The manager placed in Alec&amp;apos;s hand a stick with a bit of red, white and blue cloth nailed to it. &amp;quot; Look here,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot; when you hear them begin God Save the King, you stand up and wave this. D&amp;apos;you see ? That&amp;apos;s all you&amp;apos;ve got to do. When they play God Save the King, mind; not before.&amp;quot; Alec took the stick. He was just sufficiently confused to do what he was told without demur; to put his trust in anybody and nobody. And that gnawing pain.... &amp;quot; Now then, up you go! You&amp;apos;ll find a place to sit on at the top. Stay there till you hear God Save the King, and then. ... You know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; All right,&amp;quot; said Alec. The pain made his breath short. He climbed the ladder on all fours, like a dog going upstairs, sat down, and waited. The ladder rose on its end, turned over, disappeared. Time seemed long up there, and the place all the darker for the little light that filtered in. He was almost frightened; was wondering indeed whether the hill was safe to slide down, until a voice came up from below: &amp;quot; Y&amp;apos;all right there ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes,&amp;quot; replied Alec manfully. &amp;quot; They&amp;apos;ve started. Remember!&amp;quot; A young man, sitting on an artificial eminence in semidarkness at the back of a London stage, and wishing himself at home in a sleepy country town. . .. XI Never in theatrical history had exceedingly powerful magic lanterns, cinematographs and dissolving-view apparatus been so brilliantly combined with all the ordinary spectacular and panoramic resources of the stage. Hardly any among the enormous and enthusiastic audience which crowded the Neapolitan Music Hall-sitting, standing, lounging, in defiance of County Council regulations-hardly any, except some scientists present, could tell where illusion ended and make-believe began, so triumphantly had stagecraft and optics come to the aid of Church, Empire and the management. To the strains of Rule Britannia the curtain rose, disclosing another on which was painted (or optically cast) a map of the known world, on Mercator&amp;apos;s projection, with the British Imperial possessions coloured a very bright red. A moving finger appeared, pointing to the British Isles. It travelled to the prairies of Canada, and thence, across the continent of North America, down the Atlantic Ocean, to the malarial West Coast of Africa. By way of St. Helena, it proceeded to the Transvaal; then crossed the Indian Ocean and Australia to antipodal New Zealand. From the northern islands of Australasia it moved to India and up the Red Sea to Egypt. It traversed the Mediterranean, resting a moment at Gibraltar. Finally, ascending the Bay of Biscay and the English Channel it pointed exactly at London. Whereupon the finger changed to a Royal Standard and Union Jack, interlaced with a cross between them; and the emblem swelled and grew till it spread all over the world. Rule Britannia was repeated at the orchestra&amp;apos;s loudest. Everything faded. The music ceased. There was much applause. The curtain rose again on a scene of embarkation. To the tune of See the Conquering Hero Comes there passed slowly and with dignified gait across the stage, to a great ship, missionaries with rapt looks, bearing crosses, and privates of the army in fighting kit with rifles; colporteurs bearing Bibles of all shapes and sizes, and engineers with matlocks, spades and surveying instruments; red-cross nurses and sisters of medical missions; clergymen and merchants carrying Brummagem ware wrapped up in the flag; dignitaries of the Church and starched officers of the army; finally a field-marshal in full uniform together with a bishop in cope and mitre, who had borne before him a richly jewelled pastoral staff on which the lights of the music-hall flashed and glittered. k The martial music changed imperceptibly into a hymn, and, whilst the audience listened in wonder to the noises of a ship getting under way, the stage became totally dark. A transfused glimmer brightened into sunshine and disclosed an Indian encampment in old Canada. Afar, snow-clad mountains were brightly visible; in the foreground stood several wigwams about which squaws were busy with their primitive household work. A party of Red Indians approached warily with hostile intent. One of them sprang forward, yelling his war-cry, and seized by the hair a beautiful girl who was reclining in the entrance of the largest wigwam. To keep her quiet, he knocked her on the head. The owners of the wigwams returned bearing spoils of the chase from which blood dripped. There was a fierce fight, so wild that the audience could distinguish plainly neither the combatants nor what they were about. They saw only, with tight apprehension, the beautiful girl being dragged backwards and forwards across the stage. Tomahawks flourished. Bloody scalps swung on high. Then it was that the Church and Empire Procession passed along the side of the stage, rifles to the shoulder and the emblems of religion held aloft. The fighters were stricken into stillness. The light died down. When next the stage was illuminated, the Indians were seen squatted by their wigwams and smoking the pipe of peace. Certain members of the Church and Empire joined in the ceremony, whilst the remainder stood by, singing a hymn. The beautiful girl and a fine young chief were married by the bishop according to Christian rites. The Indians rose and fell in with the Church and Empire Procession, which once more crossed the stage, in a solemn manner, to the sound of triumphant music. Through the succeeding darkness there came a monotonous throbbing and jarring that made the more sensitive among the audience shudder. The sound, the horrible beating sound, gradually developed into a savage and voluptuous music, made up of rhythmic discords. When the stage lightened a little, so that black figures could just be distinguished, flitting about in the darkness, the rattling wail of the music became as furious as a tropical storm. The scene was a small clearing between the tree-trunks and tendrils of a swampy West African forestone of those orgies to which from time to time frenzied negroes abandon themselves. A dim fire in the centre of the clearing threw strange streaks of light on the dancers around it; who were apparently naked; on the foliage and tree-trunks and on the slimy ground; but it illuminated nothing. The music alone, beating ever and ever more fiercely, suggested the weird depravity of the dance: the dancers themselves remained always more than half invisible, black against blackness, a shadowed rhythm on the darkness, dancing wildly to a mysterious music, rising, falling, whirling, jarring.... Fiercer grew the mad orgie-awakening a latent savagery, visions of unimagined lustfulness, in the audience, till many ached and twitched to join the negroes. Suddenly at the side of the stage appeared the Church and Empire Procession, rifle and crosses uplifted; and the dancers, screaming, rushed to the back and there crouched down in a fearful heap. For a moment darkness: then the music changed to a fresh, cool gladness, while the missionaries and privates, the colporteurs and engineers, the red-cross nurses and sisters of medical missions, the clergymen and merchants, the dignitaries and officers, the field-marshal and bishop, filed past the desolate scene of the orgie, accompanied by regenerate negroes now clad respectably in white duck trousers. In the next scene, the ship of Church and Empire appeared steaming along beneath the cliffs of a rocky island. The ship&amp;apos;s company were assembled on deck. Bishop and field-marshal stood by an altar draped with the flag. &amp;apos;Twas Sunday service aboard, and they were singing a hymn the words of which, to the audience, seemed far distant and indistinguishable; nearly overwhelmed by the plash of the sea. As the ship passed the island, the figure of Napoleon stood forward on a headland. And he doffed his hat. With the darkening of the stage the hymn died away. Once more the music became barbaric; not voluptuously so this time, but ferociously. There was an unholy dry clacking in it, and, as it were, a reek of blood. A cannibal feast in New Zealand was revealed. Tattoo&amp;apos;d Maoris, wrapped in blankets, were dancing and gesticulating greedily around a fire by the side of which was a white corpse partially bereft of its limbs. Garments of a missionary and of a European woman were flung over a hovel close by. One of the dancers wore the white woman&amp;apos;s hat-a hat trimmed with blue cornflowers which wobbled on his head. Another was kicking his legs in her petticoat. Nearly all of them brandished bones-thigh bones, arm bones, ribs. The skull they used between them like a football. Smears of blood added to the ghastliness of their tattoo&amp;apos;d faces. Sometimes they gnawed at the bones. &amp;quot;How horrible! &amp;quot; exclaimed some in the audience. &amp;quot;It oughtn&amp;apos;t to be allowed,&amp;quot; said others, not without satisfaction in their voices. There was a hoot from the gallery. The cannibal dance grew greedier; the music louder. Bones were thrown about. The white corpse was seized and dragged nearer the fire. Rude knives.... In a brilliant light at the side of the stage appeared the Church and Empire Procession, crosses and rifles uplifted. The cannibals flung down their bones and human joints; sank to their knees, heads bowed down. Darkness fell. When the procession recrossed the stage to the tune of a hymnal march, Maoris convoyed it. They were clothed more amply and in cleaner blankets; not more than one wife walked lovingly on the arm of each man; the smears of blood were washed away from their faces, and they were eating fruits. Four tableaux vivants, representing Indian scenes, followed cannibalism. In the first, there was much rejoicing and Eastern magnificence on account of a marriage between infants of high caste. In the second, the child-wife was on her knees weeping, with dishevelled hair, beside the bed of the dying boy, her husband. The voices of wailing women mingled with the sound of the orchestra. Thirdly, came the burning of the boy-husband&amp;apos;s body. Flames from the funeral pyre rose luridly heavenward, whilst the little wife in a transport of grief mourned and wailed beside it, not noticing the presence close by of the Church and Empire Procession, rifles and crosses uplifted. Just as the girlwife in her ecstasy was about to perform the rite of suttee, to immolate herself on the pyre of her youthful husband, a missionary and a soldier sprang forward and amid the plaudits of their comrades dragged her from the flames. The last of the four Indian tableaux represented the interior of a mission-house. Representatives of the Church and Empire were ranged solemnly round the walls, singing a hymn and looking on with manifest approval whilst the beautiful girl-widow of high caste, clothed in white, scrubbed the mission-house floor. The limelight sun went down and rose again over the Garden of Aphrodite in ancient Alexandria. Somewhat unhistorically it was arranged that the pyramids and the Sphinx overlooked the luxuriant place, its palms and large-leaved plants, its fountains and its columns festooned with flowering creepers. Courtesans, long since dead and gone, walked in the garden with voluptuous step, their garments the tall thin draperies of the Greeks. To one among them, the most beautiful, was brought ceremoniously the philtre of love and death. She drank: and to the long-drawn music of the orchestra, to its spiral convolutions of sweet sound, ever rising higher, ever becoming richer and faster, they danced the Dance of Love, which ends in death, in the Garden of Aphrodite, beneath the pyramids and the Sphinx. They danced till the Garden was a melody of twirling feet and floating filmy draperies and glimmering colours. She who had drunk of the philtre whirled in a sheen of light, adored by all the others; the incarnation of a love and rapture beyond human reach, the symbol of love&amp;apos;s uttermost frenzy; until it seemed to the hard-breathing audience that the ballet could no longer go on without becoming really too indecent for the Etiglish stage. Then it was that the Church and Empire Procession appeared, crosses and rifles uplifted; and the ancient courtesans, stricken with a new shame, fled like ripples on a lake. In the twilight of a moment the Garden of Aphrodite was razed to the ground. The Pyramids and the Sphinx were left alone in the moonlit desert, save that a cross was erected between them, and Church and Empire passed into the distance, behind the Great Pyramid, singing a hymn of rejoicing. By some optical contrivance, the Sphinx glanced at the cross, and-but without any movement-a look of fear flitted over its immobile face. This made a great sensation. Two minor scenes-the ship of Church and Empire saluted by the guns of Gibraltar, and its triumphant approach to the white cliffs of Dover-were introduced between the Dance of Love and what was described on the programme as: Grand Finale. Under the Dome ol St. Paul&amp;apos;s. THE HOLY MOUNTAIN. The nave of the national cathedral became gradually brighter, its huge square pillars and vasty spaces dimly lighted by the hanging candelabra, so that the chancel and high altar were invisible and only a glint of the coloured and golden mosaics could be seen. Already there was a great congregation in the nave. They were chanting processional hymns of triumph. Slowly and with dignified step there filed in the bishop in a resplendent cope and mitre, his jewelled crosier borne aloft before him; the field-marshal carrying his feathered hat and his baton; officers of the army in full uniform and dignitaries of the Church in their canonicals; clergymen in surplices and hoods, and merchants in silk-faced frock-coats; red-cross nurses and sisters of medical missions in their best bonnets; colporteurs with Bibles, and engineers with brand-new matlocks and spades; soldiers with down-pointing rifles and missionaries with uppointing crosses; negroes in trousers and their women in what looked like nightshirts; gentle cannibals; the high-caste girlwidow and her glad relatives, now Christians; a bejewelled native prince willing to become the widow&amp;apos;s second husband; and the rescued courtesans of old Alexandria, clothed in blouses, skirts and sailor hats. A man of the audience was heard say to his wife: &amp;quot; Foine! Oin&amp;apos;t it, M&amp;apos;rier ? &amp;quot; The gates of the screen opened and the bishop passed within them to the sanctuary. The field-marshal stationed himself at a prie-dieu placed in the centre of the aisle, whilst the remainder of the Church and Empire Procession filed off to the chairs reserved for them underneath the dome. As the congregation sangForward, flock of Jesus, Salt of all the earth, Till each yearning purpose Spring to glorious birth; Sick, they ask for healing, Blind, they grope for day: Pour upon the nations Wisdom&amp;apos;s loving ray. Forward out of error, Leave behind the night: Forward through the darkness, Forward into light !the chancel became illuminated. The audience perceived, not the high altar and its reredos, but, in a circle of bright light, seated on the top of the Holy Mountain-Alexander Trotman! Then there were three cheers, thrice resounding. The strains of the hymn changed abruptly to God Save the King. Once the national anthem was played, twice it was played. It was begun again. Alec suddenly remembered his instructions. He stood erect on the Holy Mountain. He unfurled (with fumbling), and waved, the Union Jack. Frantic enthusiasm possessed the audience. Hats, sticks, umbrellas, handkerchiefs, waved. Cheering and God Save the King arose one against the other-played vocal tug-o&amp;apos;-war. But Alec-Alec was seen to totter, and to fall from top to bottom of the Holy Mountain. Those who had good plces saw blood. Blood from the mouth. --i The curtain was rung down amid the profoundest sensation Some said it was a judgment. Others jeered. XII The last, the most impressive, scene of the Church and Empire Ballet took place behind the curtain. Alec was propped up in a fainting condition against that simulacrum of the Holy Mountain down which he had fallen. Ranged around him were the interior fittings of St. Paul&amp;apos;s and the trees of the Garden of Aphrodite-all those properties, that is, which had not been optical delusions. On the outskirts of the group were the erstwhile courtesans and priests, craning their necks, pushing their painted faces forwards. The stage was brilliantly lighted. The audience could be heard departing from the theatre. A tone of wonderment was perceptible in the hubbub of their voices, through which the shouts of newsboys outside penetrated in gusts of noise. Nearest Alec were Sir Pushcott Bingley, the Halfpenny Press man, the manager of the Neapolitan, two doctors and a call-boy. After examining his bared chest with stethoscopes, they gave him a piece of ice to suck and told him to keep quite quiet. The ice froze his teeth. He made a wry face and began to revive. &amp;quot; What is it ?&amp;quot; Sir Pushcott Bingley asked. &amp;quot; Has he complained of indigestion ? &amp;quot; said one of the doctors. &amp;quot; Nothing at all the matter with him. . ..&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He told me,&amp;quot; said the Halfpenny Press man, &amp;quot; that he&amp;apos;s had a stomach-ache, as he called it, almost ever since he&amp;apos;s been in London. His mother wrote . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; H&amp;apos;m ! &amp;quot; the doctor remarked. &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s it-lungs fairly sound-gastric ulcer, no doubt.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Will he be right by to-morrow night&amp;apos;s performance?&amp;quot; the manager of the music-hall inquired. &amp;quot; My dear sir, he won&amp;apos;t be right for a week, or yet a month. Gastric ulcer requires perfect rest and careful nursing, the best-if the cure is to be radical.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But we&amp;apos;ve got a week&amp;apos;s contract . &amp;quot; Pardon me,&amp;quot; Sir Pushcott interrupted. &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ve never had a better house than we had to night. I&amp;apos;ll give . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That cannot be helped. He must be taken to a hospital.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not to be thought of,&amp;quot; said Sir Pushcott. &amp;quot; My house . &amp;quot; Or he ought to go home. Trowbury, isn&amp;apos;t it ? &amp;quot; Alec attempted to speak. He even tried to get up, but was prevented by the doctor. &amp;quot; Well, what is it my boy?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I want to go home to mother,&amp;quot; he whispered. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t like London.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;So you shall when you are a little better.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Now,&amp;quot; supplicated the Mountain-Mover. &amp;quot; I won&amp;apos;t stay!&amp;quot; Then, being highly overwrought and too weak to struggle, he wept. The ice slipped out of his mouth. &amp;quot; I wish I&amp;apos;d never come. I wish I&amp;apos;d never gone near Ramshorn Hill.&amp;quot; On their telling him to stay quiet, he made repeated efforts to roll over and get up, like an ungainly animal. His white face rocked from side to side. &amp;quot; This must be stopped,&amp;quot; said the doctor. &amp;quot; Can&amp;apos;t we send for his people ? He will bring on the hamorrhage again.&amp;quot; Sir Pushcott Bingley did not appear to favour the idea of receiving at Park Lane the Famous Grocer and his elegant wife. After a minute&amp;apos;s meditation, he asked: &amp;quot;Would it not be possible to send him down to Wiltshire in a motor ambulance? They run as smoothly as beds, don&amp;apos;t they ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well-yes-that would be possible. But who is to go with him ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Go yourself and take a nurse, or two nurses if you like. I&amp;apos;ll see to it, you understand. He muit recover, you know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, I think he will do that. He seems to be of a rather scrofulous tendency. Heredity . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; His father wrote to him and said they were going to make him Mayor of Trowbury,&amp;quot; said the Hal/penny Press man. &amp;quot; Poor boy ! &amp;quot; said the doctor. &amp;quot; You had better go too,&amp;quot; said Sir Pushcott to the Hal/penny Press man. &amp;quot; I can manage. Let me know. No further need of me, I suppose ? Good-night, then.&amp;quot; They awaited the ambulance and the nurse. The major lights of the music-hall went out, until the group formed an illuminated spot, a dark-shadowed picture, framed by darkness. XIII Thus did Alexander Trotman, after his triumph in London, return to his father&amp;apos;s house and shop at Trowbury; lying on a swung spring-bed in a motor ambulance; watched by a doctor and a nurse; the victim of a shaky constitution and Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s table, of his father&amp;apos;s youthful smartnesses and his own most moderate gluttony. It was about eight o&amp;apos;clock in the morning when the ambulance drove down Castle Street and stopped at the Famous Grocery. The Haltpenny Press man rang the bell. Mrs. Trotman peeped out of an upper window, discreetly in order not to show her slip-bodice. &amp;quot;What is it ? Do you want Mr. Trotman ? Have you come from the police. My husband won&amp;apos;t be on the bench to-day.&amp;quot; On seeing it was not the police, she slipped on a dressinggown, tucked her hair inside the collar and went down to the front door. They told her that Alec had been taken ill; showed her son to her lying pale on the spring bed with a piece of ice in his mouth. &amp;quot; Oh, Allie, Allie ! What have they been doing to you?&amp;quot; she cried. She ran inside calling, &amp;quot;James, James! Quick! Come here! She shouted to the servant to light a fire in Master Allie&amp;apos;s bedroom, and, her voice breaking, ended in a screech. Detaching the bed from its springs, they carried the WonderWorker up to his own bedroom. Mr. Trotman appeared, not very fresh-looking at that time of day. But his coolness and dignity did not desert him. &amp;quot; You are a doctor, I presume, sir?&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot; Yes, I am.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Sent by Sir Pushcott Bingley?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And how is Sir Pushcott?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, doctor, doctor! what is it, please ? &amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman exclaimed. &amp;quot; Gastric ulcer-ulcerated stomach-hzmorrhage . . &amp;quot; Oh, I&amp;apos;m so thankful it&amp;apos;s not that dreadful appendicitis! Can he take bovril ? Or would bread-and-milk be better?&amp;quot; BOOK III I &amp;apos;ANTIENT hostelries &amp;apos; like the Blue Boar, in small towns like Trowbury, have many uses. First, of course, they are drinkingshops. Secondly, they are free clubs. Thirdly, they are informal places of appointment which seldom or never fail. If you have business with one of the leading tradesmen or minor professional men, you may go to his shop only to learn, probably, that he is out; gone to his brother&amp;apos;s funeral, his aunt&amp;apos;s wedding, shooting, fishing, bathing, or somewhere whence he is expected every minute. But if you can recollect when he is accustomed to attend the Blue Boar bar, and look in at that hour, there you shall surely find him. Who can deny that business runs more sweetly to the tune of, &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s yours ?-Good health !-The same to you, sir ! &amp;quot; ? On the Wednesday morning, despite all that had happened, Mr. Trotman entered the swing-doors at precisely his usual time. &amp;quot; Well, I never, Mr. Trotman! What ever have you been up to ? You look. . . . There ! HE-He-he-he-he ! Brandy and a small Schweppe: is that it ? &amp;quot; Mr. Trotman would not at once, however, look with Miss Sankey on the bright and bibulous side of things. He remained very serious indeed, and more faded in appearance than usual. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve had my son brought home very seriously ill.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Dear me! &amp;quot; Miss Sankey&amp;apos;s voice sank to a confidential whisper: &amp;quot; Dying, did you say ? &amp;quot; Mr. Trotman leaned over the counter. &amp;quot; The doctors hardly know. Two of them there. Ulcerated stomach. Yes -brandy-and-soda, please.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Ai, I had that, you know, when I was a young girl, and doesn&amp;apos;t it serve you out, my word! Poor boy !-Top o&amp;apos; the morning to you, Mr. Ganthorn! How&amp;apos;s you ? Eh ? I say, have you heard? You tell him, Mr. Trotman. Dying! Fancy! After all he&amp;apos;s done. . . . Moving mountains! Poor boy! And I know what it&amp;apos;s like; that I do. When everybody was talking about him everywhere. . . . Struck down ! Pride goes before a fall. Ay me ! filling glasses and a joke and a laugh isn&amp;apos;t the worst life in the world when all&amp;apos;s said and done. Shan&amp;apos;t I be glad when Christmas comes! &amp;quot; It pleased Mr. Ganthorn to look quizzical. He turned from the sympathetic Miss Sankey. &amp;quot; Is this true about your son, Trotman? Heard this morning he was dying. Not so bad as that, is it ? The Mayor looked sorrowful, as if he feared the tragic worst; as if so conspicuous an event might indeed happen to his family. He spoke in a deprecating manner: &amp;quot; I can&amp;apos;t say. There&amp;apos;s two doctors with him-Vere M&amp;apos;Lloyd and one Sir Pushcott sent down with the ambulance from London. Vere M&amp;apos;Lloyd tells my wife he&amp;apos;s got hope, but it&amp;apos;s pretty serious I&amp;apos;m afraid.&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn sipped and meditated a moment or two. The Mayor did the same, most impressively. Then the former said with a great affectation of nonchalance: &amp;quot;How about what we were talking about the other day-what we arranged that night at my place, you know?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, that&amp;apos;s it. .....&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Come into the smoke-room. Drink up and have another. -Two more brandies and a split soda, please, Miss Cora, in the little smoking-room.&amp;quot; The two wiseacres retired to a very small rectangular room, the centre of which was occupied by a highly polished brassbound table, spotted with black burns, and bearing water-jugs, match-stands and ash-trays, all with liquor advertisements upon them. At either end was an easy-chair. Ranged along the walls, as closely as possible, were other wooden chairs of the straight-backed variety, with small wooden arms and commodious horsehair seats-chairs for fat men too stiff to lounge. That cramped little room is the Holy of Holies of the Blue Bores. There, especially on Sunday evenings after church-time, they love to sit, to listen to their voices, and sometimes to see each other through the murky air. Mr. Trotman secured the easy-chair under the window. To be near him, Mr. Ganthorn took the next straight-backed chair. They got up and dosed the window, shutting out a scent of flowers. They settled down again. ... When Miss Sankey took in the drinks, she heard Mr. Ganthorn saying, &amp;quot; Well, you see, it&amp;apos;s like this: if he can&amp;apos;t be mayor after you, it&amp;apos;s the liberals&amp;apos; turn, and one of their men will have to go in; and as there&amp;apos;ll probably be a general election pretty soon, it&amp;apos;ll be as well to have a conservative mayor if we can. With a conservative mayor, conservative affairs go better. I don&amp;apos;t mean to say the mayor influences the election, and yet he does, in littl ways, you understand; and it&amp;apos;s the little ways that count when there&amp;apos;s a fight for it.&amp;quot; As they strolled across the hall, on their way out of the hotel, Miss Sankey was able to overhear a little more. &amp;quot; I hope it won&amp;apos;t turn out so serious after all,&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn was saying. &amp;quot; We shall hear when Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s specialist gets down later in the day. If anybody can pull him through, Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s physician will. Very kind of him. ...&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, good-morning. About the other matter: I think I can work that.&amp;quot; II There is happily no need to inquire how far the rapid improvement in Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s spirits was due to the Blue Boar bar, to his confabulation with Mr. Ganthorn, to the gentle exercise of trotting about Trowbury, or to all the pleasing things he saw and heard. At all events, the world assumed for him a gayer tint. Mild martyrdom plus pity is a subtle mixture, a moral absinthe. The certain knowledge that his only son-a young man just making such a mark-was dangerously ill, became glossed over by Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s being, as at the commencement of his mayoralty, a centre of public attention. Such attention too ! There was the Hal/penny Press with its five million readers. A public of five thousand thousand had its compound eye upon the house of Trotman. It was a little nebulous, that; a cloud of witnesses too cloudy; but it made Mr. Trotman feel his own importance in the universe. And, to come nearer home, men and women whom he did not know (as civic head of Trowbury he considered himself acquainted with everybody worth knowing) asked him how his son did, and all about the illness, in a manner so kindly that he appropriated the kindliness for himself. All treated him as one overwhelmed by conquering grief. A commercial traveller, no particular friend of his, rather the reverse indeed, asked him to have a &amp;apos; reviver.&amp;apos; Another man suggested a pick-me-up, and yet another was ready to broach a last dozen of the best tonic port in Trowbury&amp;apos;s cellars. Already fortified, as aforesaid, Mr. Trotman withstood the temptations, and felt all the better for that too. The Rev. Mr. Marteene, a hot and outspoken opponent of grocers&amp;apos; licences, whom he happened to meet in the Market Square, asked if the invalid might be visited and suggested prayers for recovery in all the churches. He spoke so nicely, so religiously, that a starting tear made Mr. Trotman wink. What the stricken father said about the medical details of the case might have furnished forth a writer of patent medicine advertisements, from which in fact his knowledge of the pathology and therapeutics of the stomach was mainly derived. Moving the Holy Mountain, he quite agreed, might so have exhausted the poor boy&amp;apos;s vital forces that his digestive organs-never, alas ! very strong-fell an easy victim to disease. Hitherto, he had regarded Alec&amp;apos;s multifarious ailments as a sort of pastime indulged in by Mrs. Trotman. Now he was almost anxious to abdicate his place as head of the household; willing to await permission to be taken to the sick-room, and to obey orders while there. It satisfied his conception of correct behaviour under such circumstances. Alec lay flat with only one of Mrs. Trotman&amp;apos;s best hemstitched pillows beneath his tired head. The tranquil sunshine of a Fate summer&amp;apos;s afternoon made him look simply wan and peaceful, without accentuating the truly deplorable state of his always mediocre complexion. His weakness could be judged by the way his eyes, without movement of the head, followed the zigzag flight of a bee which buzzed up and down the window until it found an opening (strongly opposed by Mrs. Trotman as likely to give the boy his death of cold, but insisted on by the nurse), and flew out. The medicated odour of the room at once put Mr. Trotman in the frame of mind for visitation of the sick. Probably for the first time since Alec&amp;apos;s babyhood, he was prepared to treat his offspring with respect. It brought a sense of pathos, even to him, to look down at this young man who had been reared with so much difficulty and now was struck down by little ulcers at the most, the only, brilliant period of his life. Alec, in reality however, was happier and more comfortable than he had been for some time. Illness, to which his mother had accustomed him, was much less worrying than the Modern Miracle; than Sir Pushcott Bingley, London, the Halfpenny Press, and all the complications that had arisen out of them. Now he was at rest. Sufficient for the day was the kindness and pain thereof. Being ill, he was content to wait patiently on the future. If the divine, the comfortable, Julia floated into his weary mind, she came accompanied by no call to immediate action. Mr. Trotman advanced to the bedside on tip-toe. &amp;quot; Well, my boy, how is it now ? &amp;quot; Alec smiled dimly. &amp;quot; All right.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You must hurry up and get better. We are going to make you mayor, perhaps.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You&amp;apos;ll&amp;apos; soon be well. Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s own consulting physician&amp;apos;ll soon put you right. We must write and thank Sir ;ushcott.&amp;quot; Alec remained silent, inert, pitiful. Other proper things to say slipped Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s mind. One cannot bully a son into conversation and filial respect when he is incontestably very ill; not, that is, if the son is surrounded by protectors in the shapes of doctors, nurses, and a mother. Mr. Trotman had never practised kind cajolery with his son. He didn&amp;apos;t know how. So he retired helpless. The Hallpenny Press, which Mr. Trotman did not fail to purchase, excited itself to great eloquence in its best best style. The Church and Empire Ballet was described vividly and without impropriety; the public consternation; the scene behind the scenes, which reminded the Hal/penny Press of nothing so much as Nelson dying in the cockpit of the Victory; the journey of the motor ambulance with its acetylene lamps and &amp;apos;the fraughted souls within her,&amp;apos; across the dark country to the Mountain-Mover&amp;apos;s beloved native town; and finally the pathetic reception by alarmed awakened parents. The journey was said to be a striking instance of the modern coalition between the mechanic and the medical sciences. The latest resources of civilisation were ready and willing to lend their aid to the resuscitator of the Age of Miracles. Readers were referred to another page, to an article by a high authority on motor ambulances. All England, said the morning&amp;apos;s leader, all the Empire, half the world, would be watching around the bed of sickness at Trowbury with anxiety, and with prayer to the Almighty Dispenser of health and disease. In fine-to strip away much verbiage-the young man, recognising that he had performed the miracle of the twentieth century only by kind permission of Almighty God, did desire, as a thank-offering, that the Church should receive the earthly benefits of what he had accomplished. But how ? There were obstacles unconquerable except by united national action.... Mr. Trotman could not refrain from ejaculating: &amp;quot;Did he I by Jove ! &amp;quot; The Evening Press, in addition to a mincemeat of the morning&amp;apos;s news, contained a bulletin (copyright) of the sufferer&amp;apos;s progress, or non-progress; a diagrammatic analysis of the motor ambulance&amp;apos;s speed; a popular article on the stomach with six reasons for the increase in dyspepsia; and a photograph of the stricken mother which Mrs. Trotman declared to be an old one, totally unlike, an impudence and a libel.-But how nice of them to put it there! How enterprising of Sir Pushcott! The Evening Press also mentioned casually a suggestion &amp;apos;emanating from an exalted quarter,&amp;apos; that the Holy Mountain might, through the agency of the Church, be used as a religious centre, to tighten the Christian bonds of Empire. And the gist of Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s meditations on all this amounted to, &amp;quot; Where do I come in ? &amp;quot; At the Blue Boar in the early evening he succeeded in drawing into conversation a solicitor who, though of course a professional man while he was trade, condescended sometimes to take a glass with him. To the solicitor as a man of the world he outlined the events of the past fortnight in the shadowy secretive manner of conferring an illicit favour, in the guise of a man-to-man confidence made to a solicitor whose personal opinion was valuable but whose professional opinion was in nowise explicitly asked. In return for such touching confidence, Mr. Trotman was informed that if such and such a thing were so, and if other things were otherwise, the common-sense, and the legal, conclusion could only be this; but if sundry things had been thus, then the result at law would be that. What Mr. Trotman could not determine was whether such and such things were so, other things otherwise, and sundry things thus. The ifs tormented him; the solicitor&amp;apos;s bill when it came in at the end of the year made him bounce: To Conversation with rourself at the Blue Boar Hotel, and Advice, say, Ten shillings and sixpense. IO/6. Mr. Trotman said that all lawyers were rogues and scoundrels who made fortunes by transacting affairs the greater part of which any good business man (like himself) could do as well or better. III Next day, Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s consulting physician arrived in Trowbury. Mr. Trotman had a fleeting notion that the Mayor and Corporation ought to meet him at the station. Mrs. Trotman nearly fluttered her heart out with proud trepidation, and became faint with suspense. The three doctors mauled the patient; poked, prodded and tapped him; questioned the nurse in slow nonchalant tones; and then they went to the drawing-room where Mrs. Trotman, in her bazaaropening, prize-giving dress, was awaiting them. &amp;quot; Do you think, Dr. Blenkhowe . .&amp;quot; the stricken mother began. &amp;quot; Quite satisfactory, quite satisfactory, Mrs.-ah-Trotman,&amp;quot; said the great physician. &amp;quot; It appears to me that the diagnosis of Dr. Garth and Dr. M&amp;apos;Lloyd is quite correct in every respect -absolutely.&amp;quot; He made a hearty meal off the highly deleterious refreshments (see Traditional Diet, by J. B. Y. Blenkhowe, M.D., &amp;amp;c. &amp;amp;c.) provided by Mrs. Trotman, and talked to the other two doctors about the celebrated air of Trowbury and the desirability of polluting the Downs with a sanatorium for tuberculous ladies. Mrs. Trotman did think that he might have said more about Alexander&amp;apos;s stomach. When he was on the point of going, however, Dr. Blenkhowe addressed Mrs. Trotman once more. &amp;quot; It appears to me, Mrs. -ah-Trotman,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot; that the treatment of Dr. M&amp;apos;Lloyd and Dr. Garth leaves nothing to be desired-nothing.&amp;quot; In the world&amp;apos;s eye, Alexander Trotman&amp;apos;s stomach slowly healed; and Dr. Blenkhowe, by means of his success in this case, so thoroughly advertised in the Hal/penny Pres5, was enabled to give up his practice, to devote himself exclusively to the stomach-aches of a few extraordinarily wealthy patients, and to write works of great popularity but doubtful literary merit. Mr. Trotman, no longer young, was moved by his son&amp;apos;s danger to meditate sometimes on death. With men of his practical stamp, to think on death is to fear it. The idea of profit and loss he could not dissociate from it. The advantages of investment in virtue, bearing interest beyond the grave, appealed to him. He felt, too, that it would be nice to do good, as he phrased it to himself. He made up his mind to do something good, and very naturally chose his son as a convenient object on which to practise good intentions. He would not himself have been allowed to tend Alec. The arrangement was that the professional nurse watched him through the night and his mother during the day. Mrs. Trotman, therefore, could obtain no outdoor exercise. So, when Alec no longer required quite such skilled and constant attention, Mr. Trotman announced that he would sit in the room while his wife and the nurse took a constitutional together. After some opposition, he got his way. He lighted a mild cigar, hoped Alec did not mind the smoke, and stationed himself beside the bed. Father and son-pretty picture ! Whilst the blue smoke from Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s cigar-end and the white smoke from his mouth curled fantastically about in the still, sunshiny air of the room, he tried to begin a pleasant chat with his son. But Alec did not want to talk to his father any more than before. Neither Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s town mansion and the appurtenances thereof, nor the future and the money to be made out of it, could lure him into intelligent conversation. He answered direct questions briefly and aloofly ; that was all And Mr. Trotman had anticipated a nice little talk, a little sympathy from his son for his own virtuous feelings. How hard it is to commence virtue! Later in the day, as soon as he was released indeed, Mr, Trotman mentioned the matter to Miss Sankey. &amp;quot; The boy&amp;apos;s got no spirits at all; no enterprise, no go. I can&amp;apos;t think where he gets it from. Not from me. In twenty-five years I&amp;apos;ve built up the business with the largest turnover in Trowbury, except this place perhaps. He&amp;apos;s been too much at his mother&amp;apos;s apronstrings, but she will have it. Delicate. . . . One of her brothers is a fair waster ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He never comes in here,&amp;quot; remarked Miss Sankey, as if to join the ranks of the Blue Bores was to show oneself decisively a man of enterprise. &amp;quot; No,&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman replied gravely. &amp;quot; My son does not frequent public bars.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ahl!&amp;quot; said Miss Sankey with her mouth full. &amp;quot; &amp;apos;Tisn&amp;apos;t always the most artful that&amp;apos;s the most happy. Have a chocolate? A nice young man of mine gave me a whole two-pound box this morning, and I didn&amp;apos;t fish for them either like I did when you didn&amp;apos;t give me any after all. HM said I had a cheery voice. Go on ! take a handful.&amp;quot; For the second time that day Mr. Trotman felt himself rebuffed; confined within the measure of other people&amp;apos;s stupidity. Sick people are commonly supposed to lie by, to think of their sins and to repent. The testimony of observers unbiased by grief indicates rather that in the majority of cases an invalid does no such thing, because weakness brings procrastination in its train, and death steals away the power of thought before it is aware of its own decline. Nevertheless, it does more frequently happen that young people, recovering slowly from an illness, collect themselves together, as it were. They break through their former easy subjection to the wills of others. They take into their hands the tillers of their own boats, and by skill, not strength, they steer them. In their weakness they are more decisive than in their power. Knowing at last what they want, they take steps to get it. So with Alec. Up to the time of his illness he drifted merely; a piece of flotsam on the currents stirred up by his neighbours. He was a grown-up schoolboy whose attempt to write an article showed the aimless befuddlement of his wits; a fool. Now, while his mother watched over him, trembling for his weakness, he developed, by a sort of inward communion, a dull apprehension of the aimlessness of his life, of the lack in it of any definite hopes, and also sufficient initiative to bend his mother to his newly aroused will. He became a man; not much of a man; but a man that&amp;apos;s a man for a&amp;apos; that. He determined to see his Julia. One morning, therefore, while his mother was fussing about the room, he said: &amp;quot; I want to see Julia Jepp.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Who? Julia Jpp. . .. &amp;quot; Miss Jepp at Clinch&amp;apos;s.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; &amp;quot;You must lie quiet and get better, my dear,&amp;quot; said his mother, with some asperity in her voice. Alec bothered no more about it then, but next morning he asked simply: &amp;quot; When&amp;apos;s Miss Jepp coming ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Alec! Your father would never give his consent.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then don&amp;apos;t ask him.&amp;quot; Again the subject dropped, and again Mrs. Trotman did nothing but decide inwardly that it was absurd and out of the question-naughty of Alec. It happened, however, that Dr. Vere M&amp;apos;Lloyd, concluding the ulcers healed, put Alec on a less restricted diet-a little sole, a little good wine (he knew what the Mayor&amp;apos;s wines were like), and a little custard. Alec was told, moreover, to brighten up. He was to have some unfatiguing diversion and enjoy himself. Games, some reading, visitors. &amp;quot; I should like to have some visitors,&amp;quot; said the patient. &amp;quot; So you shall, my boy, by all means. Let him see people he likes to see, Mrs. Trotman, if it doesn&amp;apos;t fatigue him or excite him too much.&amp;quot; While the doctor was being shown downstairs with the usual ceremony, he remarked: &amp;quot;Everything to brighten him up, Mrs. Trotman. He seems as if he wants more object in life. With care, he ought now to make a steady recovery; but, you understand, there must be no relapse.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Let him do anything he wants to, in reason. Goodmorning, Mrs. Trotman. Beautiful day.&amp;quot; On returning to the sick-room Mrs. Trotman found her son visibly brighter. &amp;quot; Now you&amp;apos;ll send for Miss Jepp. I want to see her more than anybody else.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Your father . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Haven&amp;apos;t you ever done anything when father was out ?&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman escaped. But when she next appeared, bearing food, Alec asked, &amp;quot;Well ? Have you done it ? You say you want to make me better, and you don&amp;apos;t do what the doctor says. &amp;quot; &amp;quot; All right, dear. I&amp;apos;ll send. Only I hope your father won&amp;apos;t get to know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Never mind him! Do it first and see what he says after- wards. He can&amp;apos;t kill you for it, and he won&amp;apos;t kill me &amp;apos;cause I&amp;apos;m profitable.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But he&amp;apos;ll talk.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;So he will anyhow.&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman was relieved-almost jubilant-when she was able to tell her son: &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve sent round to Clinch&amp;apos;s for Miss Jepp, and she says she can&amp;apos;t come.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Give me some paper and an envelope and a pencil, please.&amp;quot; He thereupon wrote with all a lover&amp;apos;s artfulness: &amp;quot; DEAR JULIA,&amp;quot;You aren&amp;apos;t going to chuck me now I&amp;apos;m ill, are you ? &amp;quot;Your affectionate Friend, &amp;quot; ALEXANDER TROTMAN.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Send that,&amp;quot; said the invalid. &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;ll fetch her.&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman couldn&amp;apos;t see the writing through the envelope. She sent the note at once. IV It was not till next morning that Alec received a small pink strongly scented envelope sealed with a dab of bright blue wax. Inside it he found: &amp;quot; Early closing. Coming half-past two. Haste. J. J.&amp;quot; And just after half-past two, Alec, whose ears had become preternaturally sharp, heard double footsteps coming up the stairs. He raised himself slightly in bed, smoothed the coverlet, touched the bedclothes round him. His mother was talking very fast. &amp;quot; Yes, he&amp;apos;s better now, thank God; but we didn&amp;apos;t know what would happen at first, or for some days.&amp;quot; People of the Trotman stamp mention God to their foes in order that God may appear to be on their side. As the last rays of sunset glide into a room, seeming to warm it and to fill it with a half-earthly radiance, so did the yellow girl from Clinch&amp;apos;s rustle into the sick-room in the wake of Mrs. Trotman, and warm it and brighten it for Alec. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s looking better now, not quite so pale,&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman was saying nervously, &amp;quot; and the doctor has ordered him a little fish.&amp;quot; She fiddled with the blind. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s a little glaring, this room, but very cheerful, is it not ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mother,&amp;quot; said Alec. &amp;quot; Hadn&amp;apos;t you better go and see where father is l &amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman stopped like a talking-machine run down. With a glance behind her, she went. &amp;quot; Julie . . . &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Sh! you must keep quiet, or I shall have to go.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;They&amp;apos;re always saying &amp;apos;Sh!&amp;apos; Tell me some news. How&amp;apos;ve you been getting on ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, I&amp;apos;m all right.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, everybody ? How&amp;apos;s Miss Starkey. She wasn&amp;apos;t up to much, was she ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Miss Starkey is out at nurse&amp;apos;s-Mrs. Parfitt&amp;apos;s. I think she&amp;apos;s better, but . . . I generally go out to tea with her on Sunday. Only it won&amp;apos;t do to let people know I&amp;apos;m chummy with her still. You see . . . Now, keep quiet. You mustn&amp;apos;t get excited, or else you&amp;apos;ll be bad again, like you were in London. Miss Starkey&amp;apos;s all right.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; D&amp;apos;you know, Julie,&amp;quot; said Alec in an uncommonly grown-up manner for him, &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve almost forgotten about London lying here. It&amp;apos;s like a sort of dream, and I often say to myself, &amp;apos; Did I really go to London ? &amp;apos; and all that. Have you been to see where Ramshorn Hill went from ? My father says they ought to start a quarry company there. Julie, do you remember what we said up there ? &amp;quot; Alec craned forward on his pillow. &amp;quot; I was so frightened. Don&amp;apos;t let&amp;apos;s talk about it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But you remember what nurse said ? &amp;quot; Julie began chattering unintelligibly to gain time. Alec raised himself in bed, hanging on her mixed-up words as an innocent man, almost talked into guiltiness by the prosecution, hangs on the foreman of the jury&amp;apos;s. He plucked at the sheet -a pitiful object of weakness and suppressed excitement. Julia tried to calm him. But he besought her: &amp;quot;You do remember, don&amp;apos;t you ? You must remember, Julie?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Sh, sh! You mustn&amp;apos;t, Alec. You&amp;apos;ll make yourself ill.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There! you called me &amp;apos;Alec.&amp;apos; Do it again. We will be engaged, won&amp;apos;t we, Julie ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;No, no! I didn&amp;apos;t mean that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But you did! We were. Nurse thought we were.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You must keep quiet, Mr. Trotman.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Why&amp;apos;s everybody against me ? They always sit on me -everybody ! They always have. And now you&amp;apos;re doing it too.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You mustn&amp;apos;t take it that way. You&amp;apos;re going to be rich and not have to work, and have motor-cars. Think of poor Edie Starkey with nobody belonging to her. I&amp;apos;m almost keeping her, but you mustn&amp;apos;t tell anybody, because . . . Well, I don&amp;apos;t want it to be known.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I don&amp;apos;t care about Edie Starkey. I don&amp;apos;t want to get better-not if we&amp;apos;re not going to be engaged. Julie, I&amp;apos;ve got better for you. I&amp;apos;ve thought about it here . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No! I can&amp;apos;t ever marry you. I really can&amp;apos;t. But I&amp;apos;ll be friends. We will be friends, won&amp;apos;t we?&amp;quot; This was exceedingly common place; almost fictional if it had been done more stylishly. But there were harried and suppressed emotions beneath it all. Miss Julia Jepp was touching that part of life not to be found in a country Emporium except through the medium of fiction. Therefore, searched and worried to her inmost being, she talked about continuing friends with Alec. The lovely Lady Verbena Gwalter talked so, at first, to the noble navvy, in Love&amp;apos;s High 7ump. Alec, unlike that genteel and herculean navvy, cried out, &amp;apos;Julie ! &amp;quot; in a tone of despair that Julie did not soon forget. And he showed signs of fainting. In fact, he did faint for a minute or two. Then was Miss Jepp in a situation familiar to her, and at her best. She rushed to the washhandstand, wrung out the towel in cold water and applied it to Alec&amp;apos;s forehead. She opened the windows wide; searched the mantelpiece, found a bottle of Eau de Cologne, and sprinkled it over a handkerchief, which she substituted for the wet towel. Tipping out some more of the scent upon her own handkerchief, a folded delicate thing for visiting, she placed it to his nose. On his remaining inert, she took fright and rang the bell. Whereupon he revived. Mrs. Trotman, appearing, found her son&amp;apos;s face half hidden under handkerchiefs, and the room pungent with Eau de Cologne. &amp;quot; What have you done?&amp;quot; she demanded. &amp;quot; He was a bit faint.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And look at the windows!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I let some fresh air in. Give him a little brandy.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No. The doctor hasn&amp;apos;t said . . . &amp;quot; Yes. Just a little. Where is it ?&amp;quot; Like rapier-play went the words: &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s my son ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s my young man!&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No, he isn&amp;apos;t ! &amp;quot; Yes, he is ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;You&amp;apos;d better go!&amp;quot; I shan&amp;apos;t ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;You shall!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I will! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s this ?&amp;quot; asked Mr. Trotman, who had just come up, in his sepulchral tones. &amp;quot;Miss Jepp ! Why&amp;apos;s she here. I won&amp;apos;t . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Be quiet, father,&amp;quot; said Alec from the bed. And, strange to say, Mr. Trotman obeyed his son. &amp;quot; Good-bye, so long, Julie.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Good-bye.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; will you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ll see.&amp;quot; Julia was left to find her own way downstairs and out of the house. She was hot for vengeance. So, too, were the Mayor and Mayoress. Their faces all showed it-faces incongruous in the midst of the workaday world. But it is to be recollected that the affair was both serious and heart-moving to the comical people concerned in it. V Alec recovered rapidly from the excitement of Miss Jepp&amp;apos;s visit, which indeed woke him up a little from his state of coddled apathy and in so doing hastened his mending. Mr. and Mrs. Trotman recovered less quickly, under the compulsion of events, so to speak. They-Mrs. Trotman especially-would have liked to get Julia Jepp dismissed from the Emprium, much as Miss Starkey had been flung out of the Famous Grocery Establishment. That, however, could not be done, since she was valuable to the Emporium, in that her taste (in other people&amp;apos;s dress) attracted the custom of ladies from the country as well as of tradesmen&amp;apos;s wives and faithful aspiring gullible servant girls. She gave the place a tone, and with that a profit which Mr. Clinch&amp;apos;s expensive gross habits could ill have done without. And Mrs. Clinch, she was fond of her. Therefore she stayed; though had the Blue Bores known that an unfortunate girl in trouble was mainly supported by her charity, out of her earnings and savings, they would have felt it necessary, for the sake of respectability, to procure her discharge, and would have spent many hours deeply regretting such a scandal. Other matters, too, drew off Mr. and Mrs. Trotman&amp;apos;s angel. The Mayor had an appointment with the vicar to discuss a reconstruction of the Coal and Blanket Club, of which Mrs. Trotman was ex-offieio president. The vicar was of opinion that too large a proportion of the funds had been applied towards the committee&amp;apos;s bazaar expenses, and also that some starving families had been receiving the club&amp;apos;s warmth without deserving it as much, for instance, as the vicar might have, had he been destitute. He spoke his mind, and as a small attention after doing so, he gave Mr. Trotman a marked copy of that week&amp;apos;s Anglican Churchman with which Mr. Trotman straightway hastened home to his son. &amp;quot; What do you think of this, my boy, from the Anglican Churchman ? &amp;quot; said the happy father: &amp;quot; We hear, on good authority, that the Church is likely to reap at least some advantage from the miraculous removal of Ramshorn Hill from the neighbourhood of Trowbury, in Wiltshire, to that of the metropolitan suburb of Acton. Nothing could be more appropriate, or more in accordance with Divine Command. By the Church it was moved. To the Church (D.V.) it will come. For we need not to remind our readers that Mr. Alexander Trotman is a convinced and active, though not a communicating, Anglican. We trust, however, that the terms of the gift-if gift it is to be-will be clearly laid down at the outset. The Church has had enough of half-measures, has suffered enough at the hands of non-sectarians and infidels. How long, 0 Lord, how long ! Divine service demands free gifts. We can have nothing to do with undenominational religion. We have no doubt but our dissenting friends would be ready to help us and to make the so-called Holy Mountain a conspicuous centre of propaganda directed against the righteous union of Church and State. Verbum sat sapienti! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That sounds as if we shan&amp;apos;t have much to do with it. . &amp;quot; Oh,&amp;quot; said Alec. &amp;quot; But Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;ll give &amp;apos;em what for.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes.&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman entered the sick-room with a telegram in her hand. &amp;quot; Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s coming down to-morrow! We simply can&amp;apos;t ask him to stay here.-D&amp;apos;you hear, Alec, Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s coming! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Let &amp;apos;em all come,&amp;quot; replied the invalid wearily. On looking into the Hal/penny Press next day Mr. Trotman was astonished to find that a newspaper which had tried often to scare the nation with articles on the alcoholic degeneration of the British imperial race, had now displaced the gracious doings of the Royal Family, the little war in the Himalayas, the Anglo-Zulu crisis and even the Holy Mountain, by several columns in support of the falling conservative ministry-by a leading article on premature temperance legislation and the sacred British right of individual liberty. &amp;quot;Good again!&amp;quot; remarked Mr. Trotman, thinking of his grocer&amp;apos;s licence. Then he recollected that there was no knowing if the family of Trotman would need to be in trade much longer. A country house appeared to his mind&amp;apos;s eye-coverts, motor-cars, obsequious villagers, himself a sportsman, a seat in parliament, a title, Sir James Trotman, Lord Trowbury.... For James Trotman had his day-dreams as well as his livernightmares. VI &amp;quot;Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s coming! &amp;quot; What excitement in the Famous Grocery Establishment ! Mrs. Trotman very nearly forgot for a moment her son&amp;apos;s internal arrangements. Sir Pushcott Bingley was exceedingly sorry not to be able to accept Mrs. Trotman&amp;apos;s kind hospitality. She would understand, would she not ? It was-ah-necessary for him to be near his motor, which was in the Blue Boar garage. A new chauffeur.... A public life had to be lived in public places. He had, in fact, ordered dinner at the Blue Boar by telegram. But if Mrs. Trotman would allow him, he would look in after dinner.... Charming man! &amp;quot; He might have asked you to dinner with him at the Blue Boar,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Trotman to her husband, nevertheless. &amp;quot; Public men like to be by themselves sometimes. Perhaps he&amp;apos;ll dictate to his secretary while he&amp;apos;s at dinner,&amp;quot; replied &amp;apos;Mendment Trotman, for the sake of amending what he otherwise completely agreed with. Sir Pushcott Bingley was forgiven after supper. He was jubilant, merry, jolly; most condescending. He told them exalted secrets. &amp;quot; The curse of the British Empire,&amp;quot; he said, holding up to the light a glass of the Famous Grocer&amp;apos;s port wine and replacing it on the table somewhat decidedly, &amp;quot; is, as you say, a lack of enterprise-an inability to take the tide at the flood. I am sorry Alexander is not well enough to join our conclave: you must inform him gradually, Mrs. Trotman, as his strength warrants. But you must please understand fully that what I am saying must not leak out-not a word (&amp;apos; Not a word!&amp;apos; echoed Mr. Trotman)-or all our efforts will be quite fruitless, and instead of making money, we shall certainly lee it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;D&amp;apos;you hear, Lilian,&amp;quot; said Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;d better listen to Sir Pushcott too,&amp;quot; retorted Mrs. Trotman with a touch of acerbity. &amp;quot; I am sure I can trust you to preserve our interests-your own interests-your own interests,&amp;quot; was Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s brilliantly tactful stroke. After journalistic strife in London he liked to have these provincial fools, as he thought them, hanging on speeches of his. Possibly to let rip, more than it usually behovecl him to do in London, made him feel the equal of the extremely clever writers (in their own way) that he employed. &amp;quot; Well,&amp;quot; he went on, &amp;quot; as I was saying, the Gods fought for us. I should never have been able to obtain the lease of the Holy Mountain if the situation, political and religious, had not been what it is. You see, the conservative government will have to go to the country very shortly, and if I were to print everything I could print, it&amp;apos;s fairly certain that they would not return to power for a year or two. The election will really turn on the temperance question, and there is nothing like temperance unless it&amp;apos;s education for pandering to the desire of every virtuous man and every busybody to be his brother&amp;apos;s keeper. To clap your opponent into legal fetters is one of the easiest and pleasantest ways of doing good-much easier and pleasanter than loving your neighbour as yourself and less costly than sending out missionaries to savages who don&amp;apos;t want them. Missions, as you know, are mainly kept up by old ladies who, if they saw Mary Magdalene coming, would fly into the next street and then send a policeman after her to find out whether she had come by her alabaster box of precious ointment honestly. Forcing Christianity on niggers and education on the poor are two of the easiest ways of running up one&amp;apos;s credit account in heaven ; and besides, as it makes both of them more profitable, it also runs up one&amp;apos;s credit account on earth. Temperance legislation, however, is the best dodge of all. The reformer who gets drunk every evening of his life, but makes a point, for his liver&amp;apos;s sake, of drinking nothing but salts in the morning, always wishes to close the public-houses till midday.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; We certainly ought to be more temperate, as a nation,&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman remarked. &amp;quot; Precisely,&amp;quot; said Sir Pushcott. &amp;quot; Who disputes it? But I have given you the main reason why so-called temperance reform is a practicable plank in the liberal platform, and seduces so many conservatives from the broad lines of party action. The Halfpenny Press has always advocated retrenchment and reform on imperial lines; efficiency, regeneration, and all that; together with a modicum of temperance-a good deal of it, in fact, lately ;-for it would never have done for the opinion of the country to leave the Halfpenny Press behind. We have to go with it; and we find that a little temperance has a distinctly beneficial effect on our circulation. &amp;quot; One of the cabinet ministers said to me a short time ago: &amp;apos;You know, Bingley, the conservative party will go to the dogs if this teetotal foolery can&amp;apos;t be stopped, and the electorate roused up to value its damn liberties.&amp;apos; &amp;quot;Well, the government are of opinion that if once the average man can be given a sense of his inalienable right to get drunk if he wants to, and be made to see what these pin-prick temperance tactics are bound to end in, then he will rouse up and completely overwhelm the reformers, and the liberal-labour party with them. It is the conservatives&amp;apos; last chance; they&amp;apos;ve run up taxation so; and I promised we&amp;apos;d help them if they would lease the Holy Mountain, which is Crown land, to your sonto us, that is. Of course they demurred; said the liberals would scent jobbery and make party capital out of it. So I pointed out that our unequivocal support was their last chance of staying in office, and that the wind might easily be taken out of the liberal sails by our undertaking to sublet the Mountain to the Church for religious purposes. Also we-your son and myself, that is-offered to bear the brunt of any legal proceedings instituted by the Acton landlords whose property has been obliterated by the hill. In point of fact, they are men in a smallish way, for the hill luckily fell clear of the Goldsmiths&amp;apos; Company&amp;apos;s estate; and they have not enough money to guarantee their legal costs, let alone bring their cases to a successful conclusion. Capital is the tenth point of the law.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But,&amp;quot; asked Mrs. Trotman, who came of dissenting stock, though she was usually ashamed to say so, &amp;quot;why should the Church have it all ? The Church is not the only religion.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes ? &amp;quot; added her husband. &amp;quot;There are two very excellent practical reasons. The Church is the official State religion. Again, you&amp;apos;ll find that the Church will be compelled to let other sects participate, and it is always best to let the sectarians fight out their own battles. And lastly, I am not so sure that the Church will be very greatly the gainer, for we shall not sublet the Holy Mountain to them for nothing, and in these days of fierce religious competition they can no doubt be made to bid pretty high if they are deftly managed. In any case, the Holy Mountain will be leased to your son at a nominal rent for twenty-one years on the understanding that he sublets it to the Church-for how long not stated. As expressed in our agreement, I shall provide the capital. We stand to make money, I think.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Much ?&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman asked. &amp;quot; Impossible to say exactly how much at the present moment. If we can keep the Acton landowners quiet and prevent them from forming a syndicate, as I think we shall . . . I daresay you saw this morning that the Half enny Press has taken up its new policy. We are no longer Social Reformers, as they call themselves, but Benevolent Individualists-let &amp;apos;em reform themselves and devil take the hindmost! As he always has done ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; But I wonder you aren&amp;apos;t ashamed to be-like a turncoat,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Trotman, who was still smarting from some of the baronet&amp;apos;s remarks, notably those on missions and charitable ladies, both of which entered considerably into her schemes for social success. &amp;quot;People,&amp;quot; she added, using an underbred woman&amp;apos;s favourite indefinitely definite noun, &amp;quot; are generally ashamed of being inconsistent.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Of being detected,&amp;quot; replied Sir Pushcott Bingley. &amp;quot; Besides, Mrs. Trotman, it is not within the province of the press to be ashamed.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; How clever you are, Sir Pushcott!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What d&amp;apos;you think the Church will do ? &amp;quot; inquired Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot; I really don&amp;apos;t know. And what does it matter Talk, I suppose. What the Church misses is its ancient power of exs communication. Nobody takes any notice of its thunders nowadays. It is like an old lady whose complaints are received with the forbearance due to her senility, and whose charities have come to be regarded as rights. Even its power of social ostracism has passed to those who make more vigorous use of it-the nonconformists, I mean. They are our modern priestcraftsmen, even though their priests may be merely retired tradesmen, made into preachers in order to flatter their money out of them and to keep them faithful when social considerations would naturally urge them towards the Church.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But that is very serious, very,&amp;quot; remarked Mr. Trotman. &amp;quot; Oh no! not at all, when you know how to take advantage of it. Let church and chapel exhaust their ammunition on one another; not on us. The Archbishop of All the Empire, whose creation it was I who brought about, is the only man to be feared; but even he is more or less helpless to do much but talk, because his consecration is unpopular among the old-fashioned church-people who, after all, hold the ecclesiastical pursestrings., The Director of the Hal/penny Pres did not know, of course, that the revered, respected and feared parent had been an eloquent deacon of the straitest sect of nonconformists; had frightened one anzmic girl into religious mania and had laid several foundation-stones. &amp;quot; Look at this, sir,&amp;quot; said Mr. Trotman, producing his copy of the Anglican Churchman. Sir Pushcott glanced down it. &amp;quot; Yes. Very good. It was arranged for by me. You see, they are already beginning to look the gift-horse in the mouth, and to lay down conditions of acceptance which no one will stop to listen to. Excellent people-fatuous, no doubt. If they only knew how they play into other people&amp;apos;s . d.. .. They don&amp;apos;t possess the diplomacy of cockroaches, which at least lie hidden till their hosts are gone off to bed.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; We have a lot of cockroaches in the kitchen,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Trotman. &amp;quot; I believe they come from the shop.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Nonsense! &amp;quot; said her husband. He roused himself in his chair, tapped the ash off his cigar, and, with a great semblance of import, in his most sepulchral voice, spoke thus: &amp;quot; We have been diplomatic here too.&amp;quot; Then he watched for an effect. &amp;quot; We are going to make him Mayor of Trowbury if he&amp;apos;s well enough.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Excellent!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s rather a deadlock at present. We have a conservative and a liberal mayor turn and turn about, but it&amp;apos;s the liberals&amp;apos; turn next and they have nobody that wants to take office and they don&amp;apos;t want a conservative to have it. So me and Mr. Ganthorn, a great friend of mine, have dropped a word here and a word there, you understand... &amp;quot;Perfectly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And it&amp;apos;s about settled that my son is to be next mayor. You see, he hasn&amp;apos;t got any politics, except mine; always tories, my family; and he hasn&amp;apos;t helped the party like I have. It&amp;apos;s thought that a well-known mayor may bring well-to-do residents to the town. The present member, Delaine Jenkyns, you know, told me that I had more to do with his getting in than any other man.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He told Mr. Clinch that, too,&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman interrupted. &amp;quot; No, he didn&amp;apos;t ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, he did! You know he did. You said if he did it again you&amp;apos;d vote liberal.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well,&amp;quot; said Sir Pushcott, with the intention of being tactful, &amp;quot; these country mayors are of considerable importance in their own parish. It may help us . . .&amp;quot; &amp;quot; My husband is mayor now,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Trotman severely. &amp;quot; Oh! I congratulate you. I had forgotten that, of course. Father and son ! Excellent. A very responsible mayor he makes, I have no doubt, Mrs. Trotman. The duties are onerous, I believe. I must say Good-night. Son following his father-a family title. I have to thank you for your kind hospitality, Mrs. Trotman. Most kind. Tell your son he must hurry up and get quite well. I&amp;apos;ll call in and see him to-morrow, if I may. Good-night.&amp;quot; With most gracious handshakes, Sir Pushcott Bingley took his leave. But was he such a charming man after all Had it not been for her beloved son&amp;apos;s interests, Mrs. Trotman would have unsheathed her claws. &amp;quot; He must be an atheist,&amp;quot; she said savagely; and then, having thrown some of the most sticky smelly mud at her disposal, she felt better. In point of fact, it was by no means sure that the council would make Alec the next Mayor of Trowbury. His father had, during his year of office, become less popular with the governing cliques. He was suspected of having made a profit out of his mayoral salary, when by all right and precedent the town should have made a profit out of him. Within two days, however, the matter was settled by the Halfptnny Press, in which there appeared a column headed: ALEX. TROTMAN MAYOR OF TROWBURY PROPHET HONOURED IN HIS OWN COUNTRY SON TO SUCCEED FATHER IN MAYORAL CHAIR Trowbury, having tasted notoriety, craved for more. The election was settled in advance at the Blue Boar, and the world&amp;apos;s perusal clinched it. VII Sir Pushcott Bingley&amp;apos;s visit to the sick-room lasted but a short time. Alec was difficult; he would not follow the conversational lead of the Director of the Hal/penny Press. He became impatient: wanted to know when the Holy Mountain was going to bring in some money-enough to live on, say, in a little house ;-asked why it could not be sold as it stood. For he did not yet understand in the least the financial and diplomatic part of the business. When Sir Pushcott, anxious to avoid long explanations, counselled patience, and inquired if Alec was engaged, Mrs. Trotman said that her son was not strong enough to talk business, and hurried the baronet from the room. Suffering brains, she declared, ought not to be worried. Had Sir Pushcott, for all his journalistic genius, known how to deal on an equality and individually with women like Mrs. Trotman, he would have retorted that the stomach isn&amp;apos;t the brain. Instead, he was polite and nonplussed. In a short time his motor-car was bearing him over the Downs towards Lqndon. Trowbury was outwardly calm. Although the Halfpenny Press informed it daily of the Holy Mountain, Parliament, the invalid&amp;apos;s progress, temperance and its bearing on the sacred right of liberty, the revival of the State Church (to be brought to a glorious fulness by means of the said Holy Mountain); although there was the usual crop of murders, divorces, disasters, and diseases; although all this hotch-potch was served up daily with a sauce piquante of mighty headlines,-Trowburians remained their old inert selves. They read, marked, and fell to at their parish pump. Drains took precedence over the Holy Mountain, a dog-fight over the parliamentary debate. Who can say they were not wise in their generation ? Mr. Trotman alone said wonderful things over his glasses at the Blue Boar, desiring to make as much capital and to gain as much attention as possible out of the events that had befallen his family, without at the same time making public any matter that had, in the interests of both, to be kept private between the Director of the Halfpenny Press and the Famous Mayor and Grocer of Trowbury. He pointed out daily to his wife how much depended on her secrecy. It was perhaps lucky that, in attaining the rank and deportment of mayoress, she had offended her few lady friends, and therefore, poor woman! had no one, except the servant, to whom she could impart any secrets at all. In her husband&amp;apos;s phrase, Mum was the word. The sultry days of August were unfavourable to Alec&amp;apos;s recovery. He developed an excitableness difficult to control, and a bad habit of nearly fainting when his will was crossed. He was like the small child who says cynically, &amp;quot; If vou don&amp;apos;t give in to me, I shall scream.&amp;quot; Debility, the doctor called it, and once more prescribed entertainment. Sir Pushcott&amp;apos;s private secretary wrote, in answer to Mr. Trotman, that the Director of the Halfpenny Press was very busy, and that everything of importance he had to communicate would be found in the columns of the Hal/penny Press, a copy of which would be delivered daily at Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s establishment. Deprived thus of his morning progress to and from the newspaper shop, Mr. Trotman took to reading the paper in his son&amp;apos;s room. &amp;quot; Sir Pushcott is a very clever man,&amp;quot; he remarked one day, &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t quite see through his little game, but you ought to be proud to know him, my boy.&amp;quot; In love with strategy, he proposed chess, but at that Alec was his master and twice fool&amp;apos;smated him. The conservative government, on its last legs before the onslaught of the temperance reformers, and much harassed within its ranks by the uncompromising stubbornness of the brewing interest, was only too glad to give forth the new cry of Individual Liberty ! They acted faithfully by Sir Pushcott Bingley. They hardly dared do otherwise. The Holy Mountain was debated; the closure ruthlessly enforced. The Church, they said, had lacked encouragement to show what it could do. The Holy Mountain-Ciown land, that is national land-ought not to remain untenanted and useless, a standing disgrace to that sense of economy and efficiency that it was the duty of the Conservative party to foster. The sacred cause of religion.... The diminution of piety among the working classes.... After all, the nation owed a miracle, and London a mountain-a hill-an eminence-only to, and to no other than, Alexander Trotman. Who so fit as he to be rewarded, always with our regard to national interests? His Majesty&amp;apos;s Government counted on the support of all right-thinking men in the act of elementary justice.... A Liberal leader, an enthusiast on the subjects of social reform, small holdings and Back to the Land, declared eloquently that it would be a standing disgrace to the nation if such land, miraculously placed almost in the heart of London, were not used to produce a pure milk-supply for ailing slum-babies. Amid roars of laughter, the conservative agricultural members brought forward overwhelming evidence to show that cows cannot be fed on chalk downland, and the debate collapsed. The temperature of London, and grouse shooting on the cooler northern moors did the rest. Against all constitutional precedent, according to the radicals, the Holy Mountain was made over to Alexander Trotman on a twenty-one years&amp;apos; lease, on the understanding that he would sublet it to the Church (for a period not debated owing to the cows), and that he would reward the landowners whose puddled fields had been buried beneath the hill, and also that he would compensate the relatives of the deceased families in accordance with the provisions of the Consolidated Compensation Acts. The nation, led by the Hal/pexny Press, rejoiced. Church bells were rung in some places. There was, it is true, something of an outcry when, after prorogation of Parliament, the Presi. dent of the Local Government Board authorised, of himself, the extension of the Central London tube railway to the foot of the Holy Mountain. But the Hal/penny Press pointed out that in a time of swift and ever-growing progress, national works could not, and ought not to, wait for Parliament&amp;apos;s return from its holidays. Either Parliament would have to sit all the year round, or else ministers should be able to anticipate provisionally the enactments of a subsequent session. &amp;quot; The Constitution must be brought up to date! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s only common sense,&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman observed. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve often told the town council the same thing, but they won&amp;apos;t listen to reason and can&amp;apos;t understand progress when they do.&amp;quot; VIII In September, Mrs. Trotman took Alec to Weymouth. She was secretly delighted at the prospect of showing her wonderful unfortunate son to the public outside his native town, and the public exhibited its appreciation in the customary manner-by mobbing him. On the third day of their visit, an American woman, not long landed from the Cherbourg boat, flung her arms round Alec, exclaiming: &amp;quot;You poor boy! I guess you English will beat us after all if you&amp;apos;ve gotten mountains to move for you.&amp;quot; And she kissed him several times, as if he had been a pianist. It was this episode which decided Mrs. Trotman to take Alec on to Weston-super-Mare, under the assumed style of Mrs. and Mr. Alexander Argyll. Visitois at the boarding-house wondered what woman it was who talked so constantly of good manners and decent privacy. A major&amp;apos;s wife, they said, until her extremely elegant and finical behaviour at table. undeceived them. A romantic adventuress, they hazarded; certainly not a relation of the Dukes of Argyll. The many portraits of Alec, which had appeared in the papers, were of little use in identifying him; for the portraits had idealised him according to the popular notion of how a young mover of mountains ought to look, and illness had, so to speak, very much de-idealised him. Mrs. Argyll and son spent a fairly happy ten days at Weston before their landlady drew Mrs. Argyll aside after lunch and said: &amp;quot; Dear Mrs. Argyll, there&amp;apos;s a lady come here, No. 13, who went to that Crystal Palace revival, and she says she&amp;apos;s sure your son is the Alexander Trotman who moved the mountain. Now, if you could tell me, quite in secret, that he has patronised my establishment. . .. Poor young gentleman! It is so hard to make both ends meet. The short season here . . . to think of his looking so ill.. This was precisely what Mrs. Trotman had been hungering for. Quite in secret, during half an hour&amp;apos;s chat in the private back sitting-room, the landlady was informed of everything, and a good deal more besides. At dinner that evening, whilst the fishballs were being served (most of the guests were not interested in faked-up fish), there was something of an ovation-very nearly speeches. A spinster, resident in the house, offered Alec a share of her bottle of colonial port-wine, and begged Mrs. Trotman to accept for her poor, poor son a box of the special strengthening pills recommended so highly by Lady Coate of Brandon. Only doses of brandy enabled Alec to leave Weston next day for Trowbury. While he was away the question of the mayoralty settled itself. Those who talked much, Mr. Ganthorn in particular, impressed upon those who talked less, three main considerations. First, that having a celebrated mayor would attract notice and wealthy residents to the salubrious town of Trowbury; second, that the political deadlock (whether the mayor should be Conservative or Liberal) would be avoided, since Alexander Trotman was too young to have political opinions and in any case had no vote; third-and this was the crowning reason-they of Trowbury would look such various sorts of fools if they did not, after all that had appeared in the press, put the Mountain-Mover into the high office of mayor. Mr. Trotman, with a show of modesty and reluctance, agreed perfectly. The press, he said with an air of resignation, did expect the mayoralty to devolve upon his son. He could assure them, on the authority of his friend, Sir Pushcott Bingley, that it was so. It was no use going against things. . .. &amp;quot; And so say all of us! &amp;quot;they all replied in effect. The events of Lord Mayor&amp;apos;s week, as the children called it, began to excite the town, and fortunately drew attention from some muddle or other (no one knew exactly what) in the borough accounts. On Sunday, November 6, the outgoing Mayor and the Corporation attended morning service at the Parish Church in all municipal state, preceded by mace-bearers and guarded by the Fire Brigade in full uniform. Alec was absent; his mother thought it best for him to husband his strength. The Vicar did not preach one of those excessively personal sermons which so delight a small town. He took as his text, Take heed lest ye fall; and under five heads followed by a peroration, in the good old-fashioned way, he showed how and why pride goes before a fall. Trowbury, already annoyed by the smallness of the Vicar&amp;apos;s subscriptions to local objects, out of his stipend of ?230 a year net, was still more incensed by what it termed his pessimism. Church services, the windbags said, ought to be brighter. It was the clergy&amp;apos;s own fault that people stayed away, as they indeed sometimes did, from church. If they had had the choosing of the hymns-nice bright hymns--something to sing at-something to buck them up for the stress and strain of modern life&amp;apos;s money-making! . . . What was the good of telling them they were miserable sinners l How could the Vicar expect liberal Easter offerings if he took no pains to please Trowbury? On the Monday, the Outgoing Mayor&amp;apos;s Supper took place. On the whole, it went off more satisfactorily than municipal Divine Service. Formerly, in heartier days, it had been called the Mayor&amp;apos;s Wine Party, but in deference to teetotalers, the name had been altered to Outgoing Mayor&amp;apos;s Supper. Not that its character was changed; liquor was still consumed; but the name-the said name-was more temperate, and reference to total abstinence as a cure-all for the poverty of the working classes could now be made in speeches. That was a famous victory for local temperance. Alderman Trotman had spent but little during his year of office. With the help of his wife he had made a good show on small money. He reckoned, indeed, that if he took into account the free advertisement the mayoralty gave his business (in his official speeches he had frequently referred to the lamentable adulteration of food-stuffs, and, by implication, to the purity of the Famous Groceries), he was nothing out of pocket and his salary or honorarium as mayor was almost entirely clear profit. Therefore, with characteristic generosity, he decided that, retaining fifty pounds for himself exclusively, he would spend the other fifty in giving a really classy (his own word) outgoing supper. He ordered down from his own wholesale house several cases of wine and liqueurs at trade prices. He took spirits out of bond. On the advice of Mr. Ganthorn, who had once attended a professional congress in Paris, absinthe was served in the antechamber before the meal, thus confirming the popular impression of the Mayor&amp;apos;s enterprise, his savoir-fairr and his interest in the Entente Cordiale. Most of the guests refused the stuff as too much like cough-mixture, but it is related by those who ought to know that in the night one worthy borough councilloress had to drag her husband out from beneath the bed, whither, he averred, wild horses had chased him in his dreams. Municipal dishes, in towns like Trowbury, preserve from year to year such a sameness that, contrary to general opinion, the speeches are often a welcome diversion from the food. The guests do eat, of course, and that right heartily, as a matter of longstanding habit; they drink, too, because neither alcohol nor the virtuousness of abstaining ever pall; and then they wait in a cloud of smoke to hear something about the latest borough squabble or the last of the council&amp;apos;s muddles, or some complimentary reference to their own indispensable services. The first one or two courses of Alderman Trotman&amp;apos;s supper went rather heavily. Afterwards the guests, having tasted his wines and more of his strange liqueurs, congratulated him on his distinguished son, for whom several of those present prophesied greatness. Finally, when they had gone back to &amp;quot; Good old whisky &amp;quot;-as a witty alderman greeted it amid loud laughterthey fell to congratulating the outgoing mayor on his noble self. Hilarious was the remainder of the feast. Profuse the thanks. For an evening, at least, the burgesses were united. At the moment of breaking up, you might have thought the genial old days were back again. His worship, together with Mr. Ganthorn and Alderman Clinch, stood on the pavement outside the Town Hall, singing-singing a religioso-sentimental ditty ! The police looked on respectfully. Then, suddenly, the brute&amp;apos;s teeth showed. A young woman, partly veiled, walked round the corner, touched Mr. Ganthorn&amp;apos;s arm, and tried to draw him away and speak to him. &amp;quot;Here, Mr. Mayor,&amp;quot; shouted Ganthorn jocularly, &amp;quot;your progressive town&amp;apos;s as bad as London.&amp;quot; Whereupon he saw who it was. But Mr. Clinch was already saying, &amp;quot; Give her in charge.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, give her in charge,&amp;quot; echoed the Mayor. &amp;quot; Here, constable, constable ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Very good, your worship.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, no! &amp;quot; said Ganthorn. &amp;quot; Yes! &amp;quot; commanded his worship. &amp;quot; Yes, yes. Of course. Disgraceful! &amp;quot; Mr. Clinch exclaimed. &amp;quot; What for, sirl&amp;quot; asked the policeman, taking out his notebook. &amp;quot; The usual,&amp;quot; replied the Mayor, &amp;quot; in the public thoroughfare.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But will any of you gentlemen come forward and give evidence to-morrow ? &amp;quot; the policeman inquired. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s no use me taking her in charge if you don&amp;apos;t.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;ll she get ? &amp;quot; asked Ganthorn. &amp;quot; Oh ! &amp;quot; replied his worship, &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll have her turned out of the town when she&amp;apos;s done time.&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn was beginning to protest. &amp;quot; Disgraceful! &amp;quot; repeated Mr. Clinch. &amp;quot; An offence against public morality. I will come.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Take her away, constable,&amp;quot; the Mayor continued. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ll be all right. I shall be on the bench. Don&amp;apos;t put me down as giving her in charge, and that&amp;apos;ll be all right.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Very good, your worship.-Come on, now! Come quiet!&amp;quot; It was noteworthy how very quiet the young woman was. The three borough fathers went on to Mr. Ganthorn&amp;apos;s house, where, with some others earlier arrived, they extended the merriment of the evening. And the policeman locked the young woman up. But, being kindly disposed to all such, a gallant policeman in his heart, he supplied her with paper, pencil, and an envelope; allowed her to write a note addessed to Miss J. Jepp, and went slightly off his beat to drop the letter into the letter-box of Clinch&amp;apos;s Emporium. IX Very early on Mayor&amp;apos;s Day Mrs. Trotman got up and peeped out of the window. To her great relief there was no rain, though a black northeaster was blowing off the Downs. When Mr. Trotman marched downstairs it was in his cotton shop-jacket and trodden-over carpet slippers. Even he was flurried. &amp;quot; Get that boy up,&amp;quot; he said to his wife. &amp;quot; But I want him to sleep on as long as he can,&amp;quot; replied that lady, who finally had got up dressed for going out or for receiving visitors. &amp;quot;Get him up, I say. He&amp;apos;s not ill now. Laziness, that&amp;apos;s what &amp;apos;tis. He&amp;apos;ll be late. My mayoralty has gone off all right and I&amp;apos;ll see that his does too.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; &amp;apos;Twouldn&amp;apos;t have if it hadn&amp;apos;t been for me hurrying you out of bed often and often. Why, I&amp;apos;ve half dressed you ever so many mornings ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Be quiet ! I&amp;apos;m busy.&amp;quot; The police inspector entered: &amp;quot;Court is at ten, your worship.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Right. Any cases ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Only the one from last night.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;H&amp;apos;m. . . . Need we take it ? Give her another chance.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Must be taken now, your worship. Gone too far. She&amp;apos;s been in the cells all night.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll be there then.&amp;quot; As the inspector was going out, Messrs. Ganthorn and Clinch came in: &amp;quot; I say, how about that girl, Mr. Mayor?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m going to hear the case at ten o&amp;apos;clock.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But look here, I can&amp;apos;t give evidence. There&amp;apos;ll be a scandal. You know how people talk.&amp;quot; Mr. Clinch took up the protest: &amp;quot;and I can&amp;apos;t possibly come,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot; Autumn stocktaking. Means pounds to me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But you&amp;apos;re coming to the council meeting and church and the dinner, aren&amp;apos;t you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s another thing. Duty. Besides, I don&amp;apos;t know whether I shall be able to get away for church.&amp;quot; Mr. Clinch&amp;apos;s large fat face did not look very pressed for time. &amp;quot; I shall go up to town by the nine-fifty if I&amp;apos;ve got to appear.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And where will you go to in town, eh?&amp;quot; Mr. Ganthorn inquired. Silence. Each spent a few moments measuring the other one&amp;apos;s and his own interests. Mr. Clinch walked to the door, stood there fumbling his heavy watch-chain, snorting and puffing, wishing for the wings of a dove perhaps. Meanwhile Mr. Ganthorn buttonholed the Justice of the Peace. &amp;quot; Look here, Trotman, I simply mustn&amp;apos;t be mixed up in this. D&amp;apos;you hear If I am, I shall make resrials. Those borough accounts . . &amp;quot; All right, all right! There&amp;apos;s no need to talk like that. I&amp;apos;ll see to it. We don&amp;apos;t want anything of that sort to-day. Everything will be in the London papers. Those infernal reporters. . . . We&amp;apos;re stark in the eyes of the world here. I&amp;apos;ll work it all right, and if I can&amp;apos;t I&amp;apos;ll allow an adjournment. I don&amp;apos;t suppose she&amp;apos;ll be represented by a lawyer. Mr. Ganthorn&amp;apos;s face brightened. As he hurried out of the door to catch up Mr. Clinch, he called back: &amp;quot; The better the day the better the deed, Trotman ! &amp;quot; And as he went down the street with Mr. Clinch, he remarked sapiently: &amp;quot; You can always twist that old fool round your finger if you know the way to get at him.&amp;quot; Nevertheless the tone of his voice was by no means free from anxiety. X News spread rapidly through the town: &amp;quot;There&amp;apos;s a good case coming on before the beak! &amp;quot; Somewhat before ten o&amp;apos;clock, a little knot of people had gathered outside the double door on which was painted in bold white letters Magistrates&amp;apos; Court, Public Entrance. From minute to minute another loiterer would join the group, or a cyclist would dismount at the edge of the pavement and remain talking there. A butcher&amp;apos;s cart, a farmer&amp;apos;s gig, a motor-car drew up in the road. An air of expectancy was noticeable in everybody. When the Mayor arrived a movement was made to view him, and while he was passing in through the magistrates&amp;apos; entrance, he heard behind him a faint-hearted hoot, and a &amp;quot; Well, what &amp;apos;bout it, &amp;apos;Mendment Trotman ? &amp;quot; He had hardly thought that news of the case would have spread abroad so early. He felt an impulse to turn back and have it out with the impertinent person, but, luckily remembering his dignity, conquering nobly the base instinct, he proceeded in and took his seat in the dark fusty little court. On the bench also, there beforehand, was one of those magisterial nonentities who, attending every court, does little except give seven days and platitudinous advice to tramps. Mr. Trotman&amp;apos;s will would be free from interference. Those two magistrates would take the charges. Before the prisoner was brought in, however, the Superintendent of Police desired respectfully to congratulate his worship on an occurrence without precedent in the history of Trowbury, namely that, from that day forward, father and son would be sitting on the same borough bench. The police, he said, had always found his worship a just, helpful, and &amp;quot; perspicious &amp;quot; magistrate. No doubt his distinguished son would have inherited the same qualities, only he, the Superintendent, hoped that the Mayor-elect would not try his, the Mayor-elect&amp;apos;s miraculous powers upon the court, the police station, or the prison. (Laughter.) The Mayor-elect must be in possession of powers as yet unexplained by science. But the police were only ordinary men. There had been complaints against them, but his worship knew that they always tried to discharge their difficult and onerous duties to the best of their ability. His worship signified that he did know, and beamed upon the Superintendent. Applause in court. The magistrates&amp;apos; clerk-a white-haired old man whose robust common sense had directed many a fuddled magistrate, had prevented many a miscarriage of justice-was heard to break his quill and to growl, &amp;quot; Damn&amp;apos;d rot!&amp;quot; His worship would now hear the case. Miss Starkey, small and frail, was brought in by a large blue constable who appeared positively to overhang her. Every neck craned forward. She looked round defiantly, recognised some one at the back of the court, and smiled. The charge, solicitation, was read over to her. Evidence was brought by the police to the effect that on the previous evening she, being twenty-four years of age, did behave in a wanton and disorderly manner in the streets of Trowbury, outside the Town Hall, to wit, that she had been of no occupation since the birth of her child; that she was unmarried; but she had never applied for an affiliation order; that she was not known to have any private means; that she plucked a certain gentleman&amp;apos;s arm outside the Town Hall; that she made certain overtures to him; that it was not known exactly what she said. His worship remarked severely that it was the worst case of the sort he had ever had to try, and that he was glad to know prisoner was not a native of Trowbury. More evidence was called for, but, as the police explained, the gentleman refused to appear against her. His worship had been present . . . &amp;quot; Can&amp;apos;t be on the bench and in the witness-box too,&amp;quot; said the magistrates&amp;apos; clerk. &amp;quot; Is there no more evidence, nothing as to what she said ? You&amp;apos;d better discharge her, sir.&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman began a speech setting forth the wickedness of the prisoner&amp;apos;s conduct, the sad immorality of her life, and the good repute of Trowbury. Before he had got very far, a note was handed up to him from a young woman at the back of the court. He read; gasped; ended his speech abruptly with: &amp;quot; As you are a first offender, Starkey, the sentence of the court is that the police be instructed to see that you remove yourself from the town of Trowbury within twenty-four hours.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s a bit better,&amp;quot; observed the clerk. Miss Starkey was removed. When she was ready to leave the precincts of the court, the friendly policeman told her: &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;re living outside the town, ain&amp;apos;t you ? He didn&amp;apos;t say as how you wasn&amp;apos;t to live where you have been, but don&amp;apos;t you get caught at it again, young woman, or you&amp;apos;ll get it hot.&amp;quot; His worship said, before leaving the bench, that people would see now, he hoped, his good reasons for dismissing the prisoner. . . . &amp;quot;Not the prisoner, now,&amp;quot; interjected the clerk. &amp;quot;For dismissing the late prisoner,&amp;quot; continued Mr. Trotman, &amp;quot;from her place in my establishment.&amp;quot; After his worship had departed (to the Blue Boar) and whilst the court was being closed up again, the note was found beneath the magistrate&amp;apos;s chair, whither it must have dropped instead of into the worshipful pocket. It was read aloud to the accompaniment of a general laugh; for it ran: &amp;quot; It was your own son that got her into trouble, Mr. Trotman.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; So I thought,&amp;quot; said the clerk, gathering up his papers. Mr. Clinch very soon heard that his assistant, Miss Jepp, had been at the police court and had sent up to Mr. Trotman a note which made him look queer. It was also reported to Mr. Clinch that she had been in constant communication with, and had visited regularly, the unhappy Miss Starkey. He therefore tried menacingly to question her on the interesting and disgraceful subject, and that failing, he gave her a month&amp;apos;s notice of dismissal in such opprobrious terms that she decided to leave that same day, and did so. Unfortunately, he could not prevent her (Mrs. Clinch refused to have anything to do with seizing her luggage), nor could he well claim a month&amp;apos;s wages from her in lieu of notice, as he would otherwise have done; for his pure wrath had led him to attack her before every one in the Emporium with such impure language that a full half-dozen could have borne witness against him had he sued Miss Jepp or had she brought an action against him for defamation of character. He pitied himself profoundly, and wondered what the world was coming to. XI Mrs. Trotman had a very trying morning with her son, the Mayor-elect. As the hour of the statutory meeting of the borough council drew near, he suddenly took it into his head to look on mayor-making as an insupportable ordeal; and he declared that, if they really wanted to make him Mayor, they could easily do it in his absence. &amp;quot; For goodness&amp;apos; sake, don&amp;apos;t tell your father so!&amp;quot; exclaimed poor Mrs. Trotman. She tried to brace up her son first with thin gruel and brandy, then with hot bovril, then with a special brand of tinned truffled chicken that he was fond of, and lastly with port-wine jelly. Three-quarters of an hour before noon Mr. Trotman returned home from court; he said: &amp;quot; Where&amp;apos;s Alec ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s not very well, James.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Can&amp;apos;t help that now. See he&amp;apos;s ready. Where&amp;apos;s my white shirt ? Where have you put my patent boots? Has he got a clean collar ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; James ! As if I shouldn&amp;apos;t see to that... &amp;quot; All right: I haven&amp;apos;t always. Make haste. Not a moment to spare. At the end of a period of tremendous bustle, the Mayor took the Mayor-elect off to the Town Hall. He remarked on the way that the Mayor-elect had not shaved himself properly behind the jaw and wanted to know why he hadn&amp;apos;t been to a hairdresser&amp;apos;s for once. Several councillors were waiting at the entrance and in the vestibule. They were telling each other beforehand what they were going to say-like naughty boys outside a headmaster&amp;apos;s study door ;-for which reason it was that the statutory meeting in the old Georgian council chamber, hung round with framed charters and portraits of past Mayors and curiously decorated royalties, resolved itself into a reproduction of rehearsed harangues and a reduction thereof by the local reporters into something resembling King&amp;apos;s English. Alec was told that he was a lucky young dog, and then the council seated itself for business, the Mayor-elect being on the right hand of the outgoing Mayor. Nominations for the office of Mayor were formally invited-the election had, of course, been settled long ago. Mr. Ganthorn rose to speak. He stood silent till only the fatter councillors&amp;apos; breathing could be heard, then: &amp;quot; There is no need,&amp;quot; he said, perhaps with a double meaning, &amp;quot;to make long speeches. Alderman Trotman, the Mayor, and Mr. Alexander Trotman, the Mayor-elect, are both of them as well known as they are highly respected. I have been connected with them in many business transactions, public as well as private, and have always found them honest and straightforward and upright. The man who succeeds in business is the man to trust in public affairs-look at the immense progress of America under the rule of business men. It is the first time within living memory that our Mayor has been chosen from without the council. It is the first time in the history of our loyal and ancient borough that a son has succeeded his father in the highest office it is ours to confer. But I need say no more, because the occasion and the reason of it is public throughout the land, and our mayoral election here is a national affair, and Trowbury stands-thanks to the press-before the eyes of the civilised world. That, gentlemen, is good for trade. The hotel proprietors are already reporting better receipts. It is good for trade, I repeat. The fortunes of Trowbury are on the turn. On the advantages of choosing a mayor outside the council, and they are many, I will not now enlarge. Many towns have lords and earls. Mr. Alexander Trotman is not a lord or an earl-though nobody knows what may happen(applause)-and he is more celebrated than either. I beg to propose Mr. Alexander Trotman as Mayor. The MountainMover, the Miracle-Worker! Long live Alexander . . . I beg your pardon.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; This isn&amp;apos;t the Mayor&amp;apos;s dinner, Ganthorn! &amp;quot; arose in a chorus which was not taken down by the reporters. Alderman Clinch rose to say a few words seconding the motion. In the excitement of speech-making, he relapsed from the polite tones of a draper&amp;apos;s shop to the mongrel English of a provincial burgess, retaining, nevertheless, some of the delicacy which he was accustomed to use in selling garments to a lady. He endorsed every word his good friend, Mr. Ganthorn, had said, and remarked in speaking of the Mayor-elect: &amp;quot; I do think as it&amp;apos;s wonderful to do what he did moving Ramshorn Hill to London without even taking a third-class ticket for it (which joke did not go down) and in succeeding his respected father as mayor of this here town. (Applause.) We&amp;apos;re all proud for to know Messrs. Trotman and Son. It&amp;apos;s a good old firm, I say. I&amp;apos;m not going to say much, as I knows of, but I do want to say that this is a proud day for Messrs. Trotman, and a proud day for the good old town of Trowbury; and I hope Alderman Trotman will do good business and Master Alec bring good trade to the town for many a year to come, I do. And I desires to take this here opportunity of congratulating both on &amp;apos;em. That&amp;apos;s all as I&amp;apos;ve got to say. . . . Oh, yes ! I seconds the motion.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And zo zay all on us!&amp;quot; cried a young member who was opposed in politics to Mr. Clinch, and who, not being listened to, looked innocent with a faint he-he ! The motion was put and carried unanimously amid a loud applause that only the Town Clerk&amp;apos;s forbidding legal aspect prevented from becoming uproarious. Mr. Trotman rose from his seat and made Alec do the same. Round his son&amp;apos;s neck he placed the chain of office; to him he gave the seal; and then, exchanging places, he sat him down rather forcibly in the mayoral chair. Alec swore sundry quaint and formidable oaths, signed what the Town Clerk called the long and honourable roll of the Mayors of Trowbury, and was once more egged out of his chair-this time to return thanks. It was a part of the ceremony for which his father had forgotten to prepare him. He stood up blankly. Then, remembering no doubt the tone of the speeches that had gone before, he began: &amp;quot; Thank you very much, gentlemen. A great honour. I didn&amp;apos;t want to be Mayor-as true as I&amp;apos;m here. . . .&amp;quot; Realising he had not said quite the right thing, he looked round at his father; looked at the councillors seated along the table in various comfortable attitudes, one or two of them with sympathetic faces; looked up at the ceiling; blushed; sat down. The ex-Mayor sprang up: &amp;quot; As you know, gentlemen, my son, the Mayor, has hardly yet recovered from a long and dangerous illness, and under the circumstances you will not expect him to thank you at length for the very great honour you have done him-us-our family. Speaking as an alderman and a tradesman in a large way of business, and not as father of the present Mayor, I can only say that, in making my son Mayor, we have done the very best thing for the town. Gentlemen, I believe in advertisement. It is by advertisement-and a sound stock-that I have built up my business from a small way to the largest and growing grocery establishment in the town. I believe, I say, in advertisement; advertisement for a business and advertisement for a town, which is only a large business with the Mayor as director. My friend, Sir Pushcott Bingley, whom we hope to see at the dinner to-night-(applause)-he assures me that to-day&amp;apos;s proceedings will be fully reported and illustrated in the greatest newspaper the world has ever seen. I allude to the Hal/penny Press. That is what I call a thorough good advertisement for our good old town. I hope you will forgive my son, our Mayor, any shortcomings due to his youth, bad health, or inexperience; and I can assure you that I shall always be at his right hand to make his year of office a success and to help in the progress of the good old loyal borough of Trowbury.&amp;quot; During the subsequent business, which included the election of new aldermen and the appointment of the year&amp;apos;s committees, Mr. Trotman did make himself of the very greatest use. But for his repeated admonition, &amp;quot; Harmony, gentlemen! Harmony on this day! &amp;quot; and his skill in defeating by amendments and relegation to committee any inquiry into the state of the borough&amp;apos;s minor finances, his son&amp;apos;s first council meeting would in all probability have been the reverse of pleasant. At the conclusion, he invited the council to accompany his son, the Mayor, to the parish church at half-past three in the afternoon. And in the street, after the meeting had broken up, while the usual after-meeting was being held, it was discovered that the customary vote of thanks to the ex-Mayor had been clean forgotten. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t mention it, gentlemen,&amp;quot; said the ex-Mayor. &amp;quot; My son&amp;apos;s election is my vote of thanks.&amp;quot; Mrs. Trotman had wished Alec to have a brand-new mayoral robe; she wanted to choose the material herself; but Mr. Trotman ridiculed the idea. If the old one was good enough for his own self, wasn&amp;apos;t it good enough for his son. Mrs. Trotman spent most of the time between the statutory meeting and the church service in trying to clean out a recognisable winestain on the left-hand side of the robe&amp;apos;s front. She consulted her favourite chemist as to the best solvent for iron-mouldy stains. After much hard work, she succeeded in turning the stain into a blotch, and in cleaning only too visibly a circle of the robe just around the blotch-in giving the blotch a halo, as it were. In a furred blue blotched mantle did Alec march from the Town Hall to the parish church. The vicar, the mace-bearers and the town-crier went before him, his father almost beside him, and his Mhother a short way off with the smelling-salts. The procession, coloured in front and funereally black behind, proceeded with step slow and dignified from the grey November daylight into the dim parish church. The congregation which had gathered there stood up while the corporation passed up the nave to its high carved wooden seats in the chancel. Out of the blackness the sound of the organ crept as if it were a messenger from some other world or from the depths of Trowbury&amp;apos;s history. Mrs. Trotman had made the vicar promise that divine service should be as short as possible, for, she said, Alec could not attend a long service and the dinner too, and it was most necessary he should be present at the dinner. For that reason the vicar, an uncompromising churchman in controversy, contented himself in the pulpit with expressing his satisfaction that the youthful Mayor, after taking part in a heretical revival at the Crystal Palace, should, on the most important day of his young life, have returned to his mother-church, the church where he had been christened-a step taken, no doubt, on his own initiative, for which he was greatly to be honoured. Much more he said in the same vein, receiving Alec into his church as a very prodigal son. Tactless vicar ! Mr. Trotman was furious. Dictate what his son should, and should not, do indeed! Hadn&amp;apos;t his son come to church that day at the risk of his health, at the risk of his life perhaps ? There was a nodding and a whispering among the members of the corporation as they prepared to leave their seats and to march down to the west door. Suddenly, just at the crossing of the aisles, an old woman in a black wobbling bonnet trimmed with bobby-dazzlers, ran out of a pew and flung herself on Alec. &amp;quot; La, Master Allie, how glad I be to see &amp;apos;ee in that there nice gown ! But don&amp;apos; &amp;apos;ee go movin&amp;apos; no more hills and losin&amp;apos; the squire&amp;apos;s lambs. How like your dear father you d&amp;apos; look! An&amp;apos; I&amp;apos;ve nursed both on &amp;apos;ee, I have ! &amp;quot; She insisted on a kiss. &amp;quot; Give your ol&amp;apos; nursie a kiss, now do &amp;apos;ee.&amp;quot; Then she brought his head down to a level with hers and whispered in a loud voice: &amp;quot; They be goin&amp;apos; to leave the little chap &amp;apos;long with me when they goes to Lon&amp;apos;on, an&amp;apos; you come out an&amp;apos; see your own just whenever you like. Blood&amp;apos;s thicker than water, Allie dear. . ..&amp;quot; Mr. Trotman replaced her forcibly in her pew. With all its antique dignity the corporation left the church. A reverent babble arose. How the ex-Mayor had scowled! Merrily the bells clashed out. XII Alec himself did not understand fully the drift of old Mrs. Parfitt&amp;apos;s speech in church: When Mr. Clinch had given Julia notice in a volley of unclean language, she had rushed from the shop to her bedroom red in the face and breathless with indignation. She intended to pack and leave the Emporium at once. But what could she do ? She would have either to go down below again and claim the wages that were due to her, or find Mrs. Clinch, or spend three days drawing enough money from the Post Office Saving&amp;apos;s Bank. She could not possibly go right away at once. After she had calmed down a little, concluding that she might just as well be hung for a sheep as a bodkin, and feeling inclined to do nothing so much as to defy Mr. Clinch, she put on her yellow hat, now long past its prime, and a jacket, and hurried off out in the direction of Mrs. Parfitt&amp;apos;s. The rapid walk by heating her body further cooled her mind. Her attention was distracted by the dead leaves that an autumn wind blew down upon her head. They fell into the brim of her hat, and she had to take it off, still walking quickly, in order to clean them out. The age of the hat shocked her. She had not the moral support of being well dressed. And how miserably the varicose veins in her right leg ached! Further up the road she saw three or four loutish youths scrambling along with comic gait after a woman whose skirts swung and flapped around her because she was going at a greater pace than her legs were made for. Surely, Julia thought, that&amp;apos;s Edie&amp;apos;s short jacket or one very like it, and Edie&amp;apos;s hat.... It was Miss Starkey. She stopped and, turning round, gesticulated angrily at the louts behind her. The wind lifted her hat upright. The louts laughed recklessly. She whisked round again and hastened on with the louts still behind her, still mimicking her gait. Julia caught them up. She took Miss Starkey&amp;apos;s arm and looked a look at the louts. Dropping behind with a last ribald insult, they stopped to light cigarettes. All that Miss Starkey asked Julia or said to her was, &amp;quot; What d&amp;apos;you want ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Edie, dear, I&amp;apos;ll come with you. I was coming out. I was, really.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You can come if you like.-Oh, Julie ! I feel so faint.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There, there ! &amp;quot; Julia cosseted her, and they walked on to the cottage. Julia wept a little, but without breaking down. Edith Starkey remained sulky and dry-eyed. Her face and gait revealed her state of mind. Mrs. Parfitt in her lonely little cottage knew nothing of what had happened either to Miss Starkey or to Julia. Having the baby to herself had pleased the old woman, and so had the absence for a night of the baby&amp;apos;s mother, whom she had never quite taken to and whom she had kept at the cottage only because she was lonely, and for the baby&amp;apos;s and her Allie and his sweetheart&amp;apos;s sake. Though quite certain in her old woman&amp;apos;s mind that Alec was at the bottom of Miss Starkey&amp;apos;s mischance, she did not inquire, neither was she told. &amp;quot; My dear,&amp;quot; she exclaimed, &amp;quot;where baue you been to, leaving the baby and all. And I&amp;apos;ve a-had to feed &amp;apos;en wi&amp;apos; spoon- food and he&amp;apos;s done beautiful &amp;apos;cept for a bit o&amp;apos; wind in his precious little tummie.&amp;quot; Miss Starkey took her baby. Then at last she wept, while old Mrs. Parfitt ejaculated from time to time: &amp;quot; Here&amp;apos;s a pretty kettle o&amp;apos; fish ! Here&amp;apos;s a pretty kettle o&amp;apos; fish. I do declare ! Now, do &amp;apos;ee, my dear. . . . There, there ! try an&amp;apos; bide quiet.&amp;quot; Events to date were related-with certain reservations. Miss Starkey spoke of Mr. Ganthorn, his domestic arrangements, with a vehemence which rather astonished and mystified Julia. Mrs. Parfitt was told about the police court, and that Mr. Trotman had only sentenced Miss Starkey to remove herself from the moral town of Trowbury. It was the policeman and the sentence which had fixed themselves in Mrs. Parfitt&amp;apos;s mind, much more than the injustice, for since she had lived among labouring people she had lost her hold on official morality and had come to regard troubles with the police as a part of life. &amp;quot; Ah ! &amp;quot; she said, &amp;quot; Mr. Trotman let &amp;apos;ee off wi&amp;apos; that, did he, when you didn&amp;apos;t ought to have been summoned at all. But he didn&amp;apos;t know that, bless you. He&amp;apos;s such a kind sort o&amp;apos; man. But look &amp;apos;ee, my dears, if I be going to see Master Alec go to church in his mayor&amp;apos;s mantle an&amp;apos; all, I must hurry up, an&amp;apos; I &amp;apos;spect the baker&amp;apos;s cart, as I&amp;apos;ve a-give a cup o&amp;apos; tea to many a time on a hot day, will gie I a lift into Trowbury.&amp;quot; Mrs. Parfitt had two lady&amp;apos;s maids that afternoon. Her hair was done and her bonnet set on her head so that she said she&amp;apos;d hardly ha&amp;apos; knowed herself; and off she went in her baker&amp;apos;s cart. Then the two young women, each disgraced, both lonely, fell to talking over ways and means. What they did not tell one another was the most important part of their conversation. Miss Starkey allowed Julia to think her very very greatly wronged, nothing more; while Julia hid the practical charity in her heart-the very real chanty for a woman in her position-under a gush oi sentiment. Occasionally one of them sniffed and dropped a few tears. Neither was able to suggest any promising course of action until Julia said that her old guv&amp;apos;nor in London might take her back. &amp;quot;London! London!&amp;quot; Miss Starkey took up the word, and the hope that lay in it, with all the ardour which London imposes on untravelled provincials. &amp;quot; London! &amp;quot; They would go to London. That was it. But baby? Who would take care of the baby? Mrs. Parfitt ? Miss Starkey was sure she would. Julia thought so too. She still had some money in spite of what she had lent -or given-Miss Starkey. Instead of a new dress, she had had the yellow one turned and retrimmed. The material had been good. . . . &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;re a dear, Julie!&amp;quot; But London! They rang the changes on the magic word, the first mention of which had been decisive. Damnable Dick Whittington ? After dark-they were sitting without a light-Mrs. Parfitt&amp;apos;s small toppling footsteps approached the cottage. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve a-seen him an&amp;apos; I lost me head, I did, an&amp;apos; I didn&amp;apos;t mean to, but there. . . An&amp;apos; I kissed &amp;apos;en as he were coming down the church in his lovely big blue mantle, an&amp;apos; I told &amp;apos;en as the little chap were as right as ninepence an&amp;apos; as he could come out an&amp;apos; see &amp;apos;en just the same now he is Mayor; an&amp;apos; his father, he took hold o&amp;apos; my poor arm an&amp;apos; pushed I into the wrong pew; but I did kiss &amp;apos;en an&amp;apos; I told &amp;apos;en the little dear (let I give &amp;apos;en a kiss !) was quite bonny out here an&amp;apos; as good a baby as you might find; an&amp;apos; look you what a bruise he&amp;apos;ve a-made on my poor arm-black an&amp;apos; blue-he always had a temper when he were a boy, he did!&amp;quot; She slipped off her bodice and exhibited the blue mark on her withered old arm. While that was going on, the two girls asked her if she would keep the baby with her. &amp;quot; On course I will, pretty dear ! Not having no childer o&amp;apos; me own. . . . Deary me ! Just you leave he here. I&amp;apos;ve a-nursed James Trotman, an&amp;apos; Master Allie, both on &amp;apos;em mayors, an&amp;apos; why shouldn&amp;apos;t I nurse this little precious too, for company like. The babies as I nurse be all mayors.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s the Mayor&amp;apos;s Dinner to-night,&amp;quot; said Miss Starkey, who always showed impatience when Mrs. Parfitt babbled on, and always had festivities in her mind. &amp;quot; They must be going in to it now,&amp;quot; Julia added. &amp;quot; I must go. I really must. Good-bye, dear.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t you get in their light when they&amp;apos;re coming outthat&amp;apos;s all! &amp;quot; Miss Starkey&amp;apos;s voice could be very bitterly unpleasant. The that&amp;apos;s all echoed in Julia&amp;apos;s ears as she walked back to the Emporium. It seemed to be dragging her into the company of the non-respectable. It depressed her and made her feel as if the world was off its hinges. Again the side-door of the Emporium banged behind her as if she were stir its property, still forced to sell herself for a bed, bad food, and a few dresses. That&amp;apos;s all ! And it was all. XIII In reporting the mayoral banquet, the Trowbury Guardian, with a humility and enterprise rare among local newspapers, did it&amp;apos;s best to imitate the Halfpenny Pres.s It was notably successful in the use of headlines. THE HOLY MOUNTAIN ALEXANDER TROTMAN MADE MAYOR OF HIS NATIVE TOWN (Then followed an account in pyrotechnical language of the investiture of Alec Trotman as Mayor of the ancient borough, together with photographs of himself and his relatives, and a faked reproduction, from a borrowed block, of the MountainMover standing in an inspired attitude on the summit of a precipitous Holy Mountain.) TROWBURY S MAYOR S BANQUET BRILLIANT LOCAL FUNCTION DELAINE JENKYNS, M.P. IN THE CHAIR IMPORTANT SPEECHES THE MAYORS HEALTH INTERVIEW WITH HIS DOCTOR Full copyright account &amp;quot;TROWBURY CHRONICLE &amp;quot; ENLARGED TO SIXTY COLUMNS &amp;quot;Yesterday, at noon, amid the alderman and councillors assembled in the historic council chamber, Mr. Alexander Trotman was unanimously elected Mayor of Trowbury, and invested with the heavy gold chain of office. The value of the mayoral chain is estimated at C420. In the fine old Parish Church, beneath tattered flags from Waterloo, Inkerman and Balaldava, his mayoralty received Divine Sanction. Alexander Trotman, Mayor of Trowbury! The prophet honoured in his own country ! &amp;quot;THE MAYORAL BANQUET was held in the Town Hall Assembly Rooms. A good spread, worthy of Trowbury&amp;apos;s gastronomic traditions, was provided by mine host of the Blue Boar Hotel, reinforced by a celebrated London caterer. The tipsy cake was moulded into the form of the Holy Mountain, and inlaid with the heraldic arms of Trowbury in coloured jellies. &amp;quot; The Mayor was surrounded by a representative company of aldermen, councillors, borough officials, and burgesses, and by the flower of the local nobility and gentry. &amp;quot; The Right Honourable Delaine Jenkyns, Member for the Trowbury division of Wiltshire, occupied the chair. &amp;quot; Grace before and after meat was said by the Vicar of Trowbury. &amp;quot; The Chairman first gave the toast of King and Empire, followed by that of the Prince and Princess of Wales and the Royal Family. Great and loyal enthusiasm prevailed.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;,UNAVOIDABLE ABSENTEES &amp;quot;The Chairman read a telegram from the King: &amp;quot; &amp;apos;I am commanded by his Majesty to thank the loyal and ancient borough of Trowbury.&amp;apos; &amp;quot;A telegram from Sir Pushcott Bingley, Bart., Director of the Halfpenny Press, was next read: &amp;quot; &amp;apos;E mpire watching Mountain - Mover&amp;apos;s festive banquet. Deeply regret detained in town.&amp;apos; &amp;quot; It was understood that the ex-Mayor had also received a private communication from Sir Pushcott Bingley. When the resounding applause which followed the reading of the telegram had died down, and letters of apology for unavoidable absence had been read from several noblemen and gentlemen, Mr. Ald. Clinch, the senior alderman, gave in felicitous terms the Bishop and Clergy and Ministers of all Denominations. &amp;quot; The Vicar, in replying, alluded to the strange coincidence that the evening the miracle transpired he had been preaching from the text: &amp;apos; If ye have faith even as a grain of mustard seed ye shall say to this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place, and it shall remove.&amp;apos; He regarded it as another sign of Almighty God&amp;apos;s watchfulness over His Church and over Trowbury. It spoke well for the natural pleasures of temperate eating and drinking, that the clergy and ministers of all denominations could be found at the mayoral banquet peaceably seated together. He was sorry to see how few of the well-cooked dishes the Mayor was able to partake of, and hoped it would please God to mercifully restore his health-(applause)-grant him a long, useful life -applause)-nd graciously accept his miraculous work for the good of His Holy Church. (Great applause.) &amp;quot;t REV. SNOOKS&amp;apos; PRAYER &amp;quot;The Rev. Bertram Snooks (Congregational) in responding for the other denominations, said they lived in critical times, and everything tending to promote the cause of religion in an atheistical age-(No, no)-was to be encouraged. -&amp;apos;Such, he felt, was the removal of the Holy Mountain and the heartfelt, heartening revival at the Crystal Palace, where the attendance of the Mayor, who had worked so great a miracle, even as the prophets of old, had evoked a scene of extraordinary religious enthusiasm-(applause)-and many souls were brought to repentance. He craved permission on so auspicious an occasion to offer up the following prayer: &amp;apos; 0 Almighty God, who art always with us when upon our knees we cry unto thee, vouchsafe that our beloved young Mayor shall receive Thy blessing, and shall evermore perform miracles to the glory of Thine elect, to the furtherance of true religion wheresoever found, and to the confusion of the stiff-necked and of sinners, in Thy Holy Name, Amen.&amp;apos; &amp;quot; At this stage of the festivities the Vicar pleaded attendance at a bed of sickness, and left. &amp;quot; The toast of the Army, Navy and other Imperial and Territorial Forces was given amidst intense enthusiasm, one of the councillors remarking that if they could not have work for all, undoubtedly a strong Navy was the next best thing. (Applause.) (To be continued)</FullText></Record>