<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2444027</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127132307</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>THE VAN ROON.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Nov 1922</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19221101</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Review</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Austin</FirstName><PersonName>Austin Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Austin</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>477</StartPage><EndPage>477</EndPage><Pagination>477-477</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2444027/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>THE VAN ROON. By J. C. SNMTH. Appleton. 7s. 6d. net. VERY few blood and thunder merchants give us as much suspense and excitement as Mr. J. C. Snaith gets out of the adventures of a lost and found old master. Indeed, when the priceless little picture is safely housed in the keeping of the National Gallery, and the young couple, who have been intimately concerned in its discovery and preservation, have leisure and opportunity to go on with their love affair; when the drama of pursuit and frustration reaches the transformation scene with only Harlequin and Columbine to watch, one longs for the Clown, Pantaloon and Policeman to give verve to the soft and golden scene. The story, which opens in the shop of &amp;quot; S. Gedge, Antiques,&amp;quot; in a back street off the Strand, is so faultless in verisimilitude, so full of surprise and inevitability combined, S. Gedge and the tricky dealers are so true to life, and &amp;quot; June &amp;quot; and &amp;quot; William &amp;quot; so well contrasted in their characters for the purposes of intrigue, that one almost grudges them the space for mere opulence and lovemaking. Still, Mr. Snaith is good at an idyll also; perhaps he knows his readers best.</FullText></Record>