<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2446198</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127132248</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>A Goodly Heritage and Others</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Jul 1934</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19340701</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Review</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Chilton</LastName><MiddleName>Carroll</MiddleName><FirstName>Eleanor</FirstName><PersonName>Eleanor Carroll Chilton</PersonName><OriginalForm>CHILTON, ELEANOR CARROLL</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Jerrold, Douglas, 1893</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>113</StartPage><EndPage>115</EndPage><Pagination>113-115</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2446198/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>A Goodly Heritage and Others Nmws Fox HAi. By GzoRGa DuIEmEL. (Dent 7a. 6d.) A GOODLY HERTAGE. By MARY ELEN CHAS. (CosbL-. 7s. 6d.) DulY TE FOUL FEDw. By JoHN Courn. (Macmiian. 7s. 6d.) As IT WAS IN TE BEGINNING. By G. E. TREVELYAN. (Secke. 7s. 6d.) Thu Cmmmm TRIUMPHANT. By PHYLS PAUL. (Secker. 7P. 6d.) IT must be contered that often the reviewer mi the point of a novel, but it is always arguable that the burden of proof rests with the author, and that if he intends his story to contain a criticism or even a comment on life, he has only himself to blame if his intention is not clear to the reader. Each of these five books tells the story of an individual, showing with some detail the influences in childhood. and adolescence which shaped that individual&amp;apos;s life and coloured his mind. &amp;quot; News from Havre &amp;quot; is the first volume of a series and carries the small boy who tells the story only as far as adolescence, but the other four narratives all convey their protagonists to some full stop which in terms of acr is pposed to be definitive, if not final. The inteting aspect of this comparson is that the only one of these five books in which the building of character as such is taken into account, and therefore the only one attempting a criticism of life, is autobiography, rather than fiction. &amp;quot; A Goodly Heritage &amp;quot; is the story of a community as well as the story of a girl who was born and brought up in that community. Miss Chase justifies her uneventful autobiography by diming that the world into which she and many others were born some fifty years ago has ceased to exist, and that her own home-Blue Hill Bay on the rigorous coast of Maine-was both unique and typical and so deserving of a record for posterity. In all these claims she is right, but her book needs no justification. It is absorbing from beginning to end, and will read to all young people like the rarest kind of fiction. Blue Hill Bay was settled by a few restless colonists from ausetts It grew into a self-contained little community of non-Conformists, many of them sea-going folk during the great days of the clipper ship trade-all of them intering, as ambitious and inventive people are likely to be when they are cut off from all organized amusements, and prevented by a strict moral code from dissipating their e ies in frivolous ways. Such a way of life builds character, encourages personaity, and produces eccentrics; and Miss Chase&amp;apos;s story is full of rich variations on the theme of human nature. Her childhood, with its religious training, its discipline of &amp;quot; chores &amp;quot; and a high standard of scrip, was the embodiment of everything to which modern education is opposed; but only a rabid theorist would deny the evidence, and the author&amp;apos;s assertion, that hers was, indeed, a good and a happy heritage. Not good at all, and far from happy, are the back ds and inies given their creatures by the other four authors. Of &amp;quot;News from Havre,&amp;quot; since it is only the beginning of a long story, little can be said except that it is extremely amusing and at the same time rather haown. The amsment derives chiefly from that very Dicksan creation, M. Pasquier, the father of the hero, and the central figure of the story. The whole volume deals with the tribulations of the Pasquier family while awaiting the realization in hard cash of a legacy. The reader shares their suspense, as years pass with no good news from the lawyer at Havre, but sees at the same time that the suspense must end in disappointment, just as every reader knows that nothing will ever turn up for Mr. Micawber. The book is eminently worth reading for the sake of this one admirable character. &amp;quot; Defy the Foul Fiend &amp;quot; is an intereing novel, disappointing in that every pae promises more than the next reveals. It deals with the misadventures of Willoughby Corbo, legitimate son of Lord Ollebeare; of how he found love, lost it through perversity found it again, and then lost it because he had meanwhile made for himself a way of life which meant more to him than happi . The quality which makes it disappointing is that of unreality, and yet this quality aises from the quality of Mr. Collier&amp;apos;s mind and style, both of which are strongly iscent of Meredith in their bias toward the fantastic, their acute analysis and eloquence, their satirical vigour. Mr. Collier will probably write an important novel when he has organized his gifts around some philosophy. &amp;quot;Defy the Foul Fiend &amp;quot; is only comparatively good. Comparatively good seems a great deal, however, as one turns to &amp;quot; As It was in the Beginning &amp;quot; and &amp;quot; The Children Triumphant.&amp;quot; Miss Trevelyan&amp;apos;s only claim to our gratitude-a claim staked out last year in &amp;quot;Hot-House&amp;quot;-s that reading her has the novel effect of maling one satisfied with human nature as it is, and glad that reality, poor as it is, is a lovely and wholesome thing compared to Mis Trevelyan&amp;apos;s imaginary world. The publishers hail this book as an &amp;quot; experiment &amp;quot;-but in reality it is a pretentious excursion into triviality, and reads like an unkind parody on some of Miss May Sinclairs early work. There is nothing whatever one can say about &amp;quot; The Children Triumphant&amp;quot; except that it is so completely lacking in even the ilsion of reality that one can hardly remember to deplore the honest work and intelligence that obviously went into it. ELEANOR CARROLL CHILTON</FullText></Record>