<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2446576</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131111</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>The Wife of Altamont</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Feb 1910</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19100201</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Hunt</LastName><FirstName>Violet</FirstName><PersonName>Violet Hunt</PersonName><OriginalForm>Hunt, Violet</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Austin</FirstName><PersonName>Austin Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Austin</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>456</StartPage><EndPage>528</EndPage><Pagination>456-528</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2446576/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>The Wife of Altamont By Violet Hunt xv MRS. ALTAMONT sat in the great red omnibus going back to Town, and wondered what she had done ? She was on her way home at least; she gloated on the thought of her last quiet evening in her own quiet house. For had she let loose the Furies ? Had she done something, mad, foolish, and Scriptural, a Christian act of the extremest foolishest charity. She felt now as one who has received extreme unction, somewhat bemused and yet equable. She was like those persons who give seldom to offertories or subscription lists, but when they do give, give copiously. She seemed as if she had just attended a long and unwieldy church service-to have once for all penetrated to the very core of philanthropy, and she was tired to death ! Yet she could have done no less. It had been, now that she came to disentangle motives, the sight of Little Katie which had so affected her and moved her to benevolence; Little Katie, who couldn&amp;apos;t grow, who wasn&amp;apos;t going to live, she felt sure of it, not even though they should begin feeding her well from now! . . . Well, to carry on the religious metaphor, she had had her call, and she had responded to it. She was glad, she was changed, invigorated, uplifted, not with pride, but the pleasure of Doing, for once. This was Living indeed-squalid, utilitarian, grotesque, but still, Living. She began to plan to make up her old winter jacket for Ada Cox, and there were some of Wilfrid&amp;apos;s baby clothes that his mother had put aside long ago which might do for the children ! In her mind, the scissors flew hither and thither-she heard the tearing of stuff. . .. Later on, when the tram turned her out in Victoria Street, and the region grew less slummy, she began to think of Ernest Veere, and wonder if he would be pleased with her or no. But Veere was not pleased, he thought the arrangement absurd. He used the time-honoured fetish word, quixotic, in this connection, and was vexed with Betsey for disdaining his proffered pecuniary assistance for Mrs. Cox. She tried to explain to him how she felt about it. In vain. His utilitarian negation of the picturesque as a factor in human affairs made him blind and deaf to her reasons for her action, and they were, though she did not realise it, the purely sentimental. Mrs. Altamont could not deny that Ada Cox, so far, proved to be no cook. That was Ernest Veere&amp;apos;s opportunity, eagerly grasped at. He wasn&amp;apos;t going to have his beautiful friend starve and grow thin, at all events ! He insisted on taking her out to dinner nearly every night during the month that elapsed before Altamont mended and was able to be brought to the court to stand his trial. It was over at last. Two days of squalid recapitulation of horrid details, a hint of female influence, quashed at once, and then the verdict. At the Vienna Cafe, at the top of Leicester Square, where Veere brought Betsey to dine two days after the trial, she might, while she waited for him, read the questions of counsel, the judge&amp;apos;s summing up, and the verdict. Furthermore, poor Miss Altamont&amp;apos;s disgraceful history in full, the sin of Sir Joris&amp;apos;s youth lightly adumbrated. It was all there, in The Sweep. As for the bare facts of the case, she had no need to read them up, for Inspector Whortlebury made it his business to keep her informed. She had not been asked to appear, the Veeres&amp;apos; solicitor, through Rose&amp;apos;s intercession, had made that all easy for her. She was supposed naturally to be ill. That was why she met him at obscure places like this. When he had been too busy to motor out to fetch her, she got there first and waited for him. On the white tablecloth beside her lay one or two of the daily papers, mounted on wooden frames for reading, like horn books of old. The large catchy headlines of The Sweep caught her eye. She was able to read there &amp;quot; The Convict Altamont,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot; The Condemned Man&amp;apos;s Health,&amp;quot; while &amp;quot;Altamont in Prison &amp;quot; stared at her from another sheet. She could not have asked the waiter to remove them if she had been inclined, for it might have attracted attention to herself, and revealed her identity, which she had taken the greatest pains, short of positively cloistering herself, to conceal. Besides, she did not care much, she had grown used to the impact of the shocks dealt her by sensation-mongers on placards and posters. There was, indeed, only one form of headline that she had, from the peculiarities of the case, been spared, &amp;quot; Strange Development.&amp;quot; Wilfrid&amp;apos;s counsel naturally was debarred from that line of defence-there could be nothing new. His solicitor, paid for by Rose Veere, had she but known, was trying to bring him off on the plea of insanity; his wife had been questioned, but she had not chosen to contribute anything to the theory. No, Wilfrid, to her knowledge, had never been strange in manner, or done anything particularly perverse until now. She knew of nothing, and the removal of the other witness, his mother, by death, had left her the sole depository of the previous facts of his life. Ada Cox had not even been called. The waiter removed the papers; a client wanted them. A man behind her was even then hanging up his hat, he came round the corner of the coat-stand to their table ! It was Veere, who smiled, as he always did when he saw Betsey again. The waiter hovered over him as he sat down: &amp;quot; Two dozen oysters. Poulet Paprika. Pommes Sautees. Omelette au Rhum-or will you have Kirsch? For two. And bring the wine card, please.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; How are you ? &amp;quot; he addressed himself to her. &amp;quot;Why wouldn&amp;apos;t you come out with me yesterday ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Because of Ada.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Your cook ? &amp;quot; scornfully. &amp;quot; Yes,&amp;quot; she smiled, &amp;quot; and a bad one at that.&amp;quot; He interrupted her. &amp;quot; One minute! Champagne?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, not to-day.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh yes, do you good. I want some.&amp;quot; He pointed to a number on the card. &amp;quot; A pint of that.&amp;quot; The man departed. &amp;quot;Now ! Do you mean that Ada took it conventionally ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, the morning of the day on which you get the news of your husband&amp;apos;s condemnation-! He was my husband, of course, but she&amp;apos;s the one that feels it. She couldn&amp;apos;t, really, do a single thing all day-headache sat in a corner with her apron over her head, woman-of-the-people fashion. I had to cook the dinner, and mind&amp;apos;the children. Little Wilfrid, of course, chose the occasion to be more uproarious than usual. It took me all my time to keep him out of the copper. Georgie had come in to do some washing for me. Domestic detail ! So you see, it would not have been possible for me to come, even if I had wanted!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Didn&amp;apos;t you want ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I think not. I&amp;apos;m not a monster. It would have seemed too callous. But I don&amp;apos;t pretend that I want him to get off. Ada, of course, does.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I suppose he was fairly kind to her ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He doesn&amp;apos;t seem to have knocked her about. She&amp;apos;s got no marks, anyway.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You have?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, the usual scar. It was my own fault. You see I&amp;apos;ve got a tongue, unfortunately, and I let Wilfrid have it pretty hot sometimes. Ada noticed the cut the other day.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And did you tell her who gave it you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;No. Poor old Ginger gets the credit of it. But I&amp;apos;m not sure she believed me. She&amp;apos;s quiet, but she&amp;apos;s got a lot of elementary wisdom and a sort of doggy instinct that goes right, sometimes. She&amp;apos;s rather jealous of me still. She is always trying to find out if Wilfrid and I got on together, and when I do my best to let her understand that she was his first and only love, she resents it on his account, and implies that I neglected my wifely duties.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You did, thank God! And sent him to her, an inferior article. She or her like was his true mate. They were probably very happy together. If she had had enough money to run the show, he would have stayed at home, lived on her, and let my uncle alone. She knew how to manage him. Why wasn&amp;apos;t she tied to him instead of you ? That&amp;apos;s the irony-the pity of it Why weren&amp;apos;t you like her-and she Altamont&amp;apos;s widow?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You wouldn&amp;apos;t have cared to be my friend then.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; On the contrary, I&amp;apos;d have married you-if you&amp;apos;d only been his mistress, instead of his wife. That&amp;apos;s another thing, and fatal ! &amp;quot; It was not Betsey&amp;apos;s way to check and annoy him in the full flush of his charming arrogance and egoism by representing to him the possibility of a difference of opinion. She let him take it for granted that she would have accepted his offer if he had seen his way to make it. The thing could never be put to the test, as he said. And she had plans. She wanted to keep him in a good humour. Wilfrid was as good as dead. The plea of insanity which was his only line of defence had failed. His wife, and only his wife, could have substantiated it; and she had refused, tacitly, to lie to save his life. She showed Veere the trend of her thoughts by her question. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t you think that if the relations of a criminal help the lawyers to trump up the plea of insanity and invent all sorts of strange, mad things that he has done in the past to save him, that, when they succeed in proving it, they should be liable to prosecution ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; How so ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Because if they do get him off that way they establish the fact that they were all the time harbouring a madman, and should have had him examined and shut up before he did any mischief ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I certainly agree with you. It&amp;apos;s a good point. Many more people would get hanged, though, and Broadmoor would be emptied. Well, where shall we go to-night ? There&amp;apos;s a splendid play at the Shaftesbury- Oh, I forgot! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, let&amp;apos;s go to it, I have no feeling of that kind.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; All right. I&amp;apos;ll go and pay.&amp;quot; She dropped an enormous veil with large velvety spots over the features she was interested in hiding from the British Public. It would interfere with her plans should her face become public property. Neither was it good for Veere to be seen too much about with her. They went to the pit of the theatre. Since her husband&amp;apos;s definite condemnation, Betsey, confronted with the greatest issues of her life, looked them full in the face, and formed a distinct plan of action. She meant to tell this young man, who had elected himself to be her friend, and beg for his co-operation. He was the dearest boy in the world, the cleverest, the most generous, a young man with a future, though he was consecrating the present to her, the wife of a condemned murderer, and a woman older than himself. But not for long now. To-night after the play and supper he would motor her back and she would tell him what she meant to do. She had no fear of him. She dreaded no cheaply audacious enterprises on his part. Yet she knew well enough that he admired her deeply. She would not have cared to be with him otherwise, she could not have confided so thoroughly in a man who did not desire her as a woman. He probably was not entirely proof against the subtle whet of sex, though no man could show himself less prone to the vulgar trivialities of flirtation. Against the big gun and forceful batteries of passion, her want of any deep feeling for him made her safe, and he would use no other. A queer, deep, concentrated nature his, though outwardly easy-going, negligent and trivial. So she thought of him in the comparatively brief moments devoted by her to the consideration of his character. She was, for the moment, full of sidelights on Thi Lyons Mail. &amp;quot; This is an old-fashioned play ! Murderers don&amp;apos;t seem to get found out now like that. There&amp;apos;s no poetic justice in real life.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Because miscreants have learned not to give themselves away. They avoid committing that one little bit of idiocy that makes the whole world kin and themselves discovered. They don&amp;apos;t neglect the smaller precautions-I suppose it&amp;apos;s the result of the capital Board School training we give them ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes; we teach them to criticise the Bible and to join their flats, and then when they are old they do not depart from it. Do you think Wilfrid meant to shoot your uncle ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He took his pistols out with him, didn&amp;apos;t he ? Were they new ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Had them years! I missed them, and at first it worried me, and I didn&amp;apos;t tell Miss Altamont. Then I made up my mind that he had taken them out of bravado, he meant to threatena man armed is always more persuasive. I&amp;apos;ll tell you what I think. No one heard exactly what they said to each other, but my idea is, he begged for money.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You said so in court.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And threatened to blow out his own brains if he was refused. Sir Joris was a brave man; I expect he first shrugged his shoulders and suggested a strait-waistcoat. That would infuriate Wilfrid and suggest to him a change of plan. It drove him mad, in fact, and he pulled the trigger at Sir Joris. The shooting at himself after was pure remorse.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; My dear friend, aren&amp;apos;t you rather morbid ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, the opposite of morbid-healthy. Death isn&amp;apos;t so terrible to perfectly well people.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; A good digestion, in fact, can deal even with a horrible murder and male it into chyle.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, I do think it&amp;apos;s physical weakness makes one shrink so from the idea of death-one&amp;apos;s own or other people&amp;apos;s. If a cook wasn&amp;apos;t healthy she&amp;apos;d loathe-or enjoy too much-drawing a turkey. Animals can go on feeding, cropping grass beside a comrade that&amp;apos;s dying under the most disgusting conditions-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve seen Dobrie once, staying at my uncle&amp;apos;s, jab at a hunted otter with her parasol and spoil its nose-add to its last grunting agonies ! I&amp;apos;ve seen her. Yes, I&amp;apos;ve seen her.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; She has no imagination, I suppose ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No more have I, but I couldn&amp;apos;t stand that. I didn&amp;apos;t say any more to the girl all day. . . . She&amp;apos;s up there, now, in a box! Do you see ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; How like you to keep it dark all through the first act! Has she seen us-you, I mean ? &amp;quot; she whispered excitedly. &amp;quot; I shouldn&amp;apos;t think so. She would never look for me here in the pit!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, no, of course not!&amp;quot; she said sarcastically. After a moment&amp;apos;s deliberation-&amp;quot; I see her quite well. She&amp;apos;s not so pretty as I thought. She&amp;apos;s steely.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Say aluminium ! Rather good!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m disappointed in her, any way. She&amp;apos;s the sort of woman I&amp;apos;d have expected to be soft, and sweet-born in the purple as she is ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; If the purple isn&amp;apos;t lined with ermine it&amp;apos;s no good. The Angernounes are hard up ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What do you call hard up?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Paupers at two thousand a year. But old Angernoune&amp;apos;s got a big estate to keep up.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why should he keep it up Let him cut it up into small holdings.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And the ancestral mansion, that James the Fourth slept in on the night before Flodden &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Make it into a museum! &amp;quot; XVI &amp;quot;Oh, do give me something to give that poor child!&amp;quot; she begged as they came out of the theatre, and were at once beset by a shivering specimen of organised London misery. &amp;quot; I will not. You should never give in the street.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh; but it&amp;apos;s genuine. Look! He doesn&amp;apos;t even beg.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Best draw of all! Do come on, dear.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; All right ! &amp;quot; She hastily slipped her fine scarf that he had given her from her neck and wound it deftly round that of the boy, flashing back her pretty defiance of the questioner of the morality of charity. He only smiled. &amp;quot; It won&amp;apos;t matter. I&amp;apos;m not a bit hurt. Though why you should disregard me on the subject-I was my uncle&amp;apos;s almoner !-I dispensed his charities ! &amp;quot; Crossing the strip of pavement on their way to the motor they passed the series of wet posters laid in the mud with stones apposed at all four corners to keep them down. The chief item of news was &amp;quot; Altamont&amp;apos;s Letter to His Wife! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes,&amp;quot; said she, &amp;quot; that came just before I started. Ada&amp;apos;s got it now, wearing it next her poor heart.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; How could you let her ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; She wanted it. She didn&amp;apos;t see through it. It&amp;apos;s just conventional-dictated by the prison chaplain, I should think.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, you are a queer mixture ! &amp;quot; he said, regarding her half kindly, half cynically. They were rolling along now smoothly towards Wimbledon. &amp;quot;How am I? &amp;quot; - &amp;quot; Full of misplaced charity and whimsical hardnesses.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Look here! &amp;quot; She turned to him solemnly. &amp;quot; You like me to be natural, you encourage me to talk quite freely to you. But if I had to fag to sham sensibility, I tell you, I wouldn&amp;apos;t be with you in these days at all ! I would refuse myself to you as I do to the others, the Wimbledonians. They all come bothering -one after another, and I hear that they are all down on me now because I go about with you and won&amp;apos;t let them see how I am bearing it. I am bearing it too well, I know. It&amp;apos;s indecent. I&amp;apos;m supposed to be broken with shame and grief. But why should I be bowed down with shame for the act of a man in whom I have no part, with whose doings I am not in any way connected, just because I once was fool enough to go and have my union with him blessed ? It wasn&amp;apos;t even a real union-as I see it. I can&amp;apos;t possibly feel sorry because I am going to be freed from such vermin! That&amp;apos;s how I think of him-perhaps you didn&amp;apos;t know it ? Ada is properly broken-hearted--she is my Vicar. She works it off for me, and you I let see me as I am, and how I feel-not conventionally!&amp;quot; She flung herself back in the car, spent with her tirade. &amp;quot; I often wonder what you really do feel?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, man, can&amp;apos;t you see ? As Christian did when-the burden rolled off his back! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yet you married him-for love, I suppose?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; For love of his mother, I think. I don&amp;apos;t fall in love easily, for all I am so friendly to men! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s perhaps why ? Cuore di carciofolo!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s that ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Artichoke heart-peels off in flakes-don&amp;apos;t you know? Well, you are very charming and life is very complicated. I love to hear what you make of it all. I can make nothing of it except that anything so adorably natural and breezy mat be right ! In your heart, Betsey, it is always spring-cleaningone smells the smell of antiseptic soap, and knows the windows are open ! One touch of spite or cattiness, taken in conjunction with your eyes, and you&amp;apos;d be a minx, any one can see that ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;m not a minx! &amp;quot; said she gravely. &amp;quot; Never was. And now- Say a nun, walled up in a cell, buried alive, paralysed! But no more-no more! I see daylight-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Through a prison window! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I am not going to let myself think of that,&amp;quot; she said brutally. &amp;quot;I only know I shall be a widow on the twentieth, and thenI&amp;apos;ll do things.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You can&amp;apos;t do so very much. He has spoiled your chances for you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, not quite! I won&amp;apos;t let him. I mean to try to begin again. That&amp;apos;s why I have been so careful to keep my face out of the papers. No one out of Perton-the great public, I mean-knows what Mrs. Altamont is like. Can&amp;apos;t I go to a new country and begin afresh?&amp;quot; She seized his hand. &amp;quot;Ernest, can&amp;apos;t I ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Can&amp;apos;t you? Yes, why not? I suppose you can if you care to ! &amp;quot; He was suddenly cast down. She was too eager about her plans to notice it, but went on&amp;quot; Of course I care. I am determined to pull it off.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; rou can pull off anything if you have a mind. Go to America, marry again, even-&amp;quot; He laughed harshly. &amp;quot; I had thought of that,&amp;quot; she said seriously. He started. &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s what I mean. I had rather be married than not, and to a good man this time. I don&amp;apos;t absolutely hate men, as you know! &amp;quot; she smiled. &amp;quot; Now, listen. I should start with a sort of what do you call it-a nom de guerre.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; A nom de Saturday to Monday, I suppose!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Are you being quite nice ? I mean, he wouldn&amp;apos;t know who I was till we got to know each other and then, of course, I&amp;apos;d tell him the truth about myself. Out there, on another continent, it wouldn&amp;apos;t sound so bad ? I should start quite fair, and penniless, for I&amp;apos;ll leave the lease of the house and a hundred a year to Ada.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And how do you mean to get to America?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Through you, of course. I should ask you to give me my passage as a parting gift. I wouldn&amp;apos;t be expensive, for I shouldn&amp;apos;t want a return ticket, you know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And supposing I refused ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You wouldn&amp;apos;t. Why should you You&amp;apos;re rich-and if you weren&amp;apos;t, I could always pay you back.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; When you got the man! &amp;quot; He hesitated, ashamed. &amp;quot; No, Betsey, poverty isn&amp;apos;t the reason why I should refuse to frank you across. I certainly should refuse &amp;quot;To help me - &amp;quot; &amp;quot;To help you to leave me. No. I had hoped-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;What ? &amp;quot; she asked sharply. &amp;quot;That you would stay with me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Marry you, do you mean ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;How could I The wife of my uncle&amp;apos;s murderer! It would ruin me! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; It would. I shouldn&amp;apos;t think of it. Neither would I allow you to ruin me!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You mean that there&amp;apos;s nothing to ruin. That I&amp;apos;m done for already, because of Wilfrid ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t see what&amp;apos;s left for you but the protection and care of some decent man, frankly, as the world goes. The widow of a criminal-.--&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t see why because I have been the wife of one beast that I should sink into becoming the mistress of another ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; But that&amp;apos;s the long and the short of it, I&amp;apos;m afraid,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;I may be wrong-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Of course you&amp;apos;re wrong. And another thing-you don&amp;apos;t love me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I believe I do. Honestly. I began to be quite sure when you talked of going to America!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That was just temper.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, Betsey, I assure you. You have wound yourself round my heart in these days-I am getting to feel that I cannot do without you. I can&amp;apos;t bear to think of letting go your hand, or having to hold it across continents. That&amp;apos;s why I got so sulky when you spoke of leaving Europe. All this, I know, can&amp;apos;t go on for ever-our little jaunts-our good times together; but something might have been arranged, not necessarily derogatory to you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I should have liked that still less,&amp;quot; said she frankly. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t you see, I want to launch my poor little boat out into the full stream of life again, not to get stuck in a wretched back-water. You don&amp;apos;t understand me a bit.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; On the contrary, Betsey, I do. I appreciate you as no one else ever did. I appreciate you so much I feel that I can&amp;apos;t bear to part with so much excellence. Curse that man-your husband! Why couldn&amp;apos;t he have kept quiet! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then I shouldn&amp;apos;t have been a widow at all.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, simply committed suicide, then-ended his useless life without getting mixed up with my family. Betsey, I&amp;apos;ve never wanted anything as much as I&amp;apos;ve wanted this in my whole life.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s not saying so very much if you pretend you love me. But I know all the time that you only want to keep a soothing companion by you for the present, while intending by-and-by to marry Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e and consolidate your race.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I had thought of that,&amp;quot; he said simply. &amp;quot; It was a fine plan. But it may never come off. Meantime, I am utterly upset and miserable at what you have told me of your arrangements. Will you give me a kiss ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Certainly,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; You have been very good.&amp;quot; She held her soft cool cheek to him, and a loosened bow of her hair fell over his forehead. . . . He breathed heavily, and touched her hair, like a blind man feeling his way. &amp;quot; I shall never kiss Dobree like that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t marry her then. That&amp;apos;s my advice to you. Take it. It&amp;apos;s good. Here we are at my diggings. Good-bye. You&amp;apos;re the nicest man I&amp;apos;ve ever met-so far-but you&amp;apos;re younger than me, remember, and I&amp;apos;m quite young still.&amp;quot; She moved to get out. He put his hand on the door. &amp;quot; Betsey, if I could marry you, you&amp;apos;d stay &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I believe I would. I&amp;apos;m very fond of you. And I am so keen now on respectability and above-boardness. Marriage with you would be that-perfectly all right. I&amp;apos;m so sick of grovelling here in the suburbs, hiding and pottering and wasting my life on church bazaars and dress talk and ugly nothings. I feel as if I must get out of it, somehow, get into the light, if I can. Marrying you would give me that, wouldn&amp;apos;t it ? But-the other thing you proposed would mean going back into the dusk and the gloom, or rather, staying there! You&amp;apos;d hide me, and I want to be produced.&amp;quot; Veere was silent. The moon-rays broke faintly through the glass panel of the car. The chauffeur&amp;apos;s back as he sat there, impassible, waiting, was a solid screen of discretion.. She laid her hand on his shoulder. &amp;quot; Dear, nice boy, don&amp;apos;t be angry with me &amp;quot; What for ? &amp;quot; he muttered. &amp;quot; For being so set up, for presuming to want to make my own life my way, not yours-having the cheek to refuse you ! Don&amp;apos;t visit it on me. Come and take me out again. See me through this. I am all alone, and it&amp;apos;s rather awful, although I talk big. Ada&amp;apos;s not company. The others avoid me, I&amp;apos;ve grown to look to you for-such a lot of things. Don&amp;apos;t fail me. . . . Let me be myself. . . . I don&amp;apos;t love you, not even as much as I thought I did. I knew it when you kissed me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Ah, but &amp;quot; He came out of his sullen fit, caught her to him, strained her close, murmured soft things to her, called up all the resources and furiously stoked the fires of potential passion. It was a moment that could not last without real emotion to back it. He released her, and her eyes, that had been closed and flattened in the vast fur collar of his coat, opened again on to the moonlit panes, and the rain-pools, like flakes of silver flashing in the roadway in front.... &amp;quot; You see there&amp;apos;s no doubt about my loving you! &amp;quot; he said, as calm, smiling, gently breathing, exhibiting only the faintest signs of discomposure she came out of his arms. &amp;quot; But what about me ?&amp;quot; she just breathed, sadly, getting out of the car. XVII Lady Dobrie De Saye owned a little flat in town, the rent of which was paid by her godparent, the Duke of Lax, and lived in it with the slavish little companion that her mother chose for her. This was the condition of her freedom. The earl her father lived at Low Water, far away in the North of England. His dull, but worthy, punctilious and psalm-singing milieu was intolerable to his high-spirited daughter, who had once threatened to run away with her brother&amp;apos;s tutor, unless she were permitted to live her own life. The permission was given. She lived it now conveniently-with her family&amp;apos;s forced aid and help. The ancestral oaks of Angernoune were gradually being carted away to pay for her keep. Lady Angernoune&amp;apos;s toilette was sacrificed to her fancies. There was not a numbered edition de luxt she didn&amp;apos;t order or a Paris model off the nail when she had a mind thereto. Lady Angernoune in her remote northern fastness dressed worse than the housekeeper, who showed the state-rooms, to pay the bill for it, and to supplement her daughter&amp;apos;s exiguous allowance. Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s account was always overdrawn. The impoverished parent birds yearned that she should marry, but not a tutor. Lord and Lady Angernoune fondly imagined that this result would be attained, if, taking her strong character into account, they allowed the young lady to compass her destiny herself. Dobree&amp;apos;s head was screwed on the right commercial way, she used her title wisely enough, and at home they had heard of Ernest Rose Veere. The rich Duke of Lax, who wrote books to prove that his vast estates in Somersetshire brought him in nothing, made his niece, yearly, a handsome present of money, which she usually anticipated, and lent her his box at the Opera pretty often in the season; but that was all he could do for her, she knew. He meant to leave her nothing to speak of, for he had too many sons. Dobrie was only four and twenty, a slight, tall stripling of a girl, with smooth, quite ordinary hair, and grey inexpressive eyes. Her length of limb would have fitted her for the saddle, but her father could not afford to mount her. She swam, fenced and danced in London, but at other people&amp;apos;s expense. She used her position for all it was worth, her title procured her her creature comforts and helped her to &amp;quot; nobble &amp;quot; even bourgeois celebrities, for whom she had a mysterious unracial weakness. Those persons of her own station whom she neglected were of opinion that poor Dobree was running rather to seed in London. She would pitch her set so many pegs lower than that to which her rank and name entitled her. The reason was this, that she loved to bask in the atmosphere of flattery, as it were a savoury joss-stick burned in the room she occupied. Adulation, no matter from what motive it sprang, was the breath of life to her, and she was too simple to realise that she could be of any use to people, and that the oldest name in England had its magic apart from the social merits of its possessor. With tradespeople it practically sent up her bills, in society it made her a persona grata, so that she need not patronise the butcher or the fishmonger who overcharged her, but could dine and lunch out free every night of her life. Presuming on her Norman blood, she did as she liked, and went where she liked. She trifled,.with morbidity, she paltered with perversity, she entertained pathetic blackmailers and amiable adventuresses, and remained what she was, intrinsically, a simple, egotistic, sweet-natured English girl. Ethel Taylor, her unpaid companion, was respectable, Scotch, a poor relation, and knew Dobree through and through. She was over fifty, a feather bed, a mat, boiled rag, all of which engaging appellations her young charge called her in turn, nagging the rag, trampling on the mat, and hugging the feather bed, as the fancy took her. The real society chaperon of Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e was the tall, faded, handsome Lady Maude Erskine-Robertson, who had passed through the Divorce Court, but through the right lobby, the one on the side of the angels, so she said. It must have been so; it was she who had divorced him, or the Angernounes would never have allowed their girl to go out with her. The two went everywhere together, and left &amp;quot; Effel &amp;quot; at home with the dogs and the cat. Effel patiently combed the cat and tied a blue bow in the dog&amp;apos;s fringe and sat the evening through, knitting things for Dobr&amp;amp;e. She was not allowed to knit when Dobr&amp;amp;e was at home, &amp;quot;It looks so smug and companiony ! &amp;quot; When there was a dinner-party in the flat, Effel went to spend the evening with her sister, who was nurse-housekeeper to old Lord Druid at GarsinRton House. Lady Dobree knew this sister well and went to see her sometimes, to please Effel. She liked to be kind and please people when it was fairly convenient. But Lady Maude was always commandeered to chaperon Lady Dobrie on official social occasions. She was nothing loath. She drifted in one evening of a dinner-party five minutes before the prescribed hour of arrival, so as to discharge her duties. The front of her gown was a marvel of alternate reticence and revelation. She was never dicoUeti; it might have been better, from the point of view of obvious morality, if she had been. She managed, as Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e said, to be &amp;quot; highly indecent &amp;quot; instead ! She had reduced her weight to less than seven stone to suit the exiguities of her banana-skin, and could scarcely sit down in her suggestive costume. There was time for a few questions. &amp;quot; Who&amp;apos;s your sixth ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I asked Ernest Veere over the telephone.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Isn&amp;apos;t it rather soon ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, he&amp;apos;s accepted. It&amp;apos;s only a small dinner, and dear old Ernest is very modern.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, very ! &amp;quot; Lady Maude yawned. &amp;quot; Do you know that he&amp;apos;s spending his whole time, when he&amp;apos;s not giving evidence or paying estate duty, with the wife of the man who murdered his uncle ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I like that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;ru would.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I felt at once, when I met him-where did I meet him ?that he would amuse me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And marry you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;That too, perhaps! Don&amp;apos;t be nasty, Maude. It&amp;apos;s the best thing I can do, on the whole. I accepted the situation practically, when I went and stayed at the Veere place in Surrey, and had Ernest up at Low Water. Oh dear ! When once I get over&amp;apos; his-what shall I call it-his expectednesshe&amp;apos;s not a bit artistic or cultured, is he-? &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s pure commercial. That&amp;apos;s it. His manners are a little too good and too much of them- &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s when he talks to us. We&amp;apos;re not his world, Maude, and he knows it. I wonder, don&amp;apos;t you, how he talks to this Mrs. Altamont ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Fried fish and onions style! Very pally! Says whatever comes into his head, or nothing at all, as the case may be. Long silences. I don&amp;apos;t suppose he rattles on to amuse her, he keeps that for society, puts it on the moment the man at the door takes his coat and passes him in to us. We don&amp;apos;t know where these flies, that amuse us, have been buzzing. I often think we deserve to be strangled in our beds by the people we pick up in the street. We never think of asking for references ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; We don&amp;apos;t ask for bread because we know we&amp;apos;ll be given a stone ! He could fake them so easily. That&amp;apos;s worse, to get caught by an adventurer,&amp;quot; said Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e. &amp;quot;Now I know Ernest&amp;apos;s trade. The Veeres were originally Dutch, I know that. The old man had an estate at Veere in Holland.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Probably bought it cheap to motiver the name. Trade has all sorts of dodges. . . . Oh, and let me tell you not to talk to Lee-Brice about his last book, for it&amp;apos;s a sore subject. It&amp;apos;s been forbidden and the publisher has undertaken to burn all the existing copies.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What, The Red Corpuscles ! Oh, how I do sympathise!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; With the Vigilance people ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, with him. I think it&amp;apos;s a wonderful book ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; If you young girls didn&amp;apos;t take to books like that so furiously,&amp;quot; said Lady Maude, &amp;quot; there&amp;apos;d be a chance of their being allowed to stay on the counter for the people they really do good to.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s what he says-that he doesn&amp;apos;t write for the young girl.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But I&amp;apos;m the proverbial duck&amp;apos;s back, Maude. Somehow, I&amp;apos;ve no use for indecency ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I believe it- There&amp;apos;s some one-I hear the bell!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Rose Veere. I know his voice. I mean to rag him about last night. Listen, I was at the Shaftesbury with the Vallance girls &amp;quot; The door opened and Veere was announced. &amp;quot; Am I the first ? &amp;quot; he asked, looking round the room. &amp;quot; The first shall be last,&amp;quot; said Dobrie. &amp;quot; We want you to take us out to supper.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t think I can. I am starting for the north at eight o&amp;apos;clock to-morrow morning, and I want just to taste my bed for an. hour or two.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is that sincere ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Sincere that I love my bed I adore it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I believe you sincerely adore something else! &amp;quot; she said, giving rein to her implanted taste for the simplest forms of chaff. She added: &amp;quot; If the husband gets off, he&amp;apos;ll bring an action for divorce ! &amp;quot; Lady Maude laughed, and arranged her feet on the footstool. &amp;quot; Why isn&amp;apos;t her portrait in the papers ? &amp;quot; pursued the eager young girl, enjoying herself. &amp;quot; Because she won&amp;apos;t have it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Why ? Is she ugly?&amp;quot; No.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Does she look a lady?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That I won&amp;apos;t tell you. It&amp;apos;s the most descriptive description you can give, and some of these days you&amp;apos;ll be seeing her with me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I did. Last night. Saw you sitting in the pit of the Shaftesbury with the wife of your uncle&amp;apos;s murderer!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Dobr&amp;amp;e, don&amp;apos;t be a brute! &amp;quot; murmured the chaperon. &amp;quot; Maude, you know you&amp;apos;re enjoying hearing me heckling him. We&amp;apos;re so modern. Ernest doesn&amp;apos;t mind it. He&amp;apos;s modern too.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t mind me, Lady Maude,&amp;quot; said Veere cheerfully. &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ll answer any questions-decent questions, that is!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well then, tell me, is she very much upset ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Rather upset-and very busy, as the schoolboy wrote when he was assisting his widowed mother with her replies to condolences. She-well, you are both so modern you won&amp;apos;t be shocked if I tell you-the wife of Altamont is placidly, quietly happy, delighted to be a widow. The man was a regular beast, he drank and struck her and was unfaithful to her, and she&amp;apos;s glad to be rid of him. She&amp;apos;s modern too.&amp;quot; Veere rose-they all rose-to greet the famous author, LeeBrice, the distinguished-looking man who wrote undistinguished novels about common people, and visited with the pick of the aristocracy. He was tall and rather grey, with a black pointed beard, this Don Quixote, who had tilted, now successfully now unsuccessfully, against the windmills of Wellingtons and Mudie. Fastidiousness was the note of his face, his small imperial suggested early days spent in diplomacy. Lady Maude had a great weakness for him, as, indeed, she had for all handsome men, and mono lised him for the moment. Veere and his young hostess were left alone. &amp;quot; So that&amp;apos;s your new toy-author ?&amp;quot; he said, alluding to LeeBrice. &amp;quot; Not much of a toy, is he? More like a greyhound,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s splendid, I think. I say, do tell me what your Mrs. Altamont is going to do with herself, after &amp;quot; &amp;quot; After her husband is hanged,&amp;quot; said he calmly. &amp;quot; Well, she has her plans, like the rest of us.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Are you in them ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I regret to say. She is going to America, where she intends to re-marry, if it is possible. No one need know her story out there, you see.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s the meaning of the Mammoth veil in court-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Precisely. Now talk to Lee-Brice, he&amp;apos;s got something to say to you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I saw you in my part of the world the other day, Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e,&amp;quot; said the author approaching, partially impelled to this move by Veere&amp;apos;s valedictory remark. &amp;quot; In Mount Street ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, in Wimbledon. I went there to finish a novel-I can&amp;apos;t work in town, with the telephone going contantly and people calling. When I have something to finish I take a room somewhere in the suburbs, and work hard at it, seeing no one and leaving my secretary at home to open my letters. Anywhere to avoid the advantages of civilisation ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh yes,&amp;quot; said she, &amp;quot;I remember. I went down to Wimbledon once to see Effel&amp;apos;s sister, who&amp;apos;s companion to old Lord Druid at Garsington House. And oh, I must tell youyou can put it in a story-I had such an adventure! Suddenly I saw a naked child run screaming out of a house, and down the drive and a bit of the road, and an awful looking woman with a beard run out after it and catch it and take it in. It yelled then like fury; and went on yelling inside. I thought it was my duty, so I rang the bell and gave the girl my card, said I was an inspector-Cruelty to Children, you know-and that I must positively come in and make inquiries. She let me in, and they were really quite nice in a suburban way. There was a tea-fight going on, but the woman of the house took me up and explained. The child was having his bath and he got naughty anA ran out just as he was, and the old Nanny-she had a beard but she was all right, I found, and adored children-had to go and get him back, but hadn&amp;apos;t liked to disturb the tea-party. Wouldn&amp;apos;t you have thought it your duty to inquire ? And all I said-I was very cunning-was that I had heard the screams-and so Igdid, for all the time we were talking he was yelling fit to take the roof off. Oh, here are the Blessingtons. Now we can go in to dinner.&amp;quot; XVIII Lady Dobree was on the whole too egotistic to be a good hostess. She made no effort to lead the conversation, not even in her own direction. It glanced on and off the Altamont trial several times during the meal. Veere sat impassible, like a good boy, eating his dinner, which was neither good nor well served. Betsey, with Ada&amp;apos;s help, could manage to give him a better. &amp;quot; Did you hear ? &amp;quot; said Lord Blessington, whose approaching senility was indicated more or less by the fact that he could not keep off the subject connected, and painfully so, with one of the guests, &amp;quot; that one of the halls had offered the wife of Altamont two hundred a week just to appear and sing one song ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is she a frump or a beauty ? &amp;quot; asked Lee-Brice. &amp;quot; Very fine hair, I believe. The Sweep had a whole column about her. She lives somewhere about Wimbledon in an old Jacobean manor-house-romantic and so on. They gave a photo of it. The article was in Monday&amp;apos;s issue, I think.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I didn&amp;apos;t see it,&amp;quot; said Veere. &amp;quot; Who do you say wrote it ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Simpson or Simmons-a name like that. A local authoress. Some one who&amp;apos;d got a down on the poor little woman, I imagine.&amp;quot; Veere made a mental note to advise Mrs. Altamont to beware of Evangeline, but forgot. He was interested in a talk he was having with the intensely versatile author about archeology. Lee-Brice, among his thirty-seven literary nurslings, numbered one book of which the scene was laid in Early Saxon times. &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s an old burying-ground on the links near a place of mine I should like you to see,&amp;quot; Veere was saying with all the zest of a Wardour Street shopman, who has got his lesson well by heart. &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ll get it opened. I&amp;apos;ll give any one leave who&amp;apos;ll undertake it, and pay the damage. There&amp;apos;s all sorts of traditions about it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What period ? &amp;quot; - &amp;quot; They&amp;apos;re pre-Christian burials, I think. We find a bit of a lead coffin now and again and sometimes a whole jaw-bone, with very white teeth-that is when the ladies have picked them with a bonnet-pin.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;How disgusting of the ladies,&amp;quot; said Dobr&amp;amp;e. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s bad enough to pick your own teeth, but some one else&amp;apos;s ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;d do it, if you were there. It&amp;apos;s quite a fascinating occupation. Come and do it. . . . It&amp;apos;s at Angernoune.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; My ancestral home,&amp;quot; said the young lady coolly. &amp;quot; Your father sold it to my uncle, all fair and square,&amp;quot; said Veere. &amp;quot; Forgive him for buying it, and come and entertain for me there this summer, and bring the present company. There are twenty-three bedrooms in the Dwelling House, and as many more in the Keep. I&amp;apos;ve no lady of my own family to entertain for me, except an old aunt who&amp;apos;s doited, and says the wrong thing all the time.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s where you get it!&amp;quot; muttered Lady Maude in a careless whisper. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t mind coming,&amp;quot; the girl said, in her harsh voice that could not adequately express the pleasure she felt at this decisive move on Veere&amp;apos;s part. &amp;quot; But Maude must come and housekeep.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Certainly,&amp;quot; said that lady complacently. &amp;quot; I take housekeeping in my stride. I&amp;apos;ll come certainly if the Blessingtons come too, and my cherubic latest-Lord Vallance ! &amp;quot; Long long ago Lady Maude had taken Lord Blessington in that capacious stride of hers, that now included the boy Vallance. The Blessingtons accepted the invitation con amore. The wife&amp;apos;s facile conjunction was forthcoming, &amp;quot;Dear Maude is so safe! &amp;quot; was the general opinion of her female contemporaries, victims some of them, once, of her Courts of Love that sat perpetually in Eccleston Square. She went always to fancy balls dressed as the Comtesse de Champagne, and was admitted to have all the passions under her patronage. Veere obediently wanted the company of Vallance of all things, Lee-Brice promised to give Lady Dobree a fortnight in August, and amid jests and laughter, the houseparty for Angernoune was made up. The Blessingtons made their adieux, Lady Maude and Lee-Brice, and all four packed into the tiny self-working lift. &amp;quot; By the way,&amp;quot; Lee-Brice said to Lord Blessington, &amp;quot; I didn&amp;apos;t like to mention it before that young fellow, but there is some talk about a petition on foot to the Home Secretary for Altamont. I understand Veere is interested in the wife ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, not to that extent! &amp;quot; said Lady Maude. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s romantic, that&amp;apos;s all.&amp;quot; The lift, bumped. Her smile was subtle as she bade the author good-bye in the hall, and got into the Blessington carriage. &amp;quot; Romantic ? Veere ? &amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;He&amp;apos;s going in for Dobr&amp;amp;e, that&amp;apos;s a fact. What else could that invitation to pose as hostess at Angernoune mean!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It might mean that he and the Altamont had had a row,&amp;quot; said Lord Blessington. &amp;quot; But we shall see.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; At Angernoune. It will be great fun! &amp;quot; said the vivacious lady. &amp;quot;Don&amp;apos;t go!&amp;quot; said Lady Dobrie to Veere when the two were left alone. &amp;quot; Effel&amp;apos;s come in. I heard her. I say, do you really want me to come to Angernoune and bring all my friends ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, unless you think they are too good for me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t say things like that, Ernest. But I could not help wondering if you asked me for myself.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why else should I ask you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, I don&amp;apos;t know.&amp;quot; She was ashamed to taunt him with the truth, that she had thought him pushing, and made a hasty accusation, which had, however, some validity in her mind. &amp;quot; I thought, perhaps, the wife of Altamont might have huffed you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t talk about her, it bores me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But why should I be so careful not to bore you ? You don&amp;apos;t mind boring me &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m sorry. How?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You don&amp;apos;t behave nicely to me-at least not how I should like you to.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Tell me how you&amp;apos;d like me to, and I&amp;apos;ll try, for you&amp;apos;re a good fellow, Dobr&amp;amp;e. And when you plead, you are very pathetic, because your voice doesn&amp;apos;t exactly lend itself-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There you are ! What a way to talk to a woman ! Telling her straight out that her voice is unsympathetic ! Voice isn&amp;apos;t everything ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Your only weapon, no. You&amp;apos;ve got others, and, as I say, when you soften &amp;quot; &amp;quot; But your voice now, Ernest-I suppose you wouldn&amp;apos;t be bothered, talking to me, but your voice never has the sort of inflections that I thought men used to women they admire and desire, when they are alone with them-?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why, you said Miss Taylor was in! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, but safely tucked up in bed by now.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I had better go then ! &amp;quot; She laughed stridently. He rose, and looked at her dissatisfied face, and was touched by it. True, Betsey had huffed him, and he was tired to-night. and spoke roughly. &amp;quot;Look here, Dobr&amp;amp;e, do you want to make me want to make love to you ? For I tell you honestly, I am not going to. It wouldn&amp;apos;t be good for you, you aren&amp;apos;t actuated by the right feminine motives. You&amp;apos;re not really a flirt, my dear, and the pose doesn&amp;apos;t suit you at all. You are a creamy English girl-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Tcha ! &amp;quot; She turned away. &amp;quot;Talking about desire! It&amp;apos;s not a word for you to use; not your line at all. It&amp;apos;s as if an aspic were to try to be a mayonnaise. And I&amp;apos;m in a rather bad temper to-night-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I see you are. Good night.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Good night, my dear. I dare say we shall-&amp;quot; He stopped. &amp;quot;What ? Say it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Marry each other all right in the end; that is to say, if you care to when the time comes.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I shall never marry you till I have seen the green light in your eyes.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;What are you talking about, you perverse child!&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Something AMaude said-connected with that word you disapproved of my using so much. Good night ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Use it as much as you like, but not to me,&amp;quot; said Veere. &amp;quot;You don&amp;apos;t come in there with me. Good night! I&amp;apos;ve enjoyed myself very much, thank you.&amp;quot; He kissed her hand. &amp;quot; So glad! &amp;quot; They both laughed. &amp;quot; You should learn not to stick your knuckles out so when they kiss your hand!&amp;quot; said he as he left the room. &amp;quot;He meant when I am the wife of a Cabinet Minister and receive foreign notabilities-Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e Veere, At Home!&amp;quot; Dobr&amp;amp;e told Effel, waking her up, and relating the experiences of the evening. &amp;quot; But I must say I feel a fool when some one is kissing my hand, and I am thinking of all sorts of different things as I look out over his bald parting-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mr. Veere isn&amp;apos;t bald,&amp;quot; remarked Effel sleepily. &amp;quot; No, but he&amp;apos;s the kind of man who soon will be, if he works so hard, and runs the wife of Altamont at the same time. He makes, but he&amp;apos;s not made of, cast-iron. Effel, laugh!&amp;quot; Effel laughed. &amp;quot; As for Mrs. A., I&amp;apos;ve fought her and I&amp;apos;ve beaten her, and I feel proud, for she&amp;apos;s what they call desirable, I&amp;apos;m sure. I teased Ernest about it to-night, when he was courting me in his usual casual fashion. Is he cold-or am I ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I hardly know what you mean ? &amp;quot; said Effel. &amp;quot; No, poor dear. Well, the fact is, I like fifty men better than Ernest, in that way, even the author who dined to-night! But alack, they have none of them sixty thousand a year!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Has Mr. Veere ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; More. And it will take it all, all, to make him go down.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But I thought your people-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, they&amp;apos;re all right. Father&amp;apos;ll stop tree-cutting and mother will start her model dairy. And, of course, the Laxes and the Minians are quite aware which side of their bread isn&amp;apos;t buttered. They don&amp;apos;t want to go on keeping me. And they don&amp;apos;t think I&amp;apos;ve got quite the right woman to go out with, but what have I to offer to a really smart person ? It&amp;apos;s the Veeres and so on that she can introduce me to, with some chance of my going down and off ! Do you think I don&amp;apos;t know that ? I&amp;apos;m rather deep really; I go with the tide. I go with Veere. Only I wish he&amp;apos;d take some lessons in the art of making love!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s such a nice-looking young man, I think! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Dear old Effel ! &amp;quot; said her young charge sorrowfully, stooping down and kissing her. &amp;quot; Good night!&amp;quot; XIX Mrs. Altamont was intent, all her faculties surrendered to the cutting out of a suit for little Wilfrid on the dining-room table in Worksop House-it was the only table in the house you could cut out on. Ada, from the adjoining kitchen department, wandered in and out, carrying, absently, various stained and sooty culinary implements backwards and forwards-a lovely scullion, for she had gained weight and her complexion had improved since her domestication in Betsey&amp;apos;s home. &amp;quot; Ada, put that pan down-not here; it&amp;apos;s all black round the bottom-and catch me Billy. This is basted ready for him to try on. He&amp;apos;s under the table, with Ginger.&amp;quot; Mrs. Cox stooped under the table and addressed her apparently inanimate son. &amp;quot; Come out, Billy! Come to your mammy!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Which one ? &amp;quot; said Billy, with a mind to tease and procrastinate. &amp;quot; This one! &amp;quot; said Mrs. Altamont sharply. &amp;quot; Come along, quick ! I&amp;apos;ve no time to waste.&amp;quot; Billy was then temporarily arrayed in a sober, manly serge covering, held together precariously by scant white threads, and stood up in front of his own mother, whose secret ideal of clothes for her boy was that embodied in the picture &amp;quot; Bubbles.&amp;quot; She murmured tamely, &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;ll look quite the man in it! &amp;quot; Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s mouth was full of pins. Ada went on: &amp;quot; I wish his poor father could see him in it. Billy, don&amp;apos;t you long to see daddy again ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Don&amp;apos;t,&amp;quot; said Betsey, removing such pins from her lips as positively impeded speech, &amp;quot; don&amp;apos;t work him up like that! Wat&amp;apos;s the good of putting impossible ideas into the child&amp;apos;s head ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Impossible ideas? &amp;quot; Ada&amp;apos;stared. &amp;quot; The idea that he&amp;apos;ll see him again when he won&amp;apos;t.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; My goodness, you are hard! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I&amp;apos;m not.&amp;quot; The eyes of the speaker filled with tears. &amp;quot; Oh yes, you&amp;apos;re crying fast enough,&amp;quot; Ada said resentfully. &amp;quot;But not for him. It&amp;apos;s for yourself you&amp;apos;re crying.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, for myself, and Billy, and you, for anybody but the man who&amp;apos;s plunged us into this for nothing! &amp;quot; She threw down the scissors. &amp;quot; For nothing! His children were starving and I told him so.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Miss Altamont was going to do something.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But she went and died first,&amp;quot; Ada complained, sitting down and falling into her second fit of tears this morning. She generally had five or six. She fed and fostered her insurgent nerves with continual sluicings of tea; there were days when her usual allowance of sixteen cups was exceeded. She drank no spirits. Mrs. Altamont swept the materials of Billy&amp;apos;s suit off the table and began to sew, feverishly, inexpertly, but sturdily. Ada was ashamed. She rose and wiped her eyes on her apron. &amp;quot; Look here, this is the way to nowhere. I&amp;apos;ll go back to my work. Shall Billy stay with you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I&amp;apos;ll mind him. I&amp;apos;ll take him for a walk as soon as I have got this put together, so that I don&amp;apos;t lose all the pins.&amp;quot; She sat and worked. Her head, a shining platter, a disc of gold, was downcast, and her cheek was flushed. The child played happily at her feet. Presently there was a ring at the outer door bell. Mrs. Altamont, without waiting for her hysterical cook, rose and admitted the friendly detective who had brought her the news of the crime in the first instance. Inspector Whortleberry admired the wife of Altamont and was impressed by the dramatic circumstances of her case. His histrionic leanings were, however, a good deal damped by the life he led, and would never have betrayed him into a breach of discipline, though, indeed, the spectacle of the murderer&amp;apos;s wife with the murderer&amp;apos;s child by another woman on her knee, was stimulating and richer in suggestion than most of the usual combinations that came under his notice. Betsey knew exactly the state of his feelings about her, and manipulated them at her pleasure. She encouraged him to call often, and give her all the news she wanted. &amp;quot; I have called to tell you, Mrs. Altamont, that there is going to be a petition signed and sent up to the Home Secretary.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;What for ? &amp;quot; Her eyes grew round and strained; she suspended the play of her needle. &amp;quot; Run away to your mother, Billy, and tell her I sent you.&amp;quot; The child went at once-he always obeyed Betsey faithfully. &amp;quot;It is a petition to commute the death sentence,&amp;quot; the inspector said solemnly. &amp;quot; Is that so ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes. It may be granted-we cannot tell. It depends on the list of names-and popular feeling is rather strong in his favour.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I wonder why?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, you see, Mrs. Altamont, the attempt at suicide-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Showed the purity of his intentions! &amp;quot; she sneered. &amp;quot; It showed the state of despair that the man was in. And then the doctors bringing him round-operating on him only to fit him to be hanged; after all-you see, it gets up a lot of sympathy in the public-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The public doesn&amp;apos;t reason.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, Mrs. Altamont, we have to take that into account. But the present Home Secretary is a stern man-there ain&amp;apos;t no nonsense about him. He doesn&amp;apos;t take much count of petitions, especially those The Sweep gets up.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;M My husband was once on the staff of that paper. . . . Well, thank you very much, Mr. Whortleberry, for coming here to tell me these things.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not at all, madam, I am very pleased to be of any use to you.&amp;quot; He was distrait and so was Mrs. Altamont. During the course of his last speech they had heard a motor stop outside Worksop House, and both the inspector and Betsey knew who it was. Whortleberry took his respectful leave of the enchantress. He had come across Veere in Worksop House before; this made twice-it was custom, then ! It was another aspect of the unconventionality that ran all through the Veere Murder case. He knew well enough that his news was unwelcome to Mrs. Altamont. Naturally so. The poor girl was young, handsome, and absolutely indifferent to her criminal husband. What was sport to the British public was death to her and her future. He also, for Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s sake, rejoiced in the reputed severity and unyielding character of the Home Secretary of the day, which would impel him to reject the careless popular cry. Petitions like this go to the very root of human nature. It is as impossible to avoid inscribing one&amp;apos;s name at the bottom of an appeal to mercy as to refuse to put one&amp;apos;s hand in one&amp;apos;s pocket at Christmas in response to the prayers of indiscriminate, ill-judged charity. &amp;quot;Well, Betsey, I&amp;apos;m back. Travelled all night,&amp;quot; Veere said, coming in rather boisterously. &amp;quot; And have you pulled it off-what you went to do?&amp;quot; she asked, making an effort of detachment. &amp;quot;Yes. Done the deed-deal, I mean. I say,&amp;quot; he grew serious, &amp;quot; have you seen the papers this morning-or did that stout beggar I met going out come to tell you It&amp;apos;s not his business-but I suppose your eyes &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t, Ernest, he means to be kind. Yes, he told mebut he reassured me as well. He says it&amp;apos;s most unlikely the Home Secretary will agree to it. I&amp;apos;m speaking low, because of Ada. I never know-she is so keenly interested, she listens!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, will you come for a spin in the car ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, if I may take the child. I promised him a walk.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; All right, I&amp;apos;ll take you to Kensington Gardens.&amp;quot; &amp;apos;To Kensington, when we live on Wimbledon Common?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, and it is common to him. We&amp;apos;ll buy him a boat and swim it on the Round Pond. Come on.&amp;quot; Betsey opened the door leading to the kitchen and called: &amp;quot; Ada ! Mr. Veere is here. Send Billy along, will you &amp;quot; Veere stooped and kissed the child, tweaking his &amp;quot; Bubbles&amp;quot; frills. &amp;quot; You dear little figure of fun ! &amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve no moustache for you to pull. Pity, isn&amp;apos;t it ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Daddy has a moustache. . . . I&amp;apos;ve only one daddy and two mammys !&amp;quot; They dressed him between them and hustled him off, promising to buy him a little ship at the first shop they came to in Kensington. As they packed into the motor, Evangeline Simmons passed by and gawkily made a gesture between a familiar nod and a distant bow to Betsey, who pretended not to see it. She was not inclined to forgive Evangeline for the interview just yet, though she fully admitted the terrible temptation to make capital out of a friend&amp;apos;s misfortunes that had been presented to a young lady of journalistic tendencies. They had stopped half-way at a fancy repository in West Kensington to buy the little ship that Billy was clamouring for. A large printed paper was spread out on the counter, which the quick-eyed Betsey spied, and at once turned away from. The shopwoman, however, timidly presented it to Veere&amp;apos;s notice. &amp;quot;Petition to reprieve Altamont ! Not I !&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Perhaps the lady would like to sign it ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; The lady doesn&amp;apos;t approve of the object of the petition,&amp;quot; Veere informed her offhandedly. &amp;quot; Are you aware that the man himself is not anxious to live ? He tried to kill himself.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ah, but think of his po&amp;apos;r wife?&amp;quot; said the shopwoman. &amp;quot;And her left with two litte children!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You are misinformed,&amp;quot; said Veere carelessly. &amp;quot; She has none.&amp;quot; The woman gave it up, and went for the change. Betsey nudged him. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t let us wait for the change.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; We must, or she will begin to think things.&amp;quot; They lunched at the hotel overlooking Kensington Gardens, and then sailed the little ship on the Round Pond for half an hour in such a thoroughly half-hearted and ineffective manner that Billy was disgusted, and said he didn&amp;apos;t care about sailing his new boat at all, but wanted badly to sit down under the trees on a penny chair with green slats. 1t&amp;apos;s too cold ! &amp;quot; was Betsey&amp;apos;s cross reply to his petition. &amp;quot;We had better be getting home. I don&amp;apos;t know whatever your mother will say to me, you&amp;apos;ve gone and messed your nice suit all over with water -&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Betsey! Betsey! &amp;quot; objected Veere good-humouredly. &amp;quot;Here are you crabby-when you have a good right to be tragic ! It&amp;apos;s the sign of a healthy nature, I suppose ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh yes.&amp;quot; She flew out, pettish as a child. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m healthy -damn healthy-but just now I&amp;apos;m so tired I can hardly stand! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;We will sit down for a minute then,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot;and please both the children. It&amp;apos;s really quite mild. . . . Betsey, I understand.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You do. You&amp;apos;re an angel.... You don&amp;apos;t think me a monster, do you ? &amp;quot; she half sobbed, looking up into his kind eyes as she sank into a seat. &amp;quot; No, of course not. I consider you&amp;apos;re a woman awfully put upon-regularly bashed by Fate ! No one, knowing all the circumstances, and your own peculiar temperament, could blame you for feeling-not quite en rigle, shall we say ? Even the inspector doesn&amp;apos;t, and he&amp;apos;s not so much prejudiced in your favour as I am, at least I hope not. But we can none of us do anything one way or another. The Law must take its course.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, if they&amp;apos;d only let it! Oh, my God, what am I saying ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t mind me!&amp;quot; He idly threw Billy&amp;apos;s ball, which he was holding, to a little distance, so as to get rid of the boy and his inquiring gaze till Betsey should right herself, for she was crying. She dried her eyes, and spoke passionately. &amp;quot; Ever woman-even a woman of no temperament at allwould feel as I do, if she had the honesty to admit it, or was as blunt and tactless as I am. Don&amp;apos;t I know that if they&amp;apos;d had a tithe of what I&amp;apos;ve had to put up with, they&amp;apos;d be mad, enraged, wild, to find themselves taken out of the sun they had just crawled out into for a moment, blinking their eyes-and put back again into their dark cages alone with a maniac ! . . . Tied to him with a chain, and when he moves, they&amp;apos;ve got to move too! Oh, if Wilfrid were only dead, and the earth over him! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;You do say dreadful things, my Betsey, somehow, but somehow I understand you. It is this way, isn&amp;apos;t it ? You mean, if that were so, you would feel he was redeemed-purified from his sin by the wholesome earth, with robins bringing dead leaves to cover him, and so on ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, don&amp;apos;t be poetical, please,&amp;quot; she replied brutally. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m afraid I wasn&amp;apos;t thinking of him, I was thinking of me. Yes,&amp;quot; relenting a little, &amp;quot; that is what I do mean. He would be safe underneath,&amp;apos;all his wickedness cancelled down there, thrown away like dirt, like old clothes, like last year&amp;apos;s slumber. But to have to think of him continually, alive in a sickening cell, the disgusting papers telling you day by day how he is in health and spirits, gloating on it in their horrid way, and all the world expecting me topelt off to go and see him in prison! My God!&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Hush ! &amp;quot; said the man at her side. &amp;quot; Billy&amp;apos;s coming back.&amp;quot; She rallied to his caution and when Wilfrid&amp;apos;s boy toddled up to her, she bent to him kindly and normally. &amp;quot; What is it, Billy ? What do you want ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; To give you a kiss,&amp;quot; said the child timidly. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s his way of showing you sympathy,&amp;quot; said Veere hastily. &amp;quot;Do. She obeyed and hugged the boy very nicely. Contented with his little demonstration, the child sped away again, and Betsey murmured, shamefaced: &amp;quot; He wanted to console me for crying, and I was crying because they were going to spare his father&amp;apos;s life ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, but I don&amp;apos;t think they will,&amp;quot; said Ernest Veere. &amp;quot;They won&amp;apos;t prevail with the man who&amp;apos;s boss now. I know him a bit. He&amp;apos;s firm. And the public&amp;apos;s a mere sentimental idiot, collectively, and its sympathy&amp;apos;s all misplaced, for I hear, on the best authority, that they have all the trouble in the world to prevent him from finishing himself in prison.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Poor Wilfrid! &amp;quot; she said gently, drying her eyes. On the lips of the fierce revengeful Maenad of a moment ago, Veere felt that this tardy expression of sympathy was sincere, the slow shining forth of the true womanly sense of pity, whose workings in her had been temporarily obscured by selfish considerations. He loved her, but this exhibition of a raw soul which he had laid himself out for, troubled and worried him. Did she apprehend that her slave, even in so little, was becoming alienated ? For she stood up and stooped to him, saying sweetly, with her tremulous, bow-shaped mouth: &amp;quot; Ernest, I&amp;apos;ve made a fool of myself, and you&amp;apos;ve let me. Thank you. Come Billykins, we&amp;apos;ll be going. Send us home, will you, Ernest? Don&amp;apos;t come with us this time. I want to tell poor Ada.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Let&amp;apos;s have a look, what a nice ship you got!&amp;quot; exclaimed poor Ada, opening the door of Worksop House, and dusting the flour and currants sticking on her hands. &amp;quot; I was just making you a nice cake for tea.&amp;quot; Betsey, though thrall to deepest tragedy, made a wry face at this announcement. &amp;quot; Who gave it to you ? Mr. Veere ? He is a nice kind man. And good gracious, Betsey, my dear, whatever makes you look so down in the mouth ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I hadn&amp;apos;t better tell her this very moment,&amp;quot; thought the other woman, half considerate, half cowardly, and busied herself in extricating the child from damp garments complicated by reason of their smallness. Nervously she said, &amp;quot; Look what Billy&amp;apos;s done to his pants, messing about by the Round Pond, I knew you would be cross.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not I ! &amp;quot; said Ada cheerfully. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m not a fusser. No more&amp;apos;d you be, if you&amp;apos;d had two. gut you&amp;apos;re a regular old maid, you are ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Somebody may as well be pleased,&amp;quot; said Betsey then, in a hard voice. &amp;quot; Ada, there&amp;apos;s a petition set up in all the shops to the Home Secretary to get Wilfrid off ! &amp;quot; Ada dropped Billy&amp;apos;s cap that she was holding. Mrs. Altamont picked it out of the grate. &amp;quot; Now- don&amp;apos;t faint-don&amp;apos;t be silly, or I&amp;apos;ll wish I hadn&amp;apos;t told you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You just dare not tell me! Who d&amp;apos;ye say&amp;apos;ll get him off ? The King ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I said the Home Secretary. He can reverse the verdict if he thinks proper.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t bother me with your Home Secretary ! Does he think Wilfrid&amp;apos;ll get off-I mean, do you ? I don&amp;apos;t know where I&amp;apos;ve got my head. You might be kind, Betsey, though you don&amp;apos;t care. It&amp;apos;s life and death to me ! &amp;quot; She sat down bv the fire and rocked herself to and fro, and the firelight caught one of the grey strands in her hair. There were several. Betsey saw them. Ada was only twenty-seven. Betsey knelt down. &amp;quot; Yes, I will be kind. But I know nothing more than that there&amp;apos;s a petition out-which I didn&amp;apos;t sign-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, Betsey, and you his wife! How could you!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I couldn&amp;apos;t, Ada. It&amp;apos;s no good, I don&amp;apos;t want him saved. I&amp;apos;m not a Catholic, but I want him to be well punished for his fault here, and then perhaps God will let him off purgatoryafterwards. He ought to pay, and then they won&amp;apos;t send the bill in again.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s paid! He&amp;apos;s paid-in full. He tried to kill himself. That was paying-his way of paying. And then there&amp;apos;s me ! Can&amp;apos;t you think of me ? Why must I pay? I never murdered anybody. And if Wilfrid dies it will be my life that they take. Oh, Betsey, you are so much cleverer than me-you&amp;apos;ve been edicated-give your mind to it ! Think and tell me what you think. I can&amp;apos;t put two ideas together. I&amp;apos;m too addled with misery. Oh, say you think he may come back! &amp;quot; Mrs. Altamont spoke her pious lie distinctly. &amp;quot; I think it is possible he may live to come back-to you. In twenty years or so! &amp;quot;Oh, thank you. You mean-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I mean they won&amp;apos;t let him out all at once. They will send him to penal servitude, and, if he is very good, they might commute his sentence-let him out sooner, you know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll be dead, perhaps, first,&amp;quot; said Ada, staring into the fire and grasping a fold of Betsey&amp;apos;s gown. &amp;quot; I may never see my children&amp;apos;s father again; you don&amp;apos;t seem to think of that, Betsey ? Oh, cruel, cruel &amp;apos;tis! You don&amp;apos;t pity him-but you might pity me ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I do, I do,&amp;quot; returned the other, in full generous tones, putting her soft white hand over the bony talons that clawed her gown. &amp;quot; And that&amp;apos;s why I- But I don&amp;apos;t-now--&amp;quot; Her incoherency mattered little, for Mrs. Cox paid no attention to such strangled meanings. She spoke on, swiftly, interrupting her comfortress: &amp;quot; Oh, but Betsey, even if I never see him again I can get on, for I shall know he won&amp;apos;t be dead-not hanged-by his poor thin neck. . . .&amp;quot; A long shudder ran through her. &amp;quot; Such an awful death, Betsey. You couldn&amp;apos;t wish it for any one-not even a man you hate-as you hate Will. . ..&amp;quot; Mrs. Altamont made no reply. She had slid down on her knees on to the hearthrug beside her cook-her husband&amp;apos;s mistress, of whose hand she did not choose to let go. She alternately chafed and clasped it. Ada evidently derived comfort from her unspoken, only faintly indicated sympathy, the touch was all.... Firmly she held the kind nurse-like hand, as a baby might, uncritical of the quality of the emotion that radiated thence. Presently she raised her head and flung back the shroud of her crisped black hair: &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s settled, isn&amp;apos;t it ? He&amp;apos;ll be let off. . . . The Home Secretary&amp;apos;s a kind man. A just man. He can&amp;apos;t deny . . . and all England&amp;apos;s on Will&amp;apos;s side. . . . He can come back to me ! He can come back when he likes, and any hour of the day or night he&amp;apos;ll find me waiting! A ause. Ada was dimly vexed. She could not see Betsey&amp;apos;s face, sedulously concealed, and that disturbed her. She repeated: &amp;quot;He&amp;apos;ll find me waiting! And, Betsey, you&amp;apos;re tied to him . . . fast tied too. We&amp;apos;re both tied to him, aren&amp;apos;t we . . . Oh, Betsey, do speak, do say something! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; How can I ? &amp;quot; exclaimed the other passionately, between her sharply taken breaths. &amp;quot; Do you want me to say that he&amp;apos;ll find me waiting too ? You do ? Two women he&amp;apos;s-! My God! &amp;quot; Her voice changed. &amp;quot; Where&amp;apos;s the child?&amp;quot; She jumped up, leaving the other prone under her withering displeasure. &amp;quot; Where&amp;apos;s Little Katie ? &amp;quot; she continued. &amp;quot;Having their teas, bless them!&amp;quot; answered Ada in smothered tones, then plucking up a spirit, she declaimed: &amp;quot; Poor innocent children, that you want to make orphans of!&amp;quot; She nursed her knees, and rocked to and fro, an interminable gesture. Betsey, tearless, sat up, in a high chair, sardonically regarding her vicar, officiating now in the full panoply and trappings of grief. XX Weeks passed. The Petition for Altamont&amp;apos;s life lay on the counters of shops and gathered up names, the lists in the papers swelled apace. The two women whose very fate depended on the will of the Home Secretary, acted on by the whim of the sentimental section of the British public, knew no ease. The prayers that went up from Worksop House must have clashed and neutralised each other on their way to the Throne of the Most High. Ada formulated her prayers; she was a believer. Betsey did not, but Betsey&amp;apos;s were none the less insistent, addressed to no specific arbiter and unregistered on the mental altars we all have within us. They could not &amp;quot;settle to anything.&amp;quot; Ada Cox could not cook, but then this omission was adjusted by the corollary that Mrs. Altamont could not eat. Billy and Little Katie did not starve, their joint guardians took care of that; they were as happy as quiet little children ever are at Christmas. For Christmas and its enforced jollity came down on the sad, expectant household of four, and sucked them up in its insensate round of meaningless ceremonies. To please the children ! The colour of oranges, the sound of crackers, a blue ribbon round Ginger&amp;apos;s neck: all this followed. In the tactless papers there was much talk of a Christmas prisoner and seasonable clemency, which did not escape two pairs of eyes in Worksop House and gave rise to very different feelings. Both Ada and Betsey bought halfpenny papers and conned them in their cold winter bedrooms. Either woman would have died of shame if the other had caught her. And their confusion proceeded from divers motives. Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s attitude towards the appeal to mercy was never again alluded to by the other excited participant in the Perton tragedy, who honestly tried to forget that Betsey, whom she loved and who was so kind, eagerly scanned the papers to find a result counter to all her own dearest hopes. The whole neighbourhood that ostracised, and were in their turn ostracised by the wife of Altamont, watched her behaviour keenly. Her cook, when she went out of doors to do the necessary marketing-for Betsey herself never went into a shop now, or out at all except with Veere, was stared at by Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s old friends occupied on the same errand. One or two of them went so far as to ask her how her mistress was ? The BurneJones&amp;apos; cook-&amp;quot; a queer-looking woman, you know, but I dare say Betsey finds a difficulty in getting respectable servants to come to her ! &amp;quot; was used to answer shortly, sullenly, and refused to contribute the information, a desire for which had prom pted the question. Evangeline Simmons, kind, curious soul, did more than speak to the cook, she thought she would like to send Mrs. Altamont a Christmas card. She carefully chose out one that did not in any way bear on the situation, and she left it at the door, which Ada answered, little Katie clinging to her gown. Evangeline was grateful for even this transitory glimpse into the interior of her dear Betsey, whose sorrows she had made twopound-ten out of. She asked to see her as usual, and as usual was told that Mrs. Altamont was not at home. &amp;quot; How proud she is ! &amp;quot; was her respectful thought as she turned away. A large London tradesman&amp;apos;s cart rattled up just then and left-actually-a small Christmas tree at the door of Worksop House! Mr. Veere was going to give the cook&amp;apos;s children a Christmas tree ! Her novelist&amp;apos;s mind jumped at once to that conclusion, which happened to be the right one. This romance going on under the shadow of the gallows delighted Evangeline. The motor-clad, furry Prince, the cloistered beauty, the Burne-Jones&amp;apos; cook, the mysterious, starved-looking children that went with the cook, and whom Veere thought it necessary to provide with a seasonable fir-tree from Baltic forests ! -Oh, why wouldn&amp;apos;t Betsey see her and let her be in it ? It was her due. She wasn&amp;apos;t narrow, like Mrs. Gedge; she was truly the confidante proper, or improper-built for the part. She supposed Betsey was a bit annoyed by that wretched interview! She was, indeed, a little ashamed of having written it. She was a Judas now who felt inclined to quarrel with the scanty wage of silver doled out to her by The Sweep, that patron of lost, sensational causes. She took to haunting the outskirts of Worksop House, making it convenient to pass by the door at least, three or four times a day. Thus, the daily visits of Mr. Veere to the house, and the slightly more spaced out ones of Inspector Whortleberry did not escape her encouraging notice. But they were only accessories, she would get speech of Betsey, the chief protagonist, too. Of that she was determined. Her opportunity came. The next time Inspector Whortleberry came, it was on Twelfth Night. The snow had come and Ada was interviewing a snow-away at the door. Whortleberry nodded to Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s cook, whom even he was far from suspecting to be the Ada Cox mentioned in the Altamont trial, and passed in. Miss Simmons, with the courage of romance, followed him, and by some dexterous juggling with outer and inner doors that folded back, succeeded in evading his eyes and stowing herself away in one of the upstairs rooms, where she patiently suffered the worst extremities of cold while the interview with the inspector lasted. 1I Inspector Whortleberry had not much to say. In fact his was a Christmas visit. His superior soul revolted against wishing Mrs. Altamont either a Merry Christmas or even a Happy New Year, but by sheer good luck he had found a card in one of the vast trays exhibited by the shops which embodied his hopes on her behalf and stated them, so it seemed to him, in the most delicate way. Under the floral emblem that decorated the card, a line from Shakespeare was blazoned: cc . .My gentle lady, I wish you all the joy that you can wish.&amp;quot; Mrs. Altamont tore off the envelope and looked at it ruefully. She was embarrassed. But she reflected, with her usual elasticity of thought and sympathy, that the choice of this card showed nothing but nice feeling on Mr. Whortleberry&amp;apos;s part, and she therefore thanked him for it cordially and prettily, stuffing into his hands some splendid crackers for the children he had not got, though he was much too shy to tell her so. His unofficial visit had lasted a shorter time than poor Mrs. Cox expected. She fell away from the door in a strained position as soon as Betsey opened it to let the inspector out. He cleverly turned aside and looked out of the window while Betsey raised Ada. &amp;quot; Mly poor girl,&amp;quot; said she kindly, &amp;quot; we were not talking about that ! &amp;quot; After the stress of the moment was over and Whortleberry had gone, she was inclined to be a little more severe. She interviewed her cook in the kitchen as she was preparing the potatoes for an Irish stew. &amp;quot; You mustn&amp;apos;t, Ada, you really mustn&amp;apos;t let yourself down so as to listen at doors. And why you should imagine that Inspector Whortleberry always comes to talk about Wilfrid-? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s he come for then ? To blarney you and get your name up! Oh, you needn&amp;apos;t toss your head, that&amp;apos;s what they&amp;apos;re all saying ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Who&amp;apos;s all saying ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; They ! They ! &amp;quot; Ada repeated obstinately. &amp;quot; I tell you, you won&amp;apos;t have a bit of character left. There&amp;apos;s that Miss Simmons always hanging about, trying to get by me-I shouldn&amp;apos;t wonder if she isn&amp;apos;t in the house now-I thought I saw something go past when that man came ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Nonsense, Ada. Keep to the point, and that is, you must really stay in your kitchen when I have visitors.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And leave you and him shut up for hours together-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s not true, Ada.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Poor Wilfrid ! Nobody cares what becomes of him but me! rou aren&amp;apos;t talking about Wilfrid, you says-no, trust you ! Your own two beautiful selves, of course. And yet that&amp;apos;s the man that knows all about my poor boy and could tell me if he liked. But you&amp;apos;re right, it ain&amp;apos;t no good my listening at doors to what you and he say, or I&amp;apos;d do it, and more, if I could get to know about him. I&amp;apos;m fit to burst. I have to go picking it up bit by bit from the tradesmen, and look silly, arsking questions as if I was keeq on knowing about murders and bloody details and that-I who never knew anything about that sort of thing till I came into this family! . . . No, I know well enough as the policeman doesn&amp;apos;t come to talk about my affairs-not he! I&amp;apos;ve listened to you two enough to know that it ain&amp;apos;t worth my while to listen. Nor Mr. Veere, neither, comes for that. I call it shameful, you, his wife, his real wife, not to take more care of his name! &amp;quot; She paused, exhausted with the mere effort of vituperation. Mrs. Altamont turned away with a disagreeable smile on her lips. Her outward tranquillity calmed the other woman, who turned and looked back to the other end of the room where her child was playing in the window seat. &amp;quot; Now then, I suppose I&amp;apos;ll have to go,&amp;quot; she sighed, spent. &amp;quot;You give me notice, don&amp;apos;t you ? Here, Billy, leave them bricks of yours, and let&amp;apos;s take ourselves off where we come from ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Leave the child alone, Ada!&amp;quot; Betsey put herself in front of the boy, who in his full confidence never even suspended his making of bridges. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m not going to take a bit of notice of what you say, except to tell you you&amp;apos;ll be sorry for it afterwards. You&amp;apos;ve got a lot to put you out and vex you. So have I, but in a different way. Be quiet now, stop crying, there&amp;apos;s a dear! We won&amp;apos;t talk of it again. . . . I don&amp;apos;t know how you will look at the piece of news Mr. Whortleberry did tell me-not to-day, but a few days ago. I didn&amp;apos;t tell you, not to hurt you more, but Wilfrid nearly managed to do for himself last week in prison-got hold of a knife or something. That&amp;apos;s all he cares for their reprieve ! And to tell you the truth I respect him for it ! I think better of him than I did for attempting it. . . . And I think it was a shame of them to prevent him making an end of himself at the first, and getting nicely out of it all ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, and leave you free to marry your man! . . . Nowyou may believe me, I&amp;apos;d sooner go! &amp;quot; She clutched the little boy again, and with hysterical strength lifted him right over her shoulder. &amp;quot; Wil you put that child down! He&amp;apos;s far too heavy for you -now, thank goodness ! &amp;quot; The mother let him slide out of her arms, and Billy sidled up and dung to Mrs. Altamont. Her breast heaved-she took him on her knee. Ada stood looking at the pair with sullen vindictive eyes. At last Betsey looked up, hers were full of kindness and contrition. &amp;quot; Poor child, he doesn&amp;apos;t know what to make of it, us two quarrelling! You looked as if you were going to claw my eyes out, my dear, don&amp;apos;t you know ? &amp;quot; Ada said nothing. She looked tired, and leaned against the kitchen table, while Mrs. Altamont went on, softly: &amp;quot; Of course I shan&amp;apos;t let this outburst of yours make any difference-not even your last taunt about Mr. Veere. But I&amp;apos;ll tell you how it really is. You silly girl, do you suppose that Mr. Veere would think of marrying the widow of a man who has been hanged for murder-the murder of his own uncle too ! My poor Ada, don&amp;apos;t you see that your precious Wilfrid has spoilt both our lives, yours and mine, whatever happens. Only if he is reprieved, mine will be spoilt a little worse and you&amp;apos;ll be no better off. Look at it like that. Try to see my point of view. For I-&amp;quot; she paused-&amp;quot; it may sound brutal, but I had hoped to be able to do something decent with the remains of my lifemake a fresh start-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; If I understand you,&amp;quot; said Ada quite quietly-she had begun to peel potatoes-&amp;quot; you are building your happiness on a man&amp;apos;s death ! That seems a bit queer to me ! . . .&amp;quot; She picked out an eye from the potato vindictively. She heard Betsey catch her breath, almost sob, and when she looked up again her victim was gone. The kitchen fire crackled brightly, Billy had returned to his bricks, Ginger the cat lay stretched full length in indolent ease in front of the blaze. The sight roused Ada&amp;apos;s smouldering rage. She seized a broom -but desisted weakly. Then she addressed her little son, who regarded her, wide-eyed. &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ll let the cat be, won&amp;apos;t we, Billy She&amp;apos;s fond of him, as much as she&amp;apos;s fond of anybody ! Hard as nails she is. ... Go &amp;apos;long, Ginger, go &amp;apos;long to her! She&amp;apos;s in the dining-room, warming her toes, and naught but a man&amp;apos;s life between her and her happiness ! &amp;quot; XXI Mrs. Altamont rushed up to her bedroom to get a pockethandkerchief. Evangeline came forward: &amp;quot; Oh, Betsey, I had to-I had to see you somehow. Won&amp;apos;t you forgive me ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, yes. Sit down,&amp;quot; said the other wearily. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m too tired to have another row! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Who&amp;apos;ve you had a row with?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; My cook,&amp;quot; said Betsey laconically. &amp;quot; She gave me notice.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; After all your kindness to her ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;What kindness ? I give her her wages-the same as Georgie had.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, but you took her with all those children. And I dare say a husband out of work somewhere &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, no husband.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Are the children- ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Illegitimate-yes.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; How awfully good of you. Look here, I&amp;apos;ve brought a book for you-you know you wanted it. The condemned book. Lee-Brice&amp;apos;s. I&amp;apos;ll give it you. I caught it up just before I left home &amp;quot; &amp;quot; And came on here with your burnt offerings,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Altamont. &amp;quot; Thanks, I never read novels now.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; The novel has come to you, hasn&amp;apos;t it ?&amp;quot; hazarded Evangeline, laying her present slyly down. &amp;quot; Come to stay, I think, like motor-cars. Well, as you&amp;apos;re here, we had better go and sit where there&amp;apos;s a fire.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Delighted. My crop of chilblains is terrific this winter.&amp;quot; She babbled about her chilblains till they were settled by the dining-room fire downstairs. Ada&amp;apos;s children were banished to the kitchen for the first time in their stay, by a visitor. &amp;quot; You see one reason why I refuse myself to people,&amp;quot; said Betsey. &amp;quot; These poor little things have the freedom of the house, and I don&amp;apos;t fancy Mrs. Wormeley caring to come here and tumble over my cook&amp;apos;s family using the dining-room.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh,&amp;quot; said Evangeline, &amp;quot;if that was all! Mrs. Wormeley-! &amp;quot; Betsey was eyeing her curiously. &amp;quot; But why need we talk about Mrs. Wormeley ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What do you suppose I let you in for, Evangeline ? I want to know all the gossip about me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, do you ? &amp;quot; Evangeline settled in, threw off her boa, and bared her ankles to the blaze. &amp;quot;What fun! Well, of course, you know- But do let me say first, that I personally utterly approve of you-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;ro would ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, you see I am a thorough woman of the world. Nothing shocks me that the smart set does. I adore sharp contrasts and antithesi-is that right ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I dare say. I keep off such dangerous ground myself. Go on. What do they say ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, you know, you are not taking it quite as they think you ought. Mrs. Gedge is a wee bit jealous, as we all know, and the more Dr. Gedge asks her to look you up, the more she won&amp;apos;t, and it&amp;apos;s worth as much as his life is worth to offer to go and see you himself, or he&amp;apos;d have bounded! Madge Wormeley&amp;apos;s really all right, only Mortimer is the usual reactionary husband, don&amp;apos;t you know, the kind of Helmer man we all used to talk about ! He told Nora-Madge, I mean-that he&amp;apos;d have had no objection to her supporting you, if you had been keeping quiet, but you&amp;apos;ve chosen your atmosphere wrong, for him, don&amp;apos;t you know, being consoled all over the place by the son of the &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Nephew.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-Nephew of the man your husband-attacked. And they say you went to call on the barmaid-he liked, and gave her money ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is that all &amp;quot; &amp;quot;No. You&amp;apos;re supposed-you know what people are !-to have a flirtation with the policeman who brought you the newsthat he&amp;apos;s in and out the house constantly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; After my cook, perhaps ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; That may be. I&amp;apos;ll tell Madge Wormeley. But the worst thing you&amp;apos;ve done is casting me off so completely. Me, the only woman in all Wimbledon who could understand you, knew you through and through-a real broad-minded woman who went a little too far, even for them, and you kept me away ? As if, Madge said, you couldn&amp;apos;t stand even a tolerant person seeing what you were up to ! Some of those motor rides, for instance.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why didn&amp;apos;t I take you, eh ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well, once or twice, say, to give a decent colour to the business. It isn&amp;apos;t as if you disliked me ! &amp;quot; She looked keenly at Betsey, wondering if she had really read the article before her-Betsey, who now looked so innocent and unwitting. She concluded that no generous woman could be so full of guile as to conceal her knowledge thus perfectly, and felt emboldened to say appealingly: &amp;quot; Now, my dear old pal, why wouldn&amp;apos;t you make all right and see me sometimes ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; To tell you the truth, old chum, I forgot you! So much going on! I&amp;apos;ve never had a dull moment since the day Wilfrid was tried.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, Betsey, I&amp;apos;m so sorry for Mrs. Wormeley, she would so enjoy hearing you say that! You&amp;apos;re just the sameepigrammatical, and cool as ever! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You can go and tell her you&amp;apos;ve seen me-retail all my bons mots! It&amp;apos;s her day at home. Good Lord, what a way back it seems ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Gracious ! So it is her day. Do you remember those sort of things ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Submerged landmarks-yes.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You have got an edge on you, dear. They&amp;apos;d be simply delighted to see you, I believe ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; And hustle me into a cupboard as soon as they heard Mr. W.&amp;apos;s step in the hall. No, thank you. Have they still got Selina ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Gracious, no! No more than you&amp;apos;ve got Georgie.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I could have kept Georgie if I&amp;apos;d liked,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Altamont with vivacity. &amp;quot; She didn&amp;apos;t leave to better herself, like I&amp;apos;ll bet you a shilling Selina did, but to get married. Crump&amp;apos;s man, in Wimbledon-a very decent young fellow.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Well, never mind. Let&amp;apos;s talk about something interesting. That petition they&amp;apos;ve sent up-do you think it&amp;apos;ll have any effect ? I ask you because I know you&amp;apos;re broad-minded enough to look at the question dispassionately, aren&amp;apos;t you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, quite. I&amp;apos;ll answer you. Listen. Do you suppose, Evangeline Simmons, that if I had thought Wilfrid would get off, and that it was on the cards I might have to go on living here among you all, that I should have cared to set all the neighbourhood against me ? No. It would have been silly. But I knew from the very first, I had an instinct or whatever you like, that he&amp;apos;d be hanged. So I wanted to make the place too hot to hold me, and to have every excuse for getting out of it. I&amp;apos;m glad you all took your cues so quick and dropped me ! It doesn&amp;apos;t make it at all hard to leave, as it might have been, if people had been kind to me and stood by me. You left it to an outsider to do that, a man who had the grace to come to Miss Altamont&amp;apos;s funeral because he respected her. Think of that !&amp;quot; Her voice broke. &amp;quot; And as for me, why, you have all been horrid to me. Perfectly detestable! You too, Evangeline! Don&amp;apos;t suppose I don&amp;apos;t know quite well what you&amp;apos;ve done in particular-the shabby trick you played on me! You can&amp;apos;t think, can you, why I didn&amp;apos;t speak of it before ? The fact is I didn&amp;apos;t care to. I&amp;apos;m going away to shake the mean tale-bearing dust of you all off my feet, and break new ground, good clean fresh ground instead of the weary old dust of a squalid suburb. You can call me cynical if you like ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I do,&amp;quot; murmured Miss Simmons hastily. &amp;quot; Yes. You used to admire it in me ! Well, take this from me now, and for ever after hold your peace. I am not going to marry Mr. Veere. I won&amp;apos;t hide anything from you. I&amp;apos;m not going to bind myself to any one-on this side of the Atlantic, at least.&amp;quot; Evangeline looked stunned with this impact of intelligence. &amp;quot; Well, this is news! &amp;quot; she mumbled. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ve got what you came for, haven&amp;apos;t you &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think, Betsey, all the same, if you&amp;apos;ll allow me to say so, that you might show a little human feeling for the poor man whose wife you still are. A husband is a husband-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not when he&amp;apos;s doing time,&amp;quot; said Betsey, jumping up. &amp;quot;You see I&amp;apos;m bent on disgusting you. I have. Joy! It serves you right. Now go and tell them all. Here comes Mr. Veere. I must send you away. &amp;quot; Oh, Betsey, mayn&amp;apos;t I stop and see him ? I met him once.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; On my doorstep. I heard. No, I am afraid I must really ask you to go. Mr. Veere has a horror of meeting local people. I&amp;apos;ve promised never to let him run the risk of it, so you see- &amp;quot; XXII Veere passed Miss Simmons as she went out, and took not the slightest notice of her beyond giving her immensely too much room to pass him. His mien was so portentous that Ada Cox, in whom all the cords that tent-pegged her down to conventionality seemed to have snapped, walked into the room with him when she introduced him, and witnessed his greeting of her mistress. Furthermore, he did not offer to shake hands with Betsey. She rose, startled, and Ada from behind exclaimed: &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s something! You&amp;apos;ve got news ! &amp;quot; Veere did not seem to be aware that it was not Betsey who spoke. His teeth were set. He flung off his motor-coat, revealing the alert stripling imprisoned in the hoggish shape of custom. . . . &amp;quot; Hasn&amp;apos;t your faithful Whortleberry told you The Home Secretary&amp;apos;s commuted the sentence ! &amp;quot; It was Ada, her eyes bleared with the tears that were coming, who shouted, &amp;quot; What&amp;apos;s that mean l &amp;quot; He answered her. &amp;quot; Penal servitude, and a woman tied to him for life ! &amp;quot; Ada fell prone on the floor. Betsey, who had been standing with her hands down, knuckles firmly planted on the table, came round and helped Veere to pick the woman up. &amp;quot; Oh, Wilfrid-Wilfrid-not to be hanged-not to be killed!&amp;quot; she moaned as she fell into complete unconsciousness. &amp;quot;Brutes we are!&amp;quot; Veere murmured under his breath, as according to Betsey&amp;apos;s concise directions he carried her upstairs. Ada&amp;apos;s tragic unseeing eyes seemed to glare down at Betsey as her head dangled over the banisters. &amp;quot; Oh, take care, take care! &amp;quot; Betsey murmured, shame-stricken, but indeed he was doing as well as he could. &amp;quot; Keep Billy quiet ! &amp;quot; she said to Veere when he left the room, having laid Ada on her bed. The poor frightened child had followed them up. The door of the room where his mother lay was sharply closed, and Veere, sitting down on the stairs, took the boy on his knee. &amp;quot; Billy ! -Billy!&amp;quot; he murmured. He could think of nothing else to say. But Billy, fortunately, liked him, trusted him, and forthwith rammed his head between Veere&amp;apos;s chin and breast and lay still so. Veere reproached himself for his crudeness, shading into selfishness. He should have been less sudden in his revelation. He had been absorbed in the effect of this piece of intelligence on his and Betsey&amp;apos;s fortunes; wondering so deeply how she would take it, and if she would still adhere to her plans of the other day; he had forgotten to be gentle with the other poor creature, whose heart was concerned in the salvation of Wilfrid Altamont, and to whom his news was so outrageously joyful that it should have been softened to her nerves, seared with long waiting and suspense. To Betsey it represented part of a mere business calculation-the reprieve was inopportune, untoward, but not of vital significance, since she cared for neither Wilfrid nor himself. He thought her cruel to Altamont . . . she was running counter to his own wishes . . . she was hard, as they said. . .. The door of the bedroom opened and Betsey came out. Her eyes were blazing, her hair looked alive. At once all his love and passion returned at the sight of her. She beckoned to Billy. &amp;quot; Go to your mother, Billy.&amp;quot; The child unwound his arms from Veere&amp;apos;s neck and sidled into the room Betsey had vacated. She evidently introduced him and then closed the door on him. &amp;quot; She&amp;apos;s better now,&amp;quot; Betsey said in a strange voice that he had never heard her use before. There was caution, too, in her walk as she approached him, and leaned on the banister at the stair-head. He was going to get up, but she signed to him to remain where he was. That poor girl ! &amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;Do you realise that she fainted for joy ? Joy ! She adores my brute of a husband.&amp;quot; Her eyes narrowed. She looked down inquiringly at him. &amp;quot; I suppose you&amp;apos;re quite sure the news is true? Because if it isn&amp;apos;t t &amp;quot; True as death, and far more horrible. Oh, Betsey, what will you do now ? Tell me. Let me help. I&amp;apos;ll do anything you like.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Look here ! &amp;quot;-she spoke roughly, permitting, at least not denying, his clasp of her knees as she stood over him. She made a violent dab at her chin with a handkerchief, then spoke with a rush&amp;quot; Do you still want me &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Of course I do.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then I&amp;apos;ll come to you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; D&amp;apos;ye love me, Betsey ? &amp;quot; was his stiff, unaccountable answer. A deep wave of distrust washed over his love for this woman as she stood there, blushing, for the first time in his knowledge of her. He was actuated by a desire to probe her motives judicially, to sift them to the bottom once for all, while her soul stood naked before him and her cheeks blushed for her words of self-revelation. Then let the glamour steal over the beloved again, and he would give way to it. But he must know the truth, so far as she could tell him, first. Betsey replied squarely, as he would have her. &amp;quot; No. I feel to you as I always told you I did. Half and half. Nothing to speak of. As Miss Altamont felt to your uncle, perhaps ? But I ask you now definitely if you want me ? I have made up my mind. Fate&amp;apos;s against me! I&amp;apos;ll fight it. I will not be tied for life to a convict with twenty years or more to serve-and a woman here fainting for joy at the news that kills me. She&amp;apos;s his real wife, as she&amp;apos;d have been his real widow. There! You can take me if you want me. I&amp;apos;m done with it all!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then, with your gracious permission-&amp;quot; he said, rising, and taking her in his arms. The great dull clock at the stair-head ticked out the parcels of her surrender. She lay there, blinking. She was pained by the irony piercing through the man&amp;apos;s cynical phrase. She was soothed, as the slow seconds counted themselves out, by her intimate awareness of its overcoming by the glamour that she knew how to cast over the first embrace. She did not know that Ernest Veere, permitting his inclination for her to have full sway, made at the same time a solemn reservation. &amp;quot;You trust me, at least ?&amp;quot; he asked, setting her on her feet again. &amp;quot;Yes,&amp;quot; she sighed. His kiss had moved her a little. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s a funny world, isn&amp;apos;t it, my sweetheart ? Well, come downstairs now, and help me on with my coat. I&amp;apos;ll be with you again this evening to arrange things.&amp;quot; She demurred. &amp;quot; Oh yes, they must be arranged. No tricks shall be played on you. I know you like people to be business-like. We shall see if your poor life is to be as maimed as you thought it would be. It all depends. Your ideal may be attained after all, some of it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What do you mean ? &amp;quot; She laughed, but the light had all gone out of her face, which was a little puffy, and heavy, and the lips clumsier in curve. &amp;quot; She&amp;apos;ll look like that when she&amp;apos;s fifty,&amp;quot; thought Veere, involuntarily. &amp;quot; Coarsish, like the old applewoman who had a stall near my school.&amp;quot; She helped him on with his coat. She murmured; &amp;quot; What do you mean by talking of my ideal ? I&amp;apos;ve smashed it up. I&amp;apos;ve promised to go to the dogs with you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s what it&amp;apos;s called, my dear.&amp;quot; He shrugged into the sleeves. &amp;quot;And that&amp;apos;s what it is. Don&amp;apos;t suppose I&amp;apos;m under any delusions as to what I&amp;apos;ve done. I&amp;apos;ve done it with my eyes open. The moment Ada fainted, I made up my mind to make you that proposal-and I have! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Yes, you did it and no mistake! &amp;quot; he answered, softly pinching her ear. Both speech and gesture had no relevance to his thought, and she felt it to be so. His frivolous attitude could not conceal a definite hardness concerning her, he was what a business customer might have called &amp;quot; nasty.&amp;quot; He continued: &amp;quot; You leave it to me, and don&amp;apos;t be so cocksure about your own destruction. You&amp;apos;ve led the ass to the water, but are you so sure you can make him drink ? Ass, I say. And obstinate at that ! . . . Good-bye-for the present ! &amp;quot; He was going, she looked so like a chidden child that he returned, to kiss her. &amp;quot;By Jove, you are a pretty woman, and I love you all the same! You&amp;apos;ll always get me, this way. . . . Will you give me some dinner when I come back &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Are you coming back ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, of course, why not ? I said I was. That woman-&amp;quot; he indicated the room above, where Ada lay, &amp;quot; won&amp;apos;t be about again to-night, will she ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No. I shall put her to bed, and give her some soup last thing.&amp;quot; Her eyes questioned his. &amp;quot; Had you rather I didn&amp;apos;t come back ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No.... I have no feeling either way,&amp;quot; she replied sturdily. XXIII It was early spring. Veere never missed April in England. He brought Betsey back from the Continent, where they had been travelling about for three months, and established her on his yacht, cruising in English waters. Mrs. Altamont liked England better than Paris or even Sicily. She was glad to have seen these places, though. She never wanted to go abroad again, and she was thinking so, as she stood and sat and lounged on Cowes Pier. She had got them to row her in from the yacht to meet Veere, who had run up to London about some business, chiefly connected with her affairs, she believed, and who was reutrning by the Cowes boat, due even now. He would have seen Ada Cox, left sole chatelaine of Worksop House and with Betsey&amp;apos;s income to draw upon for herself and the children. It had been formally made over to her. The lease of W&amp;apos;orksop House ran for a few years more, but Veere was going to dispose of the remainder, and Ada was to retain the sum accruing from that negotiation as well. By-and-by, Mrs. Altamont had arranged to go back to Ada for a short while to help her to &amp;quot; get out.&amp;quot; Then the connection would cease. Ada had been offered, and had accepted, the post of housekeeper, cicerone and caretaker at Angernoune Castle, which Sir Joris Veere had bought eight years ago as an experiment, in a highly dilapidated condition, from Lady Dobrie&amp;apos;s father. Much money had been spent on it, the Keep, tempo William II., was bolstered up and rendered habitable. But that ancient fabric, it had been found, would not stand the introduction of electric lighting and dinner-lifts and other modem appliances, so a modem house, at fabulous cost, had been built in the courtyard, whence the flag flew when the family were in residence, and not enjoying the balmier airs of Mill Strand, Sir Joris&amp;apos;s place in Sussex. The purchase of decrepit Angemoune was a millionaire&amp;apos;s freak, an extravagance, a decided convenience to the vendors; yet the haughty impoverished nobleman who took his title from thence could never bear to accept Sir Joris Veere&amp;apos;s repeated handsome offers of hospitality. He had, however, no objection to allowing his daughter to marry the heir thereof. Ada, with her one surviving child-Little Katie had never &amp;quot; growed &amp;quot; but had died while Veere and Betsey were abroadmeant to wait there for Wilfrid. The cold north had no terrors for the city girl, fixed, rapt in her mulish central idea. Niched up there, in a medieval Keep, she would gain health, and look more picturesque than ever, while her boy would grow strong and hardy and defeat as far as possible any vicious inherited town instincts. Mrs. Altamont&amp;apos;s plans were of necessity vague. Not from a business point of view, indeed. She knew she was amply and solidly provided for. She and he had not minced the matter of the pecuniary basis of their alliance. Stock had been made over to her and invested in her name, she had an income for life-if she should leave Mr. Veere&amp;apos;s protection to-morrow! That night at Worksop House, when he came back and dined with her and they had settled things, she had been as hard as nails, almost rapacious in her determination to have the thing in black and white, something solid to depend on in this crumbling of her moral standards. Veere had almost hated her for a moment. The ugly joints of her character came uppermost, jogged forward with the violent rift in her self-respect. She meant, and showed that she meant, to sell herself dear. And he had not exacted the quid pro quo ! Even in Paris, she had only half realised it. She was tired, he was forbearing, he was a dear. They had been to see everything. They did monuments and plays together. He had bought her clothes and jewels. She had accepted them as one accepts gifts which one expects to have to repay in kind. At the end of a week she asked him seriously to buy her no more presents, her income, of which she had already received an instalment, would, she averred coldly, suffice to dress her and pay for her cabs unless he was with her. Her tone was sour and strictly business-like. He was not always with her. He treated her like a woman of the world, not as a pretty doll that he brought away to seduce. She was allowed to preserve her somewhat gloomy independence. He had friends in Paris, he preferred not to introduce her to them at all, to labelling her as his permanent companion. She did some of the monuments and some of the plays alone. He was never out of temper. They often talked of Dobr&amp;amp;e. In Italy she was happier. They led a life of errantry, riding about, bathing, mountaineering. Betsey was a frank tomboy; that side of her nature had been in abeyance too. Her hair, warmed through and through by Italian sun, was more golden than ever. And the nice thing about Italy was that it was all new to Ernest too. They had adventures in Sicily, and after in Bosnia. Then when they reached England and got aboard, an exciting episode, which nearly resulted in the loss of the yacht off the tame little Needles, supervened. They had nearly died together, and yet, take it all in all, they were less intimate than they had been in those far back days when they had strolled about the streets of London together and scanned the posters for news of Betsey&amp;apos;s deliverance. That wretched, hasty moment on the stair-head, at Worksop House, had been a turning-point-which had decided nothing. Betsey&amp;apos;s move towards the social abyss had been checkmated by her guardian knight. She was grateful to him in theory, irritated in fact by her insistent surmise as to whether it had cost him anything to keep her virtuous ? Betsey was vain. She was waiting for him now, with several little rods in pickle for him, and only a lukewarm welcome. She found a sort of seat on the landing-stage and watched the boat ploughing its way to her. It held the man whose society pleased and delighted her, but whose attitude was a perpetual blister to her self-love. The steward of the Elisabetta (renamed in compliment to her) approached and touched his cap. &amp;quot; I came to tell you, madam, that there&amp;apos;s nothing to prevent our getting off as soon as the skipper comes. The washing is in.&amp;quot; The Cowes boat made the pier. Veere was coming off, hurrying along the raying boards, slender, business-like, alerthe was two years younger than she. &amp;quot; Here you are, Betsey ! I&amp;apos;ve settled everything. St. Malonow ! We can get off this afternoon-has the washing come?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, Masters just told me so.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s good. Come down to Bingley&amp;apos;s. I must get a few things. I&amp;apos;ve just remembered that I haven&amp;apos;t any films.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes ! &amp;quot; said Betsey agreeably. They turned and went off together, chatting amicably, like a husband and wife. They were returning to the yacht for luncheon, their arms laden with odds and ends of marine stores, cigarettes, and films, when Betsey touched his arm: &amp;quot; A lady, bowing and beckoning to you!&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, I say! Good luck! It&amp;apos;s Dobr&amp;amp; and her Miss Taylor. His honest face radiant with good fellowship, he went forward to meet them, and Betsey fell back and studied a stationer&amp;apos;s window. Blind rage leaped up in her heart. She condemned it, yet it sprang up anew. She heard all they said. &amp;quot; Oh, I say, Ernest, angel, lend me threepence ! We are lunching at East Cowes Castle, and I&amp;apos;ve not got enough to pay for the tram boat across Medina.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Here, take sixpence,&amp;quot; said Veere. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s awkward borrowing coppers of your hostess, however rich, to come back, isn&amp;apos;t it ? Where are you two staying ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; On the Godiva, my godfather&amp;apos;s yacht, you know. I say, where&amp;apos;s that pretty woman got to that was with you ? She&amp;apos;s hidden herself somewhere! Oh, I suppose I oughtn&amp;apos;t to ask ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh yes, you may ask.&amp;quot;9 &amp;quot; And you&amp;apos;ll tell me she&amp;apos;s a Mrs. Jones, wife of an old college friend ! It isn&amp;apos;t the person you&amp;apos;ve renamed your yacht after ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, you twigged that, dyou ? Well, now be off to your lunch, and keep yourself respectable. Who is it has got East Cowes Castle this season ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Very rich Australians. Good-bye. We may come to tea with you-and the wife of Altamont.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Shall have sailed ! &amp;quot; Veere called after her as he rejoined Betsey, who came out from behind the sheltering eaves of Binglev&amp;apos;s like a chidden child. When they were in the dinghy, being rowed out to the Elisabetta, she said softly, playing with the fringed end of the tiller roe, &amp;quot; I wish you&amp;apos;d marry her soon.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Lady Dobrie.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Never was further from it in my life! Why do you say that sort of thing You are always saying that sort of thing now.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Am I a cross-patch ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Rather.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I was nicer-in the Worksop House days, eh &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You were gayer.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I was! I was! Isn&amp;apos;t it funny! I suppose, if I&amp;apos;d been like this, an ill-tempered virago-as I am now-you&amp;apos;d never have wanted to take Andromeda away from her rock.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t say that ! &amp;quot; He was casting about in his mind to say something more, his answer struck him as too sincere, but the end of the short trip had come, and he helped Betsey out and up. He gave her hand a little squeeze, and said, &amp;quot; Come and smoke a cigarette.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I think I&amp;apos;ll go to my cabin now, and have a real good cry, till after we&amp;apos;ve started! &amp;quot; He laughed. &amp;quot; Nerves! You! Did the meeting with our young friend upset you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, rather. I believe I wanted you to grasp your nettle and introduce me. After all, I&amp;apos;m quite respectable, bating the little fact that I&amp;apos;m the wife of a convict.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, she&amp;apos;d rather like that. But the other thing-I couldn&amp;apos;t have persuaded her of it, at any rate.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Doesn&amp;apos;t she know you&amp;apos;re a crank?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Not to that extent ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Nor did I,&amp;quot; Betsey just breathed, as she ran down the companion and bade the steward, whom she met below, bring her a glass of wine and some biscuits to her cabin for lunch. She meant to lie down till they were off. Veere heard her close the skylight of her state-room, she did not mean him to hear her cry-if she cried ?-then ! Her expressed determination to do so did not disturb him much; he thought it rather nice of her to announce a cataclysm of nerves and set a limit to it. She was given to having nerves now, it was a new phase. What she said was true enough. She was not nearly so good-tempered as she used to be. She had a tongue and she used it on him sometimes-her benefactor! He was her benefactor-not her lover. A busy, bustling, hustling man, he was not sufficiently versed in the ways of women to realise that his attitude was the goad that drove Betsey&amp;apos;s tongue, and made her occasionally smite him whom she should have spared. He was more or less happy, which was all he ever expected to be. He was a materialist and a crank. It is your idealists, your conventional moralists who cannot be happy with a woman without seducing her. He was neither nervous nor excitable; his emotions waited on his fancies. Betsey had &amp;quot; huffed &amp;quot; him too deeply, that moment, two months ago, on the stairs, when in despite of Fate she had flung herself at him and said: &amp;quot;Take me, yet believe me I have no pleasure in the giving.&amp;quot; His positive domineering nature bore her some malice. She had made a moral convenience of him. XXIV They went down to dinner in the little state-room. Her eyes were as bright as if she had not carried out her threat, while the mind behind them was full of cross motives that chased each other hither and thither, and peeped in and out of its recesses like black and white cats in a suburban garden. She sat down with a little air of furtive wildness that was charming. There was a streak of blue ribbon in her hair and the steward and Veere thought they had never seen her look so well. The pocket of Veere&amp;apos;s smoking-jacket bulged with papers. &amp;quot; We&amp;apos;ll go over these papers after dinner,&amp;quot; he said as soon as Masters had left the room. &amp;quot; But it&amp;apos;s all done, and all done right. You&amp;apos;re a woman of means, like Miss Altamont of famous memory ! &amp;quot; These were the little things he said that jarred, and at once evoked the protecting motherly instinct in the woman of tact. She did not know that Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e had once remarked that if Veere hadn&amp;apos;t been so clever, he&amp;apos;d have been a bounder, but with far less knowledge of the world than that possessed by the green girl of rank, Betsey realised that sentiment, which Veere disdained, is tact&amp;apos;s best ally, and that the strenuous life of business is too apt to brush aside the thin cobwebs of tradition that would cloak and veil for us half life&amp;apos;s inevitable grossnesses. &amp;quot; Life is ugly, life is earnest. And the smart is not its goal !&amp;quot; was a parody she was fond of making. But she answered, complying with him: &amp;quot; How much have I now?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Fifteen hundred a year secured to you - safe from all interference from me, even if we quarrel.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; How perfectly hateful it sounds ! &amp;quot; She tried to thank him but could not, her lips framed the pettish exclamation instead. &amp;quot; Anyhow, Miss Altamont would have approved. A thousand a year, which I shall retire on when you have married Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e, though after all I&amp;apos;ve nothing to retire from! I&amp;apos;m not earning my salary.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t talk like that !&amp;quot; She could shock him easily. He could not shock her. Masters came back into the room, and she asked Veere a colourable indifferent question: &amp;quot; When is Ada going to Angernoune ? &amp;quot; August.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Shall I go there and stay with her?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, do,&amp;quot; said he calmly, though it was the first time the idea had been mooted by the wayward woman. &amp;quot; It would be all right. I rather wanted you to. Let me tell you about it. There are practically two complete houses standing in the courtyard. That is big enough to enclose a whole township, and did, in the Middle Ages. The old Keep is where Ada will live, and keep it clean-with help from the village, of course-and show it on Thursdays. That was the arrangement in my uncle&amp;apos;s time. Then there&amp;apos;s the completely modem building he built opposite-an act of vandalism, and Veere&amp;apos;s Folly they called it; I never can see the harm, personally, but then I&amp;apos;ve got no taste.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think it&amp;apos;s a cursed thing to remove landmarks ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why-if they&amp;apos;re so crocky they can&amp;apos;t stand up, let alone habitable ? The old people were just like me, Betsey, if you only think of it! They never scrupled to pull about or pull down the old and insanitary or even the too small to hold them. They&amp;apos;d have laughed in your face if you&amp;apos;d talked to them about the Preservation of Ancient Buildings Society-thought it all your eye and your d-d cheek! They considered that they had ideas of their own quite as good as the ideas of the previous man.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, once you go back to medieval times, they wert as good. The ages of Faith, you know. Men without a religion can&amp;apos;t have an architecture.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Tosh, dear! It&amp;apos;s got nothing to do with it. You&amp;apos;ve been reading Ruskin.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Among others. But I do think the spirit of the ageand you&amp;apos;ve got it finely exemplified-is antagonistic to beauty. Inventions for stupid, selfish, besotted comfort-hideous mouldings by the piece-creaky doors to not fit anywhereand all your minds given up to labour-saving appliances &amp;quot; &amp;quot; The old people hadn&amp;apos;t to think of saving labour when they&amp;apos;d got slaves. Thomas of Lancaster put thousands of men on to the neighbouring castle, Kymarays. You shall go and see it. Wish we had &amp;apos;em now, instead of these Trades-Union-ridden, uppish, brawling masses we have to work with! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t, Ernest. I happen to know you are awfully good to your men and they adore you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Have to be! Well, to resume. There we have these two complete dwelling houses connected by an underground passage. When Uncle Joris had one of his big, dull houseparties, I used to have a bed in the Keep-in the haunted room for preference. I&amp;apos;ll go there this time. Dobrie and her little lot wouldn&amp;apos;t care to dig me out there, and stick my sheets together with acid drops, even in the daytime. She&amp;apos;s got no moral pluck at all. She&amp;apos;s afraid of ghosts.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;When is she coming ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well, you see-did I tell you?&amp;quot; He went on, without waiting for the reply which, indeed, she was not minded to give, for it was in the affirmative and would have muzzled his further explanation she longed to hear. &amp;quot; I asked her long ago to play hostess for me in the home of her ancestors for the month of August. Do you mind ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, of course not ! She was invited before me,&amp;quot; replied Betsey sedately. &amp;quot; And I don&amp;apos;t see very well how we could clash-I in the old house, and she in the new.&amp;quot; She looked across the table at him, using all the power of appeal of which her eyes were capable. &amp;quot; I would so like to beg a promise of you. May I ? Say at once if you think you can&amp;apos;t do it ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You sweet baby! What ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Promise you won&amp;apos;t propose to her while I am there-if I do settle to come.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll promise that, easily-if you on your side will faithfully promise to come,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot; And-do you think I shall ever propose to her at all ? I&amp;apos;m very half-hearted. A month&amp;apos;s reign at Angernoune along of me might choke her off from caring to reign there altogether. You know I don&amp;apos;t love her. She knows it-or she will. And when the sacrifice is consummated I see myself flying out of our big receiving house in Belgravia or Bloomsbury to have tea with you in your little nest in Brompton-or perhaps you&amp;apos;ll choose Kensington ? &amp;quot; She gave a little moan-of disgust, discomfiture, alienation. He was really rather trying. &amp;quot; Ernest,&amp;quot; she spoke severely, &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll ask you one question, without prejudice, mind! Why, if you don&amp;apos;t care for Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e more than that, do you dare to contemplate marrying her ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Shall I tell you ?&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot;and then you&amp;apos;ll see that you&amp;apos;ve known the answer to your own question all along ? I am ambitious. For ambition I would sacrifice anything, even love. I&amp;apos;d certainly sacrifice Love. One passion&amp;apos;s as good as another. There are only three that really move the world. Ambition, Revenge, and Love. I choose Ambition for my ruling one.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You make a mistake.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You say that because you&amp;apos;re a woman. Women haven&amp;apos;t got beyond Love yet. I can see what Dobrie is. I can see that, try as I might, I couldn&amp;apos;t make her unhappy. So why shouldn&amp;apos;t I marry her and improve my own position, which I care about as an actor cares about his art or a politician his party ? By the way, I should stand for Angershire. Dobr&amp;amp;e will get that for me, and I shall get her the money she wants-quite nicely, you know, but it&amp;apos;s in the Angernoune blood. They are Norman peasants au fond and money&amp;apos;s their god. Dobrie, personally, is not exigeant. Give her a child and a couple of motor-cars and she&amp;apos;ll be as happy as the day is long.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No. Au fond she is like other women, once you&amp;apos;re married to her, she won&amp;apos;t stay a schoolgirl ! The baby-or the carwill bring her on. Then-where Love isn&amp;apos;t, Jealousy rushes in, and instead of helping you in your schemes she may hinder you. Now I&amp;apos;ve done. You said it might be without prejudice.&amp;quot; She had saddened him. He fiddled with the spoons on the table. Masters came and deposited a coffee-maker in full blast. He spoke. &amp;quot;Of course, without prejudice. Perhaps you&amp;apos;re right ? One has to take risks, and marriage is the biggest gamble of all. I&amp;apos;m getting commonplace, am I not ? Anyhow, I&amp;apos;m with you now-you, my chosen companion-the woman who&amp;apos;s never bored me once since I&amp;apos;ve known her.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; A &amp;apos;dead cert &amp;apos; of amusement,&amp;quot; she said bitterly. &amp;quot; Well, I must play up, I suppose, or else you&amp;apos;ll complain of me. You did to-day, I remember.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, Betsey, I should love you if you cut your hair off and preached all the time, so be as cross as you like.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Love me-do you say ? &amp;quot; she asked with wistful contempt. &amp;quot; Well, inferior being that I am, crassly material, you do stand for Love with me ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; The passion you rank after Ambition and Revenge!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, not quite that!&amp;quot; he whispered. &amp;quot; Let me kiss you, and see i &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I won&amp;apos;t let you play with fire,&amp;quot; she said with a forced laugh. &amp;quot; Fire ? &amp;quot; I am fire, for the present.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Are you ? Yes, by Jove, you are, a regular burning bush! Only-such a pal as well ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I&amp;apos;m here, alone with you. I dare say you find it rather trying, but Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s interests must be safeguarded.&amp;quot; She busied herself with the coffee. He was silent. She could not know that he was thinking of Dobr&amp;amp;e, in her conventionally cut dress that formally exhibited a brief section of her chest-somehow one could not think of it as her breast ! He had never seen Betsey except in a high black gown such as she wore now. &amp;quot; Why do you never wear a low-necked dress he asked her suddenly. &amp;quot; Because I&amp;apos;ve never in my life had occasion to wear one,&amp;quot; said she, in as bitter a tone as she had ever used. The answer revealed at once the depths of the suburban horror she had suffered. &amp;quot; I have never been asked out to proper dinner in my life, and I wasn&amp;apos;t going to bother to dress for a few scrubby Town Hall concerts.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; The pathos of that!&amp;quot; He laughed. &amp;quot; It is the whole Book of job in a sentence. Now I see why you were so keen to come out and live-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;With you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I suppose no one has ever told you that you arc ten times more charming en Cinderella ? I am sure it i; so, at any rate, though I&amp;apos;ve never seen you dicollti. That plain dress of soft black, like a nun&amp;apos;s, except that you&amp;apos;ve no wimple and that your round white neck rises frm and straight from it like a pillar-of alabaster, shall I say ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I hate frills and horse-collars,&amp;quot; said she, blushing at his praise. &amp;quot; And I suppose my neck is self-supporting because I don&amp;apos;t put it in stays. Never did. The kettle boils ! &amp;quot; She began to pour out the coffee. &amp;quot; See how my hand shakes ! I&amp;apos;m as nervous as a cat. I cried dreadfully this afternoon. I believe you are right. These prolonged tSte-J-thte between a man and a woman generally lead to nerves and neurasthenia and so on. I&amp;apos;ve got it in my arm, all down. That&amp;apos;s why, I suppose, dull stupid marriage is found to be the best arrangement for spacing out one&amp;apos;s raptures. Sugar ? &amp;quot; XXV Angernoune Keep, like a grey-haired respectable man of science, caught and hemmed in by a gathering of smart modern people, stood isolated, bewildered, and mediaeval in the vast courtyard, opposite the sophisticated Gothic of the new Dwelling House. Grass no longer grew from the roof of the tower, shorn of its battlements. Battlements had been supplied, the grass had been tidied away; but the white cockle-shells of pilgrims still dotted the lower courses of the north wall, and Ada&amp;apos;s boy, standing on the pediment, used to try in vain to pull them out of the mortar, welded together by the traditions of Roman science. Modem and old seemed to stand and hate each other; the young sneered, the old frowned. The boy linked them, playing quietly round the low Norman doorway that gave entrance into the Keep, but longing child-like to pull the shiny electric bell fixed in the modem oak portal of the Dwelling House. Billy was growing healthy, he had no dislike of the strong sea blast that drove perpetually round the comer of the lone Keep, and tossed his hair, and kept him in continual disarray. It lifted, too, the white locks of Boris, the great Newfoundland, who couched and curveted all day on the tiny lawn whence sprang the carefully husbanded ivy that was supposed to soften the angles of the Dwelling House. Nothing clothed the squareness of the Keep, the north wind took care of that. It was difficult to be complicated in a place like this. The wife of Altamont, maimed by suburbanity and short views, imagined her cribbed and cabined thoughts to unroll like banners in this noble wind; the clear air revealed the deeps, and the deeps were pure and translucent, after all. She was glad she had come. She thought that, if that great change called marriage really should enter into Veere&amp;apos;s fortunes, that winter, she would choose to remain here with Ada. She, then, would be naught but a wounded animal, and the Keep at Angernoune would be the lair to which she would creep wherein to sit and nurse her sorrow. The guardroom, as it was called, which comprised nearly the whole ground floor, was dark and soothing, the windows, mere slits for archers to shoot from, could hardly illumine the lowpitched, arched roof, whence all remnants of the authentic plaster of the time had been scraped off by the hand of the restorer, leaving the deeply pitted surface that had held it so well. The floor&amp;apos;s covering of stout hempen matting muffled the feet of outsiders coming in. Betsey chiefly habited this part, leaving the kitchen and housekeeper&amp;apos;s room that had been carved out of it to Ada and her child. During her visit, she agreed to relieve the less well-informed woman of her job of showing the Keep on Thursdays, a task which the latter detested. But Betsey did it con amore. She got up her facts carefully, from some old county histories which she found upstairs. Ada had not been expected to do more than render herself mistress of the sixpenny guide that lay by the Visitors&amp;apos; Book. Local antiquaries, visiting the Castle with their friends, set down the pretty intelligent woman&amp;apos;s attention to their words as a mark of intelligence, and posted her in many a recondite fact which she was able to retail again. She became quite an accredited cicerone in Angershire, where the castle of Angernoune was the staple of antiquarian discussion and interest. Ada must of course resume her duties as soon as Veere should join Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s party. It came numerous, eager and bustling on the first of September, in motors, and bus loads, with lorries for its belongings, and thin maids and stout maids, and one hairdresser-Lady Blessington&amp;apos;s. Betsey in the indulgence of her boundless curiosity, so strangely divested of morbidity, disinfected as it were by the holy airs of Angershire, showed them all over the antique structure they pretended so cleverlyto be interested in. They did not notice the exceptionality of the cicerone, perhaps her beauty was not quite so glaring; she had grown thinner, paler, sharper featured, and attracted less superficial observation than she would have done a year ago. Before opening the door she always peered through a side loop-window, mounting up into the embrasure the better to ascertain that Veere did not form one of the party seeking admittance. He was pledged to write and tell her when he was on his way. He was detained for the present in Town by some rather tiresome business, relative to his succession to his uncle&amp;apos;s fortune. But she knew him, he was the sort of person who might motor down without the slightest warning, on a sudden impulse. That is, if the impulse to see her again should become too strong. She had his heart-such as it was. Lady Maude Erskine-Robertson visited the Keep, escorted by the novelist, Lee-Brice. They looked all over together, but Lady Maude soon tired of Lee-Brice&amp;apos;s real and insulting interest in antiquities and cried off. &amp;quot; I promised Vallance to have a game of tennis with him,&amp;quot; she declared as soon as they got on to the roof, &amp;quot; and I see him down there on the common, actually-waiting for me and letting his moustache droop and looking miserable.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, they said there was a view up here ! &amp;quot; answered Lee-Brice, without sarcasm. &amp;quot; Let us go down.&amp;quot; Betsey piloted them past the haunted room, which she never showed to visitors if she could help. It was Veere&amp;apos;s room, and she slept in it. They got to the bottom of the stairs; she had felt the novelist&amp;apos;s eyes in her back as they went down, and was not surprised when he whispered to her at the door, &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m coming back.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Like Gilderoy in the ballad ! &amp;quot; she thought, laughing, as she waited. She wondered if she would be called upon to reel off &amp;apos;any more facts about Angernoune, or if he was like his books? She could take care of herself, even with the author of The Red Corpuscles. He wanted no more facts, and yet he was not in the least like his books. He sincerely wanted to gloat on antiquity, to feel the atmosphere of mediaevalism. He knew more about Angernoune than she could tell him, and though he had probably got it all up from the County History in the smoking-room of the Dwelling House, he managed, with literary sleight of hand, to reissue it with the imprint of his own personality. He did not flirt with Mrs. Altamont, not so much as by the turn of an eyelid, but she had a subtle sense that he had come back to study her. He left her, with a consciousness of power suggested by his reticence, his pointed imperial, and his record of expurgation, and which he seemed to take pride in falsifying. There was nothing squalid, nothing morbid, nothing passionate about him. His pose was perfect. She enjoyed his visit. Lady Dobrie had a maid-of sorts-she wasn&amp;apos;t what either Betsey or Ada considered a proper maid. &amp;quot; More like a dresser at a theatre,&amp;quot; Ada said, and Ada knew. For Betsey, she had her uses. She manceuvred it. Miss Parker and Mrs. Cox, they knew not why or how, struck up a friendship, and sometimes, after dinner and when the wind was not too cold, the former would potter across and ring the bell of the doorway in the Keep, for the key of the underground door of communication between the two buildings had been lost. Betsey knew who had it in his safe keeping. Ada, her Billy safe tucked up in bed, would be sitting, mending, sewing, Betsey dreaming, playing endless patiences, to soothe her mind before she slept. . . . The woman&amp;apos;s talk was all, as Betsey had supposed it would be, about her mistress, and incidentally, about Mr. Veere. The second time she came in to see them, she began, as usual, with a long competent sigh of satisfaction, to con her own perfections and business value. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know, I&amp;apos;m sure, whatever my lady would do without me ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; She always looks very nice,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Cox politely. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;m proud to say she does, but she wouldn&amp;apos;t last a day if it wasn&amp;apos;t for me washing and mending her. Not that she&amp;apos;s not neat, she&amp;apos;s got it in her, she&amp;apos;s not like Lady Maude, overfond of shoving things on-but would you believe it, Mrs. Cox, that poor girl, for all she&amp;apos;s a title, hasn&amp;apos;t got more than a couple o&amp;apos; pair of silk stockings to her name ? And the ladders that come in them along of the suspenders, you know, it takes me half my time mending them ! And washing her veils-chiffon will wash, but it rightly ought to be cleaned. But, gracious, we can&amp;apos;t run to so manv cleaner&amp;apos;s bills! And her gloves-by rights a lady oughtn&amp;apos;t to wear darned gloves-but I&amp;apos;ll defy you to see my darns ! I join the long ones at the wrist same as the girl at the shop showed me-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s very good of you, isn&amp;apos;t it ?&amp;quot; said Betsey. &amp;quot; Well, I put my back into it, so to speak, when they engaged me. &amp;apos;Twas my first place. I wasn&amp;apos;t so particular. I took a fancy to her, a sporting chance. I said, I&amp;apos;ll see if I can&amp;apos;t get her married all off my own bat, and a nice husband to pay for her things. Maids bring these things off, more than you know. With a little help from other ladies, that take an interest to begin with-for reasons, mind you ! I&amp;apos;ll tell you a secret. Lady Maude&amp;apos;s got a bet on it. Last season we had several of Maude&amp;apos;s own dresses. Her maid didn&amp;apos;t like it at all, I can tell you, seeing those good clothes go past her ! She&amp;apos;s a fool, that Chaytor! I shouldn&amp;apos;t allow it if I were her. I mean to have my lady&amp;apos;s wardrobe when she&amp;apos;s married. I deserve it, I think, don&amp;apos;t you ? It&amp;apos;ll be worth while. I&amp;apos;m never going to leave her-not an Earl&amp;apos;s daughter like her, who&amp;apos;s under obligations to one. And Mr. Veere&amp;apos;s the kind of man who wouldn&amp;apos;t have me chucked.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mr. Veere ? &amp;quot; said Betsey, with a mute appeal in her eyes to Ada to ask the necessary question. Ada played up: &amp;quot; Is your lady marrying Mr. Veere, then ? &amp;apos; &amp;quot; Some time in December, I believe. The day ain&amp;apos;t settled, for the Earl don&amp;apos;t want it announced till-I&amp;apos;m sure I don&amp;apos;t know what it is exactly-something about business. Mr. Veere&amp;apos;s business. Seems as if he was in some sort of hole-something that&amp;apos;ll pass off. He&amp;apos;s a queer sort of man, though he&amp;apos;s rich.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is he odd ? &amp;quot; Again Ada spoke. Betsey vowed gratitude. &amp;quot; Well, it&amp;apos;s an uncomfortable sort of business-not my idea of an engagement, somehow ! He&amp;apos;s just as nice to everybody as he is to her, and more so. She cries about it sometimes, and she was never a crier ! It&amp;apos;s my belief he&amp;apos;s never kissed her properly, except once when he proposed-in the drawing-room of our flat, and Lady Maude was there, actually, in the room ! They call themselves modern, and that, but if you don&amp;apos;t holeand-corner over an engagement, when do you ? And an Earl&amp;apos;s daughter, too-so off-hand, not treating her respectful, I think ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; It seems a queer way to manage things,&amp;quot; Ada remarked. &amp;quot;But I say this; if he don&amp;apos;t care to kiss her or to be with her alone at all, it won&amp;apos;t come to nothing.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well, he gave her an engagement ring. They went and bought it themselves. He gave Lady Maude cart-blank. It&amp;apos;s a queer sort of stone, an archimandrite they call it, green by day and red by night-not a proper engagement ring at all. And although the engagement isn&amp;apos;t announced, she can wear it fast enough, for no one would ever take it for an engagement ring, I say.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why isn&amp;apos;t the engagement to be announced ? &amp;quot; said Mrs. Altamont, whose voice shook. &amp;quot; I told you, didn&amp;apos;t I ? There&amp;apos;s what you call a Pretender. Mr. Brooks was telling me, saying that the late Sir Joris Veere was married after all, and that the fellow claims he can prove it. The business is a company now-they can&amp;apos;t stop Mr. Veere being one of the managers, but his legacy and the places-it&amp;apos;s a lot of money to change hands, isn&amp;apos;t it, if Mr. Veere was to lose his case ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; l should be sorry,&amp;quot; said Ada with simple emphasis, &amp;quot; Mr. Veere&amp;apos;s been kind to me-putting me in here, and all.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It isn&amp;apos;t at all likely. Mr. Brooks says the other man hasn&amp;apos;t a ghost of a chance. Just good money wasted-his bringing the action, but he&amp;apos;s going to have a try for it, I&amp;apos;m told. Would he keep you on, Mrs. Cox ? Oh, I expect so! Good for you if he does. You&amp;apos;ve got a nice place of it, haven&amp;apos;t you ? Nothing to do but spin a tale about the old place once a week to the people who come. And visitors too, as much as you like. Your friend here is getting a nice blow, after London. You&amp;apos;re a Londoner, aren&amp;apos;t you, Mrs. - &amp;quot;Mrs. Adamson. I&amp;apos;m Mrs. Cox&amp;apos;s sister-in-law.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And I&amp;apos;m sure I hope it will do you good. You don&amp;apos;t look well, for all you&amp;apos;ve got such a nice colour. Rather nervous, aren&amp;apos;t you ? Circulation not very good, I expect. Do you get chilblains ? My lady does-cruel, in the winter, and a bit of a red nose too, at times. We have to be very careful ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I saw her come home from riding yesterday with a nose the colour of beetroot,&amp;quot; said poor Betsey. Ada thought the little ebullition of spite dangerous, and lest Miss Parker resented it, hastened to add: &amp;quot; She looks nice in the saddle.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes. She&amp;apos;s only just taken to that since she&amp;apos;s been engaged. Mr. Veere stood her the lessons and gave her the horse. But he&amp;apos;s never rode with her. Mr. Lee-Brice does now-in the Park. Isn&amp;apos;t he a fine figure of a man ? &amp;quot; Betsey cordially agreed. She had had enough. She withdrew her magnetism, and soon the loquacious creature took her departure and was literally blown across the courtyard, with her mincing London steps. XXVI Betsey, pondering in her little haunted bedroom, where she had gone anxiously after Miss Parker&amp;apos;s departure to ascertain if that lady&amp;apos;s remarks about her circulation bore the further implication of a red nose, absolved Ernest Veere from any double dealing in the matter of his engagement. He ha proposed to Lady Dobree before coming to Angernouned while Betsey was absorbed in the task of getting rid of Worksop,House in Ada&amp;apos;s interest and selling the furniture. She had been too busy to see him. &amp;apos;Twas loneliness had tossed him to Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s breast. He had been, moreover, practically engaged to the girl at a date prior to their first meeting in Charlton churchyard. . . It was sharp practice, though. She could not sleep, but lay tangled in her golden hair, crying through it, stifling her sobs in it, drawing meshes of it across her burning eyes. Half-way through the night her dismay culminated in an access of hysteria. She sobbed and shrieked and bit her pillow. Then she sat up, leaned forward and touched old Ginger, the cat, that professional soother of the menage of Worksop House, who lay curled up at the foot of her bed. He murmured pellucid response, a loving gurgle-no more. It comforted her a little. It was her one reaching out for sympathy. Ada, who knew her heart, also knew better than to console. Next day, Betsey took Billy and went to the Harker Rocks to get shells. She and the little boy went barefoot, paddling in and out of the little pools, like eyes with lids of yellow sand, that lie in the crevices of te long reefs of basaltic rocks half a mile from Angernoune. Walking like this, the distance was as good as doubled. Billy with his short legs might get tired, so she presently anchored him at a single-handed game in one of the eight little sandy coves that lie at the Harker Rocks, each one hidden from, and as beautiful as the other. She had no hat-she seldom wore one-and she had let her hair down, half savage, half swagger, and left her hairpins in charge of Billy, while she prospected a little, to find what shells might linger in the next bay, having thoroughly explored this one. She came suddenly upon Mir. Lee-Brice, his great length stretched out full as he pored over the golden sand, intent on the same innocent quest as herself. Betsey stopped, looking down on him, a little but not deeply confused. ... He thought he had never seen-or imagined-such lovely feet, with nails as pink and polished as the tiny winged shells he was even now collecting, prying them out of the fine fringe of coal that lay like a moustache on the lips of the strand. He gazed at the fair feet boldly, they were nearer to his line of vision than her face. And they were at least as beautiful. Lee-Brice was a man of tact. He did not at any time outrage conventionality, he treated it cavalierly, and knew how to be indiscreet without indiscretion. Rising to his full height, dignified, graceful, easy, for he was a man in his prime, he addressed Betsey, after due pause for consideration of her beauty. He did not call her goddess ; with royal facility he remembered her name: &amp;quot; Mrs. Adamson, have you ever seen this shell ? It is very rare.&amp;quot; He held it out to her, giving its Latin name. &amp;quot; No, never. I didn&amp;apos;t know you were a-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Conchologist ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;-As well as a novelist.&amp;quot; She got out the little complimentary phrase with a shyness that charmed him, and continued to charm him as she went on &amp;quot;I have read your novel. I&amp;apos;ve got a copy.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Have you, indeed ? Then stick to it,&amp;quot; he said laughing. &amp;quot;You know what happened to that book ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes. It was a shame ! We all talked of nothing else at-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Where ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Where I lived.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;There are three copies in the Castle, then,&amp;quot; said he, respecting her reticence, though, author-like, he would have enjoyed hearing the data for his popularity. &amp;quot; Lady Maude Erskine-Robertson-the lady I &amp;apos; shed&amp;apos; the other day and came back to see over the Castle properly with you-has one, and Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e de Saye.&amp;quot; It isn&amp;apos;t a book for her at all.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You are quite right. But the young girls of the present day are too quick for us. They seem to shin up the ladder of the Impossible and Improper while we still have but one foot on the lower rungs. Luckily, the younger they are, the less it hurts them. You see they have not begun to think in colour yet. &amp;quot; How do you mean ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; As a line drawing, or a Flaxman outline, to a Titian, or a Tintoretto is the young girl&amp;apos;s consciousness-do you understand me ? Lines have no corporeality. Nature has no outlines, only washes of colour blocked in, grey or gorgeous as the case may be. Virtue in the next block to sin, is only demarcated by delicate differences of hue. So only you may know water from wine, the lamb from the wolf-and the last two lie down together, in society at least.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then if only one&amp;apos;s mind is like those empty whitewashed paddocks one sees at railway stations before you put the sheep and the goats in them, one can read your novels with impunity ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, as long as you remain unable to fill up the blanks or put words for the asterisks! But enough of my contributions to contemporary literature. Tell me, do you know that charming fellow, our host, who is engaged to supply the colour-scheme for Lady Dobree ? Pure accident ! &amp;quot; She winced. &amp;quot;Yes. I have spoken to him. Why do you say their engagement is pure accident ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Because I met him at a man&amp;apos;s dinner the night before Mlaude Erskine-Robertson faked that engagement, and I never knew a man less likely to make a woman an offer next day.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Did he think in line only then, too ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;No not exactly. . . . He was describing to me the type he admired, and it wasn&amp;apos;t hers. It was far more like yours.... He considers Romney&amp;apos;s Lady Hamilton to be the highest female type of beauty.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos; In his cups only,&amp;quot; said she quickly. &amp;quot; And anyhow, that&amp;apos;s no guide. Men who admire the fair type always marry dark women, just as women swear they like a clean-shaven man, and then go and marry an imperial! When is Mr. Veere due to come here ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;This afternoon.&amp;quot; No, is he ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, he wired suddenly to the butler-old Brooks-do you know him ? And Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e wanted the motor, both motors, in fact, to go over to Kelso. So he&amp;apos;s to be met in the &amp;apos;bus. Poor Veere, who simply can&amp;apos;t bear crawling! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, I do think he might have been allowed to have one of his own conveyances to bring him to his own place,&amp;quot; she replied nervously to this amiable man. They had walked on and now they came to the shielded cove where Billy&amp;apos;s intent head could be seen. He was having a dinner-party of shells on a bit of smooth golden sand. The ugly part of wading-shoes and stockings, of which the prettiest exemplars will look squalid, deprived of their context, lay near him: his and Betsey&amp;apos;s. Lee-Brice tactfully touched his hat and was making off, when a cry of the heart arrested him. &amp;quot; You little villain, what have you done with all my hairpins ? I left them here on this bit of rock &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I made &amp;apos;em all into boats and fish-hooks,&amp;quot; said Billy, thus objurgated and mildly shaken. &amp;quot; And they wouldn&amp;apos;t float and they&amp;apos;re at the bottom of the pool.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Which pool ? &amp;quot; The child indicated a neighbouring cranny, deep and secret, and Lee-Brice came to the rescue. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ll dredge them up for you, while you put on your shoes and stockings again, if I may ? &amp;quot; Five minutes later he reappeared, with a small handful of hairpins, to find Betsey clothed, shod, and demure, but with her lovely hair still spread over her shoulders. &amp;quot; Are these all ? &amp;quot; he asked. &amp;quot; Enough to work the ship, I dare say,&amp;quot; said Betsey, using them with celerity. Lee-Brice watched her, appreciatively, but not impertinently, and finally proposed to walk home with her. His dripping shirt-cuff, earned in her service, was a strong argument in favour of her acceptance of his escort; besides it was not like Betsey to object, although her heart was torn in two by the news that had been given her the night before by Lady Dobree&amp;apos;s maid, and the excitement of an imminent meeting with Veere. She never disdained the present for the future, or one man for another. As luck w ould have it, Veere, in his horrid fusty &amp;apos;bus, drove past them in the village. He saw Betsey and the author delicately stepping it along the road up to the Castle, but scrupled to follow his first cordial impulse to get out and join them in their walk up the hill. He betrayed it, however, by a quick forward movement of his hand to the check-string. He thought better of it, and falling back he nodded to them both and was slowly bowled on. Betsey was in a silent flutter. Mr. Lee-Brice, who noticed it, began to converse with judgment, and an absence of direct questioning. &amp;quot; The charm of Ernest Veere&amp;apos;s face,&amp;quot; he observed, &amp;quot; lies in his open yet cute smile. He always, somehow, reminds me of cutlery-of some serviceable tool, shiny, smooth, and pre-eminently efficient.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Would it be a bradawl ? &amp;quot; inquired Betsey, laughing. She was terribly excited. She did not care what names she called Veere. She was to see the beloved bradawl in a short while-an hour, two hours-at all events, that very evening. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s an extraordinarily clever young fellow,&amp;quot; pursued the author. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s almost a pity he&amp;apos;s got all that money-he might have done so much without it!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What, for instance ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Married the right woman, for one thing! A woman who would have nothing to &amp;apos; get over &amp;apos; in him ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What has Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e to get over ? He doesn&amp;apos;t eat peas with his knife, I suppose ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Of course not ! He&amp;apos;s all right in those things. Something far more subtle than that. You&amp;apos;re quite clever enough to understand. He jars, believe me. It&amp;apos;s so funny to watch them.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Quite a privilege!&amp;quot; replied Betsey sourly. &amp;quot;Poor Mr. Veere !&amp;quot; She was talking commonplaces. He was carrying her into fields where her natural wit had no play. She herself was too rough~and ready to faithfully envisage those pitfalls imminent in daily intercourse with Lady Dobree and her set which beset the self-made man, and Lee-Brice missed her sure-footed criticisms and comments on the kind of workaday life she knew best. He did not choose to let her wallow any more in sloughs of incompetent spite. She was a very pretty thing and deserved her millionaire, whom he would help her to get, furthering at the same time a not altogether inchoate scheme of his own. Half an hour later, the unused key grated in the door that connected the smart Dwelling House with the stern Keep, and he was with Ada, herself, and Billy. He was cheerful. &amp;quot; Good luck! They&amp;apos;re across the border and away, I hear. So I&amp;apos;ve got my freedom till dinner-time.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think she ought to have stayed to receive you, when she knew you were coming! &amp;quot; Betsey said. &amp;quot; Rather not ! I purposely misled her. She didn&amp;apos;t know I was coming till to-morrow. I arranged it all with Brookie. How do you like Brookie, Betsey ? He&amp;apos;s an old faithful dear, isn&amp;apos;t he ? Yes, Billy, my son, that&amp;apos;s for you-and this! And this is for your mother! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, thank you, sir-indeed,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Cox. &amp;quot;And for Billy too.&amp;quot; She took her son&amp;apos;s hand and negligently left the room. Lately she had grown a delicate sense of not being wanted. &amp;quot; Well, Elisabetta, are you happy here ? I needn&amp;apos;t ask. I saw you escorted by the greatest novelist of the day up the hill, I saw your golden hair shining in the setting sun-very casually, but effectively, done up. And so did he, you bet ! The cheek of you-wearing no hat ! Well, at any rate you&amp;apos;re having a good time, and I&amp;apos;m delighted to see it! Do you like the lamb-like author ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mr. Lee-Brice has very nice modest manners, hasn&amp;apos;t he?&amp;quot; she said demurely, &amp;quot; for a man who writes books that-well, books that every gentleman&amp;apos;s library should be without ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Ha ha ! A very decent chap all the same, don&amp;apos;t you think ? And a regular Cresus. Why, the royalties on his book alone-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The one they&amp;apos;ve suppressed ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, he doesn&amp;apos;t get any more on that. But the one before -the one they made a play of-that brings him in a few good thousands a year. I declare he&amp;apos;s a better parti than I, if only the fair Dobree&amp;apos;s advisers would let her see it. Especially now, when I don&amp;apos;t know if I mayn&amp;apos;t be chucked out of house and home by the turn of the law ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;The law ! It&amp;apos;s not cleverness needed to prove it, but right. Either that pretender is your uncle&amp;apos;s son or he isn&amp;apos;t.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I believe he&amp;apos;s faked a register or something. And if the finding is on his side, I shall only have my wits.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; They&amp;apos;re excellent ones. Mr. Lee-Brice says that you could do anything you liked. He even says that you would do better without any money at all ! &amp;quot; The cute smile glittered. &amp;quot; Does he expect me to make a handsome present of my wealth to any one ? To him, say? Then he could marry Dobr&amp;amp;e. Is that what he&amp;apos;s after ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; But I thought you were going to marry Lady Dobre ?&amp;quot; she asked innocently. &amp;quot; Every one about here says you are ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s the idea ! &amp;quot; he replied uneasily. Was she going to reproach him for his engagement, and the march he had stolen on his promise ? He cared so much for her opinion on everything, more than for that of any other person in the world, excepting himself, that he was actually driven in his own despite to ask her in so many words what she thought of the step he had taken. She primmed her full sweet lips; it was a little drop of balm in the draught of bitterness, and she enjoyed it to the full. But Veere hated any approximation, on the lips of a woman dear to him, to the disturbing smile of Mona Lisa. &amp;quot; Are you quite sure you don&amp;apos;t object to anything ? &amp;quot; he insisted curtly. &amp;quot; To what ? Everything&amp;apos;s quite nice here, I think. Good air-lovely sands, only I wish they had run to electric light in the Keep! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, no, my engagement, I mean. I had to settle that in London &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Before you got here ? Practical, as ever.&amp;quot; He gave her up. &amp;apos;&amp;quot; Practical, yes, and so is the girl&amp;apos;s fatherWon&amp;apos;t have it announced until the Pretender is disposed of. Full of schedules and mortgages and what not. Oh, they&amp;apos;re an awful lot ! She&amp;apos;s the bright spot in the family. Would you believe it, he doesn&amp;apos;t like me to take her name ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s right. A Norman name wouldn&amp;apos;t suit you at all !&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Now that&amp;apos;s the first delightful bit of spite you&amp;apos;ve shown, Betsey. It quite warms the cockles of my heart ! But I&amp;apos;m afraid, my dear, it will have to be, for I mean to stick to that point and get my own way. I shall have old Angernoune under my thumb as soon as the gentleman calling himself Ernest Louis Veere is safely disposed of, as he will be. We&amp;apos;ve retained the best heads in England. We can&amp;apos;t fail. And I shall be a cad with a Norman name. And am I a cad, Betsey ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve heard people call you a bounder.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, I say ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s not so bad as cad, that you&amp;apos;re trying to call yourself. It doesn&amp;apos;t, at any rate, mean anything dishonourable.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; One who bounds, merely. Do I bound, Betsey ? I should have thought I was too busy. Too hard-worked. Not selfindulgent enough. Besides that wretched word&amp;apos;s often the last arrow in the quiver of people who are too slack, too weakly, too fastidious to get on. It&amp;apos;s such an easy thing to say-the sort of reproach you hurl at a Labour Member with a majority of two hundred behind him ! You see after all I come back to the House-I can&amp;apos;t get away from the House. I must be in it. I can&amp;apos;t settle down to be a mere manufacturer with a headpiece like mine. My head&amp;apos;s got to get me into the House, with a little adroit jockeying of social values, and Earl&amp;apos;s daughters thrown in. Betsey, isn&amp;apos;t it a fair game ? They&amp;apos;re pretty overweening, one has the right to get the better of them, don&amp;apos;t you think ? Say so, if you can ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I should think it quite fair if only you were prepared to give rather better value for your title. I don&amp;apos;t mean money, I think you&amp;apos;ll be generous about that, but I mean that poor little Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e wants something more.&amp;quot; His head dropped on to his hands. &amp;quot; Betsey, I can&amp;apos;t. Positively, I can&amp;apos;t. And that&amp;apos;s the weak, the mean point in my scheme.&amp;quot; Is it me ? &amp;quot; she asked frankly. &amp;quot; For if it is, I could go ? &amp;quot;No, I desire you as a woman, if you must have it, but I hold on to you still more as a pal. Don&amp;apos;t desert me, please. You would do her no good, and you&amp;apos;d send me off my head, I believe. Stay here, and let me come and talk it over with you sometimes, as I am doing now. I am quite good and amenable, don&amp;apos;t you think I am ? You must admit I don&amp;apos;t persecute you by making love to you ? Since I can&amp;apos;t-mayn&amp;apos;t-I am resigned to see Lee-Brice doing it, or any other fellow you like to take on.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, you let me manage my own affairs-of the heart. But now tell me, would you like to explain how you came to take the plunge, and then I can see if Mr. Lee-Brice was speaking the truth ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, did he talk about it, the beggar ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, you talked to him. You mentioned the type of beauty you happened to admire.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yours, of course,&amp;quot; said the young man simply. &amp;quot; But I hope he hasn&amp;apos;t twigged ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh no. You said too many kind things for the portrait to be recognised. I&amp;apos;ve gone off sadly. Hair three shades darker! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Nonsense ! Pure gold wire, spun glass, floss silk, all the nice things they can possibly call hair. But about Dobr&amp;amp;e, you wanted to know. . . . Well, I proposed to her one day in July, during that week when you were too busy packing up and so on to see me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I know,&amp;quot; she murmured sombrely. &amp;quot;I took my eye off you for one minute and-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh, I know you disapprove. But-I don&amp;apos;t know how it was, I seemed to get myself fixed up for life in a sort of unamorous fury, the business-devil driving me, don&amp;apos;t you know ? He does ride me sometimes-he&amp;apos;s an inherited devil, he made all this . . . ! &amp;quot; He waved his hand to indicate the Castle mound of Angernoune and the park-like drives that spoiled it. &amp;quot; I knew I was down in his book to commit this error, or act of wisdom-what you will, and I thought to myself, &amp;apos; Oh, come, damn, let&amp;apos;s get it over!&amp;apos; Lots of fellows, it&amp;apos;s my firm belief, scuffle into it like that! They get hypnotised by the notion of the general suitability of an engagement-it grows to seem a thing that&amp;apos;s got to be, like confirmation-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Or death ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; If you like. Well, I went to call at the flat, and I said something leading, I suppose. They had got me into that sort of mood-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; They ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Lady Maude and Dobr&amp;amp;e. It was in that horrid upholsterer&amp;apos;s Louis Quinze room of hers, all flowers and frames and cushions and hot cakes-you seem to be swimming in an atmosphere of spooniness the moment the ribbony maid closes the door on you-and Dobr&amp;amp;e was less arrogant than usual. It might even be called yielding. Then Lady MIaude, who was more or less about, took good care to clinch it-told the sun to stand still upon Gibeon, don&amp;apos;t you know, until I&amp;apos;d made her mine-and left the room. Not before she&amp;apos;d, as it were, knocked our two heads together in an engagement kiss. So I had to stand to it, and pretend I was thoroughly in the picture, which I wasn&amp;apos;t. I was in your picture.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then I think you did very wrong. And now-she cries herself sick about your backwardness-so her maid says.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; What can I do ? It&amp;apos;s only three weeks ago. I&amp;apos;ve given her a ring, two kisses and a dozen riding lessons. If she can&amp;apos;t stand me, she can chuck me. Ha ha! Perhaps that&amp;apos;s what I&amp;apos;m driving at all the time ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Good Heavens ! I hope unconsciously?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I expect so. I don&amp;apos;t formulate any plan. And yet-there does seem a kind of barbaric honour in making her find me inadequate, isn&amp;apos;t there ? Not a good bargain ? It would be the sort of thing she would throw me over for-if anything-something personal, something that hurts her poor little pride. She&amp;apos;s proud, though she loves money. Whereas, if I lost the case and all my tin, I believe I should positively have to bash her to make her give me up. You can&amp;apos;t tell, but that&amp;apos;s my idea of her. And I ought to know her pretty well ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; You don&amp;apos;t know her a bit-any more than I do. I confess I don&amp;apos;t think there&amp;apos;s much to know. But one thing I&amp;apos;m certain of and that is, that though you&amp;apos;re every sort of dear yourself, your attitude is that of a cad.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Hold on! . . . No, dear Betsey, you may shake your pretty head till your pretty hair comes down-as it has !-but you&amp;apos;ll not convince me that I&amp;apos;m a cad. I&amp;apos;m not! I&amp;apos;m not! Human beings when it comes to the real big things, can&amp;apos;t order their lives on conventions. Those are all right for merely social difficulties. A man&amp;apos;s a man for all that &amp;quot; &amp;quot; The bounder&amp;apos;s gospel! &amp;quot; said she bitterly. &amp;apos; Fais ce que peut-not dois.&amp;apos; A gentleman, wrecked and clinging to a plank, would take his hands off and drown if he incommoded a lady. You&amp;apos;re a darling, and you can&amp;apos;t help it if you&amp;apos;re an opportunist.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Who has taught you to use such big words? LeeBrice ? &amp;quot; said he, dissatisfied. XXVII Some of Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s house-party next day, an evervarying moiety, for people came and went freely, were sitting in one of the wide embrasures that bowed out from the battlemented curtain-wall of Angernoune looking out to sea. It was two days after Veere&amp;apos;s arrival. Lady Maude and Dobr&amp;amp;e had been talking him over; when he joined them with the novelist, they talked over some one else. &amp;quot;That&amp;apos;s a nice-looking pair of women you&amp;apos;ve got to keep the Keep, Ernest,&amp;quot; remarked Lady Maude. &amp;quot;The dark one&amp;apos;s like an overworked Burne-Jones, and the other like a Romney gone to seed.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes,&amp;quot; said the author, innocently, leaving the looks of Mrs. Cox out of count. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s not a beauty that will last. But she&amp;apos;s a splendid vision now. Her colouring is so vivid, the lines of her face so defined as to be almost hard in effect. There&amp;apos;s so little shading, so little gradation, the cavities of the eye-sockets are so clean-cut and sharp. Those dark arched eyebrows, over bold blue eyes, that fine bow-shaped mouth and Greek nose remind me of the best Lady Hamiltons! And her hair with its two shades &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Shows she doesn&amp;apos;t dye it!&amp;quot; said Lady Maude, generous, but bored to death. &amp;quot; I was looking at it as she sat on the sands with me a few days ago.&amp;quot; Lady Maude raised her eyebrows ! &amp;quot; It was so like the shading of the basalt-gold and tawny, with deep strong shadows-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You appear to admire her &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes-as much as I admire anything so full blown,&amp;quot; said he, with a glance at Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e&amp;apos;s pure null profile with its Roman nose and touching angularities of cheek. &amp;quot; She had a child with her ? &amp;quot; he added in a vaguely explanatory manner. &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s not hers, it&amp;apos;s Mrs. Cox&amp;apos;s, the dark one&amp;apos;s,&amp;quot; said Dobr&amp;amp;e. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s not a bad-looking child either-reminds me of some one I know, somehow ? But I suppose it&amp;apos;s like its papa, Mr. Cox ? &amp;quot; She laughed. &amp;quot; Next time you&amp;apos;re down in the village do buy him a fourpenny ball and I&amp;apos;ll pay you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Is the Romney married too ? &amp;quot; Lady Maude asked Veere. &amp;quot; I haven&amp;apos;t inquired,&amp;quot; said Veere plausibly. &amp;quot; Mrs. Cox just asked me if she might have her sister-in-law down here for a change of air and I said yes. Perhaps-she may be married, of course-wife of a poor clerk, I should think! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; If once you come to think, I wonder you don&amp;apos;t get to know! &amp;quot; said Dobr&amp;amp;e severely, and Veere realised that he was protesting too much. &amp;quot; I must go and start the Blessingtons at croquet,&amp;quot; he said hastily. &amp;quot; Boris has chewed all the balls and made them uncertain in disposition, and there are about six blades of grass each for them to roll on.&amp;quot; He departed. &amp;quot; Wordy! &amp;quot; said Lady Maude. &amp;quot; He admires the Lady of the Keep. I have a flair in these matters. That&amp;apos;s all rubbish about her being Mrs. Cox&amp;apos;s sister-in-law. You look out, Mr. Lee-Brice, and take fewer walks with basaltic-haired chatelaines, or you&amp;apos;ll find yourself trespassing on some one else&amp;apos;s preserves.&amp;quot; Dobr&amp;amp;e looked puzzled, a little annoyed at her chaperon&amp;apos;s crudity. She stood, poised on one foot, anxious to leave them, anxious to hear more. ... &amp;quot; I suppose,&amp;quot; she said, humbly, &amp;quot; there is a something about women like that ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Something-a je ne sais quoi, that makes for un-righteousness ! &amp;quot; said Lee-Brice. But there were tears in the girl&amp;apos;s eyes. &amp;quot; Something that makes for men, I suppose you mean ? &amp;quot; said Lady Maude brusquely, for she saw the tears. &amp;quot; Oh, he&amp;apos;ll ranger himself ! That kind of man does. He&amp;apos;ll have every bourgeois virtue-soon. Dobr&amp;amp;e, why don&amp;apos;t you go and take a hand at croquet ? They seem to want a fourth badly, and I desire to talk freely ! &amp;quot; The girl got up and obeyed. Lady Maude turned to the author recklessly. &amp;quot; My dear soul, you shouldn&amp;apos;t worry that poor girl about her man ! Don&amp;apos;t you see, poor little wire-haired terrier that she is, that she&amp;apos;s now come bang against life, and doesn&amp;apos;t know what to make of it ? She&amp;apos;s got all a woman&amp;apos;s tribulations, and no &amp;apos;savvy&amp;apos; at all. And she&amp;apos;s wretched over her engagement in consequence.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s an impossible engagement. And she is, as you say, a sweet, straight, undeveloped piece of mechanism, with only one slide to her little lantern. I thought that blue tear I saw in her eye as she ran off adorable. She wept it because the strands of her hair are all one colour, like the strands of her soul. There&amp;apos;s no more twist in the woof and warp of that child&amp;apos;s heart than will suffice to keep it together. Now the other, the lady of the Keep-&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mrs. Adamson ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-Has lived.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; With Veere ? I hope not. By the way, talking of Veere, did you see in the paper this morning that that murderer-you know, what was his name ?-who murdered old Sir Joris, has at last succeeded in committing suicide ? They found him in his cell with his throat cut with a rusty nail he got hold of, and he&amp;apos;s not expected to live, this time. Don&amp;apos;t you remember at the time of the trial how Veere aflichtr&amp;apos;d himself with the wife ? Every one was talking about it and trying to get a sight of her, but all they could find out was that she had yellow hair. That they saw through the thick veil she sported. And Veere was always flashing by all his friends in a motor, breaking the speed limit so that we shouldn&amp;apos;t see who it was he had with him. It&amp;apos;s all over now, of course, but we were so afraid once he was going to marry her as soon as her husband was hanged. I suppose when he got penal servitude for life she subsided into the suburbs again.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Which was her particular suburb, do you remember ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I can&amp;apos;t remember. Stop, was it Wimbledon ? But, of course, it won&amp;apos;t make any difference now. Dobrie has really got him, if she cares to stick to it. Do you know, I think I&amp;apos;ve stood the wind long enough. My London wig resents it. Let us go down.&amp;quot; As they passed the door of the Keep, she paused: &amp;quot; Come here, Mr. Lee-Brice. Is it the effect of the wind howling round these old corners, or is it a woman crying ? I distinctly hear it, don&amp;apos;t you ? Great cruel sobs ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; His Romney Aunt has whipped the Burne-Jones child probably. She looks a bit of a tartar. Come along, dear lady, it&amp;apos;s not a case for sympathy. Morning noises are always squalid, not tragic.&amp;quot; XXVIII &amp;quot;Oh, Betsey, Betsey, you&amp;apos;re a widow now!&amp;quot; The mistress wept bitterly as she looked over the wife&amp;apos;s shoulder and read the official missive that coldly set forth the fact that Wilfrid Altamont or Adamson had at last succeeded in taking his own life in prison. That came at night. Inspector Whortleberry&amp;apos;s telegram had arrived that morning-a warning of what might be expected in the course of the day, and the matutinal wails that Lady Maude had heard told of Ada&amp;apos;s dire forebodings. When the final news came Wilfrid had been dead in her mind for some hours. She had wept till she could no longer weep, her tears for the moment dried up at the source, it seemed as if the half of her mind was paralysed. She was simply concerned to know Betsey&amp;apos;s views on many points concerning her late husband, and with childish insistence tried to inform herself. &amp;quot; Say you respect him now, Betsey! You once said you would think more of him if he took his own life! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Did I, dear ? It sounds so awful. But I suppose that is what I meant. I do think less hardly of him.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Bless you ! &amp;quot;said the poor woman. &amp;quot; And, Betsey, will you wear mourning?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I daren&amp;apos;t,&amp;quot; said Betsey. &amp;quot; It might give it away. But let me see, you might slide a little black in somehow ? . Your Sunday dress is black, isn&amp;apos;t it ? Mine is serge-very dark. The only thing is, and I am afraid it will upset you, you mustn&amp;apos;t for your life put the child into black. That would be very marked.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Mustn&amp;apos;t I really ; His own father! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;We are pensioners of Mr. Veere, Ada, and we must be guided by his wishes. He doesn&amp;apos;t want any one to know who we are-so there it is. I&amp;apos;m sorry.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think I&amp;apos;ll make a cup of tea,&amp;quot; said Ada, swallowing her disappointment and flying to her one panacea. &amp;quot; And what are you going to do after this, Betsey ? Is it any good my arsking ? You and Billy are all I&amp;apos;ve left to care for.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t mind your asking, if I only knew myself &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Are you going to America &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I&amp;apos;m off that.&amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t mean to marry ? &amp;quot; No.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, don&amp;apos;t you marry again. Stay a widow. We&amp;apos;ll be widows together-once marrying is enough. I talk as if I&amp;apos;d been married, don&amp;apos;t I-and so I do feel as if I&amp;apos;d been married to the man that&amp;apos;s dead. Oh, dear Betsey, you&amp;apos;ve been so kind, do you mind my saying that ? It&amp;apos;s cheek, I know.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Nonsense, dear! Have I ever minded ? You&amp;apos;re a good sort and as soon as I found that out, I&amp;apos;ve been quite willing to take cheek or anything else from you. I think we&amp;apos;ve both behaved very well over it. Oh, my head! &amp;quot; Ada brewed the tea and brought her a cup. Betsey put her hand up and clasped the kind one that was ministering to her. &amp;quot; Ada, I&amp;apos;m miserable! &amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; Poor soul ! It isn&amp;apos;t about Wilfrid, either, is it ? &amp;quot; No, not about Wilfrid.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You can&amp;apos;t take me in, can you ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; Nor don&amp;apos;t want to,&amp;quot; said the other spiritlessly. &amp;quot; You&amp;apos;ll not do me any harm.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Harm you, Betsey ? Why, I&amp;apos;d go to my death for you, that&amp;apos;s what I would do. If my death would give you your heart&amp;apos;s desire-and I know well enough what that is-you should have it and welcome. What&amp;apos;s that silly girl to him ? You and him been to each other-what Wilfrid and I been to each other, pretty near, or thereabouts, and why&amp;apos;s she with her blasted title to come in and part them as has known each other like you two have ? I say it&amp;apos;s a shame! &amp;quot; She went away, muttering, the other woman&amp;apos;s head remained obstinately buried in her hand. Betsey, in the depths of her despair and renunciation, realised that Ada had formed the obvious and inevitable opinion as to her relations with the young man with whom she had been constantly intimate since the day of the funeral of Miss Altamont-with whom she had travelled abroad. . . . What else could Ada think, what else could anybody think who knew of it ? She did not care to disabuse her. It was even a point of consolation that Ada, with her sad, slum-wisdom and hard and fast social code, should think no other form of alliance had been possible. Later on in the afternoon, she said: &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s to be a high tide on the Black Rock this afternoon. They say the waves will be highest about five. I&amp;apos;ll go down and see. It might cure my headache.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Wind&amp;apos;s bound to make your headache worse.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not this sort of headache. . . . No, I won&amp;apos;t take Billy, he&amp;apos;d be a responsibility, and in this gale, it&amp;apos;s not so easy for a grown-up person even, to keep his footing on those rocks.&amp;quot; She tied a veil over her cap and hair, and like a drift of grey smoke blown this way and that, made her way by the windswept links to the place where the seas were reputed to encounter most opposition in their onslaught on the land. The wind was straight off the sea and Norway. It swished and wished through the wooden slats of the railings of the golf-course, it eddied in and out the sand-hills, mowing down and flattening the bents that seemed to lay their spines sideways against its onrush. The little hard pink balls of thrift growing where sand met grass bumped about and knocked each other, and yellow ragwort rattled and shook and looked more ragged and deplorable than ever. One of the Vicar&amp;apos;s nice boys-dear boys like grey whelps in their Jaeger flannel-she liked them-told her that the waves made a splendid show, and that the Castle party were all down there. She hesitated for one moment, then she decided that she would attract no particular attention in her smoky-coloured wrappings. There were other people there, too, the Vicar and his wife, and some of the visitors. Everybody&amp;apos;s eyes would be bleared by salt spray. Yes, she would go on. She needed all the exhilaration that savage Nature can give. She passed the Castle party, staggering about absurdly on the reef of slippery broken-up rock which flung itself recklessly out to sea, like an inky hand that the white waves licked slavishly, continually. Ever and anon they rose in Kuhleborn-like rushes, to be again dissipated in falling water, as Undine&amp;apos;s ghostly waggoner, while the foam flecks flew out far down the wind and struck the lookers-on in the face. It was no place for idle seekers after sensation, for the elemental combat recked not of them, but laughed and covered them with flakes of ridicule. The sea-charges grew more furious. The cold blue sky was stained brown with the dirty spume. It was fully high tide. Betsey had gone to the shelving end of the reef, where the waters spread out lasciviously as they retreated, baffled, and the suction oceanwards was enormous. A woman in despair goes far. The worst was comfort. The sea was kinder than the man she loved . . . sunk as he was in short-sighted ease, concerned in petty issues merely, complacently looking down the avenues of sophistication that led to his pale desire for a second-rate cheap substitute for life. . . . I Between her and Veere and his chosen friends there were now material barriers, tantamount to Alpine peaks and crevasses which Betsey, agile, had leaped across and poised on easily, like a kid. The town people had none of them seemingly got any balance. Lady Bl essigton, seized protectingly first by this man and then that, seemed to spin like a saffron-ulstered teetotum. Lady Dobr&amp;amp;e, thin and slight in her elegant dark-coloured tweed, waved reed-like, and continually tried to prevent her windblown skirts from revealing her too far. Such was not Lady Maude&amp;apos;s preoccupation. Veere, in yachting cap and sailor serge, stood by them both, ready to help if either were carried off her feet. A fall into some jagged chasm, set with bonebreaking spikes, would be the result, and even the place the two women had attained unto was none too secure. Betsey was farther out than any one of the spectators. There was in her case the added danger of being attained and carried out by a heavy back-wash of some eleventh wave. She dauntlessly defied danger. Her attitude was fine. &amp;quot; What a fool that woman is! &amp;quot; said Veere suddenly to his party, or any one who cared to hear it. &amp;quot; I must tell her. She&amp;apos;s a stranger here, I dare say, and doesn&amp;apos;t know how dangerous it is ! &amp;quot; Quickly he bridged the gulf that parted him from Betsey, whom he had recognised by the poise of her figure, sharply defined every now and again. It was unlikely that any one else had done so, or heard his excuse for joining her. The senses of seeing and hearing possessed by these landsmen and landswomen were more or less in abeyance owing to the stress of wind and water. Betsey, of course, did not hear Veere coming or notice him until he was close to her. &amp;quot; Oh, mistress mine, where are you roaming? . . Come away from here, it&amp;apos;s dangerous.&amp;quot; She turned sharply, and veered towards him. &amp;quot; Good girl! That was only a blind. You&amp;apos;re fairly surefooted. Give me your hand for a minute-they can&amp;apos;t see!&amp;quot; She laid it in his. It was warm; she had held it in the pocket of her ulster. &amp;quot; That&amp;apos;s all. And now I&amp;apos;ll go back to them.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; And may I stay where I am ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; No, I&amp;apos;d rather you didn&amp;apos;t, so near!&amp;quot; As he departed, leaping gracefully, he made a little funnel of his hands, and bawled, for the benefit of the crowd. &amp;quot; Not safe ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s happier for that hand-squeeze! &amp;quot; thought the woman he had left, scornfully. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s gone back to them, with fresh strength gathered from me, to pull his iniquitous scheme through. And I, I should not have allowed him. It&amp;apos;s as bad and immoral as getting up Unemployed Winter funds-only staves off the crux to another year ! &amp;quot; She could not bring herself to believe that Ernest Veere, loving her with all his heart, could actually and finally espouse the Lady Dobree De Saye ? Something would happen, his better nature would assert itself. So she held on, day by day, a statue of frozen impotent love, a thwarted lonely goddess, disdaining to move hand or foot to meddle with the fate of her strayed votary. Egeria&amp;apos;s vaunted intelligence was in abeyance, her wisdom set on one side, but she could still heal. For she knew men, she knew Veere, she had never made a miscalculation but once. In that vital moment with Veere at the stair-head in Worksop House, she had gauged ill the worldforces given her, in ever so little, to control. She had simply done wrong, been wicked and immoral, most people would say. That was not the code of Miss Altamont, whose pupil she was. But whatever her crime, or her folly, she complied with its result, or punishment. She would not attempt to touch the pendulum of her own fate and his again. Her part was again waiting! Apt corrective for a nature like Betsey&amp;apos;s, to whom moral inaction always proved one of the worst circles of Hell. Waiting in Wimbledon-waiting in Angernoune, but always waiting! She stood there on the gradually forsaken reef for some time. She saw, through the tail of her eye, the Castle party furl their wings and go home to tea. For them the play had been played. The eleventh wave had flung itself in all its force and majesty of endeavour at the land&amp;apos;s eternal bulwark in vain; now the unhandsome rear guard, the stunted warriors of feebler masses of water did not interest; the heart of the show was over. Yet Betsey stood there glued to the rock, pensive, paralysed.. One mighty remainder, as it were, surged up, and then laid itself out, a vast plateau of foamy water, gasping, panting on the flat of the shelving rock, as on a bed of pain. Betsey watched it go, as the sea sucked it back into its reserves, with a distinct feeling of regret that she was not borne away with it to the forgettable. (To be continued)</FullText></Record>