<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2447029</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130320</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>Empire Notes</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Sep 1924</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19240901</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Remnant</LastName><FirstName>Ernest</FirstName><PersonName>Ernest Remnant</PersonName><OriginalForm>Remnant, Ernest</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>441</StartPage><EndPage>449</EndPage><Pagination>441-449</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2447029/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><Abstract>       &lt;AbsText&gt;AMPLE justification for the prominence given to the vital topic of the Dominions and Foreign Affairs in recent numbers of THE ENGLISH REVIEW was afforded by the debate in the House of Commons at the end of July. The subject was raised by Mr. Amery on the Colonial Office vote on July 29th. Mr. Lloyd George laid stress on the importance of doing nothing to assist mischief-makers who endeavour to exploit the lack of racial homogeneity in some of the Dominions.&lt;/AbsText&gt;     </Abstract><FullText>Empire Notes AMPLE justification for the prominence given to the vital topic of the Dominions and Foreign Affairs in recent numbers of THE ENGLISH REVIEW was afforded by the debate in the House of Commons at the end of Tuly. The subject was raised by Mr. Amery on the Colonial Office vote on July 29th. Mr. Lloyd George laid stress on the importance of doing nothing to assist mischief-makers who endeavour to exploit the lack of racial homogeneity in some of the Dominions. He agreed with Mr. Amery that there Dominions and Foreign Affairs had been rather unfortunate incidents in connection with the representation of the Dominions at recent international conferences, and said that it was most important that they should feel that we were taking them into our councils, as far as geographical conditions would permit, and that the old policy of Downing Street deciding for the whole of the Dominions and committing them to a policy which loyalty demanded that they should support when it was challenged by anyone was gone for ever. MR. THOMAS, in his reply, made it clear that the Government is concerned about the position, and that the adoption arck for a of the panel system, by which one of the Workable three British Empire representatives at the Plan Dawes Report Conference was provided by the Dominions in turn, was not regarded as a permanently satisfactory solution of the problem of Dominion representation, either at home or oversea. The British Government has invited the Dominion Governments to express their views in regard to the question of intra-Empire consultations on Imperial and foreign affairs. An invitation has been sent for a conference to be held in October to explore the ground, but it seems by no means certain that it will be possible to hold it so soon. According to The Times correspondent in Wellington, Mr. Massey has stated that neither he nor any other New Zealand Minister will be able to leave that Dominion for some time. He suggested that a small committee of men, not necessarily politicians, but well versed in constitutional law and procedure, should examine the problems involved, and that their report should be considered by the various Governments before the next Imperial Conference. It would seem from a subsequent speech by Mr. Mackenzie King, the Canadian Prime Minister, that this suggestion now holds the field. Obviously it is too much to expect statesmen to come to London from the opposite side of the earth every few months, particularly after the fiasco of the last Imperial Conference. Nowhere in the Empire, except perhaps in Southern Rhodesia, are the Prime Ministers sufficiently free from local political difficulties to be able to absent themselves for several months in the year from their own countries, apart altogether from the question of expense, which is a serious matter in the case of the Southern Dominions. It is, however, satisfactory to find that the importance of the subject is becoming more generally realised, and we may hope that the practical genius of the race will prove equal to the task of devising a workable and sufficiently flexible plan of consultation and representation of the self-governing units of the Empire, both in regard to Imperial and foreign affairs. We cannot afford many repetitions of the unpleasantness that has occurred in connection with the Lausanne Treaty and the Dawes Report Conference. THE Commonwealth Bank Bill, which makes important changes in the functions and constitution of the bank, may Reserve BaBkbe regarded as an attempt to give effect to for Australia the recommendations of the Committee of the Imperial Economic Conference of last October which studied the problem of Empire exchanges and the difficulties which have been experienced from time to time since the suspension of the gold standard in moving money within the Empire at reasonable cost. Hitherto the Commonwealth Bank has been merely a State bank managed by a governor and deputy governor, and it has worked in concert with the commercial banks in the matter of rates of exchange. The effect of the alterations to be made will be to transform the Commonwealth Bank into a central reserve bank with similar functions to the South African Reserve Bank. A board of directors will be set up composed of eight prominent men unconnected with other financial institutions, two of whom are to be experts on currency questions, and this board will also control the note issue department. A London board of advice composed of three members is also to be formed. An important feature is the provision that under certain conditions notes may be issued in Australia against balances specially deposited in London. It is hoped in this way to overcome the difficulty that has frequently occurred since the war of transferring balances in London to Australia except in the form of goods, with the inevitable consequence of excessive importing to the detriment of Australian manufacturers. Whether this expedient will prove successful remains to be tested by experience, but there is a widespread feeling that a return to the gold standard is the only really satisfactory remedy for the troubles that have occurred in recent years. Dr. Earl Page, the Commonwealth Treasurer, who introduced the Bill, said that it had been framed in order that banking in Australia might keep pace with the most modern systems of banking in other countries. The change was calculated to facilitate national production and trade, so far as that could be done by banking, and it would permit the ordinary laws of finance and economics to work as smoothly as possible and without harshness towards the growing needs of the Commonwealth. ALTHOUGH an agreement was reached in the latter part of July between representatives of the Federal Nationalist Australian Party and the Country Party to cover the Coalition in allocation of seats between the two wings Danger of the Coalition at the next Australian General Election, later messages suggest that harmony is far from being restored between the two parties. Mr. Stewart, the Minister of Works, has resigned from the Cabinet, as he disapproves of the terms of the new pact and intends to oppose it strongly in the State Farmers&amp;apos; Organisation in Victoria, which is unlikely to support the new agreement. In that event the remaining Country Party Ministers are expected to withdraw, leaving Mr. Bruce to form a purely Nationalist administration. The political situation in Australia is not such that the Nationalists and the Country Party can afford to fall out unless they are prepared to clear the way for a Labour Government. Labour is in power in four of the six States, and in office, though as a Minority Government, in a fifth, New South Wales being the only State not now controlled by Labour. The existence of a Labour administration in Victoria is due to the quarrel between the Nationalists and the Country Party, which seems likely to lead to a similar result in Federal politics. It is difficult to see how the interests which the Country Party represents will gain by a final breach with the Nationalists, since, although the latter are Protectionists, the existence of the Coalition enables the Country Party to exert a good deal of influence in the direction of preventing increases in import duties. A Labour Government would be more protectionist than the Nationalists, and the Country Party would no longer be able to impose any effective opposition to tariff increases, so that, in so far as one of their main interests is concerned, they would have exchanged King Log for King Stork. THE South African Government has done wisely in sending an expedition into the Kalahari desert to investigate The Locust the locust peril in the principal breeding Plague ground of this destructive insect pest. The recrudescence of swarms on a large scale during the past two years has cost the Union large sums and resulted in heavy losses to farmers. It would be false econom to spare time or money in an endeavour to rid South Airica of the recurrent menace of fresh invasions, and if a means could be found to stamp out the insect the expenditure of a million or two in this way would be well worth while. The difficulty is that in the vast and almost unoccupied regions bounded by the Orange river, the Cape-Congo railway, the Zambezi, and the highlands of South-west Africa, swarms can develop to dangerous proportions unobserved, and from this breeding ground they can emerge to ravage the crops and pastures of the settled parts of South Africa. It may be that a system of aeroplane patrols of the Kalahari, in conjunction with the employment of a number of reliable Bechuana wardens, would enable early information to be obtained of the presence of swarms in the &amp;quot; hopper &amp;quot; stage. In that event the necessary measures could be taken for destroying the insects before they acquired the extra mobility given to them by the growth of their wings. The transport problem in this hot, arid, and roadless region would, however, prove a formidable obstacle to such action. THE possibility of a return to the gold standard in South Africa in advance of similar action in this country has been attracting some attention recently in South Africa the Union, this contingency having been and the Gold]&amp;apos; Standard smentioned by Mr. Havenga, the Minister of S Finance, in his Budget statement a few weeks ago. Under the Banking and Currency Act of 1920, by which the South African Reserve Bank was set up, the convertibility of notes issued by the bank was suspended until June 3oth, 1923, and the period of inconvertibility was subsequently extended for two years beyond that date, so that it has another ten months to run, failing a further prolongation. A committee of experts is to be appointed to study the position and advise the Government. The matter is complicated by the effect that a restoration of the gold standard might have on the Witwatersrand mining industry. In present circumstances the gold premium increases the cost of plant and material required by the mines, and also tends to keep wages at a higher level than would otherwise be warranted. On the other hand, the increased value of the gold produced probably much more than compensates for the higher cost of exploitation. In fact, many of the low grade mines are only kept at work by the existence of the premium. The possibility of its disappearance introduces an element of uncertainty into the prospects of the gold mining industry in the immediate future, and will naturally affect the attitude of the mining companies towards the demands for increased wages that are about to be put forward. It is unfortunate that at a time when there seemed to be good hopes of several years of sustained progress and freedom from violent changes this cloud should appear on the horizon, and it is very desirable that the intentions of the Government in regard to the gold standard should be made known as soon as possible in order to give plenty of time for such readjustment as may be necessary. THE New Zealand Budget reflects the prosperity of that Dominion. A surplus of ?i,812,365 is something of which New such a small population may be justly proud, Zealand&amp;apos;s and Mr. Massey, in his Budget speech, was Prosperity able to say that, although ?4,600,000 had been borrowed during the year for public works and settlement, the net debt had been reduced by ?i,ixii,ooo. The desire of the Dominion Government to shoulder a larger share of the burden of Imperial naval defence is shown by the intimation that Parliament is to be asked to sanction the maintenance by New Zealand of a second light cruiser. Taxation is to be reduced by ?i,ooo,ooo in the current financial year, but Mr. Massey wisely warned the people of the Dominion that, although they were now in a fairly good position, they must avoid the temptation of indulging in extravagance, and that borrowed money should be used as far as possible for reproductive works if the country&amp;apos;s credit were to be maintained. There is no doubt that it is in safe hands at present. ONLY good can come of the visit of members of Parliament from Britain and the Dominions to South Africa. Mr. Thomas, Lord Burnham, Sir Douglas Parliamentary Hogg, and the other United Kingdom deleVisit to South Africa gates will have a most interesting and instructive tour of the sub-continent, and it is to be hoped that no untoward political developments in this country will occur to cut short the Colonial Secretary&amp;apos;s stay. Southern Africa has much to show her visitors, in the Union where, in addition to the great mining industry, which alone enables us to meet our liabilities to the United States without seriously affecting the relation of the pound to the dollar, the development of irrigation and water storage works is transforming large areas; in Southern Rhodesia, where a small white community is manfully shouldering the task of administering the youngest self-governing unit of the Empire; in Portuguese East Africa, where important developments, in which British capital will doubtless predominate, are about to take place; and in the South-West Africa Protectorate, which is well on the way to recovery from the effects of the war and is entering upon a new era of progress under the control of the Union. The quadrangular racial problem in the Union arising from the impact of British, Dutch, Indians, and natives upon one another, is a subject that cannot fail to absorb a large share of the attention of the visitors, for the prosperity of British South Africa depends to a great extent on a satisfactory adjustment of the racial issues, with which the future of the Empire itself is also inextricably interwoven. BFlroR leaving for South Africa the Colonial Secretary made known his final decision on the questions affecting Indians In Indians in Kenya and Indian immigration Kenya to that colony arising out of the White Paper of July, 1923, which had been referred to a committee under the chairmanship of Mr. J. Hope Simpson, M.P., appointed by the Government of India as a result of the deliberations of the Imperial Conference held last autumn. In the matter of the franchise and the reservation of the highlands for European settlers Mr. Thomas adheres to the policy laid down in the White Paper. Sir Robert Coryndon, the Governor of Kenya, in his opening speech to the Legislative Council, said that he thought the colony should express its recognition that a definite decision had been reached in accordance with the general wish. The community should, he added, now be able to proceed with confidence and accelerate the normal development. As regards immigration, the draft Bill to control immigration in the interests of the native African population is not to be proceeded with, and the Colonial Secretary has decided that, if danger should arise of an influx of immigrants of any class or race which might be prejudicial to the interests of the natives, he will hold himself free to take such action as may be necessary. Steps are to be taken to set up a statistical department in order to secure accurate information in regard to immigration and emigration of all races in view of the conflicting evidence in regard to Indian immigration which has been put forward. The question of reserving an area in the lowlands for agricultural immigrants from India was unfavourably regarded by Mr. Hope Simpson&amp;apos;s committee, but consideration of this matter is in suspense pending the receipt of further reports from the colony. It is too much to hope that Indian agitation will be stopped as the result of the decisions reached, but in other quarters the Colonial Secretary&amp;apos;s adherence to the principles embodied in the White Paper has been generally approved. THE proposal to build two new cruisers, pf which one at any rate is to be ordered in Britain, has aroused the ire Australian of the Australian Labour Party, which is Labour loth to recognise that its own actions have Revival made the cost of construction in the Commonwealth prohibitive, and the success of Labour at recent State elections is an additional indication that Mr. Bruce and his composite Government will have to meet a strong Labour offensive in the near future. The experience of Victoria, where, largely as the result of bickering between the Nationalists and the Country Party, Labour has become the strongest single party in the State Assembly, is a danger signal to the Bruce-Page administration. Less has been heard of the differences between the two wings since the Prime Minister&amp;apos;s return to Australia, and it may be that Mr. Bruce will be able to keep his team together, since the consequences of disunion would inevitably be the return to power of a federal Labour Government, following the capture by Labour of all but two of the States. The Times, in a leading article on July ist, referred to a somewhat significant change in the attitude of Australian Labour (in Western Australia at any rate) towards immigration, possible due to the discovery that in the Murray-Wellington group settlement the residents, most of whom came recently from the British Isles, voted Labour in the proportion of four to one at the last State General Election. Whether tosi koc or propter hoc it would be rash to say, but the State Government now appears to be quite well disposed towards the immigration policy adopted by Sir James Mitchell&amp;apos;s administration. In connection with migration it is noteworthy that at the beginning of July it was announced that all shipping accommodation for emigrants to New Zealand was booked until the end of August.</FullText></Record>