<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2451962</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131158</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>The Theatre</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>581</PublicationID><Title>The English review,  1908-1937</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>The English Review Ltd etc.</Publisher><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Mar 1937</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19370301</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Review</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Stockil</LastName><FirstName>Philip</FirstName><PersonName>Philip Stockil</PersonName><OriginalForm>STOCKIL, PHILIP</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Walker-Smith, Derek, Sir, 1910</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2275</ISSN><StartPage>369</StartPage><EndPage>371</EndPage><Pagination>369-371</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2451962/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Intellectual Life</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>The Theatre THE NEW THEATRE has for some time been establishing itself as the West End home of Shakespeare. It housed Mr. Gielgud&amp;apos;s Hamlet and Romeo and Juliet; it gave hospitality for a very few nights to M. Komisarjevsky&amp;apos;s version of Antony and Cleopatra, in which Miss Eugenie Leontovitch made so disastrous an appearance. Now it offers for a short season a charming production of As You Like It. Here is Shakespearian comedy well staged and brilliantly acted. Such a treat should be snatched-especially as Miss Edith Evans heads the cast. Her Rosalind is magnificently exuberant. Some may demand a more kittenish-perhaps a more Bergnerish ?-rendering of the part; I prefer Miss Evans&amp;apos;s ironic fun. It may be urged that she neglects the lyric quality in Rosalind, that she does not make her enough of a girl in love. She certainly gives her a sprightly rather than a treacly romanticism; but this will not appear outrageous to those who believe that As You Like It is a pretty frolic, and nothing more. Rosalind is not Juliet: she is no star-crossed lover, but a playful, resilient young woman. How bitterly would Juliet have received the usurping Duke&amp;apos;s decree of banishment; how quickly does Rosalind recover from the shock ! She is full of confidence, not clinging to Orlando, but mocking him with her boy&amp;apos;s disguise. She does not lack sentiment, but I believe that Miss Evans is right in not underlining it too heavily. That is a mistake a lesser actress might have made. If you seek sentiment in this production, observe Miss Marie Ney. She brings such enchanting sweetness to Celia that you no longer wonder why she is so easily won by Orlando&amp;apos;s penitent brother. Her good nature would never allow her to rebuff a sincere suitor. Mr. Michael Redgrave&amp;apos;s Orlando is likewise romantic, though not starved of wit. He is an athlete, too. His bout with the Duke&amp;apos;s wrestler is highly realistic. Mr. Leon Quartermaine does not make the melancholy Jacques too whimsical. He gives him a pointed assurance which serves well in the &amp;quot; Ages of Man &amp;quot; speech. Mr. Neil Porter is a nicely sinister Duke Frederick, and Oliver benefits from Mr. Valentine Dyall&amp;apos;s fine voice. Mr. Esme Church&amp;apos;s smooth production uses formal settings which suit the eighteenth-century style of the dresses. The advancement by a century or so of these gambols in the Forest of Arden may irritate some pedants. It did not jar upon me. While Miss Evans&amp;apos;s Rosalind was the acting triumph of the past month, I would not ignore a distinguished performance by a less familiar actress-Miss Valerie Taylor. It was not her fault that the play in which she appeared-The Orchard WaUs, adapted by Mr. Merton Hodge from the Hungarian of Ladislaus Fodoronly survived four nights at the St. James&amp;apos;s Theatre. The piece had little merit, but it at least tested and proved the resource of Miss Taylor. She compelled you to believe in the girl who abandoned an impoverished lover for a middle-aged, thrice-divorced, genially stupid millionaire, and for this reason: she so enlarged and improved the part that the minx who at first sight deserved a thorough spanking presently became a figure of bitter tragedy, demanding and evoking sympathy. This sensitive interpretation even emerged triumphant from the many post-marriage encounters of the girl and her jilted suitor, when the air grew heavy with memories and regrets. It is appalling to reflect how these romantic meetings might have been mismanaged by an actress less thoughtful than Miss Taylor. I hope she will soon be seen in a more worthy part. The month also saw the return to the stage of Miss Renee Kelly, who played the child in the original production of Daddy Longlegs. I wish she had not chosen to make her reappearance in E. C. Pollard&amp;apos;s Strange Barrier, which opened at the Little Theatre on February I2th. The piece so lacks suspense that my mind was always a step ahead of the argument. The nature of the main situation was apparent far too early in the evening. When, towards the end of Act i, a middle-aged cad was drowned by falling from the houseboat in which he was clumsily trying to seduce a young teacher of dancing, I knew that his son and the girl would soon be in love. And so they were. I was likewise aware, from heavy hints dropped in the first quarter of an hour, that presently the boy&amp;apos;s uncle and the girl&amp;apos;s elder sister would be engaged. And so they were. Nor did I need second sight to determine that the girl would discover the boy&amp;apos;s paternity; that she would shrink from him; that he would stumble upon her secret; that both would decide not to allow the past to destroy their happiness (they tended to converse in cliches); and that the curtain would fall on a vigorous embrace. It was all, unfortunately, so obvious. There is some excuse for lovers using the traditional jargon of romance, but all the other characters were similarly addicted to the stilted phrase. I noted two terrible examples: &amp;quot; This is no time for reproaches&amp;quot; and &amp;quot; Just as I was beginning to look upon her as I would my own daughter ! &amp;quot; Pointed talk might have helped to hide the play&amp;apos;s faulty construction; such language as this made it even more conspicuous. Miss Kelly lent grace and charm to the boy&amp;apos;s mother, but the best performance came from Miss Gillian Maude, as the girl-the only manageable part. IN Suspect, at the St. Martin&amp;apos;s, Miss Mary Morris, the American actress, made her first appearance on the English stage. She played a mysterious Mrs. Smith-it is a theatrical convention that all Mrs. Smiths are mysterious-who thirty years previously, as Margaret Wishart, had been charged at Musselburgh with axing her father and stepmother. The Scottish jury returned a verdict of &amp;quot;not proven,&amp;quot; and since then Mrs. Smith had been trying to forget her narrow escape from the gallows in a house on the Cornish coast. The play did not progress far before Sir Hugo Const, a newspaper proprietor paying a chance visit, recognized Mrs. Smith; for, as a youxig reporter, he had &amp;quot;covered&amp;quot; the trial of Margaret Wishart. He immediately passed on the news to his friend Doctor Rendle, whose daughter was about to marry Mrs. Smith&amp;apos;s son, and the play became virtually a re-trial of Margaret Wishart. Despite some forced situations, this procedure held my interest, though I felt that the &amp;quot;twist&amp;quot; at the final curtain was too sudden to be completely effective. Miss Morris gave Mrs. Smith iron nerves and a stately presence; Mr. David Home, as Sir Hugo, and Mr. Campbell Gullan, as the doctor, made a contrasting pair of inquisitors; Mr. Stafford Hilliard&amp;apos;s genial clergyman was well done. Finally, a few words on two musical shows. Home and Beauty, at the Adelphi, is said to be Mr. Cochran&amp;apos;s last revue. It is not his best, but I expect everyone will see it. That is the advantage of being Mr. Cochran. This time he offers Mr. A. P. Herbert&amp;apos;s wit, Miss Gitta Alpar&amp;apos;s voice and assorted fooling by Miss Binnie Hale and Mr. Nelson Keys. Some of Mr. Herbert&amp;apos;s lines are too allusive for the man-in-the-stalls, and Miss Gitta Alpar might have sacrificed at least one song in order to make way for a good dancing scene. Mr. Keys and Miss Hale show their comic paces whenever they have the opportunity. The piece is staged with Mr. Cochran&amp;apos;s usual tasteful brilliance. After three sticky scenes On Your Toes develops into a diverting and original Light entertainment-a burlesque of the Russian ballet which reaches its climax in a choreographic melodrama, Slaughter on Tenth Avenue. Mr. Jack Whiting is a pleasant comedian; Miss Vera Zorina points a pretty toe; Miss Gina Malo makes a charming soubrette. Mr. Vernon Kelso gives a neat sketch of a pompous impresario, and Miss Olive Blakeney booms cynicisms with terrific gusto. You will not pass a dull evening at the Palace. PHILIP STOCKIL.</FullText></Record>