<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2455944</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130807</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>CHRISTIANITY IN THE CARTOONS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Dec 1, 1865</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18651201</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Review</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>LLOYD</LastName><MiddleName>WATKISS</MiddleName><FirstName>W</FirstName><PersonName>W WATKISS LLOYD</PersonName><OriginalForm>LLOYD, W WATKISS</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>CoAuth</ContribRole><LastName>PALGRAVE</LastName><MiddleName>T</MiddleName><FirstName>F</FirstName><PersonName>F T PALGRAVE</PersonName><OriginalForm>PALGRAVE, F T</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Buchanan</LastName><FirstName>Robert</FirstName><PersonName>Robert Buchanan</PersonName><OriginalForm>Buchanan, Robert</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Godkin</LastName><MiddleName>Sarah</MiddleName><FirstName>Georgina</FirstName><PersonName>Georgina Sarah Godkin</PersonName><OriginalForm>Godkin, Georgina Sarah</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Lewes</LastName><MiddleName>H</MiddleName><FirstName>G</FirstName><PersonName>G H Lewes</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lewes, G. H.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Palgrave</LastName><MiddleName>Turner</MiddleName><FirstName>Francis</FirstName><PersonName>Francis Turner Palgrave</PersonName><OriginalForm>Palgrave, Francis Turner</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Lewes</LastName><MiddleName>Henry</MiddleName><FirstName>George</FirstName><PersonName>George Henry Lewes</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lewes, George Henry, 1817-1878</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>248</StartPage><EndPage>250</EndPage><Pagination>248-250</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2455944/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>CRITICAL NOTICES. CmIIISTUKNITY IN THlE CARTOONX. By W. WATKISS LLOYD. Wiffianms and Norgate. 1865. IT is not often that an author makes one wish him less original and independent than he is; but Mr. Lloyd&amp;apos;s book will probably produce this effect upon some of his readers. He has here united a description of Raphael&amp;apos;s celebrated Cartoons with an analysis of the facts upon which he considers that those portions of the New Testament represented in the Cartoons rest. In this analysis Mr. Lloyd adheres to that &amp;quot; mythical &amp;quot; view of the Gospel narrative with which the names of Strauss and Baur have been conspicuously connected, although Mr. Lloyd has worked independently, and in many cases reaches conclusions of his own. From this standing-point he has criticised the story with great candour, research, and ingenuity; and that profound study of the Greek mythology, in which Mr. Lloyd has probably no living English rival, has supplied him with .someC curious, and, perhaps, some over-subtle illustrations. &amp;apos;Mr. Lloyd&amp;apos;s heart is obviously in his subject, and he writes with the force inspired by sincerity and conviction. Looking, however, at the book from the side of literature, even those who, in these days of compromise and sentimental suppressio eri, honour from their hearts the thoughtful man who speaks courageously what he holds deliberately, may find it impossible not to feel that the author has here united two subjects so widely disparate, not only in their importance, but in the frame of mind which they respectively exact from the reader, that the effect of either portion, and of the book as a whole, runs a risk of injury. Had the ideas which Raphael held on the New Testament been the subject of explanation, there would have been clear reason for a biblical commentary. As the book stands, it appears open to the very same objection which would have been justly made had it &amp;quot;improved&amp;quot; the cartoons in a set of sermons of the ordinary type. It is remarkable, also, that Mr. Lloyd should have fallen into a line of argument similar to that with which preachers have often been reproached. His criticisms appear to pre-suppose that the reader shall have adopted the author&amp;apos;s creed: in Lamb&amp;apos;s phrase, &amp;quot;Ihe converts the already converted:&amp;quot; and those who do not start from his point of view can hardly, perhaps, do justice to the curious and elaborate arguments with which he has supported it. But it will be best not to follow Mr. Lloyd in what, from the literary point of view, I venture to consider want of discrimination and method. Regarding, then, the book as a critical description of Raphael&amp;apos;s art, as exhibited in the cartoons, the English public is largely indebted to Mr. Lloyd&amp;apos;s labours. Art, indeed, like theology, has its sects, heresies, and animosities; and it will be thought by some readers that Mr. Lloyd has passed too indulgently over the conventional limitations and the comparative want of characteristic expression in Raphael&amp;apos;s mature or &amp;quot;Roman&amp;quot; style. The cartoons&amp;apos; however, with some of the Vatican frescoes, and one or two great works in oil, are unquestionably the most complete productions of the great painter, and on the whole may be said to sum up more fully than any other series of Pictures the mediaeval ideas of Scriptural art. Taking them as they are, Mr. Lloyd has analysed each with scrupulous diligence, pointing out the unity of each subject, as conceived of by Raphael, and the singular dramatic power of his representations. The facts and the allusions are explained with great care and research; nor is it too high praise to say that in what relates to the art displayed in the Cartoons, Mir. Lloyd writes with a taste and technical exactness which are parallel to the criticisms of Reynolds in his famous &amp;quot; Lectures.&amp;quot; One rarely finds a book which gives so much the sense that the author is master of his subject. Mr. Lloyd&amp;apos;s taste appears to be of that high and certain kind which rests upon thorough knowledge added to natural instinct; he is one of the few cultivated men of the day who should be appealed to as a perpetual committee of reference by the promoters of public monuments, if anxious to avoid the common fate which attends zeal, without knowledge of painting and sculpture. As a specimen of Mr. Lloyd&amp;apos;s analysis, the following passage is given from his chapter on the &amp;quot; Delivery of the Keys to St. Peter.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Again, in this cartoon, we stand with the Master Jesus and the Apostles, by the Lake of Gennesareth; but between this moment and the former [the Draught of Fishes] lies a lifetime of instruction, of institution, and of suffering; the life&amp;apos;s work is finished, and the subject of the picture represents the very instant when, the personal agency of Jesus having come to an end, the world was to be left to make what it could of the germs of development with whieh His career had endowed it. &amp;quot;The bight of the lake in the background fixes the scene; and the end of a fishingboat, that extends into the picture, is reminiscent of the origin of the fishers of men. &amp;quot; The Apostles are eleven in number, the traitor being gone; and the appearance and costume of the Samiour declare that the incident ii subsequent to his passion and resurrection. The sears of the cross are visible upon hand and foot, and perhaps also in the side. * * * * S &amp;quot;Christ, then, is before us, in the aspect and array of a revelation, an apparition, an oLraqia-the significant New Testament term for his reappearance. He stands entirely apart and disengaged from the group of his disciples, in a manner to remind of the warning to Mary, &amp;apos; Touch me not, for I have not yet ascended to my Father;&amp;apos; and a tranquillity of pose and moderated symmetry of gesture complete the dignity of a conception as grand as it is appropriate. Tenderness and love are in his eyes, as he appeals to Peter&amp;apos;s profession of love to himself as warranty that he can have loving care of the flock committed to him. &amp;quot;The scene, the time, and the leading circumstance of the picture, are taken from the last chapter of John; but the text is made subservient to a broad general treatment which enabled the painter to combine a wider range of expression than belongs to the particular incident as there narrated. In the neighbourhood of the lake and the fishingboat, and in the presence of disciples, Jesus appeals thrice to Peter whether he loves him, and receives three assurances, not given without pain at the repetition of the inquiry; and thrice the commission is given, &amp;apos; Feed my sheep.&amp;apos; So far, and in the detail that John, the disciple whom Jesus loved, is following upon Peter during the colloquy, the painter is content to take his outline from the Evangelist. But the significance on which he was interested to insist, was the assignment to Peter of a certain primacy over the Church and the Apostles. He therefore assembles as witnesses all the other ten Apostles, instead of merely those enumerated in the text, &amp;apos;Thomas, Nathaniel of Cana, the sons of Zebedee, and two other of his disciples.&amp;apos; He suppresses all indication, by costume of I fisher&amp;apos;s coat,&amp;apos; of that resumption by Peter of his occupation, which is so incongruous in the text. He arrays them all with a dignity that comports with the full establishment of their office. He then transfers to this occasion the committal of the keys to Peter, the power to bind and to loose on earth and in heaven; and in displaying the effect which this produces upon the other Apostles, he finds the means to give expression to all the intimations which are scattered through the Gospels and Acts, of the workings of feeling and temperament among their community. &amp;quot; Peter, with crossed arms, embraces rather than clasps the keys, which seem to have been just delivered to him with intimation of the control that they symbolise; he is humbly on his knees, as in act of homage, but his attitude presses forward, his foot is visibly not yet inactive, ald the entire figure breathes out the zeal, and sense of responsibility, and the ardour that had so readily professed that though all others might be faithless, he would never fail, and that grieved at the renewed requirement of avowal of love, either simply or as greater than that of others. &amp;quot; The keys and the browsing sheep are realised figures of speech, which support each other harmoniously, and continue into this cartoon the spirit of symbolism which in the former suggested the introduction of the cranes. By these happy inventions, incidents from the life of Christ seem to be brought into sympathy with that very tendency to apologue and parable that (haracterise his teaching. This treatment also conduces not a little to give to the two designs in which the Saviour is introduced the same ideal air that establishes a certain contrast between the narratives of the Gospels and the greater naturalism of the Acts of the Apostles and the cartoons from the Acts. This is t gradation which always reminds me of that by which we are conducted from the beginning of the Iliad to the end of the Odyssey. The kneeling position of Peter on this, the great occasion of his preferment, signifies something in addition to fitting defecrntial homnagge to the Saviour; it is in accordance with the terms of Christ&amp;apos;s rebuke to the disciples, after they had disputed by the way which should be greatest in the kingdom of heaven, and when they were told that he that was eldest among them was bound to be as the younger, and he who should be leader of all to be as a servant. &amp;quot; The spirit indi&amp;apos; ated in that discussion finds full expression in the general group, and is indeed the key of its chief contrasts. &amp;quot; Iintiiediately behind Peter, John, conspicuous by youth and grace, presses forward with eyes of devotion fixed on the Saviour, and with countenance and hands composed to warmest sympathy and adoration. The air of his head, the lines of his drapery, lent knee, and foot, are in immediate harmony with those of Peter; and the four Apostles who are grouped with him most closely, share in various degrees his sylmpathetic impulse. &amp;quot;(in tlte othe r hand, the spirit and liveliness of his action find a contrast in the most aivinced figure of the group remote from the Saviour, where the germs or the ri mains of ,iffi rent feelings are equally evident. This figure, which in its suspended pose shows less action than any other in the picture, was probably intended for Thomas, reprewsntative of a disposition, not to denial, but to doubt. With head poised in steady attention, he stands quite upright, and his ample robe slips directly downwards from his shoulder, as his right hand-reversed as usual in the cartoon-drawn back upon his breast, seems to keep down the slightest movement to enthusiasm. The left hand has a movement to collect the cloak which is neglected by the unconscious right, and the left foot conld be prompt for advance, but that the right is so entirely quiescent,altogether the most complete embodiment conceivable of absorbed attention and most equivocal suspense, of coolness and hesitation. * * 0 0 &amp;quot;It is impossible to over-estimate the force, facility, and invention which are exercised by the genius of Raphael in this wonderful composition. The most contrasted feelings are blended by gradation, the finest lines of modified sentiment are rendered with complete distinctness. The manner in which the expression of the hands of John and Thomas are defined by contrast with those that appear on either side of them respectively, is illustrative of the principle that pervades the condensed apposition of gestures, and the play of line and flow of draperies, throughout.&amp;quot; England, which possesses so many great works of art, is much behind Frmnca and Germany in critical accounts of them adapted to popular reading. Will Mr. Lloyd excuse the wish that he would reprint those portions of his book which bear on the Cartoons as a guide to these treasures&amp;quot; Ho would thuR &amp;quot; give eyes &amp;quot; to thousands who, now that they are transferred to London, EWill see them with little profit or pleasure in the absence of a fit interpreter. F. T. PALORAvpE.</FullText></Record>