<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2458031</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131705</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>THE WHITE ROSE.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Dec 1867</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18671201</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><OriginalForm>MELVILLE, G J WHYTE</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Whyte-Melville</LastName><MiddleName>J</MiddleName><FirstName>G</FirstName><PersonName>G J Whyte-Melville</PersonName><OriginalForm>Whyte-Melville, G. J.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>649</StartPage><EndPage>670</EndPage><Pagination>649-670</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2458031/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>THE WHITE ROSE. CHAnRm XLV. &amp;quot; THE Li7rLE RED ROVERL&amp;quot; IT was not much past noon when Mr. Egremont turned his back on the Mill, a good deal disappointed with the result of his researches, intending to retrace his steps to Ripley Station, and take the first train for London. Obviously Draper was in his dotage, and no clear intelligence could be gained from that quarter. He had observed, too, while the old man rambled on about his daughter, an expression on the maid-servant&amp;apos;s face that seemed to denote contempt and impatience, as though her master&amp;apos;s hallucination were unquestionable, and of such frequent recurrence as to become wearisome. Altogether, Dolly felt puzzled on his friend&amp;apos;s account, and began to relapse into low spirits on his own. Notwithstanding the quiet promise of the fresh spring day, life seemed darker than usual. Was it worth while to take so much trouble about matters which resolved themselves, after all, into the vaguest uncertainties? Everybody was fishing, but nobody ever seemed to catch anything. Reflecting on the habits and pursuits of his own acquaintances, he could not think of one who sat down in peace, contented with his lot. Dandy Burton considered himself a model philosopher of the modern school; but the Dandy, in spite of his training, could not conceal the habitual restlessness and anxiety in which he lived. Gerard Ainslie poseed everything in the world to make him happy, but here he was in hot water about Mrs. Vandeleur! The poor old man at the Mill had nearly gone out of his mind for lack of his daughter; and he himself, Dolly Egremont, one of the most popular fellows in London, manager of the Accordion Theatre, with health, strength, a good conscience, and a balance at his banker&amp;apos;s, detected a cloud before the sun; because, forsooth, an ignorant young woman with a little red in her cheeks had of late betrayed her own want of common-sense in not appreciating him as he deserved. The malady from which this gentleman suffered has been compared with some propriety to fever and ague. Walking through the meadows by the river-side, he felt the cold fit coming on. Doing violence to his loyalty, he began even to depreciate Miss Tregunter&amp;apos;s exterior; and this is a very virulent form of shivers indeed. Was she so good-looking after all? Nay, even granting her attractions, what was beauty itself at the best ?-a mere anatomical arrangement, a combination of certain tissues and properties, simply disgusting when analysed and taken in detail! Why should all the world be at sixes and sevens about these painted dolls, differing from a child&amp;apos;s toy but in their powers of mischief? PWere not women a mistake P Should we not do better without them ? He laid his hand on a stile and vaulted into a wide grass-grown lane with high hedges on either side, and a few cart-tracks cutting deep into the soft, elastic turf. In a twinkling-his eye, was quick or he would have missed it-in a twinkling, a small dark object, whisking out of the hedge twenty paces off, whisked back again, to steal along the bramble-covered ditch, and cross at an angle out of sight farther on. Dolly stood transfixed. &amp;quot;By Jove, it&amp;apos;s a fox, and I&amp;apos;ve headed him !&amp;quot; he muttered below his breath; but his cynical reflections, his morbid misgivings of a moment back, were all scattered to the winds. I is head went up, his eye brightened, his whole frame quivered with keen excitement, he felt as you feel when the first whip&amp;apos;s cap is up at the far end of the covert, and although the soft warm air be moist and still, the gorse is waving and seething like a sea in a storm beneath your favourite horse&amp;apos;s nose. &amp;quot;sThat&amp;apos;s a hunted fox,&amp;quot; continued Dolly, when he had recovered his astonishment; &amp;quot; the hounds must be out to-day. I&amp;apos;ll take my oath, by the way of him, he means business !&amp;quot; Dolly was right; the hounds were out, and the &amp;quot; little red rover&amp;apos;&amp;quot; had been holding his own gallantly for the last twenty minutes, mostly over grass. There were eighteen couple on his line, twelve of which were workers, and the remaining six had better have been left at home. It may be the &amp;quot; little red rover &amp;quot; possessed some intuitive knowledge of the fact. It was not the first time he had been hunted by a good many since the days of his cub-hood, when he used to catch field-mice, bouncing and gambolling like a kitten amongst the acladed lawns and green shrubbery-walks at Oakover; therefore, when he woke this morning, bright, glossy, brown, and beautiful, to hear the loud crack of the warning hunting-whip, lest he should be chopped in covert, succeeded by the whimper of a puppy, the rate of a servant, and the attesting chorus of some twenty silvery tongues, he led his pursuers a gamesome dance round his stronghold, running his foil with considerable sagacity, till the peal of those vengeful voices subsided to a puzzled silence, when he made the best of his way straight across the adjacent meadows, with a quarter of a mile start, a gallant spirit under his fur coat, and a firm conviction that he could reach Belton Beeches, six miles off as the crow flies, before they caught him. The &amp;quot; little red rover &amp;quot; was but one, and his enemies, amongst whom, I presume, he included none of the horsemen, were legion; yet his heart, Like his little body, was mullum in parro, tough, tameless, and as strong as brandy. &amp;quot; He&amp;apos;s a straight-necked &amp;apos;un, I know,&amp;quot; observed the first whip, well back in the saddle for an awkward ragged bullfinch, when he had hallooed the hounds away and got them fairly settled to the line. &amp;quot; If he don&amp;apos;t mean the old drain at Mark&amp;apos;s Close, he&amp;apos;ll go straight to the Beeches. Forrard, Caroline ! come up, horse! &amp;quot; The horse did come up, though with a scramble; Caroline, somewhat shy of thundering hoofs, scored forward to her isters; and the keen ones, with the blood thrilling in their veins, made all the use of their horses they dared, feeling they were in for a run. &amp;quot; The little red rover &amp;quot; came stealing on, nevertheless, through the silence of the wide rush-grown pastures. Sheep scattered out of his way with considerable activity, rallying and forming gallantly enough when their enemy had passed, and doing their best for his assistance by crowding in on his very track. Grave oxen looked at him wistfully out of their meek brown eyes, and turned to graze again, till they heard the pack behind, when abandoning all their usual dignity of deportment, they lowered their heads, kicked up their heels, blew smoke from their nostrils, stuck their ox-tails on end, and bltndered about the fields as if they were mad. Countess and Caroline, Driver and Dairy-maid, Mar-plot, Melody, Marigold, and the rest, hunting steadily on through all impediments, now spreading and flinging themselves with the sagacity of experience, now bustling together and driving forward with the energy of instinct, came next in 8uccession. After these the body of the pack-the parson of the parish, and a hard-riding cornet at home on leave; then the huntsman, the first whip, nearly a quorum of magistrates, and those hounds that had better have been left at home, followed by horsemen who cross the fields, horsemen who stick to the roads, the boy on a pony, the man in a gig, the gipsy with his donkey, and the labourer who, shouldering his spade, ran after the vanishing turmoil to have his hunt too, as far as the nearest hedge. Of all these &amp;quot; the little red rover &amp;quot; was doing his best to make an example, and he met with less hindrance than might have been expected in his flight. Once, indeed, he found himself turned by a man at Plough, and in the very next field to that agriculturist, ran almost into the jaws of a sheep-dog that had lost its master, and was sniffing round an out-house in disconsolate bewilderment. But the sheepdog being young, &amp;quot; the little red rover &amp;quot; showed him such a sharp set of teeth, and so formidable a grin, as sent the poor frightened puppy scouring off at its utmost speed in a contrary direction; and, but for the steadiness of old Bountiful, the dog, instead of the fox, would have been chased, and possibly run into, by her comrades, to the immortal disgrace of the pack. It was hard on &amp;quot; the little red rover &amp;quot; to be headed by Dolly Egremont, when he had come two-thirds of the distance to his haven; but, although the sight of a human figure in this unfrequented lane turned him for a score of yards or so, he dauntlessly made his point after all. Dolly stood, I say, for a moment like a man transfixed. He was drawing his breath to halloo, when the light unfrequent notes of hounds running hard reached his ear. Three or four white objects dashed into the lane where the fox had entered, followed by a rushing cataract of comrades, and the whole, throwing their tongues eagerly, swarmed through the opposite fence to check, as was but natural, in the field beyond. &amp;quot;Hark back!&amp;quot; shouted Dolly, in the best dog-language he could muster, tearing gloves and clothes with frantic plunges to scramble through the fence. &amp;quot;a D--n ye ! Hold your noise!&amp;quot; exclaimed a voice from the far side of the other hedge, followed by the excited huntsman himself, just escaping a fall, as he landed in the lane, with his horse hard held. &amp;quot;,Your fox is back!&amp;quot; protested Dolly, breathless with exertion and enthusiasm. &amp;quot;He&amp;apos;s not ! He&amp;apos;s forrard!&amp;quot; replied the other, never taking his eye off his hounds. They had cast themselves nobly, and hit off the true line once more. &amp;quot;Let &amp;apos;em alone!&amp;quot; he added, in a voice of thunder, to one of the whips who was already across the lane, prepared to interfere, and ramming the spurs into his horse, without vouchsafing a glance at Dolly, scrambled over the fence to gallop on, with just one twang of his horn, that he couldn&amp;apos;t have resisted to save his life. The cornet, whose hat was stove in, and a hard-riding old gentleman who ought to have known better, followed in his wake. This succession of horses, already half-blown, made such a hole in the hedge as enabled Dolly to pass through. Though stout, he was no mean pedestrian; and on he ran at a splitting pace, keeping the hounds stir in view, and intent only on seeing as much of the sport as he could. Now the man who hunts on foot has at least one advantage over him who hunts on horseback: the former can go so straight. A hog-backed stile and a foot-board, four feet odd of strong timber with a slippery take-off, are to him articles of positive refreshment and relief. Dolly found himself able to negotiate one or two such obstacles, when the boldest horsemen were compelled to make a circuit and find a gap. He ran on, accordingly, with great enjoyment to himself, for nearly half a mile, watching the decreasing pack as they fleeted like a flock of sea-gulls over the pastures, and the foremost riders, who had again overtaken and left him behind, dipping and bobbing at the fences, as if crossing a stiff country were the easiest pastime in the world. Most of the field, too, had now straggled by, affording him an opportunity of observing the caution with which the majority of mounted sportsmen follow their favourite amusement; and after making a fruitless snatch at a loose horse, that deprived him of the little breath he had left, a deep turnipfield reduced the pedestrian first to a walk, then to a stand-still. In this field, for reasons which will presently appear, I am forced to admit Dolly&amp;apos;s vested interest in &amp;quot; the little red rover &amp;quot; ceased and determined for good and all; but the true sportsman, unless he be a master of hounds or huntsman, will not regret to learn that after a capital thing of five-and-forty minutes, this game old fox saved life and brush by entering the main-earth at Belton Beeches, just as the leading hounds crashed over the wattled fence that bounded the covert, and the hard-riding cornet, with his horse &amp;quot; done to a turn,&amp;quot; entered the adjoining enclosure on his head. Let us hope that &amp;quot; the little red rover &amp;quot; may lead them many a merry dance yet ere he fulfils his destiny, and dies a glorious death in the open, under the soft November sky. Dolly, with his hand to his side, and the perspiration rolling down his nose, was making his way to the gate, when the tramp of a horse coming up at a canter through the turnips caused him to hurry on, without looking back, that he might open it as speedily as possible for this belated equestrian. His hand was already on the latch, the horse&amp;apos;s nose was at his shoulder, when a voice that made him start in his mud-encumbered shoes, observed softly,&amp;quot; Thank you, Mr. Egremont. It&amp;apos;s impossible to catch them now. I think it&amp;apos;s no use my going any further.&amp;quot; Dolly rubbed his eyes to be quite sure he was not dreaming, giving his hot brow the benefit of the action, and looked up in the speaker&amp;apos;s face. &amp;quot;d Miss Tregunter !&amp;quot; he exclaimed, in accents of the utmost confusion. &amp;quot;Why, I thought you were in Italy! What on earth are you doing here ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Why, haven&amp;apos;t I as good right to be here as you ?&amp;quot; answered the young lady, playfully. &amp;quot; Indeed, a better, if you come to that; for I believe this very field belongs to my uncle. Besides, I am out hunting, all in proper form, with a groom I can&amp;apos;t find, and a horse I don&amp;apos;t fancy. Ah! if I&amp;apos;d had Tomboy to-day they wouldn&amp;apos;t have slipped away from me like this! though perhaps then I should not have seen you, and it is so long since we have met.&amp;quot; Something in the tone of her voice sank very pleasantly in his ear. Her eyes were softer, her colour deeper, her manner more gentle than her wont. For a moment he forgot his misgivings, his resolutions, all the estrangement of the last few months, basking, as it were, in the glow of her presence, in the delight of looking once again on the face he loved so well. She saw she had lost nothing of her ascendency, and, combined with her post of vantage in the saddle, this conviction, no doubt, gave her confidence to assume a levity she did not really feel. &amp;quot;d But how come you to be here ?&amp;quot; she resumed; &amp;quot; and in such a ridiculous costume for hunting P-umbrella, shiny boots, tall hat, go-to-meeting coat, and no horse! You&amp;apos;ve not come back to poor old Archer as a private pupil, have you P Mr. Egremont, give an account of yourself. What brought you to this part of the country P&amp;quot; SKI came down to find old Draper,&amp;quot; answered straightforward Dolly, not observing a shade cross her brow, for she expected he had made the journey to look after somebody else. &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve seen him this morning, and was on my way back to the station, when I fell in with the hounds. I little thought I should meet you after wondering where you were for nearly six months! &amp;quot; There was something of reproach in his tone, and it smote her to the heart. She felt that, if he really cared for her, she had been acting unkindly by him, and deserved to lose him altogether. It would be very difficult, she said to herself, to give him up. They had now arrived in the high road. He stopped as if to wish her good-bye before he took the direction of the railway-station, and laid his hand on her horse&amp;apos;s neck. a I am going to London, Miss Tregunter,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot; Shall I ever see you again ? &amp;quot; The Accordion, the actresses, the American star, all his offences of omission and commission, faded from her mind. If he parted with her now, here by the sign-post, without any further explanation, would he ever come back again ? She trembled to think not. He, too, dreaded the farewell as conclusive. Neither knew the power each had over the other. Looking straight into the horizon, far beyond Belton Beeches, where the chase was at this very moment coming to an end, Miss Tregunter observed, in a faint voice, and with anything but the cordiality of a hospitable invitation, &amp;quot; Are you obliged to go back by the two o&amp;apos;clock train ? Hadn&amp;apos;t you better come on to Aunt Emily&amp;apos;s, and have some luncheon after your run ? &amp;quot; Aunt Emily&amp;apos;s, where Miss Tregunter was staying, could not have been less than four miles as the crow flies from the sign-post under which they stood, and more than twice that distance from the only station at which the up-train stopped. A more inconvenient arrangement for a traveller due in town the same evening can scarcely be imagined; nevertheless, this infatuated gentleman accepted the proposal with unconcealed delight, and in two seconds had turned his back on his destination, and was walking beside Miss Tregunter&amp;apos;s horse with as light a step as if he had that moment emerged from bath and breakfastroo%. They must have found a good deal to say, for they talked incessantly, and a man breaking stones on the road observed the lady&amp;apos;s head bent down once as if to whisper. This, I think, must have been at some important stage of the dialogue-perhaps when Dolly vowed to give up the Accordion Theatre, at the end of the present season, under certain conditions, which he urged with considerable warmth. It was a long four miles, I have already said, and over one of the worst roads in England. Yet when these wayfarers entered Aunt Emily&amp;apos;s lodge-gates, I believe neither would have had the slightest objection to begin the homeward journey over again. CHAFTm XLVI. &amp;quot;IMMORTELLES.&amp;quot; BUT Dolly was not one who suffered his own happiness, however engrossing, to supplant the interests of his friend. Though feeling he had done &amp;quot; good business,&amp;quot; as he called it, for himself in his trip down to Ripley, he also remembered he had in no way furthered those researches which were his primary object in leaving London. He had nothing to tell Gerard, except that old Draper seemed in complete ignorance of his daughter&amp;apos;s fate. He racked his brain to think what engines he could set in motion for the discovery he wished to make, and in a moment of inspiration, while hailing a Hansom at the stage-door of the Accordion, it flashed across him that he had often heard extraordinary stories of the ingenuity displayed by French detectives in such difficulties as his own. He wondered he never thought of them before. Mrs. Ainslie had left her husband when abroad; that at least he knew, though he had forborne asking Gerard any further particulars of her flight. She had probably eloped with a foreigner, and must have spent at least some part of her life on the Continent. Why, of course, the French detective police, with its wonderful organisation, its mysterious intelligence, its extensive ramifications, and the unscrupulous manner in which it brought all these resources to bear on a given object, was the power to which he should have applied from the first. He began to consider how he could best put himself in communication with this formidable institution. Thus meditating, he remembered making acquaintance, a few evenings before, with Monsieur le Comte Tourbillon, attached in some undefined capacity to the French Legation, and looking at his watch, directed his driver to start without delay for that stronghold of diplomatic ingenuity. It is, I presume, an indisputable fiact that nobody ever gets his primary object effeeted by visiting a legia any dipton; and Dolly felt scarcely dissatisfied-certainly not surprised-to learn from the politest of porters how Monsieur le Comte was absent from the Chancellerie at that instant, how he had not been there in the morning, and was not expected in the afternoon. He even thought himself fortunate in obtaining the Count&amp;apos;s address over a perfumer&amp;apos;s in Bond Street, and drove off once more on the track with a welldefined hope of running his quarry down in this sweet-smelling retreat. By good luck the Count had not yet left home when Dolly arrived, and, with the politeness of his nation, broke out at once into profuse acknowledgments of Mr. Egremont&amp;apos;s civility, accompanied by fervent protestations of assistance and good-will, when he learned that his visitor had already been to the Legation in search of him. &amp;quot; What is it?&amp;quot; said the Frenchman, pushing forward a roomy arm-chair, and reaching down from the chimney-piece a deep box of cigarettes, without which sedatives it seemed impossible any conversation, involving interests of the slightest importance, could be carried on. &amp;quot; I speak in English, you know, mon cher. I think in English; I share your insular tastes and feelings; I begin my dinner with champagne. I rode a stipple-chase last autumn at Baden-Baden,yes, very well. I back the favourite; I drive my team; I shoot my gr-r-rouse! Figure to yourself that I am a veritable Briton-what you call true blue. Take one of these cigarettes; they are of all that is finest in tobacco. And now say, then, what can I do for you ? &amp;quot; Dolly lit his cigarette, and observed thoughtfully between the whiffs,&amp;quot; Your detective police, Count, is, I fancy, the best in Europe.&amp;quot; The Count laid his finger to his nose as only a Frenchman can, while he replied dictatorially,&amp;quot;For repression? No! For retribution-for fineaee-for perseverance-for eventual discovery? Yes-a hundred times &amp;apos;yes!&amp;apos; You remember that murder in the Rue Castiglione, and the number of suspected persons involved? An apple-woman, a pensioner, a convict who had fulfilled his sentence, a Swiss governess, an English butler, the cripple who lived on the&amp;apos;third-floor, a hospital nurse, the iiight porter, and a child ten years of age. It is true none of these were convicted, but our police arrested them all! You have not forgotten the robbery of diamonds in open day from the shop of one Louvet, opposite the gardens of the Tuileries ? One brigand wedged the door, whilst his accomplice broke the window, and carried off a Joarure valued at eighty thousand francs. The shopman saw the mnan, the sentry at the garden-gat~e saw the man, six bystanders (leposed on oath that they could identify the man, and pointed out the very house in which he took refuge. Well, our police hunted and hunted, like bloodhounds, till they ran him down at last; but it was unfortunately in the Morgue, and I fear nobody ever knew what became of the diamonds. Then there was that atrocious and daring murder committed by the man in the blouse, close to the Barriere de l&amp;apos;Etoile, in presence of a hundred witnesses. The assassin walked up to an old gentleman who was a creditor for a sum of fifteen hundred francs, and shot him deliberately in the bosom with a pistol, which is at this moment in the hands of our police. Less than an hour elapsed ere they were on his track. They arrested his mistress, his blanchisseuee, the boy who blacked his boots. They took possession of his furniture, clothing, and effects; they traced him from Paris to Versailles, from Versailles back to Paris, thence to Chalons-surMarne, Strasbourg, and across the Rhine into Prussia. Back through Belgium to France, they were very close on him at the frontier, and a man answering his description in many particulars was taken, descending from the coutpd of a first-class carriage, at Lille. Oh, they searched, par exenmple, searched everywhere, I can tell you, my friend.&amp;quot; The Count&amp;apos;s cigarette was done. He paused in deep meditation. &amp;quot;And they found him ?&amp;quot; exclaimed Dolly, interested in spite of himself in so long a chase. The Count stretched out his hand for a fresh cigarette, while he answered thoughtfully, in his own language,&amp;quot; On ne l&amp;apos;a pas trouv, mais on le cherche toujours!&amp;quot; Emboldened by so successful an issue, Dolly now begged the Count&amp;apos;s good offices in obtaining the valuable assistance of this detective police for the object he had in view. &amp;quot; Comment ? Vous desirez done constater la mort de quelqu&amp;apos;un,&amp;quot; said the Count; &amp;quot;ga marche tout seul! Nothing can be more simple. Is it indiscreet to ask particulars?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Not the least,&amp;quot; answered Dolly. &amp;quot; I have a friend who made art unhappy marriage.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That is very possible,&amp;quot; observed the Count in parenthesis. &amp;quot;This friend,&amp;quot; continued Dolly, &amp;quot; has for many years lost sight of his wife. In fact, she-she ran away from him. He has every reason to believe she is dead, but has no evidence of the fact. At present he is particularly anxious to obtain positive proof.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Precisely,&amp;quot; answered the Count; &amp;quot;he wants to make another unhappy marriage. I perceive-&amp;quot; Dolly smiled. &amp;quot; I hope they are not all unhappy,&amp;quot; replied he, thinking of a certain walk by a lady on horseback not long ago. &amp;quot;But in the meantime, Count, we are most desirous of finding out whether or not my friend&amp;apos;s has been dissolved by death. The lady eloped with a countryman of yours, more than ten years ago, at Homburg or Baden-Baden.&amp;quot; The Count started. &amp;quot; Une Anglaise! &amp;quot; he exclaimed eagerly. &amp;quot; Aux yeux bruns, aux cheveux noirs. Tres belle! Tres vive ! La taille un peu forte! Pardon, mon cher. Your story interests me, that is all.&amp;quot; Dolly stared. &amp;quot;You seem to know her,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot;And yet where you can ever have met Fanny Draper, I own, puzzles me not a little.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Fanni ! &amp;quot; answered the Count. &amp;quot; C&amp;apos;est Va ! Fanchon; at least, I always called her Fanchon. My friend, you came to describe a person to me; I will save you the trouble. Listen, I am going to tell you. Stop me if I am wrong. Fanchon was a brunette, very handsome for an Englishwoman. Pardon: that, you know, must mean very handsome indeed. She had dark eyes, white teeth, and a high colour. She dressed her black hair in masses low down her neck, and generally wore heavy gold earrings. She spoke French badlyvery badly; English with a tone, seductive enough, of your charming patois. She was rude to her husband, who looked younger than herself, and she had run away with him. Am I right ?&amp;quot; Dolly, whose eyes were getting rounder and rounder in sheer amazement, could but nod assent. The Count proceeded in a tone of satisfaction, such as that with which a man works some beautiful problem in mathematics to a demonstration. &amp;quot; They lived in a small and modest apartment opposite the Kursaal when at Homburg, and the husband played heavily-heavily, that is, for him. He was a poor man, but his manners were better than his wife&amp;apos;s. They lived irregularly-what we call in England, we others, &amp;apos; from hand to mouth.&amp;apos; They were not happy in their mynage. Twie, my friend! You need not trust to our detective police. I can give you all the information you require. This couple were in Paris in the spring of-voyon8-the spring of 18-. From Paris they went to Baden, from lBaden to Homburg, and at Homburg the wife left her husband with a French nobleman. Would you like to know their name? Behold, I am not yet exhausted. It was Enslee, Enslee: is it not so ? Say, then, am I right ? Have I been telling you a true story or a fable ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; How did you learn all this?&amp;quot; gasped Dolly, in the plenitude of his astonishment. The Count threw the end of his cigarette into the fire-place. &amp;quot; C&amp;apos;est tout simple! &amp;quot; said he, composedly. &amp;quot; Parbleu, c&amp;apos;est moi qui 1&amp;apos; enlevee! &amp;quot; The authority was unquestionable, but the situation a little puzzling. Dolly&amp;apos;s first feeling was the truly Anglican instinct which bade him consider this man the mortal enemy of his friend; his second, a more cosmopolitan reflection that the Frenchman had really conferred on Gerard Ainslie a very important service. Altogether, he deemed- it wise to make the best of his position and emulate the other&amp;apos;s coolness. &amp;quot; And what became of her ? &amp;quot; asked Dolly, in as indifferent a tone as if he had been talking about a cat or a canary. To increase his amazement, the Count&amp;apos;s eyes filled with tear. &amp;quot;1 She died,&amp;quot; he answered, in a voice broken by emotion. &amp;quot;Pity me, my friend; she died, and I-I was not with her to arrest her last look, to catch her last sigh. This it is that excites my regret, my remorse. &amp;apos;Tis true that she had left me--left me as she left her husband. The only difference was that she did not care for him, while to me she was devoted-yes, devoted! Many women have been in the same plight, I imagine, Egremont, but none I think more so than my poor Fanchon. Even at this distance of time I can recall the graceful pow in which she would stand at her window watching for my return, with her showers of light brown hair. Stay! No; that could not be Madame Enslee-I am confusing her with some of the others. Pardon, my dear Egremont, these soucesira of the heart are apt to distract a man in the head, and I have always been of an affectionate temperament, that is why I suffer. Oh ! I have suffered, I tell you, not only in this instance. Enough-to business. My most sacred feelings shall be repressed in the cause of my friend. You wish to camstaeer the death of this Madame Enslee? Is it not so? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I do indeed,&amp;quot; answered Dolly, beginning, as ho hoped, to see daylight on Gerard&amp;apos;s behalf. &amp;quot; She died, you say. When ? where? Are you sure of this ? How do you know ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I have seen her tomb! &amp;quot; answered the Count, rising to his feet, and standing erect in the attitude of one who pronounces a funeral oration. &amp;quot; With trembling steps, with weeping eyes, handkerchief in hand, I visited the cemetery in which her sacred ashes repose. She lies at Brussels, my friend. From my diplomatic station here, in your great country, I look towards La Belgique, and my eyes fill with scalding tears, for I shall never see my sweet Fanchon agan. Pardon my emotion, monsieur. You are a man of heart, a man of courage; you will not despise my weaknesw. I dined at the Hdtel de Flandre; I walked out in the peaceful sunset; I traversed the cemetery; I hung immortelles on my Fanchon&amp;apos;s tomb; there were flowers growing round it, the walks were swept, and the grass newmown. I recognised the attention of my friend, Prince Dolgoroukoff: he also was komme de comr. We travelled back to Paris together, and mingled our regrets. I am a philosopher. Quoi ! But philosophy can only dominate, she cannot destroy. Are you satisfied, Mr. Egremont? Bah I Let us talk of other affairm Let us dissipate these sombre memories. I go to make a little tour in the park. Do me the honour to accompany me. You excuse yourself; you have notftime. It is my loss. Permettez, adieu, monsieur; ou plut6t, au revoir! &amp;quot; So Dolly took his departure, puzzled not a little by the extraordinary confusion of feelings to which he had lately been a witness. His uninitiated palate revolted from this Mimi of remorseful memories, habitual libertinism, and shameless depravity, spiced with a seasoning of false sentiment. Nevertheless, he felt he had so far obtained good news for Gerard, and went on his way rejoicing. It would have damped his satisfaction considerably could he have witnessed the cloud of uncertainty that overspread his informant&amp;apos;s countenance as the latter paused on the threshold of his apartment, gloved, hatted, and equipped for a walk. &amp;quot;T Tien I &amp;quot; said the Count, putting his hand to his forehead, and trying hard to unravel the entanglement of memories it contained. &amp;quot; Have I deceived myself after all ? Was it the English Fanchon whose grave I watered with my tears at Brussels, or that tall girl from Innspruck, or the Alsatian blonde ? How stupid I am! Fanchon! Fanchon! It is a vile habit of mine to call every woman with whom I have relations by that endearing name. It is convenient at first, no doubt; but see what confusion it makes in the end. N&amp;apos;inporte I Fanchon, or Finette, or Fleur-de-lis, or Feu-follet, it makes little difference; the immorte8ee would have been withered by this time, all the same! &amp;quot; CHAPTER XLVII. &amp;quot;SURGIT AMARI.&amp;quot; GERARD AINSLIE sat at breakfast in his cheerful room overlooking the park, with a bright spring sunshine pouring in on his white tablecloth, and the balmy air stealing through his open window to stir the broad sheet of his morning paper, propped against the coffee-pot. There was a tender quiver of green leaves, a fragrance of opening buds and bursting vegetation, pervading the world outside; and within, for Gerard at least, late in life as it had come, the veritable spring-tide of the heart. He was happy, this bright morning, so happy! A kindly, wellworded letter from Dolly, detailing the interview with Count Tourbillon, had been brought by his servant when he woke, and it seemed like the announcement of freedom to a prisoner for life. True, he had given more than one gentle thought to the memory of the woman who had loved him so recklessly, deceived him so cruelly; but all sadder emotion was speedily swallowed up in the joyous reflection that now at last he might stretch his hand out for the White Rose, and take her home to his breast for evermore. What a world this seemed suddenly to have become! How full of life and beauty everything had grown in the space of an hour! He could scarcely believe in the listlessness of yesterday, or realise the dull weight of sorrow he had carried for so many years that he was accustomed to its pressure, and only knew how grievous it had been now, when it was shaken off. He sat back in his arm-chair, absorbed in dreams of happiness. He felt so good, so considerate, so kindly, so thankful. How delightful, he thought, thus to be at peace with self, in favour with fortune, and in charity with all men! His servant threw open the door and announced &amp;quot; Mr. Burton.&amp;quot; I suppose, since the fall of our first parents, there never was a Garden of Eden yet into which a serpent of some sort did not succeed in writhing himself soon or late-never a rose in which, if you did but examine closely, you might not find an insect, possibly an earwig, at the core. Gerard, cheerfully and hospitably greeting his early visitor, little suspected how that gentleman was about to combine ,the amiable qualities of insect and reptile in his own person. &amp;quot; Breakfasted ? &amp;quot; replied the Dandy, in answer to his host&amp;apos;s inquiry. &amp;quot;Hours ago! Been round the -park since that, and half-way to Kensington. Fact is, my good fellow, I&amp;apos;m restless, I&amp;apos;m anxious, I&amp;apos;m troubled in my mind, and it&amp;apos;s about you ! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; a About me! &amp;quot; said the other. &amp;quot; Don&amp;apos;t distress yourself about me, Dandy. I&amp;apos;ve had a roughish time of it, as you know, but I&amp;apos;m in smooth water at last. If you won&amp;apos;t eat, I&amp;apos;ll have the things taken away.&amp;quot;) While a servant was in the room, Burton preserved an admirable composure, enlarging pleasantly enough on those engrossing topics which make up the staple of everyday conversation. He touched on the political crisis, the new remedy for gout, the Two Thousand, the Derby, the Jockey Club, the Accordion, and the American actress of whom everybody was talking! while Gerard listened with a vague, happy smile, not attending to a syllable, as he pictured to himself the White Rose moving gracefully through her morning-room, amongst her flowers, and wondered how early he could call without exciting remarks from the household, or outraging the decencies of society. The moment the door closed, Burton&amp;apos;s face assumed an expression of deep and friendly concern. &amp;quot; Jerry,&amp;quot; said he, Ad I didn&amp;apos;t come here at early dawn to tell you what &amp;apos; the Man in the Street&amp;apos; says. I&amp;apos;ve got something very particular to talk to you about. Only-honour !-it must go no farther than ourselves.&amp;quot; Since they left Archer&amp;apos;s, years ago, he had not called Ainslie by the familiar boyish nickname. The latter responded at once. &amp;quot; Out with it, old fellow! Is it anything I can do for you?&amp;quot; Burton became perfectly saint-like in his candour. &amp;quot;You will be offended with me, I know,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot; But a mn ought not to shrink from doing his duty by his friend even at the risk of quarrelling with him. You and I are not mere acquaintances. If you saw me riding at a fence where you knew there was a gravelpit on the other side, wouldn&amp;apos;t you holloa to stop me ?&amp;quot; Gerard conceded that he certainly would bid him &amp;quot; hold hard,&amp;quot; marvelling to what this touching metaphor tended the while. &amp;quot; Jerry,&amp;quot; continued his friend, with exceeding frankness; &amp;quot; I have reason to believe you are going to ride at a very blind place indeed. You shan&amp;apos;t come to grief if I can help it!&amp;quot; Ainslie laughed good-humouredly. &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Show us the gravel-pit,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t want to break my neck just yet, I can tell you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You won&amp;apos;t like it,&amp;quot; answered the other. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s about Mrs Vandeleur.&amp;quot; Gerard rose and took two turns through the room. Then he stopped opposite Burton&amp;apos;s chair, and asked stiffly, almost fiercely,&amp;quot;What about Mrs. Vandeleur ? Mind, I have known that lady a good many years. No man alive, not the oldest friend I have, shall say anything disrespectful of her in my presence.&amp;quot; The Dandy began to thiink he didn&amp;apos;t quite like his job, but he had resolved to go through with it. &amp;quot;You make my task very difficult,&amp;quot; said he; &amp;quot; and yet you must know, it is only in your interest I speak at all. Sit down, Ainslie, and let me assure you that the subject cannot be more painful to you than it is to me.&amp;quot; Gerard sat down, took a paper-cutter from the writing-table, and began tapping it irritably against his teeth, while Burton watched him with about as much compunction as he might have felt for an oyster. He had no particular grudge against his old fellow-pupil, entertained no rabid sentiment of jealousy that the woman who had dismissed him so unceremoniously should be too favourably inclined towards the returned gold-digger,-but it was only through Gerard, as he believed, that he could crush the White Rose to the earth. Men have such different ways of showing their attachment. The kindly, gallant spirit, the man of a-really brave heart, can continue loyal even under defeat, can sacrifice his own happiness ungrudgingly to that of her whom he loves better than self, and while writhing in the acutest sufferings, can obey the first instinct of pluck, and say &amp;quot; I am not hurt.&amp;quot; But the cur, howling under punishment, turns fiercely on the once caressing hand, tears and worries at the heart it cannot make its own, cruel as cowardly, seeks or creates a hundred opportunities to inflict the pain it feels. Burton hated Mrs. Vandeleur with a hatred that sprang from pique, disappointment, and a sense of conscious unworthiness discovered by one whom he had hoped to deceive. Therefore, he determined to be&amp;apos; revenged. Therefore, he swore, in his own idiom, &amp;quot;to spoil her little game.&amp;quot; Therefore, he stuck at no baseness, however unmanly, to detach her from the one person in the world who could have made her happy. But effectually to work out his plans, it was necessary to be on good terms with the enemy. He had written many notes, wearied a score of common friends, and submitted to much humiliation with this object. Now he began to see the fruit ripening he had been at such charges to bring to maturity. &amp;quot; It is not yet too late,&amp;quot; said he, standing on the hearth-rug and gesticulating impressively with his umbrella, &amp;quot; for what I have to tell you. Had she been your wife, of course I must have held my. tongue. Ainslie, the world says you are going to marry Mrs. Vandeleur. I don&amp;apos;t ask you whether this is true; but you and I were boys together, and there is something you ought to know, which shall not be withheld by any foolish scruples of mine.&amp;quot; Gerard felt his very lips shake. There was more at stake here than wealth, honour, life, but he steadied himself bravely, and bade the other &amp;quot; go on.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You have cared for this woman a great many years, I fancy,&amp;quot; continued Burton, in grave, sympathising tones. &amp;quot; Believe me, from my soul I feel for you. But it is better you should be undeceived now than hereafter. Hang it! old fellow,&amp;quot; he added, brightening up, &amp;quot; they&amp;apos;re all so, you may depend upon it. There never was one born worth breaking your heart about.&amp;quot; With dry lips Gerard only answered, &amp;quot; You have told me nothing yet. Speak out, man. I&amp;apos;m not a child.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; She has made love to a great many fellows besides you, Jerry,&amp;quot; said the Dandy. &amp;quot; Mind, I&amp;apos;m too old a bird to credit half or a quarter of the scandal I hear, but, at the same time, I cannot shut my eyes to what I see. Ask any man in London if you don&amp;apos;t believe me. You&amp;apos;ve not been in the world so much as I have; and besides, you&amp;apos;re such a fierce, game sort of chap, people would be shy of telling you anything they thought you didn&amp;apos;t like. It is only a true friend who dare take such liberties. I don&amp;apos;t want to hurt your feelings. I don&amp;apos;t want to blacken anybody&amp;apos;s character; but, Jerry, indeed this lady is not fit to be your wife. You wouldn&amp;apos;t like to marry a woman that&amp;apos;s been talked about.&amp;quot; The paper-cutter broke short off in Ainslie&amp;apos;s grasp. &amp;quot;Blacken! Talked about! &amp;quot; he exclaimed furiously; then, checking himself, added in a calmer tone, &amp;quot; I believe you mean kindly, Burton, but you have proved nothing even now.&amp;quot; The latter opened his pocket-book, took from it three or four folded papers, smoothed them out methodically on the table, and observed, &amp;quot;I suppose you know Mrs. Vandeleur&amp;apos;s handwriting. Look at those P &amp;quot; They were receipts of recent date for large sums of money paid, as it would seem, by Burton to Mrs. Vandeleur&amp;apos;s account, and represented, indeed, the withdrawal of certain investments he had made, during their pecuniary confederacy, on her behalf. Gerard opened his eyes wide, as also his mouth, but common sense had not yet quite deserted him, and he pushed the papers back, observing,&amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t see what these have to do with the question. They refer, apparently, to some matter of business between-between Mrs. ,Vandeleur &amp;quot; (he got the name out with difficulty) &amp;quot; and yourself. It may or may not be a breach of confidence to show them, but-&amp;quot; (and here he hesitated again)-&amp;quot; but I don&amp;apos;t suppose a man takes a receipt from a woman he cares for! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Confound the gold-digger!&amp;quot; thought Burton; &amp;quot;where did he get his knowledge of life ?&amp;quot; He turned a franker face than ever on his friend, and searched once more in the pocket-book. &amp;quot;You talk of breach of confidence,&amp;quot; said he. &amp;quot;I am the last person in the world to betray a trust. But see the corner in which I am placed. Am I to keep faith with a woman to the destruction of my friend? Jerry, you are a man of honour. What would you do in my case? &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I cannot advise you,&amp;quot; answered the other in a faint voice, &amp;quot; and I cannot understand you. There seems to be something more to say. Let us get it over at once.&amp;quot; He could not have endured his torture much longer. He was ready now for the coup de grace. From an inner flap of the pocket-book Burton produced a note in a lady&amp;apos;s handwriting, and tossed it to his friend. It had no envelope nor address, but there were Norah&amp;apos;s free, bold characters; there was Norah&amp;apos;s monogram. The very paper was peculiar to Norah, and the scent she had used from childhood seemed to cling faintly about its folds. Gerard was steady enough now, and nerved himself to read every word bravely, as he would have read his death-warrant. It was the note Mrs. Vandeleur had written long ago to Jane Tregunter, about a fancy ball, and which Burton had abstracted from her writing-table. Every endearing term, every playful allusion, would equally have suited the hurried lines a lonely woman might send to the man she loved. The tears almost rose to his eyes while he thought what he would have given for such a production addressed to himself, but that was all over now. It had lasted forhow many years? Never mind. It was all over now. He folded the note carefully in its former creases, and returned it to Burton, observing, very gravely, &amp;quot; You ought never to have shown such a letter as that to a living soul.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; You are the last man who should reproach me,&amp;quot; retorted the Dandy, affecting to be much hurt, and feeling, indeed-such is the power of deception in the human mind-that his friend was not using him so well as he deserved! &amp;quot; Perhaps I might have valued it more had I not known the writer&amp;apos;s character so well. It would have been the worse for you. Good-bye, Gerard. I never expected your gratitude, and I came here prepared to lose your friendship, but I don&amp;apos;t care. I have done my duty, and some day you will confess you have judged me unfairly.&amp;quot; So the Dandy walked out with all the honours of injured innocence, and Gerard sat him down, with his head bowed in his hands, numbed and stupified, wondering vaguely how such things could be. Never before, in any of his adventures, at any stage of his wanderings-in the crisis of danger, or the depth of privation-had he felt so utterly lost and desolate. Hitherto there had been at least a memory to console him. Now, even the Past was rubbed out, and with it everything was&amp;apos; gone too.. There was no hope left in lifeno comfort to cheer-no prize to strive for-no guerdon to gain. The promise had vanished from the future-the colour had faded out of nature-there was no more magic in the distance-no more warmth in the sunshine-no more glory in the day. CHAPTER XLVIII. &amp;quot;HE COM3ETH NOT.&amp;quot; MAN, having the gift of reason, shows himself, where his affections are involved, perhaps the most unreasonable of living creatures. Corydon, offended with Phyllis, becomes, as far as she is concerned, a mere drivelling idiot, and a sulky one into the bargain. He may feed his bullocks, shear his sheep, plough his furrows, and thresh his wheat, with as much judgment as before their rupture, but nothing will persuade him to bring that good sense which he carries about over the farm, to bear on the reconciliation he desires. If he didn&amp;apos;t plant them carefully in drills, would he expect huge turnips to rain from heaven into his ox-troughs ? Wherefore, then, should he stand with his hands in his pockets whistling a tune at the other end of the parish, when the object really next his heart is to carry the vixen off with him in a tax-cart to the Fair? There is a certain element of self-conceit in the male animal, that he calls proper pride, for- bidding him to tender the first advances, or even to meet his rustic beauty half way, and the result of such egotistical stupidity is deep sorrow to her, much vexation to himself, possibly a continued rupture that leads to the eventual unhappiness of both. One tender word, even one kind look, in time, might have saved it all. Men deal hard measure to those they love. The better they love them, the harder the measure. Perhaps there is no injustice more cruel than to make a woman answerable for the slanders of which she is the innocent and unconscious object, nay, of which, in some cases, the man who visits on her his own vexation is the original cause. She has been imprudent, it may be, for his sake. The world is not slow in discovering such follies, nor averse to exposing them; but it is hard that he for whom the risk was ventured should be the one to exact the penalty, that he, whose very hand has soiled the flower, should, therefore, leave it to droop and wither in the shade. Gerard Ainslie, with a kindly nature and somewhat too sensitive a heart, had not one whit more of forbearance, not one grain more of good sense, than his neighbours. &amp;quot;M rs. Vandeleur had been talked about-talked about! &amp;quot; This was what he kept on repeating to himself till he had chafed and irritated the wound to a festering sore; the pure and gentle spirit he had elevated into an ideal of womanly perfection, was, then, a mere creature of common clay like the rest. His idol, that he thought so far above him, had been dragged through the mire like other men&amp;apos;s. His love was no longer spotless-there were stains on the petals of the White Rose I With masculine inconsistency, during those long years of sorrow and separation he had never been jealous of her husband like this ! Talked about ! Very likely they were laughing over his infatuation and sneering her fair fame away, at that very moment, in the clubs. Talked about ! Perhaps even now some coxcomb was sitting by her in the well-known drawing-room, looking with bold insulting stare into those eyes of which his own oould scarce sustain the lustre, plying her with the jargon of empty gallantry, nay, even making love to her, not unwelcome, in serious earnest ! And this was the woman so associated with the holiest and best part of his nature, that to him the very hem of her garment had been a sacred thing, yet all the while she must have been a pastime for half the men in London! A practised flirt; a mere faded coquette. Experienced, notorious, fast- good fun- and, talked about ! He walked up and down the room till he felt half mad. He made a thousand resolutions, and dismissed them all as soon as formed. He would order his hack, ride off to her at once, and overwhelm her with reproaches. He would never enter her house, nor speak to her, nor even set eyes on her againe He would rush into society, and throw himself everywhere in her path, to cut her to the heart by the good-humoured condescension of his greeting, the placid indifference of his manner. He would leave England for ever, and go where there was nothing to remind him of the hateful bewitching presence, the dear accursed ftace! It rose on him, even while he thus resolved, in its pale thoughtful beauty, with the sweet sad smile, the deep, fond, haunting eyes, and then, I think, he tasted the very bitterest drop in the cup he had to drain. These sorrows are none the less grievous while they last, because they are sickly, unreal, shadowy, sentimental. Gerard Ainslie was very miserable indeed, enduring just as much torture as he could bear, and all because a man, in whose honesty he placed little confidence, of whose intellect he entertained but a mean opinion, had told him the woman he loved was talked about! Nevertheless, the only one of his resolutions to which he did adhere was the unwise determination to avoid Mrs. Vandeleur. He refuned sundry invitations, threw over several engagements, and kept out of her way with studious persistency, till he made her almost as wretched as himself. The White Rose began by wondering why he did not come to see her, as was, indeed, natural enough, when she recalled the tenour of their last few interviews. He must have been summoned out of town, she thought, on sudden business, perhaps connected with herself, and this agreeable supposition caused her to wait with more patience than might have been expected; but when day after day passed by, and she kept her carriage standing at the door, in the vain hope that he might call before she went out, when hourly posts came in, and scores of notes in various shapes were delivered by footmen, commissioners, and messengers of every description, yet none arrived bearing a superscription in Gerard&amp;apos;s handwriting, she began to feel nervous, depressed, and sick at heart. Then she took to going out of an evening to such balls, dinners, or other gatherings as she thought it possible he might attend, and found herself, as usual, a welcome guest. The smartest ladies in London considered Mrs. Vandeleur an additional ornament to the best filled drawing-room; and amongst whole packs of cards ranged round the glass over her chimney-piece, she had only to select the invitations that pleased her best. She drove wearily round, therefore, from one to another of these crowded festivities, and each seemed more tiresome than its predecessor, because amongst all those vapid hundreds the only face she cared to look on escaped her still. It is dreary work to assist at such amusements when the mind is ill at ease, the heart far away. Keenly and bitterly the happiness of others brings before us our own sorrow; and the very qualities of peroo and bearing we most admire, only remind us the more pain- fully of our own loved and lost, who would have shone so brightly here. The memory of the head is the most precious ingredient of human intellect, but surely it is wise to crush and stifle the memory of the heart. Mrs. Vandeleur thought more than once of consulting her staunch friend Dolly Egremont, but was deterred from this step by a variety of motives, amongst which that gentleman&amp;apos;s continual employment at his theatre, and intense pre-occupation about Miss Tregunter, were not the least urgent. She entertained, besides, the instinctive delicacy that scares a woman from the subject dearest to her, despite the relief she feels it would be to share her burden with another. Had she met him in society it is probable that her reserve would have given way, and all her sorrows been poured freely out, but Dolly Egremont found no time now for such frivolities as dinner-parties, dances, or concerts. Every moment he could spare from the Accordion was devoted to reconciling his lady-love to its exigencies, soothing her jealousy of the American actress lately arrived, and choosing costly articles for domestic use, shortly to become the property of both. So, after a deal of hesitation, and a certain petulant conviction that she could bear suspense no longer, Mrs. Vandeleur sat down to her writing-table, determined to hazard one frank, honest and final appeal to her unaccountable lover, by letter. How should she begin P She couldn&amp;apos;t call him her &amp;quot;darling Gerard.&amp;quot; It seemed so cold and formal to address him as &amp;quot; Dear Mr. Ainslie.&amp;quot; She plunged into her task at once with a long line that reached right across the page. &amp;quot;,What has happened? How have I offended you? Why have you never been near me ? Nay, why have you systematically avoided me almost since the day (it seems now to be years ago) that, I am not ashamed to confess, made me the happiest woman in London P I need not go into the past. Heaven knows you cannot have reproached me as I have reproached myself. Whatever sorrows I may have to endure I deserve richly, and at your hands. Perhaps this is why I am so humble now. Perhaps this is why I am prompted to write you a letter that you will condemn as forward, unwomanly, uncalled for. I cannot help it. I seem to have grown so reckless of late. Since I was quite a girl everything has gone against me, and I think I have nothing on earth to care for now. There are some things people can never forget. Oh, how I wish they could! There were a few months of my life, long ago-don&amp;apos;t you remember them, Gerard ? -in which I was really happy. How quickly they passed away, and yet I have no right to repine, for I have lived that dear time over and over again, so often since ! If I were to tell you that my feelings have never altered since I was Norah Welby, keeping house for poor papa, at Marston, you would not believe me, how could you P and you would have a right to despise me for the avowal. I don&amp;apos;t deserve to be believed. I do deserve to be despised. I have been so vile, so heartless, so false, and oh, so foolish. No punishment that I suffer can be greater than I ought to expect. And yet, Gerard, I am so very miserable. I blame nobody. I am sure I have behaved wickedly by you, and it is quite right I should be the sufferer, but can we not be friends ? Dear old friends, that&amp;apos;s all. I have not too many, I assure you, and I prize the few I possess as they deserve. You need not shun me as if you hated my very sight. You were not at Lady Billesdon&amp;apos;s last night, nor Mrs. FulIjam&amp;apos;s the night before, nor at the Opera; and there was somebody I took for you in the stalls at the French play, but when he turned round it was a horrid man with an eye-glass. I was so disappointed I could have cried. &amp;quot; Gerard, I am used to disappointments now, though I don&amp;apos;t think practice makes me bear them one bit better. Do not give me another when I entreat you to let us meet once more; not here-I will never ask you to come here again, but anywhere, anywhere, in society-in the world: I only want to shake hands with you and know that I am forgiven. You will then feel that I am still, as always, &amp;quot;Your sincere friend, &amp;quot;NORA1u VUNEDEURL&amp;quot; This rather incoherent production the White Rose sealed and stamped with exceeding care, hiding it thereafter within the folds of her dress somewhere beneath her chin, and resolving, for greater security, to drop it in a pillar-post box with her own hands, though why the ordinary means of transmission should not have served her on the present occasion I am at a loss to explain. I think I can understand the reason she ordered her brougham some hours earlier than usual, and sent it round to meet her, while, still carrying the letter next her skin, she proceeded leisurely on foot to saunter through the quietest part of the park, whence nevertheless, herself unnoticed, she could obtain a view of the Ride and the equestrians who frequented it for their morning gallops. Of course, a personal interview with Gerard, especially if accidental, would be more dignified, and also more to the purpose than thus suing him ins fornmd paqperis, as it were, by letter. Moreover, while the fresh spring air cooled her brow, and the gay enlivening scene, of which she herself constituted one of the fairest objects, raised her spirits, she began to think she might have been premature in her alarm, over-hasty in her conclusions. Supposing Gerard&amp;apos;s secession was only accidental after all; supposing he was at that very moment hurrying back to town, or should even call at her house while she was out and receive her letter when he returned home, why, what would he think of her ? How would he accept that last clause in it, tantamount to giving him up P Would he take her at her word ? Not he! Surely, after all those years, he must love her still. The conviction stole into her senses like the soft spring air into her lungs, bringing with it warmth and vigour and vitality. If it was true, ought she not to punish him just a little for his late defection ? She could not quite make up her mind about the letter. At last she determined to send it, if she saw nothing of Gerard during her walk, feeling a vague sense of relief as though she had shifted responsibility from her own shoulders by thus wisely leaving the whole question to depend on the merest accident. By this time she had unconsciously drawn nearer the Ride, and now her heart leaped into her mouth, for this was surely Mr. Ainslie galloping up on a bay horse discontented with his bridle. The cavalier gave her as much attention as he could spare in passing, but resembled Gerard as little as a stout, well-dyed, well-strapped, well-made-up elderly gentleman ever does resemble an able-bodied, athletic, weather-browned man in the prime of life. She scowled at him with bitter hatred totally uncalled for, and rather hard upon a btranger whose sole offence consisted in not being somebody else. Two or three more disappointments, two or three hats flourished by men who knew that shapely figure well enough to recognise it at a hundred paces off, and Norah, with a heavy heart, and a certain veariness of gesture habitual to her when she was unhappy, bent her tsteps towards the gate at which she expected to find her carriage, resolving that, at least for to-day, her chance was over. If in town, surely on so fine a morning he would have been riding in the Park. Where could he be gone? The morning was not half so fine now. Well, she would post her letter, she thought, because she had told herself she would, and so drive sadly home, not to stir out again during the rest of the day. G. J. WimTE ME.LVIuLL.</FullText></Record>