<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2462818</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127132501</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>ROUSSEAU&apos;S INFLUENCE ON EUROPEAN THOUGHT.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>65</Issue><AlphaPubDate>May 1872</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18720501</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><OriginalForm>EDITOR</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>494</StartPage><EndPage>508</EndPage><Pagination>494-508</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2462818/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>ROUSSEAU&amp;apos;S INFLUENCE ON EUROPEAN THOUGHT.&amp;apos; SHORTLY after the middle of the seventeenth century (1666), the great dramatic genius of the age brought upon the French theatre a rude, strange, and incomprehensible figure, which puzzled and offended contemporaries, which puzzles if it does not offend posterity, and of which the master himself always said that he hardly knew what he had meant by his creation. It was the sound in the midst of men and women playing a little artificial game of life, with compliments, ribands, sonnets, of a hoarse and strident voice recalling them to truth, manliness, self-sficience, strength. The Misanthrope of Moliere was only a poetic apparition. About a hundred years later, the poetic conception took flesh, and the cry of Rousseau shook the world. This vision, too, both puzzled and offended colntemporaes: Rousseau&amp;apos;s person was proscribed, and his books were burnt in the market-place; the Jesuit archbishop and the Jansenist parliament of Paris, the Protestant Council of Geneva, and the patriarch of unbelief at Ferney, all joined for a moment of unique accord in a chorus of angry reprobation (1783). Yet this was an apparition which another hundred years have not been able to lay. The literature of imagnation and the literature of social philosophy are equally haunted by it; it still stands significantly beckoning between the hideous luxury and the sodden despair of cities; and it is not twelve months since we saw it armed with the sword and the brand, energetically transcribing into letters of blood and fiame Roseaus famous paradoxes, that science and art do not purify manners, and that inequality among men is not authorsed by the natural law. It was Rousseau who first called from the depths and launched upon the old European society that mysterious something which we know not whether to call a religion, or a philosophy, or a sentiment, or a dream; which assumes all forms from the vaguest and wildest humanitaran aspiration, up to the last bran-new system fromn Paris, which accurately maps out the future of the race, with each intellectual province and most diminutive moral township finally planted and decisively marked; which men hate or love under the fragmentar and partial designations of Democracy, Socialism, Cosmopolitanism, and the rest; but of whose presence, whether we hate it or love it, whether we hope all things from it or fear all things, everyone in Europe, from the Pope in the Vatican to the red soldier of despair in his garret at Belleville, is conscious, as a brooding and fermenting (1) A Dicoursed deivered before thlRoyul Institatiou, an Friday Eveniug, April 12, 1872 spirit of conviction that the old terms of right and duty and the old forms of humanity and justice are destined to be fitted with new definitions and to receive many unexpected applications Of the personality of Rousseau-which is one of the most extraordinary and interesting, if it is not by any means one of the most fascinating, in history-it is not necessary that I should now speak. It is hard to do so without putting on the mask of the prig. His biography is the record of a tenacious revolt against conventions, a revolt often praiseworthy and noble, often otherwise. He committed a multitude of offences against propriety, he committed many against common morality, and he repeated one cruel and shocking crime against humanity. But we need not here exercise ourselves in these matters. They did not much affect his influence. Men are wont to put aside and to let drop from their memories the foibles, the vices, the crimes even, of those whom they suppose to have brought them new light from the high heavens. Those whom the moralist justly condemns are constantly reprieved by a world which willingly forgets the multiplicity of circumstances surrounding conduct and character, and fixes with perfect admiration upon the extraordinary display of any one singular human quality-energy, tenacity, fortitude, devotion. As has been many a time said, to Rousseau much has been forgiven, because he loved much. In proceeding from the personality of Rousseau to his work, and examining the ideas with which he so rapidly inundated France, we need not expect to come upon many that are peculiarly original, or intellectually of his own conception. There is scarcely a single definite idea among those which made him so great a power, which may not be found among some of the European writers within the range of whose influence he was brought. French writers to this day systematically attribute to the hardihood and originality of his genius much of what was really due to the circumstances of Geneva, where he was born, and to which in spite of many difficulties he always preserved a strong and lively attachment. He was born in a time of great public discontent, and in the midst of perpetual discussion of the first principles both of politics and theology; his youth was passed in the thick of preparation for a revolution. The sight of the austere government which Calvin established and the paternal stringency with which it was exercised and accepted, exerted the same influence upon Rousseau which the spectacle of Sparta exerted over the social thinkers of Greece, by engendering that conviction of the artificiality of a social system and the omnipotence of the lawgiver, which is among the most shallow, deplorable, and ruinous of all the false ideas that infest modern Europe. Again, it has been always thought a sign of Rousseau&amp;apos;s marvellous prescience of the coming revolution that he should have insisted upon thesons ofthe rich and noble being taught some craft or trade by means of which they might support themselves in case they should ever be driven into exile. But this most manly and laudable prescription suggests no marvellous prescience of revolution,-though Rousseau did foresee change-when we remember that banihment was a traditional practice in Geneva, as it always has been in very small republics. When the civil troubles of Geneva came to a height in 1734, many of the oligarchs voluntarily emigrated, just as the French nobles did half a century later. It is the same with that other most unmanly and far from laudable prescription which gave such scandal to his free-thinking contemporaries, namely, that all atheists should be banished from a well governed country. This was a usage of Rousseau&amp;apos;s native city, made wider and more liberal, but still unmis bly a Genevese survival. Again, that notion of the sovereignty of peoples which Rousseau&amp;apos;s eloquence transformed so swiftly into so gigantic a force, though as yet only in a weak and speculative form, can still be shown to have been quite as familiar in Geneva as it was in England, Scotland, and Holland. Finally, the historian of opinion is able to trace in the theology of Geneva during the first half of the eighteenth century a strong movement towards that substitution of natural religion and pure deism which Rousseau expounded with such attractive eloquence in the Savoyard Vicar&amp;apos;s memorable Profession of Faith. This general connection, which needs more ample treatment than has hitherto been thought of, between the spirit of Rousseau&amp;apos;s work and the spirit of his birthplace ought never to be overlooked. History might remind us of it. The most strenuous and powerful disciple that Roussu&amp;apos;s teaching ever gained was Robespierre; and Robpie was emphatically a sort of Calvin who overshot the mark. Besides his obligation to Geneva, Rousseau abounds in ideas which may be definitely traced one by one to the writers whose works he is known to have read. He is steeped in Montaigne; Plutarch, Hobbes, Chan-on, gave him much; but above all in every page that he wrote, both upon education and government, we see how much is directly assimilated from that English philosopher, who was at once the strength and the weakness, the evil genius and the good genius, of French speculation in the eighteenth century,-our sage, firm, and sober Locke. Books have been written to prove that Rousseau was a plagiarist. If the name belongs to one who borrows the thoughts or decorations of other writers merely for a passing literary purpose of his own, it was never more entirely misapplied. Rousseau was by temperament eminently passive and receptive .It was his supreme conception of pleasure to lie profoundly still in the heat of the sun, listening to the hum of the summer air or to the light whisper on the waters of the lake, and passively inhaling the sweet fragrance of flowers and grass and the earth. He read the books that pleased him in the me mental attitude and mood. Their ideas were absorbed, assimilate and became a part of himself, and in the process they were mixed and transformed into a new and strange force. He was oiginal much as Voltaire was; he contributed a new temper and a new sentiment. He combined old ideas in a fresh pattern; he filled them with colour, and warmed them with the glow of ardent passion; with magical skill he wove around them a vesture of tender sentiment, of sympathetic association, and fervid, inextinguishable hope, which brought men rapturous into an unrecognised presence. No doubt the times were ripe, and the minds of men were already turned in the direction in which Rousseau led them with such overm ering vehemence. Had it not been so, it would have been impossible that within a short period of thirty years after the first publication of his two most important works, and almost within a dozen years of his death, the men who avowed themselves for his disciples, who kept his books ever open on their tables like some sacred fire perpetually burning, who never spoke without quotation of the master&amp;apos;s sentences and justification of their actions from his principles,-that these Jacobins should without resistance have silenced the old religion, should have silenced Voltairism, and sent the Girondins who were its professors and representatives to the guillotine, and not only made themselves masters of their country, but should have charged France with a fiery current of social and patriotic and religious energy, and kindled a great flame of heroic purpose, for which we have to seek a parallel in the noble enthusiasm of the first crusades or the stormful fanaticism of the first followers of Maahomet. Once more, then, the harvest was ripe; once more, no man scientifically or intellectually in the first rank of creative originality ever leads masses of men. He can only be original in form, and in the manner of the presentation of ideas of which the various conditions of the time have made men expectant. The theory of the great leader as a miraculously illuminated pillar of fire which flames into light we know not how; or as a colossal monolith silently reared in the darkness of night by unseen hands, and towering like a portent in the level wilderness of humanity,-is one of the thoughts which fade away at the same time and by the same process as that conception of history which makes it a long series of inscrutable conjuring tricks. Every one is tolerably familiar with the issue of the great battle in France between the old and the new up to the time when Rousseau effected Lis memorable diversion. The combatants were the Church on one side and the Philosophers, Voltaireans, or Encyclopkiists on the other. Each party had its inner factions and subdivisions, but as against one another the two great armies closed their ranks and fought without concession, compromise, or quarter. The aim of the Church is a very old story. Bad churchmen were animated by the same selfish and sinister motives which actuate bad men of all kinds in all times; love of wealth, power, ease, and that lazy darkness of the understanding in which the ignoble take comfort. Good churchmen, on the contrary, believed themselves to be defending the sacred cause of divinely transmitted truth and a divinely willed social order against the seatterers of spiritual pestilence and eternal death. The aims of the Philosophers are less easily desenibed, but they may be best understood when we remember that these extraordinary men were consumed by the thirst of intellectual curiosity; that the acquisition of knowledge was to them what the attainment of holiness was to the canonised persons of the rival church: and each new piece of knowledge thus acquired was eagerly transformed by them into an instrument for the humiliation and extinction of what they styled prejudices, that is of the ideas and uses which for so many centuries had been the far-shining beacon of western Europe. Their prime motive was not so much sympathy as curiosity: their field of action was not within their own thoughts, feelings and aspirations, but without, in the esteem of friends and the prostration of foes; their spirit in a word was not apostolic but gladiatoriaL The Philosophers had unquestionably many fine qualities; they had a sincere passion for knowledge; they had a passion for truth, though it was too often disturbed by the factious emotions of the partisan; they had a passion for intellectual freedom, though it was too often blotted by intolerant disrespect for atagonitic opinion; finally, they had the courage of bold thinking and straightforward speech, though they too often lacked that more singular courage of frank suspense and patient doubtfulness. The mark of the school was their enthusiastic belief in external progress, in the gradual perfecting of the material conditions of life by augmented knowledge and enlarged freedom. Their ideal was rationalistic, critical, argumentative, confiding the future of society rather to increased strength of intelligence than to a happier expansion of the affections; to brighter light from reason, rather than to a spread of new warmth and moral energy from the feelings The leaders of this great party, Voltaire, D&amp;apos;Alembert, and above all, Diderot-whose individuality demands a separate appreciation-had many sage reserves and just reticences, but some of their subalterns carried the movement importunately forward, until they had landed the most polished and intellectual part of French society in a creed of some three articles, of which the first was the denial of a God, the second the assertion of the origin of the difference between right and wrong in convention, and the third, the reduction of all motives to deliberate self-interest Rousseau appeared in the very thick of the conflict of these two great bodies of partisans. He speedily found that he could side as little with one as the other. Religious dogma was a stumbling-block to him, and the mere acquistion of intellectual treasure foolishness There wap no pleasure to him, but only desolation and waste, in all the triumphs of controversy. He cared little to prove falsity in opinions which he did not hold; he cared extremely that the opinions which he did hold should be a solid and undisturbed part of himself: not an element of fever, agitation, aggression, but the integral substance and all-pervading essence of a collected character and an even life. His central difference from the critical school did not lie in his demanding a system; on the contrary, it was exactly because they imposed a system from without that he found both the great branches of Christian monotheism with which he was brought into contact so deeply repugnant to him. He sought unity of character in the development of the spontaneous qualities of human nature; he leaned with all his weight upon what he counted the innate sensibility, truthfulness, benevolence, singleness of the heart of man; he insisted that these were the forces with which the lover of mankind should seek to deal, that only by warming, stimulating, and fostering these, and not by a teasing and incessant alternation of argument and objection, of replication and rejoinder and rebutter, can we effect in the world the only reform which good men can care for or bad men be made better by. It is obvious from this how it was that Rousseau&amp;apos;s writings enlarged the attack which the Philosophers had limited to theology and the Church, so as to comprehend in its criticism the whole social order. As soon as ever the point of view was shifted, as Rousseau shifted it, from knowledge to character, from the acquisition of truth to the possession of moral harmony, then it was no longer a question of a special set of dogmas or a special kind of spiritual authority, but of the whole range of those external circumstances and relations by which character and the inner harmony are affected and regulated. To one whose ideal of conduct is not triumphant disputation, but a simple life in accord with surrounding circumstance, clearly the main object is not the truth of propositions, but the fitness of institutions. It is easy to see what a vast and deep-reaching revolution this extension of the field of battle made both in the thought of the eighteenth century and in all social thought since. In comparison with the issue raised by Rousseau, which was nothing less than the entire and absolute transformation of the whole social system from foundation to coping stone, the quarrel between the doctors of the Church and the doctors of the Encyclopaedia seemed little more than the proverbial jealousy of a profession on an enormous scale. The differences between Saducee and Pharisee sink into insignificance before the messenger of a new dispensation. One way of describing the influence which Rousseau has impressed upon Europe, would be to draw up lists of the ideas which he e nd -in his various capacities of novelist, moralist, publicist: such as, in politics, the indisie, inalienable, irre ble sor ty of peoples; the propriety of having a state rligion; the folly of representative gorent, which only gives men a moment of freedom at the time of election: in education, the necessity of parents being the teachers of their own children; the mischief of anything like premature competition, and forced rivalry; the superiority of the conditions of rustic isolation and rustic simplicity. But bare catalogues of these several orders of ideas do not sfciently reveal the total force, by which Roun seized the imagination of France, surpassing thePhilosophers in disrespect for tradition and authority, and the Church in devout religiosity; introducing decisively sAtrge and hitherto unknown sentiments, the sentiment of nature for one, of world-weariness for another, into a front place in European literature; and finally achieving the sovereign distinction of true power, by making as deep a mark in the thought of adversaries as in the thought of avowed disciples. The royalist Chateaubriand and the Christian Lamennais are as much inspired by him as the Jacobin Robespierre and the transcendental deist George Sand. A man&amp;apos;s influence only completes the circle in this way, when his conception has touched the whole circle of life, and this was the important characteristic of Rousseau,-far more important than what he thought specially about government or theology or education or morals, each independently and apart,that he fused all these several sets of ideas into a whole, and subordinated them in their relations to a new type of character and a new type of life. What were the elements of this type; and what was its seret ? Its secret was the old appeal, which comes again and again, and always with stupendous effect, in moments when belief is exhausted, and purpose has become pitiful, and social circumstance has pinched and straitened the opportunity for social energy,-the old appeal away from outer society to the inner spirit of the individual &amp;apos; The true philosophy,&amp;apos; he said, , is to return within oneself-reatrer en soac ue--and to listen to the voice of conscience amid the stillness of the passions.&amp;apos; This was the key-note, the key-note of reaction against a society which was rapidly falling into decrepitude in most of the functions for which a society exists. In decrepit times, if there is ever any revival of vigour, it always takes this form of a return to something to be sought internally in spirit and in truth. Rousseau invited men to turn from dogma in which certainty was unattainable to simple contemplation of the divinity of which the witness of their own conscience gave them full assurance; to quit the pompous sterilities of art and literature and science, and evolve from their own spiritual consciousness a . simple and orderly Vstem of life; to abandon the frivolous existence of an artificial society, its meanness, its luxury, its cupidities and covetousne., and wrap t les in the sentiment of nature, in a feeling for mountain and wood, for birds and lower, for all the glorious ordering of the outer universe How famili all this is to us; bat try to measure its effect, when such a conception first dawned in the midst of the intellectual glitter, the soial dsalowne,. of France a hundred years ago. Its very familiarity to us is the measure of this effect. The stimulus which Rousseau&amp;apos;s ideas gave to imagination, sometimes genuine noble, sometimes infected with a hot and sickly sensuality, and sometimes most unwholesomely substituting bombastic sentimentslism for the robust, direct, concrete, and spacious forms of older poetry, may be seen in the magnificent expansion which has taken place in imaginative literature since his time; and this in the direction of nature-worship, the glorification of solitude, the complaint against social bonds, the professed consciousness of inward capacities far transcending the niggardliness of opportunity, and all the other notes of Rousseau&amp;apos;s teaching. If Rousseau had stopped at the presentation of his ideal of the individual life, and of the modes by which you are to prepare us to lead it, his work would have taken its place along with the other Utopion visions by which men are cheered and elevated. But he did not stop here. He advanced from the consideration of the type of manhood to the consideration of the social milieu, and the way in which he considered this was the root of the vast mischief which he has done. His method was simple. He annihilated the milieu; he insisted not only on isolating his phenomenon in thought, but in fact also The whole past of the race was to drop off from us, any clinging roots and threads to be carefully cut away, the so-called progress of the race to be re-traced at a single bound, and man to be Landed once more in the primeval paradise where there should no longer be any accursed tree of knowledge to tempt him to a second falL All was to begin over again, history to be obliterated from memory, and the old social order from sight. Does this seem too extravagant ? Why, this very spirit desoended as by a kind of -jerky apostolic succession, and with natural discrepancies, to Fourier, Proudhon, Owen, Leroux, Saint-Simon, and others, and has been see in some American attempts within the memory of us all. Let us remark some of the more momentous consequences which ensued logically or otherwise from this unprecedented associationof a moral ideal with the active negation of all existing society. Usually the projectors of new ways of living are content to leave the old ways to themselves, rendering unto Cmr the things that are Caesars, and pursuing their ideas in such tranquillity as Cesar may indulge them with. But the whole system was touched directly and aggressively by Rousseau. He maintained that you must study society by men and men by society; those, he said, who insist on treating politics and morals apart will never understand either one or the other. This was sound teaching enough, if you mean to treat them scientifically; in that case the two go together. But then his was not scientific treatment, but the d priorimetaphysical erection of a fantastic moral ideal of his own, followed by a fantastic social ideal of his own, and the whole work consecrated in the name of ,Nature, which is the modern euphemism for the great eyeless Moloch of force without a purpose. The moral ideal is full of admirable traits, and Emile, with all its faults, is one of the rare books that possess true psychagogic quality. It is possibly a question whether Rousseau meant it to be more than a Utopian romance. There is a story of some fervent disciple meeting Rousseau, and hastening to inform him that he was bringing up a son in strict conformity to the very letter of the precepts of Emile; to which the author replied, &amp;apos; Then so much the worse, sir, both for you and your son.&amp;apos; However this may be, and whatever Rousseau may have meant, the fact that the author of Emile, was also the author of the Contrat Social produced a confusion between moral aspiration and the supposed ease of instant realisation throughout society, which arising when it did, and falling on the soil which happened to be ready for it, has brought forth a great multitude of social dreams which would be purely grotesque and simply ridiculous, if men did not happen to be ready to die for them. Effect your moral transformation: the social transformaion follows alongwith it by the same proces. Rousseau neglected this, and it is a significant coincidence that the Contrat Social, or political gospel, even preceded by a little Emile, is the moral gospeL Both gospels, however, were equally forms of the doctrine that nature has given us all, if we choose to listen to her voice, an absolute ideal of the soeial union, and of the few slight and simple conditions which qualf a man for the discharge of all his duties. His practical disciples in the Convention acted in conformity with this kind of view. &amp;apos;It is necessary completely to refashion a people whom one wishes to make free,&amp;apos; began one famous report,-&amp;apos; to destroy its prejudices, alter its habits, limit its necessities, eradicate its vices and purify its desires Strong forces; therefore, must be set in motion,&amp;apos; and so forth. Here we see beyond mistake the finger of Rousseau, the confused association of swift and facile change in institution with swift and facile change in the habit and aspiration of man. The same fatal confusion of spiritual and temporal is to be seen in the ideas of Saint-Just, the most thoroughgoing fanatic of the Jacobin party. Observation and experience made him reverse Rousseau&amp;apos;s benevolent premiss of the goodness of the human heart. Rousseau contended that man is good, and that if you only move the obstructions of society all would go well SaintJust held that man is not good, and that it is for the state to see that he is made so. &amp;apos; The desire of riches,&amp;apos; he said, &amp;apos; is universal, yet wealth is a crime.&amp;apos; He conceived it to be the business of the legislators to stamp out desires which he admitted to be universal. The land was to be compulsorily divided; everyone not a functionary and not an official was to cultivate the land himself; there were to be no servants, and no vessels of gold or silver; no child under sixteen was to eat meat, and no grown person in three days of the decade. This was what nature appeared to Saint-Just. This, like all extravagances of socialistic Lycurgean thought since, had its root in the pernicious and headlong anticipations of moral reform by root and branch abolition of the existing social laws. But let us return to Rousseau&amp;apos;s own doctrine, as it was originally promulgated. To begin with, his doctrine contained the revolutionary dogma of the equality of man. There issued from it the poetised version of the old theory of the law of nature. If you strip away the surroundings of society, and pierce to what metaphysical dreamers like Rousseau view as the pure and abstract quality of manhood, there can be no reason why one should not partake as much of this abstract quality as another. In Emile, for instance, Rousseau&amp;apos;s capital production, it is impossible not to feel, in spite of all protests to the contrary, that we are preparing a life of self-contained individualism without relation either to transmitted quality and heritable predispoitions or to the active discharge of social functions. To such an ideal it is indeed indispensable that we may assume in all the material width which the educator has to deal equality of inborn capacity, benevolent sentiment, and strong generous inclination. That equality being assumed, and all the differences which we see around us being attributed to the depraving action of social arrangements, there is certainly nothing surprisng in the vehement energy with which Rousseau&amp;apos;s disciples alike in speculation and action have dealt with social arrangements It is inevitable that such a dogma as this of equality, in whatever sense it may be originally propounded, should be transformed into a proposition of politics, whenever outer circumstances should make such a transformation possible, with or without the chance of translating it from theory into practice. Rousseau declared that a iing should not hesitate to give his son in marriage to the daughter of the executioner, if he found in the pair a proper conformity of tastes, humour, character. From this to the doctrine that a king is a mere functionary like another, is not far, and the influence of Rousseau, with his sovereignty of peoples, and equality of man, and law of nature, was decisively atested before his death in the opening words of the American Delaration of Independence Democracy was never more effectively formulated than in the passage in Emile which declares that, &amp;apos; It is the common people who compose the human race; what is not people is so triing that it is hardly worth the trouble of counting. Man is the me in all ranks; and that being so, the ranks which contain the greatest numbers deserve most respeet. In the eyes of the thinker, all civil distinctios vanish; he sees the me passions and the same sentiments in the rough and the man of quality; he only finds a diference in their way of talking, a more or less elaborate colouring; and if any essential distinction marks them, it is to the isadvantage of the more - -imulative. .... Respect, then, your kind; remember that it is composed essentially of the collection of the common peoples; that were all the kings and all the philosophersto be taken away, it would hardly be perceived, and things would go none the worse.&amp;apos; (Emik, liv. 4.) It was the students of Emile who put Lewis XVI. to dea, and sent Lavoisier to the scalbod with the apophthegm, that the Republic has no need of chemists A second consequence of Rousseaus notion of the right life according to nature was the farther development of the doctrine of equality beyond both its moral and its political aspects, into equality of material condition. If merit, under fair circmstances without orgnal advantage or disadvantage, is the same in every case, how much more than unrighteous it must be that they who sow the seed, and tend and watch and bear all the heat and burden of the day, should have even les of the fruits than the loiterer who has done no more thin look on. Rousseau went futher than this, and unsealed a fountain which has since then expanded into a torrent, by this memorable declaration: &amp;apos;The first person who having enclosed a piece of ground bethought himself to say, Thiu mine, and found people simple enough to believe him, was the true founder of civil society. How many crines, how many wars, how many murders, what miseries and what horrors, would not have been spared to the human race by one who should have plucked the stakes out of the ground or filled up the trench, exclaiming to his fellows, Beware of leug to th impostor; you are lost if you forget that the fruits are for al, and that the eart belongs to no one.&amp;apos; The sificance of the fact that no one did thus rise up, and interfere with the trespasser on this interesting and momentous occasion, is as entirely ignored as the significane of the fact of the founder of the institution of propety being drawn, in spite of the goodness of his nature, which no society could as yet have warped or disturbed, into so disastrous a ra ion. With Rousseau you are always equally distant from positive evidence of what actually happened, and from a rational e yea of what he alleges to have happened. Yet the air of rigorous deduction and close reasoning which he maintains even when in the height of his passion has misled not a few into taking for genuinely scientific forms the solemn dialectic with which he works out his most ppost sophisms. People made heedless of logic, either by misery or by intense compasion for the misery of others, never stopped to inquire as to the exact accuracy of a man&amp;apos;s syllogisms who was so fervent in his assurance that the poverty which cries aloud oi the earth is due to a simple and easily removable accident, and that misery is not only unneces but is prevent by such simple processes as declaring men equal and abolishin property. It is sometimes complained that the impulse which Rousseau gave to democracy has only led men to think in an envious and ignoble way of material comfort and gratification of sense as the aim and end of the life of the people. This complaint, we may observe, is usually found on the lips of persons whose own senses are sedulously lapped in material comfort, but wherever found, it is unjust. Rousseau did not envy the luxurious liver, he despised him; he did not wish all to become rich, he wished all to become poor; the plain effect of his teaching was not to make the modest poor envious, but to make the rich and luxurious ashamed. We lose the key to all his thought if we cease to remember that his notion of democracy was not m li but spiritualist, and had its fountain in a strictly moral revolt. Roumea himself is not absolutely consistent in his aversion for society, and there is at least one place where he speakswith reference to Poland distinctly like a disciple of the historic method-. man of true genius cannot help having glimpses of common sense,-but the general tendency of his teaching, and that which was seized most eagerly by all his followers, was to hold up the social order as the evil bulwark restraining and penning up this vast and generous flood of human nature They never explained, and never seemed to have felt the need for having it explained, how this monstrous bulwark hd been raised. Voltaire&amp;apos;s attack on religion manifested the same shallowness: mankind, he sad, were very intelligent, and their intelligence would have made them very happy, only by evil chance they were all overtaken byreligion; where all the religions in the world came from, and how it was that men all over the face of the globe opened their hearts to them, and how it was that their intelligence did not prove a shield against such an enemy, he never thought it necessary to inquire. What religion was to Voltaire, society was to Rousseau Men would all be leading sweet and lovely lives, with souls open to the highest, and senses fresh for all the simple delights of nature, if only they had not been perverted by society; but whence this frightful monster, gorgon, and chima dire had its origin, who invented society, why men with all the vigour of young and ophiiated humanity strong within them came to accept the detestable invention-these were questions which the school of Rousseau never thought of asking. The fndamentl problem of origins once put, they would have been launched in that scientific path from which they revolted. They would have had to perceive that the conditions of the social union, with all its miseries and all its inadequateness, are as much the outcome of human nature as the most heroic type of character or the most perfect ideal of life. Rousseau maintained that bad institutions are in reality not institutions in any right sense; and by the same process of reasoning he counted the bad qualities of men and women as no qualities at alL Society was the unfortunate scapegoat on whose head the sins of the whole congregation were solemnly laid, leaving humanity free of spot and stain. It will be perceived that we are immersed in the abstract or metaphysical method, that our social teacher is just as competent to talk about society as the men who believed in occult virtues were to talk about chemistry, or those who believed in vital spirits to constitute biology. He was persuaded of the real existence of entities corresonding to his own abstract concepti As if society were something apart from the men and women who compose it; as if human nature were something apart from any actual qualities which men and women have ever shown; as if the Laws of Nature or the Rights of Man existed or had once existed in some known document. There is a story that at the time when the Convention were deliberating upon a new constitution in 1793, one of its members went to the national library and inquired for a copy of the laws of Minos. The librarian had to explain that Minos was the son of Zeus and Europa, a Homeric person, a mere shadow of a name in a myth, and that though no doubt his laws would have been of great sevice for France if only they had survived, as amatterof fact no copy had been preserved. Men thought in the same real and corporeal way about the Laws of Nature, and all the other metaphysical figments with which Rousseau had deluged their minds. They supposed that there had once been really seen on the earth that noble, pure, elevated life which Rousseau called the State of Nature, and which was in truth nothing bat a private invention, evolved from his own conscioae leading to the most fatal retr on in the path of civilization, but yet eagerly welcomed by a decaying and unhappy nation. For the material exastion and administrative debility of France were what gave such fatal illustration to the dialectic of the Social Contract. If the people had been materially proseu, and the government of the time a strong and coherent organ of national life, the Contrat Social and Emile would of course no more have led to the desrtion of the old frwork and the triumph of Jacobin principles, than the publication of a new transation of Plato&amp;apos;s Republic would have done so. The concurrence of certain economic and political conditions was required here as always to turn mere speculation into a violent explosive. Of all the known misfortunes of western society-there may be many more of a primitive kind of which we are blissfully ignorant-we can hardly point to one more disastrous than the external circumstances which happened to give to the speculations of Rou a short moment of absolute power, before there had been time or opportunity of sifting the sound grain of truth in them from their evil and drastic husk. That there was a sound grain in them, we perceive by considering the opposite way of seeking social truth. This opposite conception, which arose in modem thought with Montesquieu, Turgot, Condorcet, Adam Smith, more or less at the same time as Rousseau&amp;apos;s, regards society as an organism, the subject of growth and development, the direct resultant of the forces of human nature and the forces of our outer circumstance and surrounding, the final issue at any given time of an accumulation of preceding states, and therefore spontaneously regulated at any given moment by a number of conditions which are capable of scientific examination and statement. This historic or positive conception of every social state has a constant tendency to narrow the limits of social endeavour by freezing men&amp;apos;s hopes of what is possible; to exaggerate the tightness of the grip which the past has on the present and future; to reduce social truth to a mere business of historical exposition, and to confound the explanation of an institution or a use with its permanent justification and eternal warrant. The irrefragble principle not only of the value of soial continuity, but of the proved impossibility of suddenly breaking that continuity in any of its deeper elements, is in perpetual danger -first through the natural disposition of men towards the extreme application of any principle, secondly firom. the comfort which the extreme application of this particular principle brings to the indolent and selfish parts of us all-of being pushed ever on and on, until at Islt we find ourselves confronting all the cruelty, waste, brutishness, that make such havoc within us and without us, with nothing better than the dulled vision and the impotent right-hand of a philosophic fatalisn. The element of good in Rousseau&amp;apos;s passionate declamation was the impulse which it gave in the direction opposite to this. He went as far fromthe truth on the other side, believing that we have only to frame our conceptions of human nature in the abstract, and then to deduce fiom that conception all the maxims which are necessary for the construction of a perfect social system. The extreme view of the easy modifableness of society is just as untrue and just as perilos as the extreme view of the difficulty of modifying it. Safety lies nowhere but in the mean between the stationary fatalism of one school, and the retoessive dream of the other; and this mean we can only secure by fixing our eyes on the past experience of the race: by contrsting the condition of the most backward tribes, I will not say of savages, but of those who have taken some of the decisive steps that lead away from savagery, with the most advanced western communities, many and deep as are the stains still defiaing our civilisation, and marking even in the empirical and tentative manner which is all that the present development of social study permits to us, the long road and the many halting-places and the critical turning-points by which the vast. hosts of humanity have sadly or jubilantly made their way from the old lands of night. This was the experience from which Roussau turned away his face, and it was because he turned his face away from it, and had no thought nor reverence nor gratitude either for the great intellectual leaders who had, one after another and little by little, laboriously worked out a proresive modification of knowledge and laws to meet more and more tisfctorily the eternal exigencies of human nature, nor for the great moral leaders who had gradually elevated our conception of the height to which human nature is capable of rising, as well as by noble and holy example kindled in men the burning desire and strong thirst to rise to this height,-it was because he thus thrust behind him the intellectual and moral endeavour of the past that his own ideal was smitten with scientific and moral barrenness, and after a space fell to the ground like a tower without foundation or a tree with no earth about its roots. His true influence lies apart from his ideal, in the impulse which he gave to the motives for search after social truth. He set forth as no one had ever done before the nullity of a civilisation whose com benefits only the few partake of, and he brought into a Pr ineeof which it can never be again deprived the truth that the vry aim of al our art and science and ognision is missed, so long as the great majority of men are as Gentiles, standing without the gates and having no inhertance in these things. After all, as I have said elsewhere, it was much to induce thinkers to ask themselves and the bondmen of society to ask their masters, whether the last word of social philosophy had been uttered, and the last experiment in the relation of men to one another decisively tried and irrevocably aaq*AXL EDrTonL</FullText></Record>