<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2462059</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130108</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>CROSS AND CRESCENT.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>120</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Dec 1876</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18761201</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Frederic</FirstName><PersonName>Frederic Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>HARRISON, FREDERIC</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Harrison</LastName><FirstName>Frederic</FirstName><PersonName>Frederic Harrison</PersonName><OriginalForm>Harrison, Frederic</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>709</StartPage><EndPage>730</EndPage><Pagination>709-730</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2462059/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>CROSS AND CRESCENT. WHATEVER else is doubtful in this time of suspense, one thing is not doubtful. The existing rule of the Porte is scandalously evil, and its system abominably corrupt. Other governments in Europe have their special evils; one is weak, another corrupt, another oppressive, and a fourth sanguinary; but the Ottoman rule combines every evil in its worst form: it is usually corrupt, feeble, barbarous, capricious, and capable of horrible cruelty. It gives no regular protection to life or property; its system of taxation is little more than plunder legalised; the first duties of a government arc left undone; industry is treated as if it were treason; and the insurrections its oppression produces are periodically crushed by massacre, outrage and terrorism. And the whole of this system of misgovern- ment and tyranny seems to exist for the sake of a small official class, many of whom are the vilest of men. It is a waste of words to describe further this shocking disorganization of society, for a thousand witnesses have proved it; and none attempt to gainsay it. But then this picture, black as it is, is very far from the whole truth. In the first place, it is oppressive not to the Christians alone. It is a system oppressive to all who live under it, both Mussulman and Christian subjects; although in many provinces the Christian races are victims of a second oppression. Evil as the system is, it is certainly not worse than that of other Asiatic governments, at least in its effect upon the people it rules. No one has pretended to say that the condition of the Bulgarian peasant is at all to be compared in misery to that of the Egyptian fellaheen, the victims of a system in which the English money-lender and the British government more or less indirectly participate. It is hardly contended that the government of Persia is much in advance of that of the Sultan in energy, enlightenment, and honesty; and the Shah is cur excellent friend and ally. The ruthlessness of the Pashas is, perhaps, not greater than that of the Mandarins at a tiame of imperial anarchy; and the chaos in Bosnia and Bulgaria has hardly ever equalled that of Japan in the last days of the Daimios and Ronins. So that in denouncing this Ottoman government it is as well to remember that we mean simply that it still retains its old Asiatic type. But further than this. The Ottoman rule, as it is, is not much worse than that of European governments at their worst in evil times. The condition of Bulgaria at this moment is not more heartrending than was the condition of Ireland after the rebellion of 1798, or of Poland after the close of the last insurrection. It is not so dreadful as is often that of a black population where the planters have stamped out some abortive riot. The iniquity of the Sultan&amp;apos;s government is not deeper than that of King Bomba. The chaos of it is not equal to that in which Spain has found herself more than once within this century. There is in Turkey no tyranny so vast, so cemented by custom and law, as was that of the ancient noblesse in France and in parts of Germany before the revolution. The Christian rayah of the Balkan is hardly worse off than were the Russian serfs down to recent memory; than were negro slaves in the swamps of the Mississippi; than are the coolies whom Englishmen and Americans export and oppress. The lawlessness of Roumelia, is hardly greater than has been, in living memory, the lawlessness of Sicily, of Cuba, of Carolina, of Ireland. Perhaps the closest of all parallels to the rule of the Porte was in the worst days of the temporal power of the Pope; when it neglected everything which a government ought to do, and did everything which a government ought to avoid. Nay, more, the latest observers have told us that the actual peasant of Bulgaria is at this moment better fed, better housed, better clothed than the peasant of England or Ireland, in spite of the beneficent rule we enjoy. He is better off than the Russian mujik which he seems destined to become. It is certain that he is a prosperous and fortunate being- if compared with the peasant of the Nile, the subject of our excellent friend the Mussulman Khedivc of Egypt. Now these cases do not at all prove-they arc not intended to suggest-that the Ottoman rule as a whole is no worse than its neighbours in Europe. There is this great difference: that we are not responsible for the Asiatic governments, as we are for the Turk. And no government in Europe is so steadily bad. We do not suppose that any government in Europe, at least in this century, has united so consistently all the evils of the Ottoman system ; its apathy, its venality, its stupidity, its ferocity. But it is clear, first, that it is a government of the conunon Asiatic type; secondly, that European nations have exhibited in turn flagrant examples of all of its evils, and now and then all of them together. The government, vicious and wicked as it is, is not altogether different from. Eastern governments which we treat as allies, and do not propose to annihilate. It is not altogether different from what Christian and European governments have occasionally beemi. And lastly it is not so grinding to the welfare of its subjects as some systems we have known, negro slavery, serfdom, and pCasalt destitution, which may not be the work of any government at all; but which certainly have been the outcome of Christian institutions, and were maintained by a Christian people. The practical question, however, is not what is the exact moral culpability of the Ottoman system ? but how does it make it our duty to interfere? Nor is this quite so easy a matter to answer as some people think. Here is a state which for centuries has been the ally of European states, an odiously corrupt and cruel 5government, as corrupt and cruel as was that of the old Bourbons, as unscrupulous as that of the later Bourbons; with a dominant race who have held their lands and their rule for three centuries, almost as oppressive as the feudal noblesse of the last century, as ferocious as the Russians in Poland in our own day, or as the Protestant loyalists in Ireland in the days of our grandfathers. It needs little to show what are the evils we incur when foreign nations sweep away any dominant race, destroy any oppressive government, or put down a system of religious injustice. England, indeed, attempted in 1793 not to sweep away, but to restore, the French noblesse, bag and baggage, with their marshals and their governors, their intendants and their farmers-general, their provosts and their gens-d&amp;apos;armes. The French Republicans interfered to sweep away aristocracy and monarchy from many neighbouring nations, and landed in Ireland in the name of humanity to put down the ascendancy of the blooily ruling class. We can all see how thoroughly questionable in principle is interferenec of this kind. If ever there was a case for just interference it might be said to be that to put down the atrocious system of slavery. Yet we all know that the remedy would be worse than the disease. An cra of gencral aggression and lawlessness would follow from the doctrine that, given a dominant class, oppression, and misgovernment, it is the right or duty of foreign nations to step in anid crush it by arms. It is a doctrine which will scarcely be established in the public law of Europe by the rulers of Ireland and of Poland. It is true that no single case of oppression in Europe is now so desperately evil as is that of Turkey; and in some of these cases of oppression the government may be well-intentioned. But a Europe which accepts the extinction of Poland, the annexation of Lorraine, the massacres of French Republicans, and the barbarous civil wars of Spain, is hardly yet competent to inaugurate the reign of justice and mercy -at least by steel and gunpowder. But it is easy to overstate even the corruption of this Turkish government. Every single opinion in this unhappy business needs to be mollified; and the Sublimeo Porto itself is not absolutely and inevitably evil. The pretence that the whole story of Ottoman rule is one unbroken tale of blackness, is a simple outburst of fanatical rhetoric. The spirit of Turkish ascendancy is at best but a sinister type; but it has spared the rival tribes and sects within its limits centuries of anarchy and strife. The sectaries, as we see, Catholics, Greeks, Jews, and Armenians, pursue each other with bitter hatred, which the Turkish authority alone prevents from bursting into religious war. The empire is the seat of almost as many antagonistic sects as England itself; and unfortunately Eastern sects do not confine themselves to a war of tongues, but the contemptuous toleration of the Turk at least forces them all to keep the peace. The rivalries and feuds of the complex races within the empire are, if anything, yet more intricate and fierce; Hellen, Slavonian, Albanian, and the rest, being madly jealous of each other. So that men who know the vehemence of strife between sects and races in the empire have been heard to assert, that with all their griefs against the Turk, and each thirsting for mastery for itself, the Ottoman rule is still the one which would be accepted as the least galling to all; in fact the only one possible, as it divides them least. This was possibly true of the past; it explains the historical existence of the Porte. Nor is the Turkish government in itself uniformly and always corrupt. It is a bit of theological malice which tries to persuade us that all Mussulmans are wild beasts, and the Turkish Empire a hell upon earth. Men of sense well know that there are still some within it, as there have always been, desirous of raising it to better things. The misfortune is that they are so few, and, in the prevalent corruption, so powerless for good. But the fact remains, as cur own generation has seen, that there are always amongst the rulers of Turkey one or two men quite as honest and quite as capable as the average officials of Europe. The Ottoman Empire, like so many ancient empires, does still exhibit in its decay incredible powers of momentary vitality; and if it is unlikely, it is not beyond the bounds of possibility, that a group of capable statesmen might yet be borne to power by fortunate circumstances. The idea that the religion of Mahomet breeds nothing but Ezzelins and Borgias is a stupid piece of religious intolerance. Now, if the Turkish Empire stood isolated from Europe altogether, an island in the Atlantic, it might, perhaps, be left to work out its own destiny; as we have to leave Cuba, as we have to leave Ilayti. It would be simiply the case of a dominant race, yet capable of maintaining its rule, grievously oppressive and corrupt, but only as a matter of degree more corrupt and oppressive than other dominant races. Europe has never adopted the doctrine that it is the duty of foreign nations to invade their neighbours wherever they find an oppressive government or race. And there are some who assert that there is no more pretence for Europe to interfere with the misgovernment of Turkey than there is to intervene in the misgovernment of Mexico, or the oppression of the planters in the West. To this we reply, that Turkey is not isolated from Europe; but very closely bound up with it by all kinds of ties-of religion, race, interest, political tradition, and geographical connection. The possession of the Danube, the Bosphorus, the Dardanelles, and the Archipelago is a matter of vital moment to all the powers of Europe; the oppression of Christian races in Turkey is, and for a century has been, a source of endless agitation to the neighbouring states; and, above all, the existence of the empire is from day to day the standing work of European policy. It is mere self-deception for Englishmen of the absolute laissez-.faire school to repeat that this country cannot undertake to set the world to rights, and must simply decline to interfere with Turkey. The stafits qito in the East does not mean not interfering. It means interfering to maintain a very active but veiled support. Ever since the Crimean war at least, the existence of Turkey has been due to the fact that the Western powers oppose the extinction of the Porte; to the conviction above all that the whole strength of England would be thrown into the scale before the Turks should be driven into the Bosphorus. The one direct question of the day is this:-Is England prepared to recognise and renew this standing engagement, and especially is she willing to renew it without conditions ? Here then, to go no farther, we have a dilemma of almost endless complexity. It is precisely such a case as that which exercised the ingenuity of the great statesmen of Elizabeth, when they drew out a double table of reasons pro and con for the adoption of some policy or project. Every argument has its answer; every answer its rejoinder. The result we see in the clash of passion which for months has divided our statesmen and our parties, our journals and our discussions. On the one hand, it is said,-Here is a government of extreme corruption, injustice, and cruelty. On the other hand, many other governments are, or have been, almost as bad; and the world would be a scene of violence, if bad governments are to be constantly overthrown by their neighbours. But the special evil of this government is that it is the rule of a dominant race in manners, language, law, and religion, opposed to their subjects or victims. It is replied,-But there are too many such cases-Poland is one-and the evils of interference usually outweigh the advantages. But the crimes of this oppression disturb all neighbouring states, and Europe heaves and shakes on the verge of convulsion in consequence of it. That may be; but Europe must show that it is not about to deepen the convulsion, and extend the area of war. But this dominant race is the common oppressor of all Christian races. It is too true; but a war to extirpate a particular religion is an evil even greater than oppression and misgovernment. But one nation at least is (letermined to make an end of this oppression. True, so it seems; and that nation cannot clear itself of the charge that it is about to make a war which is a mixture of crusade and war of conquest. But the oppression would not exist at all, unless the nations of the West were giving it a virtual or moral support. To which it is replied that the nations of the WVest have been only labouring to avert what is either anarchy or conquest, the opening of a strife which must end in the general confusion of Europe. And so on, through an endless succession of counter propositions. Now without affecting any sort of judicial solution to this tangle of constant rejoinders, the preponderance of judgment inclines towards real but qualified interference. The dangers of the statws quito arc now at least distinctly greater than the dangers of action. The arguments that the Ottoman rule is abominably evil; that whilst it remains unchanged and uncontrolled, Eastern Europe must continue in hopeless ferment; that Russia most certainly opens war unless it is controlled; that the existence of this rule is practically the work of ancient and continuing interference:-these arguments would sceni now to overpower the risks of entering on a course of which no man can foretell the end, of proclaiming the doctrine that evil governments are to be controlled by foreign neighbours. We may hope then that, in spite of the unpardonable bluster of our Premier about the integrity of the Porte, it may yet be possible to rescue its sul)jects from the worst of their sufferings; to circumscribe the area of the evil which it works; to force it, whilst it belongs to the Europlean family of natiojis, to conform itself somewhat to EJuropean conditions. It is idle any longer to dream of the stbf us quo in Turkey as a guarantee for the peace of&amp;apos; Europe, for it is becomc its pniicipal disturbing cause. Xor neel any thought of the nominal independence of the Porte stay the nations of the West from wringing from it any guarantee for peace and better governitient which policy or force can extort, within the limits we next proceed to consider. The limits of all efforts for the welfare of the subjects of Turkey -limits to overstep which, we say, would bring evils worse than the diseasc-are briefly these. To destroy t1h (ttomaU rule, anmd then to crush and keep in subjection the (lolninunt Turkish race; to offer the Turki h E1lpire as a simI)le prize for con(1uest; to proclaim a war of religion, and to drive all iMahonetans als such from their power and possessions in Europe-these, we advisedly say, are evils of such menace, so iniquitous in principle, so sanguinary to excoute, so rife with incalculable (lisordler to the l)cpac of Europe and to the relations of humanity, that we will not accept them as remedies- no, not for the chance they promise us of thus ending the sufferings of the rayahs; no, not though our souls are wrung by the blood and crimes of Batak. No man who will calmly consider these risks can venture to call them imaginary. Gentlemen from platforms and pulpits may roundly assure us that they only ask Lord Derby to put an end to the rule of the Porte. But men who think calmly well know, that before the Porte is abolished, the Turks must be crushed in a bloody, lengthy, extended war; that before such a war can be successful, it must become a war of religion, of Cross against Crescent ; and that when such a war is ended, the vast empire of the Ottomans can only be left as the spoil of some conqueror or conquerors, who in turn will be the danger and terror of Europe. These are the things which we refuse to join in-to extirpate, expel, or crush a race of soine millions; to open a new war of religion ; to abet a new era of conquest. It needs but little to convince us how near we are to any or all of these projects, in the elastic name of humanity and civilisation. Men talk of getting rid of the Turks-with or without their bag and baggage-as if it were done, so soon as Lord D)erby and Lord Salisbury had signed a piece of paper. But one would think that the course of the war had made one fact clearer than it was before. Turkey has proved herself to be still a military power. However rotten the empire may be, it has still some fight left in it, some cohesion, some energy. The merits of the Servian army may be low indeed; still, when we come to put together all the difficulties which the Turkish government has met, we finf(l a polwer that yet must 1)e reckoned with. Bankrupt, harassed by the Great Powers, amid threatened by an invasion of almost all its snialler neighblours; illprovi(led with roads, material, or offieers; she has vet succeeded in carrying on war in three or four very difficult districts at once, and in protecting her immense and scattered territory from invasion ald insurrection. If the Servian army was contemptible in itself, it was large at the outset, and it had the advantage of sonme generals of excellent quality, and a splendid nucleus of Russian volunteers. The Montene-rins are consummate mountain warriors. In both cases the defence and the invasion had to be carried on in a most (lifficult country and under most unfavourable local conditions. We have seen wvhat enormous sacrifices and how many years it cost Spain to crush a few thousand Carlists in a mountain country. And we see what disasters befall the brave Egyptian armny in their petty Abyssinian catkipaign. But the war with Servia and Montenegro forms only part of the difficulties which Turkey has had to meet. Greece, the islands, and Roumania, hadl to be watched in Europe; and all the tribes, sects, and latent insurgents of the empire. Russia had to be watched in Asia; the Black Sea and the AEgean had to be guarded; and the heterogeneous levies drilled, equipped, and transported great distances under every kind of embarrassment. Two Sultans had to be deposed; ministers have been assassinated; and for months the empire has struggled on with latent revolution and insurrection within. Reduce to their lowest the results which Turkey has achieved, the fact remains undoubted: that, in the midst of almost every difficulty and disaster which can beset a state, she has in a few months utterly crushed a most formidable invasion. The most strenuous believer in the corruption of the empire must reluctantly admit that it has still a power of defence, such as, in the last resort, might prove a very formidable force. There can be no doubt now about the fighting quality of the Turkish soldier. The disciplined troops, apart from the brutal marauders, have every excellence of the warrior-discipline, endurance, sobriety, alertness, and perfect fearlessness. The common M~ussulman linesman toils and dies without a murmur; believing in his own God, and practising his own religion with a reality unknown to the modern Clristian. ie is devout, unblenching, obedient; burning with zeal for his faith and his sovereign; not wantonly inhuman, but entirely ready to be ruthless, when he is told to crush the enemies of his creed. Europe has had a glimpse of that fanatical and ferocious hero with whom our ancestors had such dreadful battle, and may see what that being is like, the murderous and fearless trooper who followed to the death some bloodthirsty captain of the old times: Richard of the Lion Heart, or Edward the Black Prince; Claverhouse&amp;apos;s band, or the Chouans of La Vendee; or any other famous fighting, savages, who thought it a pious work to slaughter and lay waste in the name of what they called their God and their kin,,. Modern lurope, which has outgrown belief in its religion, as well as the passions of its religion, is aghast to see the fury of men who believe in their religion and mean to fight for it. The ferocious soldier whom wo have seen in Servia is only i man who seriously does believe in the God of battles: so fitr 011 a iar with tho Russian fanatic, ho may be a triflo more barbarous. But indignation at his ferocity should not blind us to his qualities; for tbeste are lprineiplal factors in the l)rol)lem. Of the inixed races of Turkey in Europe the Turks alone possess the (lualities of force and of command. It is a fact to be counkted with, and all the indignation in the world will not alter it. As a simple iiatter of strength the average 11ulgariun of the l)aliu is no inatch for his Turkish master, any Imore thai is the Sorvian, or the Greek, or the Arnienian. This survival of fighting and dominant power in the Turk will explain (as nothing else can) the continual resuscitation of the Ottoman Empire. A hundred years ago, it seemed as weak as it is now; even weaker and nearer to ruin. Again and again, it has been driven from the Danube, and again and again it returns; and after countless defeats and disasters in those very valleys and mountains, the Crescent was the other day again in full cry for Belgrade. This disposes of the old idea that Turkey is merely a geographical expression, that its government has no longer any resisting power left. The Turks would evidently fight Russia, or Europe itself, before they recross the Bosphorus. Putting aside the invasion of other neighbours and internal insurrection, it would probably strain the resources of Russia herself to make a successful conquest of Turkey. It is far from clear that the Russians believe there is nothing but a military parade between them and the Golden Horn. The Turks, it is certain, regard the control of their own home provinces as equivalent to their own existence in Europe. The fact, then, is as proven as any fact can be, that if the rule of the Osmanlis in Europe is to be annihilated, it can only be by war; and such a war must be one of desperate ferocity, of unknown extent, and possibly of long duration. It follows that those who call for the extinction in Europe of the Ottoman Empire, for the expulsion of its civil and military officials, bag and ba-gage, across the Bosphorus, are simply calling for a most bloody and most widespread war. Now about this there ought to be no sophistication. The antiquarian and theological fire-eaters who yearn for the reign of Tzimisces and the true Cross are possibly prepared for a bloody war. But perhaps politicians who simply intend to take the liberal view, and exhibit their hatred of oppression, do not precisely contemplate war us the result. Yet war is the inevitable consequence of what they demand. To strip the Turks of all but nominal empire in Europe, to plant Servians in Bulgaria, in Thessaly, in Epiros, and to shut the Turks in Byzantium, as the Pope was restricted to Rome, if this is to be done, it can only be done by fighting. Unhappily it is not a simple matter of fighting. The destruction of the government of Ablul 1lamed (a very easy matter) would not suffice. The Turks in Europe are many millions, and they are supported by ten times as many millions in Asia. They have to be crushed as at dominant class; and when they have been crushed they have to be kept in subjection. In effect they would have to be dispossessed of their lands, and driven as a race into Asia. It is more than another Poland which has to be partitioned; it is all Eastern religion and a settled race which have to be thrust out. Turn it how we will, this is simply the cry of the ancient crusades. And which of the Dations of Europe can decently pretend that it is entitled to act as the avenging Providence ? Though no European power has reached to such height of misgovernment, oppression, and periodical ferocity as stamp the rule of the Porte, few of the powers of Elurope are so clear of these offences as to justify their proclaiming a crusade. As to Russia, if her government is somewhat less oppressive than the Ottoman, and her typo of Christianity superior to the creed of the Prophet-and both have been doubted-her record of cruelty is not rea3surin&amp;quot;. If we sum up all the deeds of blood and ralpine which have beemi wrouglht in Poland since the days of Catherine, in the secular wars with the Turks, in wars with Cai ucasian races and Tartar tribes, in massacres in Warsaw, in storminmgs of Ismail, in slaughter of Circassians, down to the order blut the other day to exterminate the Yomuds, we shall conclude, perhlaps, that the roll of Turkish atrocity is somewhat more red, iore revoltinig, more dnornious, than the roll of Russian atrocity; but the difference, after all, is one of degree. It is a fearful and humiliating thought, bow often is the whole tale (of history stained from page to page wvithi dleeds of blood anmd horror. Soulne dreadful illci(lent impels our attention to a particular race or a siiigle epioch, and(1 we are appalled to see the wickedness and ferocity its inner history (lisplays. It is as if with a magnifying glass we look into some turbid (lrop of alnimal life, auid are aghast to see wh~at. fierce and ra-,iii- monsters torture aiid prey upon their fellows. We forget bow many a page of history can reveal to us this scene of hi rife, when we flix our eyes uponJ) its crimes in detail. We liay go throtugh the whole black cataLloglle of crile and cruelty which has stained eveil Christian iatiolmi in our (luite modern times, and isununnom one after another beforel the bar of outraged humanity. Holow wimiiy hecatomnis have l)een slaini an(l provinces desolated in purtposeletss cruelty; what tales of slaughter, of burning, torture, ripe, ald rapine, raging- round the civilised world in the dynastic varsnil wars it Of plihiler; in wars of religiomi, of party, un(l race; iii savage rebelliojis, and yet more havage represfioiis; ull the Lorrors of the Frenmch Revolution, of the Irish R elbellion, of &amp;apos;Parisialn insturrectionis! If we reniciiiber all that was done ait Nuntes alnd W\icklow, at Bladajoz und Warsaw, Mihan and l&amp;apos;estlh, Ma(lrid and Paris; if we tlhink of the slave-trade and the slave system, hardly yet extinct in Christlian nations, to say nothiing of what has been (one in Al giers, and in lfindostan, in China and Japan, in Cuba and in Carolina-ieu*t, c. t ol (tritore mistro ?-woe may well wonder uwhich of the Inations1 of Europe is called upon to extirpate the Turks a-s monsters of cruelty and Oippiressioni. We do not, by one word, seek to dull the sense of horror which filled the world at the story of the Turkish crimes. We do not pretend that any single instance of the like in the slightest degree reduces their enormity. But we learn that the crimes in Bulgaria differ in degree, and not in kind, from the crimes of Christian nations; and that none of the nations of Europe have the moral right to enter on a crusade. Every one of them in turn, when pressed by desperate perils, has asserted the ascendancy of race or class with frightful cruelty; and most of them are capable of doing it again. It may be, notwithstanding, their duty to combine, that cruelty may be checked and oppression cease. But when we are asked to extirpate a dominant oppression, it is as well to know where we are to stop. If the Turks are to be expelled from Europe, why are the Russians to be endured in Poland, or the Germans to be endured in Lorraine? Some may sa, Why is any dominant race to be endre(l, which misgoverns, or is hateful to a people of different religion :e When we look into these (questiolls, and all that they suggest, we see that the proposal to root up the ascen(laney of the Turks in Turkey is at bottom a form of the doctrine that Mussulnians as such are to be driven out of Europe. Now this is to resort to the princil)le of&amp;apos; a crusade. And a crusade such a scheme would be or become. For nio military occupation or diplomatic mancuuvre would end the reign of Islam in Europe. It would bltcole Ca crusa(le, merciless, j)rolonged, ever-extending; inv&amp;apos;olving unknowII horrors and dangers not to be foreseen. The Turk witli his back to the sea would die hard; and die like a Moslem. The (lifficulty of extirpating Turkish ascen(dan.1cy is not isillil)ly tho difficulty of getting rid of the Turk, short of a sanguinary war; it is the difficulty of knowing wVIhat is to be put in his l)laee. Every one scouts the ideat that the divided aind UrLisbed subject-races are yet fit to form imidependnet states. Practically there is but one issue now ready for the succession of the Ottomian; and that is absorption in Russia. But even assuiming that the people are to gain by this change, no one can doubt the alarm with which Hungary, Austria, and Gerinany herseli; would see the south-eastern (quarter of the Empire of the HIap)sburgs eng-ulplhed in at Russian enelave. Ono who follows out tihe commplexities of Austrian politics, with its three great races and their maIllny subdivisions ; the intricate way in which Austrian polities arte interlaced ewith the politics of Germiiany; who will count up the jealousies, suspicions, hopes, hatreds, and ambitions, the traditions amid the interests interlocked with each other in the tract between tie Baltic and tho D)anube, -such an one will doulbt if&amp;apos; sltsia can enter on tile inheritance of Turkey without p)replaring for Europe a long era of bloodshed. Such were some of tho dalnlgers wlmich R0 long kept practical mien from admitting the possibility of a new departure of Easterni policy. But the events of the present year have finally closed the established otno possumus of the ancient policy. To struggle for the status quo in its rigidity, the integrity and independence of the Porte, as the treaties of Paris so hopefully decreed, is a policy that has now at least three capital defects: it is shocking to our self-respect, it makes war inevitable, and it would be certain to fail. We are far away from the epoch of the Crimean war. The Ottoman rule is being assailed not from without but from within; its enormities have forfeited all claim to sympathy; the attack comes now not from the designs of the Russian government, but from the agitation of the Russian people. Lastly, without France the defence of the Ottoman Empire is palpably impossible. Words will not do it, and we have no armies. Something must be done, and on a great scale; and that beyond securing a high road to India; for the danger to Europe is greater now than it was at the date of the Crimean war; and we have to deal no longer with the designs of an ambitious Czar, but with the religious excitement of the Russian people. In 1854, what we met was dynastic conquest; in 1876 it threatens to be a popular crusade; and the latter, on the whole, is a deeper evil than the former. The entrance on the scene of the Russian people would alone forbid us to treat the Eastern question with the mystic words, l(dise sfihire and non-intervention. We are so much accustomed to denounce the Russian greed of empire, and the Machiavellian conspiracies of her rulers, that we do some political injustice to the Russian people and the government of the Czar. Our entire judgment on the question must be perverted, if we shut our eyes to the fact which so many proofs have established, that the Russian people is stirred to its depths by irrepressible sympathy with the Christians of Turkey. The people of Russia, as being semi-civilised and semiOriental, are moved by zeal for religion and race with a fervour that is hardly conceivable by Western industrialist nations. It would be wrong to forget that the Russians are as capable of fanaticism for the Cross as Moslems of fanaticism for Islam; and if the Russian fanaticism is somewhat less violent, it is a great deal more constant. We so instinctively decry religious and national enthusiasm as political forces, that we run the risk of underrating their influence in ruder societies. The agitation of the people in Russia may not yet amount to a crusade, but it is evidently real and perfectly intelligible. There are no doubt intriguing committees and crazy enthusiasts about race, as active and as mischievous in Russia as in any part of the world; but allowing to the full for the agitation which skilful managers can always stimulate or simulate, we can see real signs of popular sympathy with the Christians of Turkey-a sym- pathy which the agitators merely inflame, and which the government is unable to control. We have seen the fever of excitement which shook the northern provinces of Italy so long as the southern were under Austrian, Papal, or Bourbon tyranny; and there is no ground to think that the sympathy of the Russian people with their brethren in Servia and Bulgaria is a whit less real than the feeling of the men of Turin, Milan, and Genoa, for the victims of Haynau, Pius, and Bomba. If the victims are neither so near, nor belong to the same nation, on the other hand their sufferings appeal more keenly to the imagination and to religious zeal. It is a strange instance of the force of national jealousy that Englishmen who understood and applauded the career of Garibaldi, should sneer at the Russian enthusiasm for the Christians of Turkey. But inasmuch as the Russian people are far more religious, or rather more theological, than the Italian-are in a far lower state of civilisation, and thus more liable to the stupid fanaticism of race-as the Christians of Turkey are not only of kindred race but of the same creed: we have every ground for believing that their sympathy with their brethren across the Danube is of a more passionate kind than any we have seen in Italy. When D&amp;apos;Azeglio and Cavour, Ricasoli and Minghetti, insisted that the good government of Italy was impossible whilst Austrian and Papal and Bourbon oppression kept up a ceaseless agitation in the peninsula, their plea was allowed as unanswerable by the public opinion of Europe. There are indications enough that the government, indeed the very crown, of Russia is becoming a matter at stake, so long as the religious and national superstitions of the Russian people are kept in constant excitement by the spectacle of Mussulman oppression. It is idle to grumble at a feeling which is certain to endure, and even to increase. The feeling itself may be ill-informed, and grossly one-sided; but the national fanaticismns of eighty millions have to be counted with as they cannot be reasoned with. It is exceedingly likely that the Russian government, in its intrigues or in its weakness, from time to time does something to stimulate this feeling; it is quite certain that adventurers-military, literary, and diplomaticplay upon it as a thriving trade. Russian officers, like Prussian officers, or British officers (the craving is not confined to one army, nor to two), undoubtedly crave for fresh careers; the Russian professor and journalist, raving about the Panslavonic race and its destiny, is perhaps more violently and more sincerely crazy about his career than the Prussian professor and journalist maundering about the Teutonic destiny, perhaps even than the Old English professor, grinding his teeth over the paramount claims of Wessex to the homage of mankind. But when we have made all the needful deductions for the Chauvinism of Russian soldiers, the intrigues of Russian officials, and the bluster of literary agitators, the solid fact remains that the Russian people cannot be kept quiet in sight of Turkish misgovernment, and their sympathy with the Christian -victims is becoming an overpowering force. It is simply jealousy and prejudice which set down every movement of Russian opinion to the orders of the government. It needs no private intelligence to convince us how false is the popular ideal of the imperial autocrat. Instead of the absolute monarch of common imagination, fixed as fate, omniscient, irresistible, serene as an Olympian deity, mysteriously faithful to the will of Peter the Great, and contriving all things by inspired decrees, the real Czar is a puzzled, overworked, irresolute gentleman of benevolent intentions and confused views; anxious unto death about his vast trust, fearing everything, suspicious of his ministers, timid about himself, and uneasy about his throne; dragged hither and thither by intriguers whom he cannot shake off, and checked at every turn by currents of opinion which he cannot comprehend. If the truth were known, there are probably few first ministers in Europe more harassed, uncertain, and insecure than the Czar; having less of a definite policy, less free to fashion events, and more insecure of power. It seems certain that he of all men least desires to take up the traditions of Catherine, knows best how loose is the organization of the huge empire that he nominally governs, and has the best cause to dread its further extension and fresh engagements. Perhaps these wild raids across Asia, into which his soldiers drag him, and this Turkish crusade, in which his diplomatists entangle him, to him alone of all Russians come home in the silent hours of distrust with a weight of sickening dread. There is something quite pathetic in the picture we form of the kindly, indolent, nervous man, worried by gigantic responsibilities and never-ending business, dreading the enterprises which he dares not to refuse, and overmastered by men whom he is e afraid to trust. In this place of vast power of which he has lost the mastery, in this necessity for enterprises for which he has no heart, in this situation which forces an irresolute man to take great resolves, there is much about Alexander II. which is ominously like Napoleon III. His personal position is not quite so precarious, and his personal vanity is in no way so tempted; but the parallel is too close to be quite reassuring. Those who know Russia best are continually reminding us that she is not so strong as she looks. The vast changes which a generation has produced are yet far from quietly settled; the unwieldy empire shows signs of the inevitable sundering which one day awaits it. Men never will sufficiently admit that she is still half Asiatic; that the civilisation which is the life of Western nations cannot be forced to order upon the Muscovite, but becomes a weakness instead of a strength. The anarchical democracy, the national rodomontade, the scientific militarism, the exotic industrialism, the principal boasts of Russian progress, are far from signs of a great future, or infallible proofs of strength. No one can doubt that the enormous armies of Russia would suffice to crush Turkey if it could be done in a single campaign; but there is very great reason to doubt if the gigantic machine of war into which Russian life is drained, is safe from internal collapse or could meet an obstinate strain. We have often heard the story of some over-trained athlete, who with the muscular system of a Hercules broke down from want of vital power. It would be to surrender their place as civilised powers if the Western nations regard Russia as the irresistible Colossus, the inevitable mistress of Eastern Europe. On the contrary there is every reason to hope that the races of Eastern Europe may work out their own destiny quite outside of an overgrown empire. Now some would console themselves with the thought that the extension of Russia to the south will diminish her strength, increase her vulnerability, and advance the hour of her ultimate dissolution. In the long run all this may be true; and the more farsighted of Russian statesmen may dread the day when she shall achieve her ancient dream. But the prize is too splendid for prudence and foresight to reject; and the immediate effect of its possession would give such a semblance of overwhelming preponderance that the rest of Europe could never see it with composure. The extension of the Russian Empire will be as menacing as was the extension of French empire in the days of Napoleon. And though his monstrous ambition was the certain prelude to the ruin of France, it was none the less alarming to Europe. The possession of Constantinople, even although it made certain the downfall of Russia, would not be less dangerous for the season to the peace and freedom of the world. At the same time the question of the Bosphorus is one of those which nature and man, history and geography, have combined to render perplexed. On one side, as on the other, the case seems unanswerable. On the one hand, when we look at it from the Russian point of view, the case stands thus:-A great power, which aspires to foremost rank as a maritime nation, is so situated by nature that its land opens both into the northern seas as well as into the southern seas of Europe; yet its fleet in the northern is locked in for more than half the year by winter ice, and its fleet in the southern seas is permanently locked in by public law. On the Black Sea she commands a vast range of seaboard, with every appliance for naval purpose-fine harbours, unequalled cruising-grounds, and a favourable climate. Yet here she is cooped up by treaties and national jealousies. Her Baltic fleet and arsenals are paralysed by winter; her Euxine fleet is paralysed by international ban. Nature and the course of her history have given her in the Black Sea the grandest naval station which the world can produce. She is burning to develop and make use of its resources; and she is forbidden to use it by the suspicions of her neighbours. If in the depth of winter a great crisis were suddenly to arise requiring Russia to despatch a fleet for the instant protection of her world-wide interests, she has not in Europe a single available arsenal from which to despatch it; not a single ship but what is dependent on hospitality for a roadstead. Physically she might have a splendid fleet at Sebastopol, with nothing between it and its intended destination; but European treaties bar the way. As the Russians pointedly say, it is not so much Constantinople they want as the free use of the Dardanelles. And indeed we may wonder what would be the feelings of Englishmen if they found all exit from the British Channel and St. George&amp;apos;s Channel closed to them by fiat of their foreign rivals ? The ease on the other hand seems no less unanswerable. If Russian fleets issuing from the ports of the Euxine are to pass at will down the Bosphorus, Constantinople becomes a subject city. Constantinople is far more to Turkey than London is to England or St. Petersburg to Russia; and a navy which has free passage up and down the IBosphorus could destroy it in an hour. It is clear that England could not exist as a sovereign state if the French navies had absolute freedom of sailing up the Thames, and if Parliament sat on the issues of peace and war beneath the guns of foreign ironclads. Nor would Russia be a free agent if the English fleet had a right of way up the Neva to the walls of the Czar&amp;apos;s palace. So that if Russia is to have free access to the Mediterranean, ipso facto the existence of Turke-y is placed at her mercy. We all know how precarious is the independence of Denmark, and yet Copenhagen is not so much exposed as Constantinople, is not so vital to Denmark, and is not at thie mercy of her one ancient enemy. The result is a dilemma only too real and insoluble. Either a great state is to forego onq of her grandest physical advantages by sentence of her national rivals, or the very existence of her ancient enemy is left to her simple goodwill. Even this is but a small part of the difficulties that arise from the unique geographical conditions of Eastern Europe. If we assume the dream of Russian enthusiasts fulfilled, that Russia had simply succeeded to the possession of Turkey, we should find her endowed with a power which would seriously threaten the rest of Europe. If to the whole of the shores of the Euxine she united the Bosphorus, the Propontis, and the Hellespont, and the shores and islands of Greece and of the Archipelago, she would simply possess a basis of maritime war to which nothing else in the world can compare, and which would far surpass all the other naval stations and resources of all the other powers put together. She could easily make the Hellespont as impassable to attack from the south, as if it were crossed by a breakwater of granite. Behind this impervious gate the Propontis and the Eux2ine would form a station, compared with which all the stations in the world are of trifling value, being port, arsenal, roadstead, practising-ground, and naval station all in one; a vast natural harbour, with its sally-port absolutely secure, within which fleets could be built, equipped, trained, and exercised until the order was given to sweep down the straits. If to this array of natural advantages we add the opportunities of the countless islands and roadsteads of the Levant, we get a combination of physical resources for naval supremacy. to which everything else in the world becomes quite insignificant. The result is, that whether we turn to Russia, or to Turkey, we get a series of problems which have long defied a solution. On the side of Turkey, is the chronic insurrection which its misgovernment causes; the difficulty of substituting another government except by conquest; the impossibility of tolerating the Ottoman rule; the fact that the Ottoman race can only be dispossessed by war. On the side of Russia, is the agitation of the Russian people, which has now gone too far to be stemmed except by solid guarantees; the imminence of agitation to end in a crusade; the certainty that the Russian navy cannot be permanently forbidden to pass the Bosphorus; the prospect of Russia&amp;apos;s ascendancy if she holds it; the fear that new Russian conquests may be merely a fresh danger to their neighbours, and a fresh oppression to their subjects. It is difficult to see what real gain it would be to the nations that lie between the Pruth and Cape Matapan, to have the privilege of swelling the Russian conscription, of being harried to pay the Russian taxes. The rule of the Czar is not marked by capricious injustice and periodical slaughter like that of the Sultan; but its pressure on the daily life of the peasant is aliwost as heavy, more systematic, moro far-reaching, more jealous ill surveillance. Some of the races of Turkey might, at least for a time, be gainers in changing the Porte for the Czar-the peasants of Bulgaria, for instance, if they were torn from their homes would not be burnt in them, or not so often; but the people of Roumania, Servia, and Greece, might be even worse off than they are. The gain at any rate would be too doubtful to risk so vast an experiment. Besides, there is not the slightest evidence that these nations and races one and all desire a Russian Nirvana. And yet they might all go together, if they go at all, home to the bosom of holy Russia. And when they had gone, we should have to await in the Catholic and 3Mussulman races absorbed; in the non-orthodox Churches persecuted; in the Albanian mountaineers and the Greek democrats; a new catalogue of Polands and Circassias, more Warsaws, and more deportations to Siberia. All this is apart from the just alarm which would agitate Europe to find the Eastern Mediterranean in the hands of a power so vast and so restless as Russia. Even if Austria could lie by and see Russia in possession of Bulgaria and Servia, if Germany could consent to make the Danube a Muscovite river, if England could see unmoved, the fleets of the Czar riding in the Golden Horn, no one can doubt that in the long run the simple accession to Russia of the whole of Turkey in Europe must involve a general and protracted war. The possession of Eastern Europe and the Eastern sea en bloc by any one power, and that power Russia; of the whole tract and its seaboard from Sebastopol to Cape MNatapan, from the Danube to Crete; of the islands, straits, and inland seas this space comprehends :-this is a supremacy so vast that it is the duty of Europe as a whole, as it has ever been, to prevent it. It is not a matter of English interests alone, or of the road to India. It concerns the very existence of France, of Italy, of Austria, of England, as maritime powers; it must really disturb the dog-slumber of Prince Bismarck himself. It is not, and it never should be represented as, a special jealousy of the British flag. The cry of national selfishness-let the Russians seize Turkey, and we will seize Egypt-is the very thing to invite the catastrophe, which is one common to all Europe. It is at cause to be made a fixed point of European policy, in which England may fairly take a leading part; but which it would be neither just nor wise that she should treat as her sole concern. And if the Western Powers together cannot make this respected as a cardinal point of their common policy, cannot guarantee it by policy rather than by arms, it is idle to talk about statesmanship or public law at all. It is quite within the duty and the traditions of all the states of the West to say to Russia: We will not permit you in EIurope a vast career of conquest, the consequences of which may be Fo formidable to us all. But when this general danger is provided for, there need be no flying to urmns at every step that is won by Russia, or every step that is lost by Turkey. A rigid adherence in politics to the old moral rule-principii8 o/tia-is not always a policy of wisdom. On the contrary, the progress of events is so slow, is interrupted so often by uncalculated chances, that to be ever preventing dangers is sometimes the surest way to produce them. A good policy has often been ruined by pedantic adherence to its form, when its substance may be otherwise secured. It is in the nature of things that Russia should advance at least for a time; and it is in the nature of things that Turkey should finally disappear. In this time of resettlement it may well be considered if Russia can be longer debarred from the Dardanelles; if some scheme for this object be beyond the reach of human skill. It would be the height of folly to make a easus belli of any infringement of the integrity of Turkey. Whatever else may have conic of the events of the past year, at least they have set aside the tradition of the old school-that the integrity of the Ottoman Empire, is sltr, is any part of English policy. That the Eastern Mediterranean should not be a Russian lake must be the policy not only of England, but of all the Western states. That the rule of the Sultan should be stereotyped as it is, can be the policy of no rational being. And it is stereotyped so long as it is the uniform conviction of the East that England will not suffer encroachment on the empire of Othman. The scheme which some still cherish, which verbally at least was put in the Premier&amp;apos;s notable game of brag-that England must fight before the territory or the sovereignty of the Sultan shall lose a jot-is a scheme of profligate obstinacy. There arc at least three grounds upon which it is finally condemned. First: there is not the remotest chance left for settling the Eastern question without infringing the sovereign, if not the territorial, rights of the Sultan. In the next place: to maintain them by arms (if it could be done) would destroy any hope of improvement in his government; would be directly perpetuating a most infamous system. Thirdly: as a mere matter of force, it is beyond the utmost resources of England to defend the Ottoman crown intact. Things&amp;apos; have come to that point, that Russia must win some guarantees for the Christians of Turkey, or cease to be a great power. Things have come to that point that the northwestern provinces of Turkey can no longer be kept under their actual rule. And things have come to that state that the actual rule of the Sultan is little more than chronic civil war. There are thus three things at least which have to be dealt withthe need to satisfy (without war) the just agitation in Russia; the need to restore peace to the provinces of Turkey; the need to force the Porto to change its system, or to reduce the area of its scandalous misgovernment. It eanniot be beyond the powers of human wisdom to satisfy these three points; indeed, there are probably several ways in which they may be more or less accomplished. They are the avowed objects of Russia, and probably the real objects of all the Western nations. In any scheme which seemed to secure them, we have no longer to ask if it impaired the dominions and the independence of the Porte. It is inevitable that any scheme should do this: and it seems to be on all sides acknowledged. The integrity and independence of the Porte, in the old Palmerstonian sense, now has no other meaning but protracted anarchy or gigantic war-probably both together. It is no part of our present purpose to consider any programme whatever for securing these ends. On the contrary, we said at the outset it is idle for journalists and essayists to attempt it. They are matters for arrangement, and give and take, varying with the events of the day and the resolves of certain persons; and the means of weighing the conditions and problems are possessed only by the cabinets concerned. But the world outside can judge what are the things to be sought, and what are the dangers to be avoided. And the dangers to be avoided would seem to be these. In securing the protection of the Turkish subjects we will do nothing-(I) To hand over Turkey, directly or indirectly, to Russia; (2) To drive the Turks to a war of desperation for their existence; (3) To abandon the Turkish provinces to simple anarchy and a war of races. Short of this we will support anything that is really demanded by the agitation in Russia, by the oppression of the provinces and the misgovernment of the Porte. To those who call upon Europe to sweep away the empire of the Porte, the simple answer suffices, that Europe has nothing to put in its place. It might be easy to destroy the government of the Sdltan by a joint attack on Constantinople; but to leave the rival races in presence of each other, and all in presence of the Turks, still the strongest of all, and yet free to regain their ascendancy by arms: this would indeed be a general invitation to anarchy and bloodshed. To those who call upon us to end all difficulties by welcoming the absorption of Turkey in Russia, the answer is that the gain does not seem to balance the cost. The Russian system of governuent it itself not so free from corruption, barbarism, and oppressimn, that for the sake of spreading its blessings we need welcome a conquest which the races to be conquered do not seem to desire, which would be a compound of crusade and spoilation, and which would fill Europe with distrust and alarm. From all sides we hear, and not least from Russian liberals themselves, to what lengths of venality, chicanery, and malversation the Russian official world has risen. From Poland and Siberia, from the Caucasus and from Khiva, comes the tale of ruthless ferocity with which she has ever suppressed those who resist her. And from the days of Catherine to the days of Kauffmann, history is red with the roll of massacres which holy Russia had perpetrated on the followers of Mahomet. Once for all we protest against a welcome being given to a new crusade on any pretext of indignation at oppression and outrage. And a crusade it will be, if England abets Russians now in wreaking on the Mussulman their ancient sectarian hate. The Russians at this moment are seething with the fury of religious passion, a passion which their rulers are unable to check, which they adopt as their own most &amp;quot; sacred mission.&amp;quot; If Russia is now launched upon Islam, it can only be in a religious war; a religious war it has already been in Servia; and a religious war it must yet more violently become, with the one watchword of &amp;quot; Down with the bloody Turk in the name of the Cross.&amp;quot; We trust that Englishmen may not abet a policy at once so ludicrous and infamous, as a war for the extension of Christianity. No doubt the wildest fianatic from a platform or a pulpit is not at all prepared to advocate an extension of Christendom by the sword. But, when all the pretexts are stript off, that is the real effect of calling upon Russia to destroy the empire of the Turk. Mlen and women who would shrink from the proposal to kill men because they will not turn Christians, are calling upon Russia to drive the Turks out of Europe on the ground that they arc Mussulmans. When we analyse the arguments for destroying the Turkish rule they always rest on an ultimate basis of antipathy to Mahometan religion; and those who are foremost in putting down this particular case of race oppression are those who applaud the oppression of race elsewhere. That it is not any special tenderness of humanity, no great political end by which they are stirred, is evident from the fact that this cry of &amp;quot; Down with the bloody Moslem,&amp;quot; comes mainly from those who never trouble themselves about oppression and massacre by Christians; who for the most part care nothing for politics, or see all politics through theological lenses. And the very Christians who witnessed unmoved the iniquities of Christian slaveholders, of opium wars, and Polish massacres, who loudly exult over the slaughter of French infidels, and who thank God that the Trish Catholics are slowly melting away, are ready to charge all who decline to adopt their crusade with coldness of heart and symn)athy with oppression. On this our ground is clear. We abhor all sorts and kinds of bloodshed anid outrage, nor have we ceased to raise our voice against all the injustice and cruelty which white men practise on black; and Christians on pagans, Mussulmans, or Buddhists; against the mercantile aggressions of the unscrupulous trader; the wars of ascendancy in all parts of the world; and the savage vengeance of retrograde governments. We give their true names to all such crimes. Nor have we been slack to make known our horror at the crimes of Turkish oppression. We neither extenuate them nor seek to forget them. The imagination can conceive nothing more enormous; nor is anything more certain than their cause-the accumulation of misgovernment increasing through ages. But when we are called on to put all other thoughts aside, to destroy the infamous system by the sword, to avenge the crimes by overthrowing the race amongst whom they were done, to open a new religious war upon their faith-when men, some under the excitement of religion, some under the spell of historical partizanship, and some for the sake of a popular cry, ask us to declare four millions of men enemies of the human race simply as Turks and as Mlahometans, outlaws who are to be hunted out of Europe in the name of Christ and general humanity-well, we who have not lost our heads decline to act upon such impulse. We have no special sympathy with the religion of 31ahomet; we are not blind to the fact that it is the most concentrated of all theologies, and we condemn theology altogether. WYe are not slow to point to its vices, its absurdities, its inhumanity (they are those of theology made fierce and fanatical). Nor do we pretend that Islam is the equal of that Christianity on which we stand, and out of the materials of which all our hopes have been built up. We are not blind to the vices of Mussulman life; but we say that the followers of the Prophet, even the Turks in Europe, have still some noble qualities which we would were more common among Christians. We see the ingrained corruption of the Ottoman rule, and the reckless barbarity with which it is familiar; but we see corruption and barbarity less only in degree, on many sides about us, and we hesitate to believe they will be cured by the general melee of war, and least of all by a war of religion. FREDERIC HARRISON.</FullText></Record>