<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2462057</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130528</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>HOME AND FOREIGN AFFAIRS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>125</Issue><AlphaPubDate>May 1877</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18770501</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>754</StartPage><EndPage>763</EndPage><Pagination>754-763</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2462057/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>HOME AND FOREIGN AFFAIRS. THE movement of the Russian forces into the Principalities, accompanying the Imperial Manifesto and the Chancellor&amp;apos;s Circular, though for so long seen to be inevitable, has sent a curious thrill through the country, now that it has at last really taken place. For a moment it was a sense of relief from the suspense of so many months; but we already find that the suspense of a straining peace is replaced by a direr suspense in actual war. If it had happened in August or September last, the feeling in England would have been one of very general, if not universal satisfaction. Unfortunately intense passion is as little to be trusted in masses of men, as it is in the average individual. The mood of the autumn was thoroughly right in its direction, but it was not sufficiently supported, as it is well capable of being, by a deliberate survey of the whole range of facts, of which the barbarities in Bulgaria were only an illustration. It is of little avail now to waste time in useless recriminations, or else we might perhaps ask how it is that the Liberal leaders in the Commons have not made an opportunity since the session began, of placing the whole case against Turkey in all its strength and breadth before the country. It was surely their business to find an expression in reason and policy for the attitude which was at first due to humane emotion. However, the time has gone by, and the chance is lost. The return of a ministerial candidate at Salford has frightened out of the front bench of the Opposition whatever inclination might have remained there, to place on the fullest and widest record an intelligible justification for the final abandonment of the old policy of Turkish aid and defence. As it is, no one can look at the prospect without the gravest anxiety. For the moment we have no doubt that the acquiescence of the country in the policy of the ministry is due to an assumption, that that policy means peace and non-intervention on the part of England. For the moment, the ideas of the time of the Crimean War are discredited. One or two journalists and public men, whose bias and rancour are too evident for their judgment to carry any weight, venture boldly to talk about repeating at once the Crimean policy. But it is impossible not to see the danger. The Ministry is strong in the country by the very virtue of its containing two semi-antagonistic sections. The presence of Lord Salisbury and Lord Carnarvon gives a certain confidence to those who think only of better government in the Turkish provinces. The tenacity of Lord Beaconsfield and the language of Mr. Hardy give a certain confidence to those who are sincerely and honestly alarmed at the alleged designs of Russia, as well as to those who have simply worked themselves up into a blind malignant frenzy in favour of Turkey. But the strength of the ministry as a whole turns to the profit of the anti-itussian part of it, because the latter are likely to have in their favour the vague pugnacity which is always stirred in this country by the spectacle of combat. The government is not at all likely to plunge us into war openly and immediately. The popular feeling must be nearly unanimous to embolden any ministry in En gland to take such a course. But there are indirect ways of bringing us, before we have had time to know it, into antagonism to Russia. It is easy to see how readily the situation lends itself to the aims of those who are bent upon once more dragging us, by-and-by if not to-day, into a conflict on behalf of the same government for which we sacrificed men and money twenty years ago. Mr. Bright&amp;apos;s position that the destiny of Turkey is no affair of ours, has again-it is not too much to say-been rejected by the nation almost as decisively in 1877 as it was in 1834, though as yet less emphatically. Mr. Gladstone&amp;apos;s position is capable of easy misrepresentation, and it is commonly misrepresented. He has never avowed himself really anymore a partisan of Russia than of Turkey; his censure of the ministry has turned, and justly, on the persistency with which they played the Russian game, and made it impossible for Russia to do otherwise than figure and act as the champion of humanity in South-Eastern Europe. But such a position now no longer hits the centre of public interest. - The question for the immediate time is how the shifts and turns of the war will affect English sentiment. Mr. Hardy&amp;apos;s vociferously applauded appeals to British interests point to where the dangerous point of the situation lies. If we could only be sure that no action would take place, except in accordance with British interests measured by calm and instructed sense, we should willingly admit that they may be taken in practicaL politics as the criterion of what we ought to do in presence of a distracting struggle. The peril is lest it should be taken for granted that British interests necessarily demand the continued maintenance of inevitably bad government in Turkey; and that they require that we should take up arms against the Power, that has undertaken a duty to civilisation in which we might have been her colleague, and even her director. There is no folly nor wrong in the history of our forbign policy from the French wars of the Edwards and Henries downwards, for &amp;apos;which the cry of British interests was not raised, in one dialect or another. And it is the same in the history of other countries. British interests may mean domething in the highest degree substantial and momentous, or they may mean the mere phantom of distinct prejudice. But phantoms are unfortunately real in their power and influences over men&amp;apos;s minds, and nothing stirs the bugbears of international jealousy so effectually as the clash of arms. Here, however, we have to deal with what has happened, rather than with what is to come, and we have to turn to the vain efforts of the past month to avert the catastrophe which has broken out within ten days of these efforts being consummated. Scarcely had the journals begun to ascribe a &amp;quot; considerable diplomatic success&amp;quot; to Lord Derby, when it was found that the Protocol was an ultimatum, and not a door of retreat. Disappointment has naturally given rise to irritation, and the pro-Turkish newspapers have been quick to denounce the Protocol as an elaborate piece of Russian insincerity. Even Lord Derby, who is nothing if not passionless, has discovered by the qncru!ous tone of his speech in the Lords the extent and bitterness of his vexation. Lord Derby does well to be angry, but he ought to be angry with himself, not with Russia. Although the whole story of the negotiations has not yet been published, it is clear from the evidence already produced, that Russia played an open hand, and acted in perfect consistency with the views she has all along maintained. The Protocol reduces the irreducible minimum of the Conference, and marks the extreme limit of forbearance. It is only by forgetting the course of events and ignoring the diplomatic steps that led to the Protocol that it becomes possible to put upon it a construction unfavourable to Russian fairness. The history of the negotiations has been one of deepening shadows, and of ever-widening possibilities of evil. Two years have scarcely elapsed since the first shot was fired in the Herzegovina. When the insurrection spread to Bosnia, and the Christians by thousands passed over into Austria and Servia, it was evident that a crisis had come that would try to the utmost the capacity of our statesmen. From the first unhappily, our Government was slow to appreciate the gravity of the situation. The consuls of the Powers were sent to the insurgent chiefs to tell them that Europe could give them no help, and thereby &amp;quot;d to make them understand the hopelessness of engaging in a contest with the imperial troops.&amp;quot; Tho irony of events is now stamped on the caution given to the consuls to &amp;quot; take the greatest pains to avoid everything that might have the appearatnce of united action.&amp;quot; The advice of the consuls was not taken, and SUeLle of them narrowly escaped being murdered through the treachery of the Turks. Then came the Andrassy Note, which established the European concert. But this also failed to induce the insurgents to give up their ar Ls; they refused to &amp;quot; trust to the mere promise of the Porte, which ho has never been knowvn to keep.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Unless Europe would guarantee their safety from the Agas and the authorities, and that the reforms promised would really be carried out, they dared not and would not lay down their arlls.&amp;quot; These fears the Porte hastened to justify. A few Christians returned, and were murdered by the Turks. Sir H. Elliot called upon the Porte to bring the murderers to justice, but, of course, nothing was done. &amp;apos;l ho failure of the Andrassy Note led to the Berlin Memorandum. It proposed &amp;quot;d ellicacious measures &amp;quot; to protect the Christians, but it destroyed tho European concert. It was too strong for Lord Derby. lIo was quite ready to adniinister sermons or homilies to the Porte, but he would take no stpl&amp;apos; that might lead to a practical application of his precepts. It required the Servian war and the inilminence of a war betweeen Turkey and Russia to revive the activity of the foreign secretatry. &amp;apos;The Conferenco assemblod, and ; slup forward was taken. Th European concert and the principle of external guarantees were combined. The Sultan repudiated both. The secret of his courage is not far to seek. lIe did not believe in the European concert, he believed the Powers wero more afraid of each other than desirous of punishing him; in a word, he thought that the same jealousies and divisions amtong tho Christian Powers which first allowed the crescent to be planted in Europe, still existed and promised him a long lease of power. Mr. Layard is at this moment reported to be repeating the old counsels and remonstrances with new scverity, but behind the words the Sultan still discerns what he has always discerned. The failure of the Conference did not settle the Eastern Question. The refugees from Bosnia and lIerzcgoviina did not return, peace was not made with Montenegro, the memory of Turkish crime in Bulgaria was still fresh. It was, therefore, expected on all hands that Russia would take the initiative in calling the attention of the European Cabinets to the situation. On the 5th of February the Russian Circular reached England. The foreign secretary characteristically decided not to answer the Circular &amp;quot;&amp;apos; until events should have developed themselves.&amp;quot; But on the 13th of March hL received from the Russian Ambassador, in the form of a Protocol, the answer that Russia wished to obtain, and so moderate wvere its terms, that the English Cabinet at once accepted it in principle. It was hoped by means of the Protocol; to keep alive the European concert, and to prevent the Eastern Question from degenerating into a duel between Russia and Turkey. Nor did Russia for a moment conceal the advantages she proposed to gain by the Protocol. On the same day on which the suggestion of. a Protocol was first communicated, Lord Derby wvas put in possession of the object of Russia. &amp;quot;1 After the sacrifices which Russia had imposed upoln herself, the stagnation of her industry and of her commerce, and the enormous expendituro incurred by the mobilization of five hundred thousand inen, she could not retire nor send back her troops without having obtained sonic tangibkh results in regard to the improvement of the condition of the Christian population of Turkey. The Emperor wvas sincerely desirous of peace, but not of peace at any price.&amp;quot; Wo cannot but think that Lord Derby in the debate in the Lords forgot this statement, and was thus led to misrepresent the attitude of the Russian Government, when he said that they &amp;quot; came and told us that they wanted an exctse for disarmament.&amp;quot; It is luite clear from Lord Derby&amp;apos;s memory of his conversation with the Russiani Ambassador, written at the time, that he confounded the attitude of Russia with his own. Russia from the first insisted upon some &amp;quot;ntangible results in the better government of the Christians,&amp;quot; as the condition of her demobilization; there is nothing to show that she wvent to the Courts of Europe for a form of sound words, as a pretext to betray the cause which, at so heavy a cost to herself, she had espoused. The Protocol in its final shape certainly exhibits the demands of Russia reduced to the extreme point of tenuity. It recites that the Signatory Powers &amp;quot; have undertaken in common the pacification of the East,&amp;quot; and affirms afresh &amp;quot;n the common interest wvhich they take in the improvement of the condition of the Christian population of Turkey.&amp;quot; It informs Turkey that &amp;quot; as regards Montenegro, tho Powers consider the rectification of the frontiers and the free navigation of the Borana to be desirable.&amp;quot; It invites the Porte to replace its armies on a peace footing, and to put in hand, with the least possible delay, the reforms necessary for the tranquillity and well-being of the Provinces. The only practical step proposed to be taken Was to watch carefully by the ambassadors at Constantinople and the local agents the manner in which the Porte carried out its promises. Finally, if the old disturbances should recur, the Protocol declares that such a state of affairs would be incompatible with the interests of Europe. This is in effect to say that Turkey is a common danger in Europe, but that she is to have one more chance, subject to consular supervision. It asserts a present right of inspection, and it holds over the Porte a vague threat of future interference. This vagueness, as might be expected, constituted the charm of the Protocol in Lord Derby&amp;apos;s eyes. The Protocol, he assures us, was a mere nothing; all it means is &amp;quot;that if certain things were not done by the Turkish government-we being the judges of whether they were done or not, then at some time which was not fixed, we being the judges as to when that time had arrived-we should consider with certain other powers and say what we should then do.&amp;apos; But though Lord Derby exults in thinking that the Protocol binds us to nothing, and elaborately exhausts the possibilities of emptiness, still lest perchance there should be something in it, he takes care to provide against the shadow of such a danger by annexing to the Protocol a condition that has made it void. It is to be binding only if Turkey and Russia agree to demobilize. Lord Derby states &amp;quot; that effective improvement in the condition of the Christian population is unanimously called for as indispensable to the tranquillity of Europe; &amp;quot; but he adds that he must not be held committed to that proposition unless Turkey is pleased to demobilize. There is a masterly inconsequence in the English declaration appended to the Protocol. In truth, however, the Protocol is hardly so inane as Lord Derby appears to consider it. It was signed with full knowledge of the Russian Declaration. It gives another day of grace to Turkey, but Russia declares that this must be dependent on two conditions. Turkey must make peace with Montenegro, and send a special envoy to St. Petersburg to treat of disarmament. This step is to be taken as an assurance that the Porte accepts the advice of Europe, and is ready seriously to undertake the reforms mentioned in the Protocol. Nothing but a fanatical antipathy to Russia could represent these conditions as hard. The Powers of Europe unite to urge the Porte to concede new territory to Montenegro. Even Consul Holmes-the man whom the Porte delights to honour-long ago advised the Porte to concede the seaport of Spitz and certain districts on the frontier, on the express ground that &amp;quot;the cession of these districts would certainly be no real loss to Turkey.&amp;quot; The other condition-the sending a special envoy-is as light as the circumstances of the case allow. The naked promise of the Porte is admitted to be worthless as a guarantee of reform. Without some guarantee the refugees will not return, and the pacification of Bosnia and the Herzegovina thus becomes impossible. Russia, however, does not insist upon the external guarantees recommended by the Conference; but she will be content with an act unequivocally attesting the sincerity of the Porte in its acceptance of the Protocol. The presence of a Turkish envoy at St. Petersburg would scarcely have been such &amp;quot; a tangible result in the improvement of the Christian population &amp;quot; as the Russian government desiderated, to justify it in scattering the vast army which after so many sacrifices it had assembled on the frontiers of the Empire; but it would have been an earnest of better days for the provinces desolated by the Turks. Of course it would have been a humiliation for Turkey. It would have been a plea of guilty to the indictment brought by the European Conference against Turkey. It would have been a sign of repentance and a pledge of reform. It would, moreover, have shown that the Porte comprehends the conditions upon which alone the Ottoman power can be prolonged in Europe; and it would have enabled the Czar to disband his armies without betraying his people, and to give peace without surrendering the Christian subjects of the Porte to ruin and despair. Too much attention has been given to the movements of Russia, and too little to the manner in which the Porte received not merely the conditions specified by Russia, but the vacuous Protocol, which, Lord Derby says, contained nothing &amp;quot;to which the Porte could reasonably object.&amp;quot; Lord Derby repeated the old error, which has vitiated the entire course of the negotiations. He was thinking only how to thwart Russia, and he was checkmated by Turkey. Turkey has thrown back the Protocol in the teeth of the Powers. The document which Lord Derby flattered himself he had reduced to utter emptiness, is repelled by the Porte as an insolent aggression. Surely this ought to be a lesson to all who are not incapable of learning by experience. Europe has met in solemn conclave, and has heard the cry of the wronged peasants of Bosnia and Herzegovina; even England, the old friend of Turkey, has been moved to demand the punishment of the ruffians who desolated Bulgaria; the world is sick of the cruelties and misgovernment of the Turkish power. But of all this Turkey admits nothing. She absolutely refuses to confess that anything has been wrong in Bosnia, Herzegovina, or even in Bulgaria; she has the coolness to say that &amp;quot;Europe is convinced that the disturbances which have troubled the peace of the Provinces were due to foreign instigation,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot; that the Imperial Government would not be held responsible for them.&amp;quot; She ingenuously affirms that &amp;quot; the Imperial Government, in fact, is not aware how it can have deserved so ill of justice and civilisation; &amp;quot; and, therefore, &amp;quot; Turkey, in its quality as an independent state, could not acknowledge herself as being placed under any supervision, collective or otherwise.&amp;quot; So far from sitting on the stool of repentance, the Porte mounts the pulpit and rates the Powers in a style which we hope they appreciate. &amp;quot;W What indeed cannot be sufficiently regretted, is the small regard in which the Powers seem to hold both the great principles of equality and justice-the sway of which the Imperial Government has endeavoured to assure in its internal administration-and its right of independence and sovereignty.&amp;quot; This is a specimen of &amp;quot; the indomitable pluck&amp;quot; which has won the heart of the first Lord of the Admiralty, and of that courage which &amp;quot;&amp;apos; is one of the highest qualities a man could possibly show.&amp;quot; The reply of the Porte comes at an opportune moment. People were beginning to think that the terrible experience of the last two years could not have gone for nothing, and that the golden promise of a new constitution might ripen into the fruit of decently good government. But the reply of the Porte shows that the Turks are now, as of old, inaccessible to evidence and the teachings of experience. If the declaration of Russia attached to the Protocol required a justification, Turkey has been swift to supply it. To complete the discomfiture of the Powers, the Turkish government makes free use of some very respectable phrases of international law. This is scarcely surprising when we remember the strange doctrines that are advocated by the sympathisers of the Porte in this country. Thus we are told by one authority that for any State to attempt to succour the Christian subjects of the Porte in Europe from the hordes of marauding Asiatics brought across to crush them, is &amp;quot;&amp;apos;a contempt for international law and morality.&amp;quot; Another lays down the axiom that &amp;quot;s a State has no right to go to war unless its own interests are positively and directly injured.&amp;quot; In this view the war of France against Austria for the liberation of Italy was most wicked, unless perhaps it may have been redeemed by the appropriation of Savoy and Nice. It is an odd travesty of the maxims of international morality to hold a war to be wicked if undertaken from a generous and disinterested motive, but to be sanctified by a purely selfish purpose. And surely of all cases in which to apply such a notion the strangest is that where the power attacked is, by the common consent of Europe, excluded from the rank of truly independent sovereign States. It is too systematically forgotten that Turkey does not possess independent sovereignty in the same sense as England, or France, or Russia, or any other civilised State in Europe or America. Turkey belongs to the same class as China, Japan, and the other semi-civilised States in which the right of internationality is rigorously maintained for Europeans. The essence of independent sovereignty is complete power over all the persons found within the territories of the sovereign. A Frenchman in England is subject to English law and to English tribunals. In like manner an Englishman leaving his own country to travel in Europe, comes under the law of each country through which he passes, until he comes to the Ottoman dominions. Bat the moment he enters Turkish territory he relapses under the law of his own country, and not under Turkish law. Tho feeblest State in Europe does not permit the meanest of her subjects to be exposed to the scourge which in Turkey takes the place of law and justice. Every Englishman, Frenchman, American, or Italian in Turkey carries with him the law of his own country, is sulbject to the jurisdiction only of his own consul, and owes not even a temporary allegiance to the Sultan. lBut for this how could a civilised Europtan venture with his family into Turkish territory, or have the courage to entrust even himself to the impartiality of Turkish judges and the hired pueiury of Mahometan witnesses ? Why is it that the journals who resent any interference with the Sultan&amp;apos;s prerogatives of abusing his (&amp;apos;Christian subjects, as a violation of his sovereign independence, do not prove their Sincerity by asking their own government to abandon the capitulations and treaties which put Turkey on a level with the Chinese ? It is evident that Turkey is not, and cannot be, an independent sovereign State in the same sensO as the other European Powers, and to pretend that it is what it can never be, is to foster a misebiovous delusion. The Turks have shown themselves apt pupils in taking the benefit of doctrines, which apply only to civilised States capabie of performing the duties that justify the exertion of sovereign rights. The Protocol, however, belongs to the past, and our interest in it has already given way to anxiety as to the future. What will Russia do? How will she use the victory, which, it seems certain, is within her grasp ? The uncertainty that must exist on this point shows us what we have lost by the destruction of the European concert. England agreed to a concert of words, but not of action. Every step that Russia takes will be watched by severe and jealous critics. But there is no occasion for alarm. Russia starts well. She moves forward in obedience to a profound national sympathy with the oppressed Slavs of Turkey. It is incredible that the Czar should have made up his mind to seize Constantinople. That would be to weaken his empire, and place Russia at the mercy of Germany, which as Fad~eff showed long ago could at any moment cut her in two. Meanwhile it is well to recall that Russia has been in Roumnelia before. In 1829 she dictated a treaty from Adrianople ; and her interference there is remembered by the emancipation of Greece. It is instructive to compare the language of the fanatical anti-Russians of the present day, with the comments of the Duke of Wellington on the events of 1829. &amp;quot;There is no doubt,&amp;quot; he says, &amp;quot;it would have been more fortunate and better for the world if the treaty of peace [at Adrianople] had not been signed, and if the Russians had entered Constantinople, and if the Turkish Empire had been dissolved.&amp;quot; This was written at the time the events occurred; and yet the Duke of Wellington was far from thinking that the right heir to Constantinople was Russia. &amp;quot;1 My opinion is,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot;that the power which has Constantinople, and the Bosphorus, and the Dardanelles, ought to possess the mouth of the Danube; and that the sovereign of these two ought not to have the Crimea aud the Russian Empire. We must reconstruct a Greek Empire . . . . .nd IiO Power in Europe ought to take anything for herself, excepting the Emperor of Russia a sum for his expenses.&amp;quot; If Greece were capable of rising to the height of the occasion, and putting more faith in the sword than in diplomatic promises, all might be well. The wave of Russian invasion may retire, leaving behind it a Byzantine kingdom on the Bosphorus and a South Slavonian Confederation on the D)anube. Amid the intense excitement of diplomatic negotiations on which 6uch tremendous issues seemed to hang, and which changed their aspect fhola day to day with the vividness of a kaleidoscope, the nation half forgot t( take an interest in the annual statement of its ot)W money all; irs. Peoplc felt a moderate curiosity as to wvhether the Chancellor of the Exchequer wvould increase the spirit duties, or raise the income-tax from threoponee in the pound to fourponce. And when, after all, it appearod that the Chaiicellor was going to leave both spirit d*uties and income-tax wvhere they were, the sigh of public gratitude and relief W-aS hardly more than languid. There had becen a rather general expectation of at deficit; it was therefore an agreeable surprise to find that we hadl really received nearly half tL million (440,0001.) more than we speiit in the financial year, 187(-7. Assuming, then, that the outlay for the current year is not to be in excess of last year, and that the income of 1877 does not fall more than a certain small and measurable sum below the income of 1876, then we shall again find ourselves with a modest excess of receipts over expenditure. The Chancellor estimates that we shall receive in 1877-8 the sum of 79,020,0(001., and that we shall spend 78,794,0001., and if this anticipation be realised, he will next spring have 226,0001. to the good. It is the business of an Opposition to oppose, and the line of criticism adopted by Mr. Goschen and others is that the estimates of revenue are too sanguine. They point out that trade is severely depressed in almost every branch, and that the rate of falling off in the last two quarters of the financial year has been greater than is assumed for next year, and that we ought to look forward to a progressively increasing decline. This is a perfectly fair warning so far as it goes, but, on the other hand, the Chancellor of the Exchequer seems justified in his reply:-&amp;quot; We have now found that, notwithstanding the same kind of apprehensive croaking last year, yet the estimates of the Revenue department have come true. It is quite reasonable, therefore, that we should again take the word of gentlemen of whose caution, accuracy, and foresight we have just had such good experience.&amp;quot; We have heard less this year than usual in the way of remonstrance against the amount of the annual expenditure. We have not heard repeated the memorable sentence of an illustrious statesman, that it is a scandal and a disgrace to any government not to be able to carry on the administration of the country for less than seventy millions a year. Yet we are now not only at nothing less than seventy millions, but at a figuro which just falls short of eighty millions. The truth is that there is not, and cannot be, a fixed and eternal limit beyond which the national outlay ought never under any circumstances to go. For one thing, we cannot remember too steadily that of our seventy-eight millions and three quarters, nearly thirty-two and a half millions are not expenditure at all in the ordinary sense. That is to say, twventy-eight millions ure interest on debt with which our forefathers Ciicunibered the national estates, and four millions and a half are the outlay necesmary for carrying on the business of postal and telegraphic service,-a business on which the gross return is something like seven millions and a lmalf. What the administration of tho country therefore really costs is no more than forty-six millions, and perhaps of this a million ought to be set dowia to Indian account. But apart from such consideratious as these, we conteud that the national outlay must necessarily be expected to go up, as our population increases, as our standards of popular well-beiug are gradually raised, and as the field of state co-operation in social improvement is gradually widened. Take education, for example. In days when Retrenchmneut was an element in the triple motto of the Liberal Party, the suI annually devoted to this great object did not exceed a tew thousand pounds. Yet nobody, except a stubborn little roinuant of veterans of the days of cries that are now worn out and issues that are now exhausted, believes that the educational charges on the Consolidated Fund represent anything but a most wise and beneficent investment of public money. In the eld days Retrenchment was a most just demand, because it meant cutting down a quantity of offices that were suiprflluous and jobbcd. W\e do not izt. that all has been done that can be done in this direction, or that every pound of Sir Stafford &amp;apos;Northcote&amp;apos;s seventy-cight millions and three quarths is put to thc best imaginable use. It is not likely that in anl account (it this magnitude there is no element of waste. But then this is for thte specialists in each branch of the public service to find out, and to insist upon lhaving set right. What %ve contend is, that the total outlay is not likely t, diminish and ought not to diminish. What the nation wants-and this is more true than ever since the governing, portionl of the laation was increased by the legislation of 1867-is not that the expenditure shall be grudging and churlish, but that it shall be devoted to good uses, anld that we get money&amp;apos;s worth for our money. Of this the defeat of the ceonoising party at the last election of the London School Board was a remarkable illustration. We believe that there is a generally spreading conviction that-as Mr. Chamberlain said in his vigorous and well-considered speech on Local Loans (April 23)-public indebtedness is a matter of conjgratulation, because it is not a debt in the ordinary sense of the word, but an investment of the whole community, returning large dividends in the shape of the health, happiness, comfort, and intelligence of the whole population.</FullText></Record>