<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2463154</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127125646</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>HOME AND FOREIGN AFFAIRS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>156</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Dec 1879</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18791201</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>913</StartPage><EndPage>922</EndPage><Pagination>913-922</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2463154/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>HOME AND FOREIGN APPAIR8. THz transactions of the present mouth between England an(? Turkey stamp the break-down of that course of policy which was entered upon after the Conference of Constantinople. The circle is completed, and the same minister who premed for reforms in 1876, has found himself still pressing for reforms in 1879. But what has happened in the interval P It is no longer the same Turkey, powerfol with the strength of the status quo, of unbroken dominion, and of unknown resource, but the wreck of a state, stripped of territory, its resources pledged to Russia, its military force practically destroyed, its doom finally sealed. If the Porte, at the close of 1876, could only have foreseen the events of the end of 1879, if it could only have seriously realised that England either could not or would not stir to rescue her, a thousand calamities would have been pared to Europe and the world. It is because she was then encouraged not to believe that she would thus be left to her fate, that a whole chaiw of calamities has followed, leaving the whole of Europe a scene of distraction, jealousy, and suspense almost intolerable. To have put pressure on Turkey three years ago would have extinguished a little fire which has since grown into conflagration. Among other effects it would have prevented the outbreak of the spirit of international hatred between England and Russia, which still promiaes us a host of evils, and prevents any approach to a stable settlement of the questions which torment the world. Nobody can dwell with satisfaction on the repulse with which our latest dipomatising in this thorny field has been met. It seems to be certain that the Sultan has promised so much of reform as consists in appointing Baker Pasha to command a force of police; that the appointment has been formally made; but that there is no force to, command; and that the Pasha might as well have remained where he was The English demands have had the effect that might have been expected, of sending the Porte into the arms of the Czar. So far as the story is yet known, it is difficult to imagine a result of greater discomfiture and confusion. Let us look at the matter rather more widely. So far as Turkey is concerned, it is doubtful whether English interference can result in any substatial goodto her populations. Thereis nocaserecordedinhistory where decaying government, so far gone as Turkey now is, has been reformed and strengthened by pressure imposed from without, even whGeu that pressure has been imposed by a foreign Power with friendly inttions such interference weakens thecentralauthority, iden- tifies patriotism with resistance to reform, and breeds intrigue with other Powers, whose motives are believed to be interested and sinister. We may tease the Porte with angry remonstrance, and the fleet may make a hundred of its absurd voyages from Malta to Vourla. There will be no reform, and the only effect will be to hurry the break-up of the Ottoman Power. At present nothing is more undesirable than any such baste in this direction. The break-up of Turkish authority in Europe was desirable just because it came in a spontaneous and inevitable course. The movement came from the populations, and where the British Government made their great and fatal mistake-Lord Derby being here not any more clear-sighted than his colleagues&amp;amp;-was in not admitting this to their minds. They will make a mistake at least as great and as fatal if they precipitate the ruin of the central Government in Asiatic Turkey. The mere presence of Russia, with her grasp firmly held upon points of such commanding importance as Ardahan and Kars, must in itself, as Lord Salisbury told the English ambassador at Constantinople eighteen months ago, &amp;quot; exercise powerful influence in disintegrating the Asiatic dominions of the Porte.&amp;quot; If England is to concern herself at all in the future of Turkey-a question which in their prwent humour Englishmen seem to consider beyond discussion, but which posterity will probably think that we ought to have discussed very carefully-then it is at least certain that we should do nothing to weaken such force as may still be left in the Turkish system. Nothing can be more mischievous than any action that tends to break up the present framework, bad as it is It is under shelter of this framework, if at all, that the strong men and rising forces in these provinces will find their only chance of slowly preparing a system that may one day supersede the present crumbling and dangerous fabric. The state of things is frightful no doubt. Every correspondent and every traveller tells the same tale of disorder, violence, and terror. But this confusion is no new thing. There are, on the contrary, some parts of Turkey in Asia where material prosperity has increased That there are elements of social strength and powers of political reconstruction among these populations, all the evidence goes to -show. The men who went up to the parliament at Constantinople from Beyrout, from Broussa, from &amp;amp;myrna, were the kind of men who might well work good local institutions of their own, and there is no reason why they should not find out for themselves the best way of using such institutions. We cannot do it for them. All that we can do is negative-to abstain, directly or indirectly, from breaking up the system under which they find a kind of provisional shelter. As it is, things look as if we were repeating in Turkey the game which has been so dioustrously played in Afgha s. Things look as if, out of jealousy of Russia, we were doing our best to replace a government more or lee organized, by sheer chaos. To persist in this is to lead the way to one of two reslts. After the Turkish government has been sufficiently weakened, either the Russians will march into the inheritance and destroy the germs of self-government in Turkey, or else England will carry on a furious struggle to prevent it. It is difficult to believe which of the two results is the more detestable. A pithy account of the outlook has lately been given by a traveller who is no enemy to Turkey, and no adherent of a tranquil and abstaining policy on the part of Great Britain. &amp;quot;The history of the past,&amp;quot; he says, &amp;quot; is sufficient to prove the utter fallacy of assertions, promises, and treaties; Turkey will perish in mal-administration; Russia, who is now marching upon Merv in spite of former assurances, as she advanced on Khiva under similar pretexts, will at the moment of her own selection assuredly break through her boundaries in Asia Minor. The position of England will be contemptible. We have thrown down the gauntlet to Russia by an ostentatious alliance with Turkey, but we hesitate to insist upon the overwhelming necessity of British official and military officers to organize the civil administration and an army of defence; thus, when the sudden emergency shall arise, Turkey will be utterly unprepared; the various races that comprise her Asiatic dominions will already have been poisoned by intrigue, and the only defence that can be offered to a Russian advance will be afforded by Turkish neglect, which has left the country devoid of roads.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; The situation is so serious that it is no wonder if extraordinary designs are imputed to the English government for rescuing themselves from it. Mr. Forster at Leeds even supposed that they intended to make the refusal of the Porte to fulfil their part of the Anglo-Turkish Convention, a plea for the abandonment by PEngland of her part-the Turks being thus formally left to their fate. This is scarcely probable. It is not in the vein of our government of adventure. What is more likely is resort to somne plan of comprehensive violence in a destructive sense. There are ominous words is the air about deposition and partition. One thing is perfectly clear, though it may be very unwelcome, and though Lord SAlisbury&amp;apos;s wantonly irritating ispemh at Manchester leads one to fear that he is shutting his eyes to it; and it is this. No scheme for the re-settlement of Asiatic Turkey, however far it may go, will be of any avail which rests on the permanent excluson of Russia. The public and press of England may rage as they (1) Sir mdl Baker&amp;apos;s Cyps e as I Saw it is 1879 (MacmiI&amp;quot;a5 &amp;amp; Co., 1879), p. 451. A book will worth reading, on the whole subject. please. The rebuff from the Austro-German alliance is as much as Russia is likely to endure, and the very effect of that movement which drives her for a time away from Turkey in Europe, will make it less possible for her to acquiesce in her own effacement in Turkey in Asia. 1er right to a voice in the settlement is as good as ours, and we shall only be battling against the nature of things if we attempt silently to exclude her with a high hand. There are rumours that the Bfitish government intend to occupy Herat in a conjunction of some kind or other with Persia; and this is duly rejoiced over by those who think that any step which will eause annoyance at Saint Petersburg, must be advantageous to England. We cannot accept that proposition as the basis of a serious policy. The assumption that if you can only throw Russia back at every point, at Merv, at Tirnova, at Constantinople, and inflict diplomatic defeats on her from Berlin and Vienna to Teheran, then peace will follow-this is an assumption not to be safely taken for granted. Nothing in the history or position of Russia warrants the belief that she is likely to acquiesce in these limitations and repulses She acquiesces for the moment, or so long as may be necessary, but she always returns with the steadiness of a natural force, and she does so because the forces which push her forward among the crumbling systems of Turkey and of Central Asia are in fact natural forces. It is constantly made a matter of bitter reproach to EngliAh liberals that Russia desires their return to power. English liberals need feel to remorse at such a circumstance, if it be true. A Russian statesman may well see two things: first, that the readjustment of the Eastern world will have to be settled between Russia and England either pacifically or by war; second, that it can only be settled pacifically with a new government in England. It need not, for that matter, be a particularly liberal government, but there can be no ranable discussion of the elements of the problem, -on the part of Russia, with a minister who has shown Lord Beaconsfield&amp;apos;s spirit or has used Lord Salisbury&amp;apos;s language. If war, a war sooner or later, is to be avoided, the men must be changed. No Russian statesman believes in his heart that Lord Hartington or Lord Granville, or Mr. Gladstone either, for that matter, would surrender a single point in any debate where English security is concerned. But Russia may expect, that if the liberals were in power, the decencies of international speech would be better respected; that a situation bristling with inherent difficulties would not be exacerbated by insults; that ministers would not reply to pacific letters from the Czar by windy menace; that she would have to deal with serious men, gravely and firmly carrying out a steadfast and serious policy, which would be none the les a policy of British interests, becamuse it recogniaed that thoe interests are not served by udertaking the responsibility of the whole of Asia on our shoulders. That the least good has been done by the recent movements nobody of any party believes. The rash and unwise minister who presides at the Foreign Office-le roweau peint en fer-must himself be aware that reforms in the sense aimed at in the Anglo-Turkish Convention cannot be secured by the strongest representations that the English Ambassador is capable of making. Promises have been made, but they have been made by men burning with resentment that such promises should be exacted, intent on making as light of them as possible, and knowing in their hearts that they cannot in the nature of things be carried out. How far a conspicuous farce of this kind adds to the dignity of Great Britain before Europe, we fail to see. And, on the other hand, what nobody can fail to see is that our solitary intervention in a matter which is obviously no more our concern than it is the concern of the other western Powers, has kindled ill-feeling towards us in France, and aggravated the soreness already cused by Lord Salisbury&amp;apos;s inconceivably foolish exultation at the alliance of the two great military monarchies of Central EuropeIt was expected by some people that Lord Beaconsfield&amp;apos;s speech at the Guildhall would contain an intimation that there was a point beyond which Her Majesty&amp;apos;s Government could not permit Irish agitation to pro . The ministerial message, instead of being one of menace to Irish disaffection, proclaimed the existence of ministerial sympathy with Irish distress, and Lord Bacofield dimly foreshadowed the possibility of the concession of liberal relief out of imperial funds. At that very moment, however, the contingency of coercion must have presented itself to the Premier&amp;apos;s mind. The arrest of Messrs. Davitt, Daly, and Killen was no sadden or hurried step. Wise or unwise, it was the act of a Government which had deliberated on the expediency and had calulated some of the consequences of such a measure. Other considerations than the security of life and property in Ireland weighed with the Cabinet. Thus far Lord Beaconsfield and his colleagues had justified the policy of Mr. Parnell and his friends by yielding in every instance the substance of their demands. It was natural, therefore, that the tactics of agitation should be continued, the more so that there are elements of equity and internal strength in the present movement which have been too generally ignored. But the time had arrived when the Government saw reason to doubt the political expediency of indefinite surrender. Jingoism may find a convenient and useful subject for its treatment in Ireland as well as in Russia. The Cabinet had been taunted with its deficiency of vigour towards Mr. Parnell and his followers, The constit was mid, were on the look out for something more stirring than Irish University Bilk It was even suggested that the best thing which the Premier could do would be to dissolve Parliament on the strengthof an anti-Irish cry. Something must be done; and the consequence of this decision was the seizure of the three men now in prison. There was no particular reason why these in preference to any others should have been selected as illustrations of the sure, if tardy, processes of retrbtive justice. The language used by them was not specially defiant of the sanctity of custom or the dignity of law. The method thus exemplified may in itself be justifiable or the reverse; the one thing certain is that it bears the appearance of having been fortuitous and arbitrary. Nor is it known whether the persons now in custody received any preliminary warning. A strong Government can afford to delay the actual infliction of a punishment, till unmistakable notice has been given that if the offence is continued punishment will not be delayed. As it may be allowed that none of those concerned are exempt from responsibility in the matter, so it cannot be denied that the entire episode is profoundly to be deplored. It occurs at a moment when the one thing to be desired is that the English public should form a sober and just estimate of the extent and causes of Irish distress. It is ill arguing with a man who has lost his temper. If, so far as relates to Ireland, Englishmen have not lost their temper, they are surrounded by an atmosphere which is certain to distort their views, exaggerate their prejudices, and heat their passions. We believe, indeed, that the conditions of Irish life are better understood in England now than they have ever been. The recent discussion on the relations of landlords and tenants, and the qualities of either class, must have produced results of the highest value. It is not denied by the Prime Minister or by any one else in England that there is dire suffering in many different parts of Ireland, or that if this calamity is due in some measure to exceptional causes-such as the abnormal inclemency of the season and the failure of successive harvests-it is also the outcome of sinister agencies which are perpetually at work. In England these are not in operation; and the deplorable and inveterate mistake which Englishmen commit is that of judging Ireland by the standard of their own domestic experience. There is no similarity, there is little or no analogy, between the agricultural conditions of the two countries That this is so will be plain to every one who has read the useful and suggestive correspondence on the subject which has recently appeared in the Tims. The wellto-do English citizen has learned that there is in Ireland a race of small tenant farmers with holdings of from thirty to ten acres, who have no resources save in the land, and who are absolutely overwhelmed with debt. They owe money to the small local banks, which have of late years increased at an abnormal rate; they owe money to their tradesmen; they owe money to each other. Thus the pecuniary position of a considerable majority of those who have the cultivation of the soil of Ireland in their hands, is not only lamentably, but to an Englishman inconceivably, bad. There is no more resemblance between the agricultural distress which exists in Ireland and that which exists in England than there is between the destitution of the beggar in the street and the impecuniosity of the luxurious spendthrift, who, if he has no balance at his banker&amp;apos;s, always contrives to dine in comfort, and is seldom at a low for ready money. This is far from being the only distinction between the agricultural classes in the two countries. Material suffering in Ireland is aggravated and inflamed by the consciousness, or at least by the idea, of moral wrong and traditional grievance. Englishmen do not understand the earth hunger of the Irish peasantry, for the simple reason that they have never thoroughly grasped its historical causei There are instincts which are part of the national heritage of Irishmen, that Englishmen cannot or will not comprehend. The history of land tenancy in Ireland is without anything corresponding to it here. Les than two centuries and a half ago the Irish kern had as real an interest in, as genuine a share of, the Irish land as the greatest territorial magnate among his countrymen. He was a member of a sept, and the fact of this membership caused him to be a participator in the soil. The property owned by the chief of the clan, who was the nominee of the clansmen, differed in extent bat not in degree. This is one of the secrets of th6 deeply rooted passion of the Irish peasantry for land. The instinct is one of those fatal survivals which constitute the standing difficulties of practical politics. No solution of the Irish land question can be satisfactory or permanent which ignores this circumstance. It is as much an historical fact as the sentiment which carried the repeal of Roman Catholic disabilities, or the abolition of the Protestant Establishment. These were the considerations that Mr. Mill had in view when, in a speech delivered in the House of Commons, May 17, 1866, he begged his hearers to reflect what a different history Ireland has had from either England or Scotland, and ask themselves whether that history must not have left an impress deeply engraves on Irish character. He went on to say&amp;quot;Consider, again, how different, oven at this day, ar the social us of Ireland from those of Engld or Sootland, and whether such different Gircumances must not ohen require different laws and iusitutions. People often ait has been aked this evening-why should tat whih works well in Bmgland not work well in Ireland ? or, Why should anything be needed in Ireland which is not needed in Englnd ? Are Irishmen an exception to all the ret of mankind, that they cannot bear the institutions and pracies which reason and experience point out as the best muted to promote natial prospenty? Sir, we were eloquently reninded the other night of that double ignorance against which a great philosopher warned his Contemporariesignorance of our being ignorant. But when we insist on applying the same rules in every repedt to Ireland and to England, we chow her kind of double ignorance, and at the same time disregard a precept olderthan Soeratesthe precept which was inscribed on the front of the Temple of Delphi: we not only do not know those whom we undertake to govern, but we do not know ourselves. No, sir, Ireland is not an exceptional country; but England is. Irish cirmtanes, and Irish ideas as to social and agricultural economy, are the general ideas and circumsnces of the human race; it is English circumstances and English ideas that are peculiar. Ireland is in the main stream of human existence and human feeling and opinion; it is England that is in one of the lateral channels.&amp;quot; This distinction between the two countries shows itself in other ways than those which have been already mentioned. It was exceedingly desirable that the case of the landlords should be heard as completely as it has been. It is well that Lord Powerasourt should remind us that so far from Irish landlords declining to expend money on their land, the weekly statements of loans obtained from the Board of Works show that large sums are constantly being laid out on drainage, building, and the reclamation of waste lands-these sums being, of course, over and above all private expenditure. Lord Poweracourt further denies that any improvements of consequence have been executed by those representatives of the class of peasant proprietors who already exist in Ireland. It is also edifying to hear from the Knight of Kerry the principle on which he has dealt with applications for reduction of rent on his own estate. When the tenant can show that the rent complained of first came into operation when prices of farm produce. were much in excess of those of the present day, and that the rent was aessed fully up to those high prices, he assents to the appeal for reduction; but when the rent was fixed at a time when prices were lower than at present, the appeal is refused. In this gentleman&amp;apos;s opinion the general adoption of such a plan would have prevented two dLstinct evils. The &amp;quot;tenant would not have been left in a state of uncertainty which made him an esy prey to the blandishments of Mr. Parnell; &amp;quot; and &amp;quot;1 many landlords would have been prevented from fain into the detrimental mistake of maling a lazy, blind, all-round abatement at the same percentage to all their tenants.&amp;quot; It is also well that testimony should have been adduced which seems to show that Irish distress is not quite so severe as it has sometimes been represented, and it is extremely instructive to hear that Lord Conyngham&amp;apos;s tenants in the county of Clare, having received notice that, his estate being about to be broken up into lots, the occupiers may become pure attended in a numerous body and expressed their willingness to buy at the rate of twenty-two years! purchase of the rent, while some offered as high as twenty-five years&amp;apos; purchase. But what do such instances as these prove ? Not that the distress in Ireland is not as severe as we have been given to understand, not that the entire class of Irish landlords has been calumniated; but that the former is not without compensating circumstasces, and that the latter are not wholly bad. The reality and, for all practical purposes, the magnitude of the evils with which we are called upon to deal are the same as ever. A policy must be based not upon a catalogue of exceptions, but upon the actual rule. It is not that Irish landlords are naturally worseihan, English; the truth is that the conditions under which they posess their land render it impossible that the relations between themselves and their tenants should be uniformly satisctor. In the first place, there are owners of property who, on the rength of the intense desire of tenants to remain in their old homes or to acquire some addition to their holdings, exact exorbitant rents, or refuse to show any forbearance when the pinch comes Secondly, there are landlords in Ireland-of a class almost unknown now in England-whoop properties are so burdened with debt and family charges, that generous dealing with their tenants is impsble. The existence of such landowners as these is a public evil, and it may be questioned whether the action contemplated by Mr. Parnell might not be conceded with advantage. Why should the compulsory sale of estates be only conceded in the cae of properties of the City companies and of absentees ? But the worst evil of all in the Irish land system is connected in it origin with a measure which has in its time accomplished much good. If the emb ed landlord who manages his property simply as the creditor&amp;apos;s trutee, and has thus no personal interest in the land, is a source of mischief, so also is the type of Irish landowners who came into existence as a natural consequence of the Encumbered Estates Act. This measure has undoubtedly been one of large and liberal relief. But it has not tended to the improvement of the relations between the owner and cultivator of the soil. Men who have purchased estates simply as an investment, and who reside little if at all in the country, can scarcely be expected to display any great interest in the condition of the peasantry. The old patriarchal ties between the proprietor and the tiller of the soil were often loose and slovenly enough, but they carried with them a sort of guarantee that the interest of the two would in the long run be identical. There may be room for doubt as to the precise shape which any measure of Irish land reform should assume, but its justice and its urgent necessity are at least beyond questioning. The most formidable thing is that English opinion is not likely to ris to the height MA cogeny of the diuiom - We shal aebisy D c remit so long a the leades of Englis ypini. int on thinkigotthewed of Ireland as th have. a right to. tipk about Yw-okre or Sme, SW so log as eV=&amp;apos; - ded - inoist ht our goal luvd be to Ahk IiImd - le, hghnd - pemwib. Irelad after A exide for the sake of the peoipe wh live in itkand if they ay choom an ifrior he ofu and grsturlecono~y, led the try their own Jr-%F. it th a do so withot injudive either to EII h or to oe anoer.</FullText></Record>