<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2463673</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127132155</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>A PLAIN VIEW OF BRITISH INTERESTS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>135</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Mar 1878</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18780301</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Laing</LastName><FirstName>S</FirstName><PersonName>S Laing</PersonName><OriginalForm>LAING, S</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Laing</LastName><FirstName>Samuel</FirstName><PersonName>Samuel Laing</PersonName><OriginalForm>Laing, Samuel</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>335</StartPage><EndPage>348</EndPage><Pagination>335-348</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2463673/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>A PLAIN VIEW OF BRITISH INTERESTS. TNE danger of the present crisis has arisen from the very vague idea. which many people have of what British interests really are. Few wished to go to war for the sake of Turkey, fewer still to sacrifice any real British interest from fear of war. But certain leaders, who were at heart philo-Turkish, shouted out &amp;quot;British interests&amp;quot; because it was a more plausible cry than hurrahing for the Turks, though it really meant much the same thing, and many well-intentioned but ill-informed people joined in the cry. Even now it is rare to find a man who has thought clearly out the question of what British interests really are, and who can give any reasonable account of the faith that is in him, whether he is on one side or the other-whether he thinks that Russia is the natural enemy of England, as our forefathers used to think of France; or, whether he thinks that to patronise the Turks is about as moral and about as likely in the long run to be successful, as it would be to send our Guards to Canada to support Spotted Tail or the Sitting Bull in a raid on our American cousins. It may not therefore be altogether useless, if one who has for many years taken a deep interest in foreign policy, and has listened to and shared in most of the discussions on the subject in the House of Commons for the last twenty-five years, should attempt to define the term, British interests, somewhat more closely and accurately than is commonly done. I may not always be right, but at any rate I know distinctly what I mean, what I believe to be true, and why I believe it; and, as an old Cambridge man, I know that a problem is half solved when it is clearly stated. What then are British interests? The answer is exceedingly simple, and any man of plain common sense can judge for himself, as well or better than those who obscure the broad outlines of the question by a haze of social prejudices or of diplomatic subtleties. Our interests are twofold: first, as an European kingdom; and secondly, as a colonial and specially an Asiatic empire. To this extent the two coincide, that the maintenance of our naval supremacy is the first condition of both. If any great power enters into competition with us in a race for naval supremacy, as Spain once did, and France repeatedly has done in the course of history, that no doubt is a serious danger to British interests, and we should be much to blame if we did not at once endeavour, by increasing our navy and fortifying ourselves by alliances, to replace ourselves in a position of reasonable safety. But, beyond this, there is the special danger to which the United Kingdom might be exposed from invasion. Without absolutely losing our naval supremacy, there are contingencies conceivable in which, by a temporary loss of the command of the Channel or otherwise, an enemy superior to us in military force might invade us with an army strong enough to have a chance of winning a battle and taking London. This is the one great and irreparable calamity which might at a blow shatter the greatness of the British Empire, and it is a blow which has more than once been menaced, and even so lately as in the reign of our good ally Louis Napoleon excited serious apprehension. But if we look at the teachings of history, or at the actual political state of Europe, it is in the last degree chimerical to consider Russia as a power dangerous to England, as being likely either to contest our naval supremacy or to invade our shores. All such danger has for the last two centuries threatened us from one source only, viz., from France; and Russia has been our old historical ally. In the greatest of modern wars, that waged to prevent Europe from being converted into one great military empire with Napoleon at its head, England and Russia stood shoulder to shoulder, and were mainly instrumental in vindicating the common cause of national independence. With the single exception of the Crimean war, which every one now admits to have been a mistake, the relations between England and Russia from the time of Queen Elizabeth downwards have been almost uniformly those of amity and mutual benefit. The reason is obvious. Apart from the question of India and the East, which we shall presently consider, no two nations can possibly have fewer points of collision than England and Russia. Russia may Be a danger to Austria, and in conceivable cases a danger to Germany, but to England never-never, that is, in the sense in which France repeatedly has been, and in certain contingencies might be again. Russia can never dream of becoming the paramount naval power of the world, or of embarking an army at Cronstadt to invade England. We, on the other hand, as an European power, have absolutely nothing to ask or apprehend from Russia. The wildest imagination cannot picture to itself a battle of Dorking, in which the trained legions of Russia are to overpower our British volunteers; or an annexation of Belgium or Holland by Russia, bringing her naval establishments within dangerous proximity to the British coast. As a test of the utter absence of any direct conflicting interests between England and Russia, we have only to suppose the case of a single-handed war between the two, all other powers, Turkey included, remaining neutral. What possible harm could we do to one another ? We might blockade their Baltic ports, and divert their trade to the railways of Germany, to the detriment mainly of our own shipping interest; or we Wight capture a few small traders or fishing vessels, and they might try to annoy us by sending out a few Alabamas; but practically we could do each other no serious harm, and when we got tired of war, the conditions of peace could only be the status quo ante. It is only therefore with reference to our interests as Asiatic empires that collision between England and Russia comes within the verge of possibility. And here I may observe that there is no natural antagonism in the position of the two empires even in Asia. Nature has drawn such a barrier in the form of mountain chains and deserts between India and Central Asia that they form two separate and independent provinces. Russia is no more cramped in her natural development in Asia by not possessing Ilindostan, than we are by not possessing Thibet or Chinese Tartary. The real antagonism between us and Russia in Asia arises from the position we have taken up of protectors of Turkey. Russia, foreseeing the possibility of a quarrel with England about Turkey, may naturally wish to be in a position in which she could retaliate in Asia for any blows we might inflict on her in Europe. And even the fear of Russia being able to cause us trouble in India, might be a powerful diplomatic weapon in her hands, in case of our adhering to our old policy of making the independence of Turkey, or, in other words, the right of Turkey to misgovern her Christian subjects without interference, a cardinal point of our system. And in considering the wisdom of this policy, it is an important consideration that its inevitable consequence is to place ourselves in a position of permanent antagonism with the only great European power which, like ourselves, has large possessions and interests in Asia. It is a great misfortune both. for England and Russia that anything like permanent antagonism should exist between them; and for this, the state of things in Turkey is solely responsible; for, apart from the question of Turkey, there is absolutely no point of collision between their respective interests. However, let us take things as they are, and supposing that some untoward circumstance brought us into collision with Russia, under what circumstances might the security of our Indian Empire be seriously endangered ? This is the real practical question of the hour; for I take it that, whatever Mr. Lowe or other politicians may say about India being a liability rather than an advantage to us, the immense majority of the country would be prepared, as I should be myself, to fight to the last rather than lose India. Show me, therefore, that any step taken by Russia is a serious menace to our Indian Empire, and I should be prepared to vote our last shilling and our last soldier to resist it. But on the other hand I am as determinedly Opposed to engaging in such a war upon mere vague suggestions of remote and contingent dangers, which originate very much more from sympathy with the Turks than from any real and statesman- like grasp of the political and, I might add, the geographical conditions of the question. How could Russia endanger our Indian Empire ? In two ways: by direct invasion and by cutting off our communication by the Suez Canal. As regards direct invasion, the Duke of Wellington and Lord Hardinge, thirty years ago, when our position in India was far weaker in a military point of view than it is at present, pronounced it to be a &amp;quot;political nightmare&amp;quot;; and for this obvious reason: The only possible route by which an invading army can attack India is that which has been followed by every invader from the time of Alexander the Great downwards, viz., through Affghanistan, rid Herat, and thence either by Cabul and the Khyber, or by Candahar and the Bolan Pass. Practically by both, for no invading army could venture to advance by one of those passes alone, while the other remained in possession of the enemy to threaten its communications. Now let any one who has the slightest acquaintance with the conditions under which armies are moved, or even I may say who has an elementary knowledge of physical geography, consider what would be necessary in order to bring a large Russian force by this route, within striking distance of British India. It must start from Astrakhan as its basis, the Volga forming the arterial communication by which troops and stores are forwarded from the interior of Russia. There must then be a fleet on the Caspian capable of transporting the army, with its supplies and means of transport, to Astrabad, at the south-east end of that sea, where a port must be created (under great difficulties, owing to the shallowness of the water) capable of disembarking the enormous number of horses, camels, stores, and cannon requisite for such an undertaking. The next stage is a march of nearly five hundred miles through a thinly inhabited country, for the most part hilly and arid, to Herat, where, in a military point of view, the enterprise may be said to commence. Suppose Herat taken, and no adequate resistance offered, the invading army must next advance to Candahar, a distance of more than three hundred miles, and must proceed to occupy Ghuznee and Cabul, the latter distant another two hundred and fifty miles from Candahar, in order to secure their flank before engaging themselves in the passes. They have then their choice of reaching the frontier of British India either from Cabul, by a march of one hundred and fifty miles, through the Khyber Pass, one of the most difficult mountain defiles in the world; or by a march of three hundred miles from Candahar through the Bolan Pass. In the former case they debouch on Peshawur, our great military centre in the north-west; in the latter case on the Indus, a river over which it would be almost impossible to construct a permanent bridge, with Scinde on the one flank and the Punjaub on the other; and in front the great sandy desert, which effectually bars the way to any direct advance on Hindostan. The invading army clearly must detach a force to conquer and hold Scinde on the south, while the main body marches some three hundred miles to the north, to attempt the passage of the five rivers and the conquest of the Punjaub. Only when those two conditions are attained could an advance on Delhi and a blow at the heart of our Indian Empire be seriously undertaken. Now let us consider for a moment what, even in the absence of any efficient military opposition, is implied in the supposition that a Russian army could reach our frontier in sufficient force to menace our Indian Empire, fully equipped and so assured of a constant stream of supplies and reinforcements as to be prepared for a protracted campaign. The line of communication from Astrabad is upwards of one thousand miles, through a country for the most part consisting of rugged mountains and deserts, and at the best thinly populated and destitute of resources. This country is inhabited by warlike and predatory tribes, who, according to all reasonable calculation, would be on our side from the commencement, and who certainly could not resist the temptation, if it were afforded to them, of plundering convoys and cutting off small detachments. There are some remarkable statistics which may give an idea of what sort of enterprise it would be to move a large army and maintain its communications over one thousand miles of such a country. In the Russian expeditions against Khiva it was found that for each effective soldier placed in fighting order at the front, there was required, on the average, one and a half camels and one horse; and our own experience, in the advance of Sir G. Pollock on Cabul, will give very similar results. The necessity for this inordinate amount of transport is apparent if it be considered that directly an army has to traverse any considerable extent of country destitute of supplies and forage, for each camel, A, doing useful work in carrying ammunition and food for the soldiers, you must have two camels, B and C, carrying forage for A, B, and C, and food for their respective drivers and other camp attendants. The transport thus multiplies in a geometrical progression, until the impossibility of providing and maintaining it becomes manifest, directly we attempt to deal with the movement of a large or even of a considerable army. To place a Russian army of one hundred thousand men on our Indian frontier would, according to the best data of military experience in those districts, require something like one hundred and fifty thousand camels, one hundred thousand horses, and a corresponding number of camel-drivers and other camp attendants. The question would stand thus, supposing there were no military obstacles. But practically the invading army would have to fight its way for every inch of the route from Astrabad, or certainly from Herat, against the whole military force both of Great Britain and India, operating with the immense advantage of communications by steamers and railways up to Peshawur. India alone could supply a contingent of thirty thousand or forty thousand European troops, with a splendid artillery, and any number of native troops, levied from martial races such as the Sikhs, Pathans, Rajpoots, and Goorkhas, who, led by such European officers as India has never failed to supply, would be, to say the least, as good as the Turks who repulsed the Russians at Zewin, and held them so long at bay at Plevna. And the whole resources of England would be available to reinforce this army. In such a war we should have nothing to fear for our own shores, or for any of our colonies, and almost every regular soldier and every battery of artillery could be sent, in case of need, to India-and with such facility, that while the Russiaju army was plodding painfully along its arid mountain march of one thousand miles, our Guards could be paraded at Peshawur within six weeks of their marching out of Hyde Park, without losing so much as a button of their uniforms. It would be no great strain on the resources of the British Empire to place and maintain on the north-western frontier of our Indian possessions a splendid and admirably equipped army of 100,000 Europeans and 100,000 Natives, in strong positions, protected, if necessary, by any amount of forts and earthworks, ready to &amp;amp;trike the heads of any Russian columns which, after wending their weary way across Affghanistan, might attempt to thread the long Khyber or Bolan passes and debouch on British territory. And this supposes them to have got there, while practically we should occupy all important strategical points in Affghanistan long before the Russians could reach them, and oblige them to take half-a-dozen Plevnas and force half-a-dozen Shipka Passes, before they could get within striking reach of our main army. It is useless to accumulate proofs where any one is so overwhelming, but it may be worth while to point out how immensely the strength of our position in India for defence, relatively to that of Russia for attack, has improved since the time when Lord Hardinge and the Duke of Wellington pronounced the idea of a Russian invasion to be a political nightmare. Thirty years ago, Affghanistan was bitterly hostile, the Punjaub and Scinde were independent, and the powerful Sikh army was a constant source of danger. Moreover, communications were excessively slow and difficult, and reinforcements from England had to go round the Cape and be forwarded from Bombay or Calcutta by bullock-waggons over bad roads. Now, steamers and railways bring Peshawur practically nearer to Woolwich and Portsmouth than Benares or Allahabad were then to Calcutta, the Sikhs are among our best soldiers, and we are in firm military occupation of the whole country up to the mouths of the lhyber and Bolan Passes. On the other hand, Russia has made no progress whatever on the only possible line of attack. On the contrary, she may be fairly said to have lost ground since the time when a Persian army, aided by Russian officers, was besieging Herat some forty years ago. Persia was then as completely under the control of Russia as now, and she was then a more powerful auxiliary. Herat was a disputed possession between Affghanistan and Persia, and at any time, by falling into the hands of the latter, might become virtually a Russian outpost. Now, Herat is a recognised portion of Affghan territory, and it is perfectly well understood that no one can venture to meddle with it who is not prepared to run the risk of a war with England. Again, all the conquests of territory in Central Asia made during recent years by Russia, while they do not advance her a single inch on the only practicable line of an invasion of India, make her much more vulnerable to counter-attacks from us in case of a war. No serious invasion by an army could ever take place, on either side, across the great Hindoo Koosh and Himalaya ranges, but it would be much easier for us to give the Russians trouble at Bokhara or Samarcand, than for them to cause us anxiety at Lahore or Mooltan. A Mahometan rising against Russia in Central Asia is a very much more possible contingency than one against us in India, where the Mussulmans are in a small minority and cannot fail to see in Russia the greatest enemy of their faith. A comparison of the respective positions of England and Russia now and forty years ago, is the best proof of the wisdom of that policy of &amp;quot;masterly inactivity&amp;quot; which, with the single exception of the disastrous episode of the occupation of Affghanistan, has been uniformly pursued by the great statesmen who have been at the head of our Indian government. Once in the experience of forty years, under the influence of a blind panic of Russian aggression, emanating from the Foreign Office in London, we were betrayed into the policy of trying to anticipate events by sending an army beyond the natural boundaries of India. The result was disastrous. During the rest of the period we have abjured this policy and looked upon the course of events in Central Asia with equanimity. The result is that we find our position vastly improved. Can there be a more conclusive argument for adhering to the policy which has worked well, and not resorting to that which has worked badly? The occupation of Quettah, and the demand to send a British Resident to Cabul, are measures which alarm me much more for the safety of India than any extension of Russian conquests in Cen. tral Asia. As long as we followed the policy of Lord Canning and Lord Lawrence, the Affghans were certain to be our allies in case of a war with Russia, for they had sufficient political sense to know that while we did not want a single inch of their territory, Russia, if she once occupied it, would be compelled by the force of circumstances to retain it. But if we depart from this wise policy, and adopt the policy of trying to civilise our neighbours against their will, by the influence of accomplished English residents, backed by military posts on the Affghan side of the passes, they know what this has led to in other cases, and not wishing to exchange their turbulent independence for the condition of the Nizam. or Scindiah, they will be bitterly hostile. These considerations apply to another cry, which some people try to raise, that any conquests Russia may make in Armenia are a menace to India. Ears and Erzeroum are no more on the route of any practicable invasion of India, than are Bokhara or Samarcand. If the Russian army of the Caucasus were about to take part in an invasion of India, it would not start from Erzeroum, to fight its way down the Euphrates Valley to Bagdad and Bussorah, and there gather shells on the shore of the Persian Gulf, which is all it could do, unless Russia had a fleet superior to ours in the Indian Ocean. But it would start from Tiflis and embark on the Caspian at Bakou, to join the main invading army at Astrabad, or possibly it would start from Erivan, and attempt to march across Persia to Herat, though such a march would be almost impossible for any considerable army, from the great distance, the ruggedness and poverty of the country, and the absence of supplies. The conquest of Armenia by Russia only affects us on the supposition that the fate of the British Empire is bound up with that of Turkey. No doubt it weakens Turkey, just as the loss of Servia, Roumania, and Greece weakened it, but our Indian Empire stands erect, though Turkish pashas no longer rule at Belgrade, Bucharest, and Athens; and as far as India is concerned it is a matter of profound indifference to us what becomes of Erzeroum. Granted that Russia would then be on the head waters of the Euphrates, and, in the event of another war with Turkey, might conceivably occupy the Euphrates Valley and Bagdad. This never has been, and never can be, a possible line of invasion, or of military communication, with India. It ends at the Persian Gulf, in a cul-de-sac from which no egress is possible unless for a superior naval power. Nor can this route ever be an important communication between England and India. If any one would be kind enough to make a railway first to Constantinople, then across Asia Minor to the Euphrates, and finally down the Euphrates Valley to the Persian Gulf, it might be a certain slight convenience for express passengers, but, even if it were in our own hands from end to end, it could never be used in competition with the Suez route for the conveyance of troops, stores, merchandise, or general passenger traffic. And, if we suppose Russia were to extend her conquests far enough to interfere with this route, what an exhaustion of her means in men and money, and what an extension of her vulnerable points does this imply! Some people seem to think that the best preparation by Russia for such a gigantic enterprise as an invasion of India is to be found in occupying enormous extents of barren outlying territory, which are of necessity a heavy strain on her resources, especially in money, where she is weakest, and which do not bring her one step nearer to what is supposed to be the goal of her ambition. Russian conquests in Asia Minor would only begin to be a menace to British interests when they brought her as far as Syria, from which an invasion of Egypt and interruption of the route by the Suez Canal became possible, and as to this we may indeed rest satisfied with relying on the old war cry of the Campbells, &amp;quot; It&amp;apos;s a far cry to Loch Awe.&amp;quot; The apprehension of danger to British interests from any direct attack on India by Russia being thus shown to be chimerical, the only question deserving of serious consideration is that of danger to our communication by the Suez route. This brings us to the question of Constantinople and the navigation of the Dardanelles. The two go together, for if Constantinople were in the hands of a neutral power and the Dardanelles unfortified, the free ingress and egress of ships of war into the Black Sea would stand on precisely the same footing as into the Baltic. There might be a certain amount of convenience to nations which have to keep fleets in the German Ocean, if no Russian ship of war could under any circumstances pass the Sound; while, on the other hand, in the event of war with Russia, it would be a disadvantage to such nations and an advantage to Russia, if no ship of war could enter the Baltic. Precisely the same arguments would apply to the Black Sea, and it is difficult to sav on which side the advantages would preponderate. But practically there is no doubt that in such a case the navigation would be free, for it is an unnatural arrangement to make a mare clausum of any sea in which a number of different nations have interests, and which nature has made accessible to all. And in the long run it must be for the interest of the power which is strongest at sea, that its ships of war should not be precluded by any artificial barriers from going wherever it had commerce to protect and may have an enemy to attack. But the real danger to be apprehended is, that if Russia had the control of Constantinople, she would so fortify the Da;rda- nelles that in case of war, while Russian ships of war could come out into the Mediterranean, those of any other power could not come in. It is clear that such a state of things would be, if not a serious danger, at any rate a serious inconvenience to British interests. If Russia had an impregnable stronghold, within three or four days&amp;apos; sail of Port Said, from which fleets and privateers could issue, with a secure refuge in case of being pursued by a superior force, it would expose our communications with India to considerable risk, and we should be obliged to maintain a larger Mediterranean fleet, to establish a great naval station at or near the mouth of the Dardanelles, and probably to occupy Egypt. There is reason therefore in considering it a legitimate aim of British policy that Constantinople and the Dardanelles shall not be occupied permanently by Russia. The question is, how this legitimate object of our policy is to be attained. If Turkey had been a respectable, or we may say, even a possible power, the policy was obvious of supporting her, and ensuring her integrity and independence by an European treaty. But the events of the last twenty years have conclusively shown that the continuance of this policy is simply impossible. Now that the country knows what Turkish rule really means, its conscience revolts against the idea of supporting it, and condemning so many millions of Christians to hopeless misery and degradation for the sake of supposed selfish interests of England. You might as well dream of undoing the work of Wilberforce and reviving the slave trade, as of bringing the English nation back to the old policy of fighting for Turkey. And even if it were possible to bring England back to this policy it is evident that it would be of no avail, and that our utmost efforts could only succeed in staving off, for a short period of feverish suspense, the evil day when the question would recur in a more formidable shape. Mussulman Turkey is decaying; it is in a minority in its own European Empire; it is incorrigible and impervious to the advice of its best friends; it is morally and materially bankrupt. And now finally, by its inconceivable folly in rejecting the proposals of the Conference, it has practically torn up the Treaty of Paris, which was the charter of its existence, and provoked a war which has annihilated the only thing on which it had to rely, its military power. Under these circumstances, it is clear that the old policy of the Crimean war has crumbled to pieces under our feet, and that we must take a new departure, and look in a different direction for a permanent solution of the Eastern Question on a basis consistent with our interests. The first point is to have a clear idea of what would suit us best; the next to consider calmly and dispassionately what are the most likely means of obtaining it. As regards the first point, I base myself on a great authority-no less a man than the great Duke of Wellington. When he heard of the Peace of Adrianople, in 1828, he said that, as the Russians had gone so far, it was a pity they had not gone farther, so that the Eastern Question might have been settled, once for all, by the establishment of a new Byzantine Empire at Constantinople as a neutral State under the guarantee of the Great Powers. It is evident that if this solution could be brought about, it would suit us admirably. If Greece were made a southern Belgium, with Constantinople for its capital, and its neutrality guaranteed by the Great Powers, with proper conditions as to the navigation and fortification of the Dardanelles, and at the same time Roumania declared independent, and Bulgaria and the Slavonic Provinces of European Turkey formed into an autonomous government, English interests would be placed on a permanently secure basis. Let us suppose Russia to have those ambitious designs which some people fancy, what would suit her best ? She cannot acquire Constantinople now, or any considerable portion of European Turkey, for Germany and Austria, who are together, or even Germany singly, vastly more powerful than Russia, have a vital interest in preventing it. When we talk of danger to British interests from Russia holding Constantinople, it is as nothing to the danger to Austria and Germany. The Danube and Dardanelles are the back-door of their houses, not of ours. We have no masses of Slavonic population incorporated in the heart of our empire, and forming a majority in some of the most important provinces; they have. We have the sea between us and Russia; they have a long line of more than one thousand miles of open frontier. In no conceivable circumstances could it be otherwise than destruction to Austria, and a most grave danger for Germany, if Russia ruled supreme over one hundred millions of Slavonians, in a line extending from St. Petersburg to Constantinople, and drawing towards itself, by the gravitation of raceaffinities, Bohemia, Galicia, Croatia, and Dalmatia. And yet Germany and Austria displayed no such flutter of fussy apprehension as was shown by the British Government at the approach of the Russian armies to Constantinople, for they feel that they have, in the first place, the solemn pledge of the Russian Government not to remain there, and in the next place, the best of all guarantees for the observance of this pledge, in the fact that if Russia broke it, the question would not be whether she could keep Constantinople in defiance of the other Powers, but whether she could defend heraelf at Mosctow and St. Petersburg. As a distinguished. Russian general said, the only possible route for Russia to Constantinople lies through Vienna; and it may be taken as an elementary fact in the politics of the Eastern Question, that a permanent occupation of Constantinople by Russia only becomes possible when Austria is crushed, and that Austria cannot be crushed while she has the support of Germany, and Germany remains the first military power of Europe. The present state of things is, therefore, the most favourable for a permanent settlement of the Eastern Question in accordance with true English interests. But for this very reason it is for the interest of Russia, if she really has the ambitious designs which are attributed to her, to make the present settlement a partial one. Who can tell what the state of Europe may be ten years hence, when the Czar, the German Emperor, and Bismarck may be gone, when ultramontane intrigues may have sapped the cohesion of the new German Empire, and the rapid growth of the military power of France may have made her a match for a disunited Germany? The really great danger looming over Europe in the future is that of a possible alliance between France and Russia, based on Russia assisting France to regain her lost provinces, in consideration of Franco assisting Russia to annex Constantinople; or the danger might take the alternative form of Germany making a great sacrifice to Russia in the East, in order to ward off the still greater danger of her alliance with France. W~Tho will venture to say that in ten years or less from the present time such a state of things may not have come to pass, and the barriers which at present block the way to Russia&amp;apos;s annexation of Constantinople may not have disappeared or been materially weakened ? If, therefore, this be the secret aim of Russian diplomacy, her present policy is clear. To make a peace which shall leave the Turks at Constantinople with a nominal independence, and give the Christian provinces just enough autonomy to make them feel the aspiration for complete independence, without fully satisfying it. Turkey has been so crushed by the present war that, whether the treaty of peace leaves her a little more or a little less, she never again can be what she has been, a power capable of resisting Russia in an arduous contest. The autonomy of Bulgaria and the other Christian provinces, reduce it to a minimumm, must practically bridge over the Danube and level the Balkans, and in any future war open the road for an invading army as far as Adrianople. If Russia cherishes ambitious designs in the future, what can be playing her game more effectually than to use British influence for the purpose of minimising the concessions to the Christians, and Eaving for the Turkish Government as much as possible of a nominal supremacy, and a right of partial military occupation and irritating interference? If you want Bulgaria to be a second Servia, treat her as Servia was treated. Leave her with an ill-defined claim of suzerainty, with her fortresses occupied by weak Turkish garrisons, and with her natural frontiers so curtailed that half the people of her own race are still groaning under Turkish tyranny, and there is little fear that Bulgaria will be as ready an instrument in the hands of Russia as ever Servia was. But treat the Christians as you have treated Greece, or rather as you ought to have treated Greece if you had given her the essentially Greek provinces of Thessaly, Epirus, and Candia; then Bulgaria, Servia, Montenegro, and Roumania will be as jealous of their independence, and as little inclined to be made cat&amp;apos;s-paws of by Russia, as Greece has shown herself. Establish the former state of things, and it is evident that not only will opportunities always be ready for Russia to reopen the Eastern Question at any moment when it suits her to do so, but that, even without her wishing it, occasions of offence will perpetually occur which will make it very difficult to prevent it. For instance, say you leave a Turkish garrison in Widdin, and a Turkish soldier insults a Christian woman in the streets, and a row ensues, which ends in the fort firing on the town, as was the case at Belgrade. Here is a spark which may light up a great fire, and make it difficult for Russia, even if so disposed, to abstain from interfering. Or, if you leave Greece, with Turkey stricken to death, and such essentially Greek provinces as Thessaly and Candia with just selfgovernment enough to be able to agitate for union with their parent country, and just enough of Turkish supremacy left to be unable to attain it, what prospect does this bold out of a peaceful and permanent solution of the Hellenic question ? Add to this that if the new Christian States are made independent, Russia cannot readily march armies into them without a palpable breach of international law, as to which Austria and Germany would have a word to say, while as parts of the Turkish Empire they are, of course, open to invasion, and no neutral power can object to her occupation of them if at war with their suzerain. On the whole, it seems as clear as any political proposition can be, that things having come to the pass they have, the obvious interest of England is not to go into the Conference as a sort of devil&amp;apos;s advocate for Turkey, trying to save as much as possible of her nominal authority, and to nmininise as far as possible the concessions to the Christian provinces, but exactly the contrary; and that the real test of the sincerity or otherwise of the professions of Russia will consist in the determination which she shows to place the Eastern Christians in a position of real and permanent independence. If Russia is animated in the main by generous and philanthropic feelings, she will readily concur in any proposals so to extend the boundaries and strengthen the independence of Roumania, Bulgaria, Servia, Montenegro, and Greece, that they may not be perpetually looking to Russia for aid to complete their half-commenced emanci- pation. If, on the other hand, she is actuated mainly by motives of selfish ambition, she will readily fall in with the suggestions of timid diplomacy, and agree to minimise those concessions down to the lowest point sufficient to save appearances, leaving a belt of halfemancipated and semi-autonomous provinces, ready to reopen the Eastern Question for her at any moment when a more favourable conjuncture of European affairs leaves the East, and possibly Constantinople itself, open as a prize for her ambition. Whether a really permanent solution of the whole problem is now possible, is a difficult question to answer. It can only be in one way, by Constantinople passing into the hands of Greece, enlarged into a southern Belgium and neutralized under the guarantee of the Great Powers. This much is clear, that such a solution, if it be possible to attain it, would be the one of all others best for English interests, having in view the paramount object of preventing Russia, or any other great military and naval power, from ever obtaining exclusive dominion over Constantinople and the Dardanelles. The recent debate in the House of Commons has done a good deal to clear up the position. With the exception of a few noisy fanatics who wish to engage the country in war from unreasoning sympathy with Turkey, or equally unreasoning prejudice against Russia, the country generally acquiesces in the policy of conditional neutrality, i.e. of neutrality so long as British interests are not affected. But when we come to a definition of British interests, and the practical course to be pursued for their protection, this unanimity ceases. The liberal party generally contend for a strict limitation of British interests to those specified in Lord Derby&amp;apos;s dispatch of the 6th of May, and which are obviously not touched by any operations of the war or diplomatic conditions put forward by Russia, as far as is known up to the present time. A small but influential Tory party is still eager, as it has always been, for gentlemanly oppressors against vulgar oppressed; and while a great mass of well-meaning, but not very well-informed, opinion still hesitates to break with old traditions, and is still inflamed by old antipathies to Russia, dating back to the totally different state of things which prevailed there during the iron rule of the despotic and arrogant Nicholas, a strong and a growing party, comprising, to say the least, a large proportion of the best intellect and conscience of the country, is earnest and resolute not to allow, if by any constitutional means and fair appeal to public opinion they can prevent it, the honour of England to be any longer tarnished and her interests sacrificed by allowing Turkophilist prejudices, whether in or out of the Cabinet, to make her play the part of advocate of Turkey and adversary of the Eastern Christians. S. LAING.</FullText></Record>