<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2464648</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131013</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>HOME AND FOREIGN AFFAIRS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>220</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Apr 1885</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18850401</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Escott</LastName><MiddleName>H S</MiddleName><FirstName>T</FirstName><PersonName>T H S Escott</PersonName><OriginalForm>Escott, T. H. S.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Escott, Thomas Hay Sweet, 1844-1924</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>575</StartPage><EndPage>588</EndPage><Pagination>575-588</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2464648/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>HOV AND I1BRIGN APPALRS. Mo-T succeeds month, and as it brings with it no abatement of our Imperial anxieties, brings with it no perceptible change in the relative position of the two parties in the State. WVe are within a measurable distance of war with Russia. Three weeks ago the Govenment narrowly escaped, by a majority that dwindled to fourteen-a majority which, when it is remembered that between thirty and forty members of the House of Commons are officials, is smaller even than it seems-defeat in the popular Chamber on a vote of censure. Another resolution of censure. the debate originated by which will have concluded before these lines are in the hands of the pubic, upon an international agreement which no one likes, and which most persons cordially dislike and distrust, is in progress; and yet, notwithstanding all this, notwithstanding their past blunders, their present difficulties and dilemmas, their future uncertainty, Mniters are to all appearance as Srong as ever, and the Opposition certainly weaker, more distracted, less able to take advantage of miniseril mistakes. It remains to be seen whether the reappearance of Lord Randolph Churchill in the House of Commons after the Easter holidays will inspire his party with any capacity of united and effective action, or will help them to recover from the staie of impotence and paralysis into which they have fallen. As matters are, the Seats Bill has produced the exact results which, from the first, we ventured to predict. There is not only no opposition to it; there is not even any plausible show of opposition. Every division taken has but served to bring into fresh relief the wchimun and jealousies by which Conservatism is rent. The compact entered into between the Conservative and Liberal leaders has raied and animaed the followers of the latter, while it has taken all spirit and strength out of the followers of the former. Nothing less than a political miracle has been worked. A constitutional revolution is in course of accomplishment by what amounts to universal consent. The chief dingrwment is as to the names by which the electorates, which will give us a wholly novel House of Coinmoms, are to be called. By a curious cincidence, just as we in England ar adopting the wcrutirn d&amp;apos;afroxdiwee , the French Chamber is busy with sstituig for crutix d&amp;apos;arudiumemt, crutin dJ Ate. Gumbetta perceived, years ago, that the principle of representative government would never receive full justice in his country so long as local interests prdinated in the selection of its members of Parliament. Comparatively few, whether among the Conservativees or the librs seriouly d as the onseq e of fwwix d&amp;apos;arrudismmiet in England, the evils which it is designed to cure by wrmftia de &amp;amp;ie in France. No doubt we are taking, after our usual fashion, a leap in the dark; but could there be a more significant illusrtion of the difference between the two countries than that the Relistribution Bill, against the principles of which the contemporary action of the French deputies is so direct and vigorous a protest, should be passing through the English Pament almost uc~hallenged.? It is, unfortunately for ourselves, as impossible to speak definitely of the issue of the dispute between England and Russia as of the fate of the Egyptian a t or of General Graham&amp;apos;s operations against Osman Digna. Whether a few weeks or days hence we may be at war with the Government of the Czar depends entirely upon Lord Dufferin&amp;apos;s interview with the Ameer and upon the reception given by Russia to the prposals and the policy that will be the result of this conference. We cannot abandon Abdur Rahman. To do so would be not merely to invite attack upon India, but to undermine the moral influences-to destroy our character for loyalty and good faith-which are as essential to the maintenance of our Indian Empire as our army itself. It is, therefore, out of the question to talk of conceding the Russian cla-im On the other hand, it is clear that we cannot reasonably expect Russia to acquiesce in a condition of things which exposes her troops to the raids of the unruly and savage tribes that inhabit it. These tribes have never been more than theoretically subject to the suzerainty of the Ameer, who to-day exerts over them no real authority. The point, therefore, is, where is the new frontier to besdrawn ? and the ultimate solution of the difficulty mut be found in a military or genuinely scientific boundary line within the undo dominion of the Ameer, which we must render impregnable,and defend at any cos If this is not done there are only two other conceivable alternatives, either of them equally to be deprecated. One is for England to retire to the Indus, the other is war. The answers given by Ministers enable us to form a correct idea of the progress of negotiations between the English and Russian governments. No attempt is made to diguise the fact that the Russian answer to Mr. Gladstone&amp;apos;s first demand that the outpos should fall back from the debatable points was an absolute refusaL Her Majestys Govent have not insisted upon the demand, although both Lord Kimberley and Mr. Cross have admitted that in the opinion of the Ministry these points are within Afghan territory. They have, in fact, allowed the vidity of the Ameer&amp;apos;s claim, which Russia disputes, to be reered to negotiation. But they have also allowed him to maintain his garrison at Penjdeh, and have-reiteratecd their intention of securing for him &amp;quot; all the territory to which he is justly entitled.&amp;quot; Of course every hour spent while the two Governments may, for all we know, be travelling on the high road to a peaIceful ning, increases the risk of hostilities being precipitated by a quarrel between the outpost. In order to minimize this danWer, there has been famed a temporary convention, which forms a curious chapter in diplomatic history. On March 13, Mr. Gladsone informed the House of Commons that it was agreed that no further advance should be executed by either side pending the final decision. Ap ntly the Prime Minister gave this assuraneC on the strength of earlier telegrams from Sir Edward Thornton of a general character, signifying that an spirit prevailed in St. Petersburg. No definite answer to the specific proposal which originated with the English Government had then arrived. It was not indeed received till the 17th, when it was promptly aounced M. de Giers accepted the t, or as Mr. Gladstone now preferred to call it, &amp;quot;the ar t,&amp;quot; but with one awkward reservation,-&amp;quot; unless in the case of some extraordinary reason, sch for instance as a distance at Penjdeh.&amp;quot; When Colonel Alhanofr8 appearsace before that fort in the hope of exciting a Turcoman rising against the Afghan officers is embered, it is obvious that this reservation puts it in Rusia&amp;apos;s power to create both an excuse and a juification for further movements. Indeed, the Government has since received informtion that the probably unpr MApted seal of that officer has again been at work with the some object. The English Government, by Withdrawing their first demand, have met with a rebuff, which is considered in Russi, and to some extent on the Continent, as a diplaic triumph for the Czar&amp;apos;s advisers. The triumph may very well turn out to be more apparent than reaL For theagement, as Lord Kimberley expressy stated on March 17, is only temporar, and by no mean s involves our acquiescence in the presence of the Russian troops where they now are for an indefinite time.&amp;quot; That is to say, unlss Sir Peter Lumsden&amp;apos;s report moifie the opinion as to the limits of anistan previously held, the Government will be confronted with the necessity of reiterating their former demand or of breaking faith with their ally. Meanwhile, in the continued absence of his Russian coadjutor, the English Boundary Commissioner is rapidly proceeding with his work of inquiry and delimfaict Deplorable and dangerous as is the existing tension, we nevertheless incline to the opinion that war will be avoided. The spark is actually held in suspense over the powder magae The severance of the most delicate thread would cause it to descend; swords with edges as sharp as razors are abing round the filament; and yet there is a good hope that&amp;apos;the explouion may after all be avoided. Is therc, it may well be asked, any jusification for this view? Does it rest upon a sentiment or a fact ? Is it only the wish which is father to the thought, or is there anything in the situation which renders war improbae ? All that we know of the Russian movements during the last feaw months points to the conclusion that they were deliberately instituted to frustrate and hoodwink Sir Peter Lumaden. Russia, in other words, has been doing her utmost to steal a march upon us. What was her goal? The reply which naturally and immiately suggests itself is that the goal can have been nothing less than Herat. Now if the assumption that Russia had conceived, and was ready to execute, the design of occupying, or at least pressing on to, Herat, be correct, where are we to find the agency which, interposingitself in the path of Russia, summarilyarrested her progress? That inquiryagainadmitsonlyofa single reply. The Eastern question, it must be remembered, whether in Europe or Asia, is a logically connected and a closely compacted whole. It is not an aggregate of isolated groups of political problems. It is as continuous as history itself. One might as rationally assert that historical periods were independent of each other, as endeavour mutually to detach the Occidental and Oriental acts in that tr drama which is popularly known as the Eastern question. Germany has done nothing more than remind Russia of a fact as plain as the sun at noonday and of a law as inexorable as the correlation of force. The Czar, as Prince Bismarck put it to him, could not limit the consequences of a campaign agains England in Central Asia by the geographical boundaries within which it was ken. Of core the Czar knew this already. What he had yet to learn was the attitude which Germany would adopt when the European continent should be shaken by the ground-swell of the Asiatic struggl. While it is at least doubtful whether the - et of a war between Russia and England in Central Asia would be the signal for an attack bry the Hungarians on the Slavs, and for commions in Bulgaria and Roumania which would compel the int r of the Powers; while we rather believe that there is for the present nothing to fear from the reciprocal animosities latent, or expressed, between the different races of the dual empire, who can doubt that Russia would no soonerbepreoccpiedinghaisan than that the Austrians stirred by an impulse they could not resist, would press on to Salonica? But Austria could not lave her feet in the Bigean without admini nga shock to the whole economy of Eastern Europe. Prince Bimnrck, for instance, might, in considera for the latitude he was allowing Rlea in the East, claim proprietorial rights over certain parts of the Baltic provinces. As a matter of fact, there is the best reason for believing that the German Chancellr informed the Czar that if he went to war with Ela he must not count too cFdently upo the I t frF iipof the Faerlan As we have repeatedly stated, there are in Germany conhicting policies. There is the peace policy of the Emperor; the aggressive and Oriental policy of Bisnarck; the western policy-the policy, that i, in favour of a rapproc eme between France and England-of the Crown Princess. These differences notwithstanding, there is the best ground for saying that the Chancellor is honestly anxious to avoid war during the life of his Imperial master. But war could not be avoided if there were a rupture on the Afghan frontier between Russia and England. This matter no doubt afforded a theme for conversation when Count Herbert Bismarck recently held his now famous interview, of more than an hour&amp;apos;s duration, with Lord Granville. But the first question then discussed was the attitude of Germany towards England in respect of Egypt. We have made certain concessions to Germany in the Cameroons. To us they are of slight importance, and if Germany values them the only comment is that she might have had them before. In return we have obtained from Germanyand there can be no doubt that the m y has been explicitly arrived at between Lord Geanville and Count Herbert Bismarckthe support of Germany in our Egyptian policy. The delay in sgning the convention which is now before Parliament was due exclusively to the obstinacy of Prince Bisarck, and the immediate sequel of his son&amp;apos;s visit to London was the removal of that impediment. Nothing, as has been said above, can be much less satisfactory than the document which Parliament is now asked to ratify. It is a coice of evils, and the only question is whether the evil which we choose is to be the greater or the lesser one. Little more will be gained, by the formal adoption of the sceme, which the Powers have approved, than the immediate pecuniary relief of Egypt. Europe or England comes to her rescue with a loan of nine millions, and two years more are given for cdering the political and financial future of the country. The real victory is not with England or France, with Germany, Austria, or any other European state. It is with the bondholders, and with the members of that financial ring who now dominate the political system of the Continent There is smething unequivocally mor il the point to which England has, under pressure, come round. Perhaps it might have been otherwise if our Government had in the first instance recognised that the origin of our Egyptian troubles was financial rather than political; that Europe, when we began actively to interfere in Egypt, had a double hold-one in conequence of the law of liquidation, the second in onequence of the In al tribunals -over the Country; that, before and after the of . Zia Eng4l , by separating herself from France, and by suffering the law oi liqua to remain intact, ejected her co-trstee from the banks of the Nile, without taking the corresponding and logically obligatory step of cancelling the deed. The abortive Conference of last summer in London, convened by the English Government on the hypothesis that the interest on the coupons must be reduced, was followed by the despatch of Lord Northbrook, whose report, published for the first time within the last few days, threw doubt upon the expediency or necessity of any such reduction. Tardily, with an il grace and in egregious inc sncy with their previous delions, Ministers have now in effect adopted Lord Northbrool&amp;apos;s view, which is also the view of the French delegates, who held to their original conviction at the London Conference, and whose tenacity upon this subject was the cause of its collapse. It therefore comes to this, that for two years more the bondholders are, with the single exception that they are subjected to an infinitimal tax, to have their way, and that when this period has expired it will be necessary to reconsider the whole Egyptian question. This may be expediency, or it My be the recognition of dire necessity, but it is not p, and it is not to be wondered at that it should be regarded as profoundly unsftory by the English people. Whatever its immediate or ultimate issue, our difficulty with Russia in A fhanistan will not be entirely a matter of regret if it forces the Government to a concluion, as regards the Soudan, that ought not to be delayed a day. Nothing can be more certain than that public opinion will not tolerate the reonmmennement of Lord Wolseley&amp;apos;s campaign six, five, or four months hence, for the purpose of smashing the Mahdi at hamtoum or at any other spot which that msis potentate may select. The object of the Nile expedition was to relieve Gordon. Why it failed, whether it would have sucd if it had been undertaken earlier, what degpee of blame attaches to Ministers for their tardinuss in destching it, those are not now the questions to consider. The sole point of importe is that directly death did for Gordon what Lord Wolseley filled to do the whole motive of the campaign dis a If it had been practiable to inflict a decisive defeat then and there upon the Mahdi;, we ought of course to have seized the opportunity for doing so Equally of course we ought still to hold ourselves in readiness to try conclusions with him whenever he harasses us again. But is that any reason why we should pursue him at infinite cost, both of blood and treasure, across the pe tial wastes of a waterless desert? If we are to fight him, let us at least do so on the ground which is most convenient to ourselves, and not dissipate resoirces which could be profitably employed-which may be essential elwhe on a foe who can always bafe us by retrieting into his native fasnesse There is an in reason perhaps for smasing Omn Digna. That is to say, it is essential that trnq should be maited an the Red Sealittoral. If the Mahdcarries the war against u into a region at which Egypt proper will be jea d, awe can mash him then and ther Our obvious course is to draw a frontier not barther mouth than Wady HalIf, and to defend that with all our might. We have, in other words, to do in Africa exactly what we have to do in Central Asia: to trace a boundary lie, which s11ha be essential to our position, and not to allow it to be Judging from past exidence, millions of money and hundreds or thousands of brave lives would be expended on a second march to Khartoum. Not ten per cent. of either would be necessary if we had, as possibly we may have, to fight the Mahdi in the region of Wady Hailfs. But it will be sad if we abandon the notion of the false prophet on the spot which was the scene of Gordon&amp;apos;s m y we shal be bringing ourselves into contempt with the Mul]man Population, both in Egypt and in India, and inviting an attack upon ourselves. The reply to these apprehensions is obvious and conclusive. If we have to hold Egypt by military force, in the name of common sense let us restrict our efforts to Egypt. If we are to be called upon to quell disaffection in Hoan, let us concentrate our troops there. Positively the only argument in favour of stituting a wild-goose chase after the Mahdi is summed up in that mischievous word p igemischievous not because there is no such thing as prestige, or because prestige is under all cirusnces valueless, bat because it dupes so many people into mitaking the shadow for the substance, the phantom for the reality. There is absolutely no enterprise, however crazy, which might not be vindicated on an analogous plea. The business of England is to deal-and to take care that she has strength to deal-with actual and not hypothetical dangers. Happily, we may be sure that the course which patriotsm and prudence suggest will be urged upon the Government by necessity. No one who understands the temper of the English people or the omnipotence of public opinion can suoe that the renewal of the Soudan expedit, as originally planned by Lord Wolseley and the G e t,later in the year, is practicable. What we have had already is enough; and when Graham has once fulfilled the task entrusted to him, the sooner the last English redcoat is withdraw from the torrid sands and the inhospitable rks of the African deserts the better. Busy as most of the public men of England have been during the past month, and are now, none is busier or is confronted with a More heavy and critical task than the Prince of Wales. Before the Eater holidays are over he will for the third time in his life have placed his foot upon the soil of Ireland. He will pass a fortnight in the country, and though he need not anticipate any other than a cordial and respectful welcome, it cannot be said that the omens are we- redly a ii M0oreov, he is a pied by the Princess of Wales, and the bhavest of w might well shrink from the diagreable p lies ih an alarmed might conjure up. The advice has been freely tendered to their oyali that they should abandon, even at the eleventh hour, the idea of their trip. Greatly to their credit, they have declind to entertain such counsel. That any political good will result from their sojourn on the other side of -St George&amp;apos;s Channel is scarcely to be hoped for. It comes too late. Had a royal residence been estblished in Ireland fifteen years ago, had the Queen or the Prince of Wales then intrd ed the cusstom of passing three or four months of every yr in Ireland, had the royalty been disestablished and the exective business of the office handed over to the Chief Secretary, many troubles which have since occurred might have been prevented. But it is not the fault of the Prince of Wales that this step was not take. The Queen has never favoured the idea. None of her Ministers have been sfficiently bad courtiers to press it upon her. The notion, whenever it has been revived, has fallen through. But now that itwas revived by no less a person than Lord Spencer, the Prince of Wales had no alternative but to adopt it. The present Viceroy of Ireland is crowned with the responsibility of a Cabinet Minister, and in declining to be deaf to his suggestion the Prince of Wales, though he may not be able to confer any signal boon upon Ireland, will be performig an act wise and politic in itself, and signally honourable to him. In the speech of Prince Bismarck before the Reichstag on March 2, and in the subsequent declrions of Earl Granville in the Houe of L-dj, we have a satisfactory clearing up of that diplomatic misunderstandin which arose from the trement of colonial topics in England and Germany. As the dispute has tem ed in an amicable fasion, it is hardly necessary to find fault with Prince Bismarok&amp;apos;s brusquerie or our own negligence and i The colonising sirit which has seized Germany evidently took Lord Derby by urprise, and the German White Books have been a direemble form of awakening; but now that both nation have agreed through their ministers to come to terms, we can heartily endorse Earl Granville&amp;apos;s remarks, a I am sure that it is more than ever in the interest of Germany and ourselves that our relations should be good at a time when we are about to meet in almost every part of the world.&amp;quot; And if public speeches and declaions on both sides do not provide us with the picture of a complete eirenicon, the visit of Count Herbert Bisnaroc to England on a pacific and most important errand, as well as the visit of the Prince of Wales to Germany to take part in the birthday festivities of the venerable German Emperor, may upply ay -possible deficency, and prove that a com- plt. accord has been aived at between the august p and heri of d tm inboth countris Forthe first ti, therefore, in our history, German colonial interests will be closely bound upwith our own, and &amp;quot; Greater Germany &amp;quot; will marh on&amp;quot; Greater Britain.&amp;quot; The scene of dipl c labours is being shifted from the well-known boundaris of Europe to the distant countries of the South Atlantic and Pacif German merchants and advent s, smitten with the new-born rasm of colonisation, and peed with the idea of commercial exan, are scanning eagerly the distant regions of New GuinA and Central Africa, or wherever else a new field for their energy presents itself. From one point of view German colonisation, if read and national and enduring-which by the way some question -may bring England and English colonists an indirect benefit. It may divert the stream of German e n from our own dependencies, and leave a clearer field than at present exists for our own labourers and small capitalis. The keenest competitor in every department, whether on farms or in stores, who confronts an English emigrant in the colonies is the German. Let the Germans, therefore, by all means develop their Greater Germany, and leave Britons in absolute possession of the pFUnities of wealth which their own colonies afford. We have never grudged them the rights of citizenship when they came as fellow-colonists to our elements, and we do not under these new conditions fear their rivalry. But the question of over-population in our small islands is daily growing in difficulty; we may need the wate lands of our colonial empire more urgently than hitherto, and when the pressure becomes terable mayprefer the room to the company of Germans or any other nation. The importance of our colonies as providing ontlets for a surplus popuation at home was explained anew by Sir Frederick Napier Broome in an interesting lecture read (March 10) before the Royal Colonial Institute on Western Australia. A semof exni was unfolded by which thousands of acres of fertile lands would be opened up by a proposed railway, and an invitation virtually given to British colonists to tur their stepa thither. Such scemes as these, possile in most of our colonies, are of extreme practical interest to those who wish to see the resources of our empire utflised to the full for the benefit of Britons residing within the limits of the empire. The presence of the Prince of Wales lent an unusual clat to the meeting of the Institute, and proves once again with what rapidity all Britons are leaning the impor e and value of their colonial na In the House of Lords, Lord Sidmouth lately raised a discusson on a colonial naval force, and Lord Nortbrook in reply to a q tion answered ,that officers in the Imperial servic would willin give their services to the colonists as training officers.&amp;quot; It rests With the agents-general, with the consent of the various colnia legisatur, to bring forward a definite heme. On thisubject Sir Sau Samuel has remarked, &amp;quot;I think it would be a good thing if the Admiralty would take charge of all the small fleets of the colonies, each colony paying its quota of the expenses. This,&amp;quot; he adds, &amp;quot;would be a step towar federation, a link that would bind the colonies cser to the mother-country than any other scheme he knew of.&amp;quot; The spectacle of the c d in arms now afforded at Sua&amp;amp;in by the presence of the New South Wales contient ading shoudr to shuder with Imperial troops is an e g one, ad justifies the hope that what has been done with one branch of the service may be done with the other. Throughout the world British soldiers and sailors, whether recruited at home or in the coloni, may prove that they are ready to defend their legitimate rights, withstand injustice, and crush rebellion. With regard to the Soudan itself, Mr. Stanley, who has been so fully engaged in colonising projects of vast moment in equatorial Africa, contributes a letter to the Man, and advocates strongly the opening up of this part of the world by means of a permanent railway from Sualin to Berber. He observes that the Soudan is not worth a penny without a railway any more than the basin of the Upper Congo; and of the railway itself he adds, &amp;quot; Give it at leas a five years&amp;apos; trial, and if no genius arises of English blood to rule the Soudan with the white wand of peace, lift up your rails of the track and begone, and seal it for the silence of ages, holding Suakin and .souan only.&amp;quot; The situation in Bechanndis particularly puzzling, and presents us, with the complexities of mre than a triangular duel. Besides the Imperial Gove nt we have to conse the Tranal, Cape Colony, Free State, the two mock republics of Tend Goshen and Stellaland, each with separate and datly conflicig interests of their own. It is a relief to learn that military law rules in this distracted and disputed country, and that the British has arrested a Mr. Van Niekerk, a Stellaland offiial, on a charge of murder, thus striking at once at the rotten travesty of goernm t too long allowed to exist by the British GuvenuTent. The British forces are collected at Vryburg, the chf town in Stellaland, and have been organised with great celerity, string fear into the hearts of the lawles advents Within two months a thousand men have been advanced to a position eight hudred miles from Cape Town, and as they consist largely of mounted men they are easily mobilised and centred quiady where neessary. An interview has taken place between Sir Chaules Warren and Mr. Krger, the Tranavam representative, and the later may be mid to have given way on all Ponts. In fact the Transvaalers have no case at alL On the contrary, they ca be onvicted of fiagrant copiiy in l ets a. We must keep the tei iqu perfetl clear before us, and the plain language of our aor to Mr. Kruger when, he sid, &amp;quot; I do not knor what you mean by the government &amp;quot; (of the mock republic); &amp;quot; I only know of a bad of robbes who call themselves mini tors of a country belonging to the Queen,&amp;quot; helps u materially in nin the situation. Some. time ago Sir Hercules Robino was equally e it n describing the shameles audacity of the Transval GoVernment when they wised to include the country of the Bechunas der the terms of the Convention of 1884, after havingillegally connived at plunder and rapine there. He wrote: &amp;quot;If the British overnment were to amend the Convention in consequenc of the npcncipled tion of the freebootess which the Transaal Goenment have taken no pains to prevent, we should be makin ourslves nsenting parties to the grievosw wrong which as been inflicted on our allies Montsioa and Mankor, and offer an _ t to the c of such proceedings in the future. Once let it be see that Transval subjects Can, heced by their own Gernment, plundr the natives across the Transvaal border of their lad, and, having done so, can then secure by an ation saable titles for their stolen farms a well as the other aantes of a iettled form of goverment, freebooting will become a trade and a precedent, the effect of which will not be limited to the four Bechuanaland chiefs whose cases are now under &amp;lt;x_ &amp;quot; About the facts of criminal iniquity on the pat of the _ , as well as of the culpable i feree of the Transvael Govrmt, there is no doubt, and it is ex y that both of them shold Aind an apolisd in the person of the Cape Premier, who, with a cerbi amount of legal sophistry, adopts the aparently congeial rik of a speial plader before a Cape audience at Stellenboach, a Dutch village in the western province. He terms the unscr borderers who hired themselves out to Moshette and assouw, simply &amp;quot;melrer sodiers,&amp;quot; and excuses their action on the ground &amp;quot; that Englishmen long before now have utilised the services of meny soldiera&amp;quot; Such an argument would be only poss-be when expouded before a biassed &amp;quot;Afikander&amp;quot; audiee. These &amp;quot;mercenaries&amp;quot; were described in 1882 by a Captain Nourse, who was sent by Mr. Hudson, the British Resident in Pretoria, as &amp;quot;merely a number of loose men, who listened to no law, and were only seeking gain, such as cattle and ground, not caring from whom they got it.&amp;quot; Captain Wourse saw the reuiting lista in the Transnal, and was himself asked by an agent who did not know his position to join. The prie of the fre was a farn each and half.the 1l Sir Heres Rob n, who must be creditedwith the bes posib e knowledgeI of the circumsn -of the cae, observed, &amp;quot;that those mn oaling theelves &amp;apos;Mouw&amp;apos; Vd _ork&amp;apos; who have taken service one native chif with the object of appropriating the lad and cattle of anter native chif with whom they have no manner of quarrel, ar committing a action, and bringing disgrace upon the Buropean_ name m South Africa.&amp;quot; The High _ . adds with emphasis, and quite rightly too, that he Wm not countenance such iany shape or form. The brutal murder of Mr. Bethell and Mr. Waker and the mutilatin of their bodies were the last and cwning l n of the customs of the &amp;quot; nay soldiers.&amp;quot; Mr. Upington may be a sif Irish barrister, but he can hardly explain away or soften down the brutal atrocities on the Tranual frontier. It is sais o therefore, to lean that Sir Charles Warren holds Beh nd with a stong military force, and has ceared the ountry for the preset. He is takin into certain land claims and- will bring the stritest and mat impartial judgment to bear upon than. It is possible that the present possessor of farms may not be the freebooters themselves, but land-jobbers who have bought them from the freboo; but this cosidea does not make the claims just The title is esstially bad, and the metod of ing it worse. Moreover, it is doubtful whether, according to Kr law, Kafi chiefs can alienate their land at all witlout the consent of chiefs in council. The recent rupture between Sir Charles Warren and Mr. Rhode4s a Cape oJIa, point. to the fact that the prese of Cape politicia altogeth ompiate the situi They seem to feel bound to conder at every tur the &amp;quot;Dutch&amp;quot; vote in the colony. The whole Beh d question lies between the Transvaal and the Home Government. The treaty which was broken. was that entered into between the British stateunen and Transvaal I with ich the Cape has had nothing to d&amp;amp; Why, therefore, cannot the question be settled between the two original contracting Parties? The British Govent ay say that the final adjustment of these Bechunnd difflties acts the Cape more than themselves. Ultimately it may, but at present ther is so much intrigue going on in South Africa, such bitterness and prejudice, such class hatred, that it seems as well if Engand were to boad with a firm hand, for a time at least, the chief stategic and commerial postions Behala is a territory which it is most essential to kep ne -1l andl free from disrbances It woud be a bold and inteligible policy if the whole of it were taken nder British Protection from the borde of the Cape Colony as far as latitude 220 norh; even if the present disu nc blow over feboot may renew their attks farther north, and threaten as they now d Kuruma The railway is gradually being extended, has erly raed Xi, sa within a few years it may be extended to Secheli&amp;apos;s country, who, by the way, has recently asked for British protection, so a perma-net force, which seems necessary in these regions, will be easily kept and mobAlised. The qui e of our movements on the present expedition, has spis the Transsaalers As in the Soudan so in Bechuanaland a railway is necesay and useful from every point of view, strategic or comeil It is the right time for England to declare a policy in South Africa. Sir Charles Warren has at his command seven or eight thousand toop, and the cost of the expedition will probably exceed ?2,000,000. If he returns from Bechuanaland with the meagre boast of having cleared the country and put down disorder for a time only, the British taxpayer will vote the expeditin a costly and profitless one. Bechnaland must be held with a British force for some time until the state of South MAia generally is more peaceful. No large number of troops are required, as a few snart and well-mounted policemen can nip disorder in the bad and check the lawlessess of small bands of adventurers. There can be no urgent need of handing over Becnaland to the Cape, with its quarrelling and contentious political parties, each trying to thwart the other, and frequently dening themselves by making capital out of the native question. Why should the Cape be o of annetonP Recently it has thrown back the respnibility of governing Basutoland upon the lImperial Government, and was more than half inclined to abandon the Transkei. As things stand now, the Transkei territories are quite enough for the Cape Government to adminis. In the future, the South Africans of every State, Dutch or British, may be trusted with the full task of governing South Africa, but they are not ready for it yet. Political education of every description is a grth, and the problem of governing native territories is a political education in itself, therefore it is unwise to saddle the Cape colonists, numbeng 340,000, with the task of governing not only the million natives in the colony and the Trnskei, but the Bech also. Unfrtunately, the dtinctions of right and wrong have been obscured just at present in South Africa by race animosities and Tran vale n pthise with freebooters because they fancy the quarrel is really one not for the pos n of the barren wastes of Behuanaland, but for the supremacy of South Africa. Cannot Sir Charles Warren, before he leaves the country finally, setde this question ? If it is not settled now it will come up again at some future time, when England, after having been indifferent and caless, is aroused by fresh tales of lawlessness and atrocity. An inile policy, as hinted above, would be to take Bechuland under direct Imperial control as far as latitude 22? north, and include on the western border part of the Kalihari desert eastward of longitude 200 east. The expinse of governing and holding it for a term of years would be trifling counpared with the perdical vast expditure we always -ey called upon to make in South Africa. And the retention of this tract of country would mean that Eingland was to have a policy or in Sot Africa. The proimity of the Diamond Fields-composed chiefy of the most lopyal British subjects in Africa-would be an additional rem for a bold and i t line of action. From the Diamond Fields at all times might be expected not only moral sympathy, but at a pinch material help. Altough inco ted in Cape Colony, Guiqualand West has a distinct life and history of its own, and is pre-eminently rich and loyal. Boerdom has little inluence here. Next to Behnlthe Tranugela territories Call for our inter. ference. The Boers have gradually n isd Zulu territory, Germans are intriguing and may still be intr galong the Zulu littoral. Our Colonial Office has been more criminally apathetic in Zululand than anywhere else. Cannot some amends be made here, andthe case of the Zulus be looked into as carefully as that of the Bechuanas? The Transvaal Boers have recently obtained three million acres of land there, but there is no conceivable reason for this land hunger. The area of the Transvaal is 115,000 square miles, the pdpulation is about 40,000 or 50,000, and the Boers can scarcely be said to be jostling one another her Moreover, there is a vast amount of mineral wealth, eqseially gold, in the Transvaal, and the slightest industry of the burghers *might be attended with imn success if they confined themselves within the bo of the Vaal River and the Drak r. Moreover, our moral oligations towards the Zulu nation have been and still are great Too long have we allowed the land to lie at the mercy of intriguers and marauders of every desripto and a rectification of our boundaries in south-eat Afnea, as well as a sheme of governing Zululand for the good of the Zulus, might worthily engage Sir Charles Warren&amp;apos;s attention There is unrest and even intertribal fighting in Basutoland, where the well-known chieftains, Letsia, Lerothodi, and Masupla, rule refractory subjects in a precarious fashion of their own. Soething might be done in this country to aid Colonel Calake and overawe the Basutos, who have proved themselves incapable of ig the subtle magic of moral force. Upon the whole there is a good deal for Sir Carles Warren to do, if he is allowed to do it, in Bechuana land, Batond, Pondola, and Zululand. As he is at the head of a Cosy editio, it would be a pity were he to return with a bare handful of meagre resalts. Jr a 1885.</FullText></Record>