<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2464736</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130923</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>THE BELTON ESTATE.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Dec 15, 1865</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18651215</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Trollope</LastName><FirstName>Anthony</FirstName><PersonName>Anthony Trollope</PersonName><OriginalForm>TROLLOPE, ANTHONY</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Trollope</LastName><FirstName>Anthony</FirstName><PersonName>Anthony Trollope</PersonName><OriginalForm>Trollope, Anthony</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Lewes</LastName><MiddleName>Henry</MiddleName><FirstName>George</FirstName><PersonName>George Henry Lewes</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lewes, George Henry, 1817-1878</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>257</StartPage><EndPage>276</EndPage><Pagination>257-276</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2464736/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>THIE BELTON ESTATE. CHAPTER XXIX. THERE IS NOTHING TO )lELL. C.APTAU1N AYLMER had never before this knelt to Clara Amedroz. Suyh kneeling on the part of lovers used to be the fashion, because lovers in those days held in higher value than they do now that which they asked their ladies to give,-or because they pretended to do so. The forms at least of supplication were used; whereas in these wiser days Augustus simply suggests to Caroline that they two might as well make fools of themselves together,-and so the thing is settled without the need of much prayer. Captain Aylmer&amp;apos;s engagement had been originally made somewhat after this fashion. He had not, indeed, spoken of the thing contemplated as a folly, not being a man given to little waggeries of that nature; but he had been calm, unenthusiastic, and reasonable. Ile had not attempted to evince any passion, and would have been quite content that Clara should believe that he married as much from obedience to his aunt as from love for herself, had he not found that Clara would not take him at all under such a conviction. But though she had declined to come to him after that fashion,-though something more than that had been needed,-still she had been won easily, and, therefore, lightly prized. I fear that it is so with everything that we value,with our horses, our houses, our wines, and, above all, with our women. Where is the man who has heart and soul big enough to love a woman with increased force of passion because she has at once recognised in him all that she has herself desired ? Captain Avlmer having won his spurs easily, had taken no care in buckling thenm, and now found, to his surprise, that he was like to lose them. Ile had told himself that he would only be too glad to shuffle his feet free of their bondage; but now that they were going from him, he began to find that they were very necessary for the road that he was to travel. &amp;quot; Clara,&amp;quot; he said, kneeling by her side, &amp;quot;vou are more to me than my mother; ten times more!&amp;quot; This was all new to her. Hitherto, though she had never desired that he should assume such attitude as this, she had constantly been unconsciously wounded by his coldness,-by his cold propriety and unbending self-possession. His cold propriety and unbending selfpossession were gone now, and he was there at her feet. Such au argument, used at Aylmer Park, would have conquered her,-would have won her at once, in spite of herself; but now she was minded to be resolute. She had sworn to herself that she would not peril herself, or him, by joining herself to a man with whom she had so little symnpathy, and who apparently had none with her. But in what way was she to answer such a prayer as that which was now made to her? The man who addressed her was entitled to use all the warmth of an accepted lover. He only asked for that which had already been given to him. &amp;quot;Captain Aylmer ,&amp;quot; she began. &amp;quot;Why is it to be Captain Aylmer ? What have I done that you should use me in this way? It was not I vho,-who,-made you unhappy at Aylher Park.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I will not go back to that. It is of no use. Pray get up. It shocks me to see you in this way.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Tell me, then, that it is once more all right between us. Say that, and I shall be happier than I ever was before ;-yes, than I ever was before. I know how much I love you now, how sore it would be to lose you. I have been wrong. I had not thought enough of that, but I will think of it now.&amp;quot; She found that the task before her was very difficult,-so difficult that she almost broke down in performing it. It would have been so easy amid, for the moment, so pleasant to have yielded. He had his hand upon her arm, having attempted to take her hand. In preventimng that she had succeeded, but she could not altogether make herself free from him without rising. For a moment she had paused,-paused as though she were about to yield. For a moment, as he looked into her eyes, he had thought that he would again be victorious. Perhaps there was something in his glance, some too visible return of triumph to his eyes, which warned her of her danger. &amp;quot;INo!&amp;quot; she said, getting up and walking away from him; &amp;quot;no!&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And what does &amp;apos; no&amp;apos; mean, Clara? &amp;quot; Then he also rose, and stood leaning on the table. &amp;quot; Does it mean that you will be forsworn ? &amp;quot; It means this, that I will not come between you and your mother; that I will not be taken into a family in which I am scorned; that I will not go to Aylmer Park myself or be the means of preventing you from going there.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;There need be no question of Aylmer Park.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;There shall be none! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;But, so much being allowed, you will be my wife?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No, Captain Aylmer;-no. I cannot be your wife. Do not press it further; you must know that on such a subject I would think much before I answered you. I have thought much, and I klow that I am right.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;,And your promised word is to go for nothing ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;If it will comfort you to say so, you may say it. If you do not perceive that the mistake made between us has been as much your mistake as mine, and has injured me more than it has injured you, I will not remind you of it, -will never remind you of it after this.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But there has been no inistake,-and there shall be no injury.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ah, Captain Ay)lner! ou do not understand; you cannot understand. I would not for worlds reproach you; but do you think I suffered nothing from your mother ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And must I pay for her sins ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;There shall be no paying no punishment, and no reproaches. There shall be none at least from me. But,-do not think that I speak in anger or in pride,-I will not marry into Lady Aylmer&amp;apos;s family.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;This is too bad;--too bad! After all that is past, it is too bad! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; What can I say ? Would you advise ine to do that which would make us both wretched ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It would not make me wretched. It would make me happy. It would satisfy me altogether.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; It cannot be, Captain Aylmer. It cannot be. When I speak to you in that way, will you not let it be final ?&amp;quot; He paused a moment before he spoke again, and then he turned sharp upon her. &amp;quot;s Tell me this, Clara; do you love me? Have you ever loved me ? &amp;quot; She did not answer him, but stood there, listening quietly to his accusations. &amp;quot; You have never loved me, and yet you have allowed yourself to say that you did. Is not that true?&amp;quot; Still she did not answer. &amp;quot;sI ask you whether that is not true?&amp;quot; But though he asked her, and paused for an answer, looking the while full into ler face, yet she did not speak. &amp;quot; And now I suppose you will become your cousin&amp;apos;s wife ? &amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot; It will suit you to change, and to say that you love him.&amp;quot; Then at last she spoke. &amp;quot;I did not think that you would have treated me in this way, Captain Aylmer! I did not expect that you would insult me! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; I have not insulted you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But your manner to me makes my task easier than I could have hoped it to be. You asked me whether I ever loved you? I once thought that I did so; and so thinking, told you, without reserve, all my feeling. When I came to find that I had been Mistaken, I conceived myself bound by my engagement to rectify my own error as best I could; and I resolved, wrongly,-as I now think, very wrongly,-that I could learn as your wife to love you. Then came circumstances which showed me that a release would be good for both of us, and which justified me in accepting it. No girl could be bound by any engagement to a man who looked on and saw her treated in his own home, by his own mother, as you saw me treated at Aylnier Park. I claim to be released myself, and I know that this release is as good for you as it is for me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I am the best judge of that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;For myself at any rate I will judge. For myself I have decided. Now I have answered the questions which you asked me as to my love for yourself. To that other question which you have thought fit to put to me about my cousin, I refuse to give any answer whatsoever.&amp;quot; Then, having said so much, she walked out of the room, closing the door behind her, and left him standing there alone. We need not follow her as she went up, almost mechanically, into her own room,-the room that used to be her own,-and then shut herself in, waiting till she should be assured, first by sounds in the house, and then by silence, that he was gone. That she fell away greatly from the majesty of her demeanour when she was thus alone, and descended to the ordinary ways of troubled females, we may be quite sure. But to her there was no further difficulty. Her work for the day was done. In due time she would take herself to the cottage, and all would be well, or, at any rate, comfortable with her. But what was he to do ? How was he to get himself out of the house, and takehimself back to London ? While he had been in pursuit of her, and when he was leaving his vehicle at the public-house in the village of Belton, he,-like some other invading generals,-had failed to provide adequately for his retreat. When he was alone he took a turn or two about the room, half thinking that Clara would return to him. She could hardly leave him alone in a strange house,-him, who, as he had twice told her, had come all the way from Yorkshire to seC her. But she did not return, and gradually he came to understand that he must provide for his own retreat without assistance. He was hardly aware, even now, how greatly he had transcended his usual modes of speech and action, both in the energy of his supplication and in the violence of his rebuke. He had been lifted for awhile out of himself by the excitement of his position, and now that he was subsiding into quiescence, he was unconscious that he had almost mounted into passion,-that he had spoken of love very nearly with eloquence. But he did recognise this as a fact,-that Clara was not to be his wife, and that he had better get back from Belton to London as quickly as possible. It would be well for him to teach himself to look back on the result of his aunt&amp;apos;s dying request as an episode in his life satisfactorily concluded. His mother had undoubtedly been right. Clara, he could now see, would have led him the devil of a life; and even had she come to him possessed of a moiety of the property,-a supposition as to which he had very strong doubts, still she might have been dear at the money. &amp;quot; No real feeling,&amp;quot; he said to himself, as he walked about the room,-&amp;quot; none whatever; and then so deficient in delicacy! &amp;quot; But still he was discontented, because he had been rejected, and therefore tried to make himself believe that he could still have her if he chose to persevere. &amp;quot; But no,&amp;quot; he said, as he continued to pace the room, &amp;quot; I have done everything,-more than everything that honour demands. I shall not ask her again. It is her own fault. She is an imperious woman, and my mother read her character aright.&amp;quot; It did not occur to him, as he thus consoled himself for what he had lost, that his mother&amp;apos;s accusation against Clara had been altogether of a different nature. When we console ourselves by our own arguments, we are not apt to examine their accuracy with much strictness. But whether he were consoled or not, it was necessary that he should go, and in his going he felt himself to be ill-treated. He left the room, and as he went down stairs was disturbed and tormented by the creaking of his own boots. He tried to be dignified as he walked through the hall, and was troubled at his failure, though he was not conscious of any one looking at him. Then it was grievous that he should have to let himself out of the front door without attendance. At ordinary times he thought as little of such things as most men, and would not be aware whether he opened a door for himself or had it opened for him by another;-but now there was a distressing awkwardness in the necessity for self-exertion. He did not know the turn of the handle, and was unfamiliar with the manner of exit. He was being treated with indignity, and before he had escaped from the house had come to think that the Amedroz and Belton people were somewhat below him. He endeavoured to go out without a noise, but there was a slam of the door, without which he could not get the lock to work; and Clara, up in her own room, knew all about it. &amp;quot;Carriage ;-yes; of course I want the carriage,&amp;quot; he said to the unfortunate boy at the public-house. &amp;quot;d Didn&amp;apos;t you hear me say that I wanted it 9 &amp;quot; He had come down with a pair of horses, and as he saw them being put to the vehicle he wished he had been contented with one. As he was standing there, waiting, a gentleman rode by, and the boy, in answer to his question, told him that the horse- man was Colonel Askerton. Before the day was over Colonel Askerton would probably know all that had happened to him. &amp;quot;IDo move a little quicker; will you ? &amp;quot; he said to the boy and the old man who was to drive him. Then he got into the carriage, and was driven out of Belton, devoutly purposing that he never would return; and as he made his way back to Perivale he thought of a certain Lady Emily, who would, as he assured himself, have behaved mnueli better than Clara Amedroz had done in any such scene as that which had just taken place. When Clara was quite sure that Captain Aylmer was off the premises, she, too, descended, but she did not immediately leave the house. She walked through the room, and rang for the old woman, and gave certain directions,-as to the performance of which she certainly was not very anxious, and was careful to make Mrs. Bunce understand that nothing had occurred between her and the gentlemnui that was either exalti ng or depressing in its nature. &amp;quot; I suppose Captain Aylmer went out, Mrs. Bunce 1 &amp;quot; &amp;quot;O h yes, Miss, a&amp;apos; went out. I stood and see&amp;apos;d un from the top of the kitchen stairs.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; YOU might have opened the door for him, Mrs. Bunce.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Indeed then I never thought of it, Miss, seeing the house so empty and the like.&amp;quot; Clara said that it did not signify; and then, after an hour of coniposure, she walked back across the park to the cottage. &amp;quot;Well ?&amp;quot; said Mrs. &amp;apos;Askerton as soon as Clara was inside the drawing-room. &amp;quot;Well,&amp;quot; replied Clara. &amp;quot;What have you got to tell ? )o tell me what vou have to tell.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I have nothing to tell.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Clara, that is impossible. Have you seen him? I know you have seen him, because he went by from the house about an hour since.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh yes; I have seen him.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And what have you said to him ? &amp;quot;Pray do not ask me these questions just now. I have got to think of it all;-to.think what he did say and what I said.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;B But you will tell me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes; I suppose so.&amp;quot; Then Mrs. Askerton was silent on the subject for the remainder of the day, allowing Clara even to go to bed without another question. And nothing was asked on the following morning,-nothing till the usual time for the writing of letters. &amp;quot;Shail you have anything for the post i &amp;quot; said Mrs. Askerton. &amp;quot; There is plenty of time yet.&amp;quot; &amp;apos;&amp;lt;Not too inuchl if volt mean to go out at all. Come, Clara, you had better write to 1 i1; at once.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Write to who-ai :&amp;apos; I don&amp;apos;. know that I have any letter to write at all.&amp;quot; Then there was a pause. &amp;quot; As far as I can see,&amp;quot; she said, &amp;quot; I may give up writing altogether for the future, unless some day you may care to hear from me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But you are not going away.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Not just yet ;-if you will keep me. To tell you the truth, Mrs. Askerton, I do not yet know where on earth to take myself&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos; Wait here till we turn you out.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I&amp;apos;ve got to put my house in order. You know what I mean. The job ought not to be a troublesome one, for it is a very small house.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I suppose I know what you mean.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It will not be a very smart establishment. But I must look it all in the face; mnust I not? Though it were to be no house at all, I cannot stay here all my life.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Yes, you may. You have lost Aylmer Park because you were too noble not to come to us.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No,&amp;quot; said Clara, speaking aloud, with bright eyes,-almost with her hands clenched. &amp;quot; No;-I deny that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I shall choose to think so for my own purposes. Clara, you are savage to me;-ahnost always savage; but next to him I love you better than all the world beside. Xnd so does he. &amp;apos; It&amp;apos;s her courage, he said to me the other day. &amp;apos; That she should dare to do as she pleases here, is nothing; but to have dared to persevere in the fanrs of that old dragon,&amp;apos;-it was just what he said,-&amp;apos; that was wonderful !&amp;apos;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos; There is an end of the old dragon now, as far as I am concerned.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Of course there is ;-and of the young dragon too. You wouldn&amp;apos;t have had the heart to keep me in suspense if you had accepted him a,gain. You couldn&amp;apos;t have been so pleasant last night if that had been so.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I did not know I was very pleasant.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes, you were. You were soft and gracious,-gracious for you, at least. And now, dear, do tell me about it. Of course I am dying to knIow.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;There is nothin, to tell.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That is nonsense. There must be a thousand things to tell. At ativ late, i&amp;apos; is quite decided?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes; it is quite decided.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;All the dragons, old and young, are banished into outer darkness.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Either that, or else they are to have all the light to themselves.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Such light as glinm2rs through the gloom of Aylmer Park. And was he contented&amp;apos;? I hope not. I hope you had him on his knee before he left you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Why should you hope that? How can you talk such nonsense?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Because I wish that he should recognise what he has lost;-that he should know that he has been a fool;-a mean fool.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;M Mrs. Askerton, I will not have him spoken of like that. Ile is a man very estimable,-of excellent qualities.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Fiddle-de-dee. He is an ape,-a monkey to be carried on his mother&amp;apos;s organ. His only good quality was that you could have carried him on yours. I can tell you one thing;-there is not a woman breathing that will ever carry William Belton on hers. Whoever his wife may be, she will have to dance to his piping.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;With all my heart ;-and I hope the tunes will be good.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I wish I could have been present to have heard what passed; -hidden, you know, behind a curtain. You won&amp;apos;t tell me ? &amp;quot;I will tell you not a word more.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Then I will get it out from Mrs. Bunce. I&amp;apos;ll be bound she was listening.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Mrs. Bunce will have nothing to tell you; and I do not know why you should be so curious.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I Answer me one question at least ;-when it came to the last, did he want to go on with it ? Was the final triumph with him or with vout &amp;quot; There was no final triumph. Such things, when they have to end, do not end triumphantly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And is that to be all &amp;apos;? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes ;-that is to be all.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And you say that you have no letter to write.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Nlone ;-no letter; none at present; none about this affair. Captain A!lmer, no doubt, will write to his mother, and then all those who are concerned will have been told.&amp;quot; Clara Amedroz held her purpose and wrote no letter, but frs. Askerton was not so discreet, or so indiscreet, as the case might be. She did write,-not on that day or on the next, but before a week had passed by. She wrote to Norfolk, telling Clara not a word of her letter, and by return of post the answer came. But the answer was for Clara, not for Mrs. Askerton, and was as follows: &amp;quot;1Plaistow Hall, Aril, 186-. &amp;quot;M D)EAR CLARA, &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know whether I ought to tell you, but I suppose I may as well tell you, that Mary has had a letter from Mrs. Askerton. It was a kind, obliging letter, and I am very grateful to her. She has told us that you have separated yourself altogether from the Aylmer Park people. I don&amp;apos;t suppose you&amp;apos;ll think I ought to pretend to be very sorry. I can&amp;apos;t be sorry, even though I know how much you have lost in a worldly point of view. I could not bring myself to like Captain Ayhner, though I tried hard.&amp;quot; [Oh, Mr. Belton, Mr. Belton!] &amp;quot; He and I never could have been friends, and it is no use my pretending regret that you have quarrelled with them. But that, I suppose, is all over, and I will not say a word more about the Aylmers. &amp;quot;I am writing now chiefly at Mary&amp;apos;s advice, and because she says that something should be settled about the estate. Of course it is necessary that you should feel yourself to be the mistress of your own income, and understand exactly your own position. Marv says that this should be arranged at once, so that you may be able to decide how and where you will live. I therefore write to say that I will have nothing to do with your father&amp;apos;s estate at Belton;-nothing, that is, for myself. I have written to Mr. Green to tell him that you are to be considered as the heir. If you will allow me to undertake the management of the property as your agent, I shall be delighted. I think I could do it as well as any one else; and, as we agreed that we would always be dear and close friends, I think that you will not refuse me the pleasure of serving you in this way. &amp;quot;And now Mary has a proposition to make, as to which she wtill write herself to-morrow, but she has. permitted me to speak of it first. If you will accept her as a visitor, she will go to you at Belton. She thinks, and I think too, that you ought to know each other. I suppose nothing would make you come here,-at present, and therefore she must go to you. She thinks that all about the estate would be settled more comfortably if you two were together. At any rate, it would be very nice for her,-and I think you would like my sister Mary. She proposes to start about the 10th of May. I should take her as far as London and see her off; and she would bring her own mnaid with her. In this way she thinks that she would get as far as Taiunton very well. She had, perhaps, better stay there for one night, but that can all be settled if you will say that you will receive her at the house. I cannot finish my letter without saying one word for myself. You know what my feelings have been, and I think you know that they still are, and always must be, the same. From almost the first moment that I saw you I have loved you. When you refused me I was very unhappy; but I thought I might still have a chance, and therefore I resolved to try again. Then, when I heard that you were engaged to Captain Aylmer, I was indeed broken-hearted. Of course I could not be angry with you. I was not angry, but I was simply broken-hearted. I found that I loved you so much that I could not make myself happy without you. It was all of no use, for I knew that you were to be married to Captain Aylmer. I knew it, or thought that I knew it. There was nothing to be done,-only I knew that I was wretched. I suppose it is selfishness, but I felt, and still feel, that unless I can have you for my wife, I cannot be happy or care for anything. Now you are free again,-free, I mean, from Captain AEliner ;-and how is it possible that I should not again have a hope? Nothing but your marriage or death could keep me from hoping. &amp;quot; I don&amp;apos;t know much about the Ayhners. I know nothing of what has made you quarrel with the people at Aylmer Park ;-nor do I want to know. To me you are once more that Clara Amedroz with whom I used to walk in Belton Park, with your hand free to be given wherever your heart can go with it. While it is free I shall always ask for it. I know that it is in many ways above my reach. I quite understand that in education and habits of thinking you are my superior. But nobody can love you better than I do. I sometimes fancy that nobody could ever love you so well. Mary thinks that I ought to allow a time to go by before I say all this again ;-but what is the use of keeping it back? It seems to me to be more honest to tell you at once that the only thing in the world for which I care one straw is that you should be my wife. &amp;quot;Your most affectionate cousin, &amp;quot;WILLIAMn BELTOXN.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Miss Belton is coming here, to the castle, in about a fortnight,&amp;quot; said Clara that morning at breakfast. Both Colonel Askerton and his wife were in the room, and she was addressing herself chiefly to the former. &amp;quot; Indeed. Miss Belton! And is he coming ?&amp;quot; said Colonel Askerton. II So you have heard from Plaistow ? &amp;quot; said Mrs. Askerton. &amp;quot;Yes -in answer to your letter. No, Colonel Askerton, my cousin William is not coming. But his sister purposes to be here, and I must go up to the house and get it ready.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That will do when the time comes,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Askerton. &amp;quot;I did not mean quite immediately.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And are you to be her guest, or is she to be yours ? &amp;quot; said Colonel Askerton. &amp;quot; It is her brother&amp;apos;s home, and therefore I suppose I must be hers. Indeed it must be so, as I have no means of entertaining any one.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Something, no doubt, will be settled,&amp;quot; said the Colonel. &amp;quot;Oh, what a weary word that is,&amp;quot; said Clara; &amp;quot;weary, at least, for a woman&amp;apos;s ears! It sounds of poverty and dependence, and endless trouble given to others, and all the miseries of female dependence. If I were a young man I should be allowed to settle for myself.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; There would be no question about the property in that case,&amp;quot; said the Colonel. &amp;quot; And there need be no question now,&amp;quot; said. Mrs. Askerton. WVhen the two women were alone together, Clara, of course, scolded her friend for having written to Norfolk without letting it be known that she was doing so ;-scolded her, and declared how vain it was for her to make useless efforts for an unattainable end; but Mrs. Askerton always managed to slip out of these reproaches, neither asserting herself to be right, nor owning herself to be wrong. &amp;quot;But vou must answer his letter,&amp;quot; she said. Of course I shall do that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I wish I knew what he said.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I shan&amp;apos;t show it you, if you mean that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;All the same I wish I knew what he said.&amp;quot; Clara, of course, did answer the letter; but she wrote her answer to Mary, sending, however, one little scrap to Mary&amp;apos;s brother. She wrote to Mary at great length, striving to explain, with long and laborious arguments, that it was quite impossible that she should accept the Belton estate from her cousin. That subject, however, and the manner of her future life, she would discuss with her dear cousin Mary, when Marv should have arrived. And then Clara said how she would go to Taunton to meet her cousin, and how she would prepare William&amp;apos;s house for the reception of William&amp;apos;s sister; and how she would love her cousin when she should come to know her. All of which was exceedingly proper and pretty. Then there was a little postscript, &amp;quot;n Give the enclosed to William.&amp;quot; And this was the note to William: &amp;quot;DEAR WILLIAM, &amp;quot; Did you not say that you would be my brother? Be my brother always. I will accept from your hands all that a brother could do; and when that arrangement is quite fixed I will love you as much as Mary loves you, and trust you as completely; and I will be obedient, as a younger sister should be. &amp;quot;Your loving sister, C. A.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s all no good,&amp;quot; said William Belton, as he crunched the note in his hand. &amp;quot; I might as well shoot myself. Get out of the way there, will you? &amp;quot; And the injured groom scudded across the farmyard, knowing that there was something wrong with his master. CHAPTER XXX. M1ARY BELTON. IT was about the middle of the pleasant month of May when Clara Anmedroz again made that often repeated journey to Taunton with the object of meeting Mary Belton. She had transferred herself and her own peculiar belongings back from the cottage to the house, and had again established herself there so that she might welcome her new friend. But she was not satisfied with simply receiving her guest at Belton, and therefore she made the journey to Taunton, and settled herself for the night at the inn. She was careful to get a bed-room for an &amp;quot; invalid lady,&amp;quot; close to the sitting-room, and before she went down to the station she saw that the cloth was laid for tea, and that the tea parlour had been made to look as pleasant as was possible with an inn parlour. She was very nervous as she stood upon the platform waiting for the new-comer to show herself. She knew that Mary was a cripple, but did not know how far her cousin was disfigured by her infirmity; and when she saw a pale-faced little woman, somewhat melancholy, but yet pretty withal, with soft, clear eyes, and only so much appearance of a stoop as to soften the hearts of those who saw her, Clara was agreeably surprised, and felt herself to be suddenly relieved of an unpleasant weight. She could talk to the woman she saw there, as to any other woman, without the painful necessity of treating her always as an invalid. &amp;quot; I think you are Miss Belton?&amp;quot; she said, holding out her hand. The likeness between Mary and her brother was too great to allow of Clara being mistaken. &amp;quot;A And you are Clara Amedroz ? It is so good of you to come to meet me! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I thought you would be dull in a strange town by yourself.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It will be much nicer to have you with me.&amp;quot; Then they went together up to the inn; and when they had taken their bonnets off, Mary Belton kissed her cousin. &amp;quot;You are very nearly what I fancied you,&amp;quot; said Mary. &amp;quot; Am I ? I hope you fancied me to be something that you could like.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Something that I could love very dearly. You are a little taller than what Will said; but then a gentleman is never a judge of a lady&amp;apos;s height. And he said you were thin.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I am not very fat.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No; not very fat; but neither are you thin. Of course, you know, I have thought a great deal about you. It seems as though you had come to be so very near to us; and blood is thicker than water, is it not ? If cousins are not friends, who can be ?&amp;quot; In the course of that evening they became very confidential together, and Clara thought that she could love Mary Belton better than any woman that she had ever known. Of course they were talking about William, and Clara was at first in constant fear lest some word should be said on her lover&amp;apos;s behalf,-some word which would drive her to declare that she would not admit him as a lover; but Mary abstained from the subject with marvellous care and tact. Though she was talking through the whole evening of her brother, she so spoke of him as almost to make Clara believe that she could not have heard of that episode in his life. Mrs. Askerton would have dashed at the subject at once; but then, as Clara told herself, Mary Belton was better than Mrs. Askerton. A few words were said about the estate, and they originated in Clara&amp;apos;s declaration that Mary would have to be regarded as the mistress of the house to which they were going. &amp;quot; I cannot agree to that,&amp;quot; said Mary. &amp;quot;But the house is William&amp;apos;s, you know,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;He says not.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But of course that must be nonsense, Marv,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It is very evident that you know nothing of Plaistow ways, or you would not say that anything coming from William was nonsense. We are accustomed to regard all his words as law, and when he says that a thing is to be so, it always is so.&amp;quot; Then he is a tyrant at home.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;A beneficent despot. Some despots, you know, always were beneficent.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;He won&amp;apos;t have his way in this thing.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ll leave you and him to fight about that, my dear. I am so completely under his thumb that I always obey him in everything. You must not, therefore, expect to range me on your side.&amp;quot; The next day they were at Belton Castle, and in a very few hours Clara felt that she was quite at home with her cousin. On the second day Mrs. Askerton came up and called,-according to an arrangement to that effect made between her and Clara. As I&amp;apos;ll stay away if you like it,&amp;quot; Mrs. Askerton had said. But Clara had urged her to come, arguing with her that she was foolish to be thinking always of her own misfortune. &amp;quot; Of course I am always thinking of it,&amp;quot; she had replied, &amp;quot;and always thinking that other people are thinking of it. Your cousin, Miss Belton, knows all my history of course. But what matters? I believe it would be better that everybody should know it. I suppose she&amp;apos;s very straight-laced and prim.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;She is not prim at all,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;1Well, I&amp;apos;ll come,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Askerton, &amp;quot;d but I shall not be a bit surprised if I hear that she goes back to Norfolk the next day.&amp;quot; So Mrs. Askerton came, and Miss Belton did not go back to Norfolk. Indeed, at the end of the visit, Mrs. Askerton had almost taught herself to believe that William Belton had kept her secret, even from his sister. &amp;quot;She&amp;apos;s a dear little woman,&amp;quot; Mrs. Askerton afterwards said to Clara. &amp;quot;Is she not ? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;And so thoroughly like a lady.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes; I think she is a lady.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;A princess among ladies! What a pretty little conscious way she has of asserting herself when she has an opinion and means to stick to it! I never saw a woman who got more strength out of her weakness. Who would dare to contradict her ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But then she knows everything so well,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;And how like her brother she is! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes;-there is a great family likeness.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And in character, too. I&amp;apos;m sure you&amp;apos;d find, if you were to try her, that she has all his personal firmness, though she can&amp;apos;t show it as he does by kicking out his feet and clenching his fist.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;m glad you like her,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;I do like her very much.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It is so odd,-the way you have changed. You used to speak of him as though he was merely a clod of a farmer, and of her as a stupid old maid. Now, nothing is too good to say of them.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Exactly, my dear;-and if you do not understand why, you are not so clever as I take you to be.&amp;quot; Life went on very pleasantly with them at Belton for two or three weeks ;-but with this drawback as regarded Clara, that she had no means of knowing what was to be the course of her future life. During these weeks she twice received letters from her cousin Will, and answered both of them. But these letters referred to matters of business which entailed no contradiction,-to certain details of money due to the estate before the old squire&amp;apos;s death, and to that vexed question of Aunt Winterfield&amp;apos;s legacy, which had by this time drifted into Belton&amp;apos;s hands, and as to which he was inclined to act in accordance with his cousin&amp;apos;s wishes, though he was assured by Mr. Green that the legacy was as good a legacy as had ever been left by an old woman. &amp;quot; I think,&amp;quot; he said in his last letter, &amp;quot;1 that we shall be able to throw him over in spite of Mr. Green.&amp;quot; Clara, as she read this, could not but remember that the man to be thrown over was the man to whom she had been engaged, and she could not but remember also all the circumstances of the intended legacy,-of her aunt&amp;apos;s death, and of the scenes which had immediately followed her death. It was so odd that William Belton should now be discussing with her the means of evading all her aunt&amp;apos;s intentions,-and that he should be doing so, not as her accepted lover. He had, indeed, called himself her brother, but he was in truth her rejected lover. From time to time during these weeks Mrs. Askerton would ask her whether Mr. Belton was coming to Belton, and Clara would answer her with perfect truth that she did not believe that he had any such intention. &amp;quot;But he must come soon,&amp;quot; Mrs. Askerton would sa-. And when Clara would answer that she knew nothing about it, Mrs. Askerton would ask further questions about Mary Belton. &amp;quot; Your cousin must know whether her brother is coming to look after the property ? &amp;quot; But Miss Belton, though she heard constantly from her brother, gave no such intimation. If he had any intention of coming, she did not speak of it. During all these days she had not as yet said a word of her brother&amp;apos;s love. Though his name was daily in her mouth,-and latterly, was frequently mentioned by Clara,-there had been no allusion to that still enduring hope of which Will Belton himself could not but speak,-when he had any opportunity of speaking at all. And this continued till at last Clara was driven to suppose that Mary Belton knew nothing of her brother&amp;apos;s hopes. But at last there came a change,-a change which to Clara was as great as that which had affected her when she first found that her delightful cousin was not safe against love-making. She had made up her mind that the sister did not intend to plead for her brother, that the sister probably knew nothing of the brother&amp;apos;s necessity for pleading,-that the brother probably had no further need for pleading,! When she remembered his last passionate words, she could not but accuse herself of hypocrisy when she allowed place in her thoughts to this latter supposition. He had been so intently earnest ! The nature of the man was so eager and true ! But yet, in spite of all that had been said, of all the fire in his eves, and life in his words, and energy in his actions, he had at last seen that his aspirations were foolish, and his desires vain. It could not otherwise be that she and Mary should pass these hours in such calm repose without an allusion to the disturbing subject! After this fashion, and with such meditations as these, had passed by the last weeks ;-and then at last there came the change. &amp;quot;I have had a letter from William this morning,&amp;quot; said Mary. &amp;quot;And so have not I,&amp;quot; said Clara, &amp;quot;and yet I expected to hear from him.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He means to be here soon,&amp;quot; said Mary. &amp;quot; Oh, indeed! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; He speaks of being here next week.&amp;quot; For a moment or two Clara had yielded to the agitation caused by her cousin&amp;apos;s tidings; but with a little gush she recovered her presence of mind, and was able to speak with all the hypocritical propriety of a female. &amp;quot; I am glad to hear it,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot; It is only right that he should come.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;i Ie has asked me to say a word to you,-as to the purport of his journey.&amp;quot; Then again Clara&amp;apos;s courage and hypocrisy were so far subdued that they were not able to maintain her in a position adequate to the occasion. &amp;quot; lVell,&amp;quot; she said, laughing, &amp;quot; what is the word ? I hope it is not that I am to pack up, bag and baggage, and take myself elsewhere. Cousin William is one of those persons who are willing to do everything except what they are wanted to do. He will go on talking about the Belton Estate, when I want to know whether I may really look for as much as twelve shillings a week to live upon.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He wants me to speak to you about-about the earnest love he bears for you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Oh dear, Mary !-could you not suppose it all to be said? It is an old trouble, and need not be repeated.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; No,&amp;quot; said Mary, &amp;quot; I cannot suppose it to be all said.&amp;quot; Clara looking up as she heard the voice, was astonished both by the fire in the woman&amp;apos;s eye and by. the force of her tone. &amp;quot; I will not think so meanly of you as to believe that such words from such a man can be passed by as meaning nothing. I will not say that you ought to be able to love him; in that you cannot control your heart; but if you cannot love him, the want of such love ought to make you suffer,to suffer much and be very sad.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I cannot agree to that, Mary.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Is all his life nothing, then ? Do you know what love means with him ;-this love which he bears to you? Do you understand that it is everything to him ?-that from the first moment in which he acknowledged to himself that his heart was set upon you, he could not bring himself to set it upon any other thing for a moment? Perhaps you have never understood this; have never perceived that he is so much in earnest, that to him it is more than money, or land, or health,-more than life itself ;-that he so loves that he would willingly give everything that he has for his love? Have you known this ? &amp;quot; Clara would not answer these questions for awhile. What if she had known it all, was she therefore bound to sacrifice herself ? Could it be the duty of any woman to give herself to a man simply because a man wanted her ? That was the argument as it was put forwaid now by Mary Belton. &amp;quot; Dear, dearest Clara,&amp;quot; said Mary Belton, stretching herself forward from her chair, and putting out her thin, almost transparent, hand, &amp;quot; I do not think that you have thought enough of this; or, perhaps, you have not known it. But his love for you is as I say. To him it is everything. It pervades every hour of every day, every comer in his life ! He knows nothing of anything else while he is in his present state.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;lIe is very good ;-more than good.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;lie is very good.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I do not see that ;-that-- Of course I know how disinterested he is.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I Disinterested is a poor word. It insinuates that in such a matter there could be a question of what people call interest.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And I know, too, how much he honours me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Honour is a cold word. It is not honour, but love,-downright true, honest love. I hope he does honour you. I believe you to be an honest, true woman; and, as he knows you well, he probably does honour you;-but I am speaking of love.&amp;quot; Again Clara was silent. She knew what should be her argument if she were determined to oppose her cousin&amp;apos;s pleadings; and she knew also,--she thought she knew,-that she did intend to oppose them; but there was a coldness in the argument to which she was averse. &amp;quot;You cannot be insensible to such love as that ! &amp;quot; said Mari-, going on with the cause which she had in hand. &amp;quot;You say that he is fond of me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Fond of you! I have not used such trifling expressions as that.&amp;quot; That he loves me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You know he loves you. Have you ever doubted a word that he has spoken to you on any subject?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I believe he speaks truly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You know he speaks truly. He is the very soul of truth.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But, Mary &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well, Clara! But remember; do not answer me lightly. Do not play with a man&amp;apos;s heart because you have it in your power.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You wrong me. I could never do like that. You tell me that he loves me;-but what if I do not love him? Love will not be constrained. Am I to say that I love him because I believe that he loves me ? &amp;quot; This was the argument, and Clara found herself driven to use it,-not so much from its special applicability to herself, as on account of its general fitness. Whether it did or did not apply to herself she had not time to ask herself at that moment; but she felt that no man could have a right to claim a woman&amp;apos;s hand on the strength of his own love,-unless he had been able to win her love. She was arguing on behalf of women in general rather than on her own behalf. &amp;quot; If you mean to tell me that you cannot love him, of course I must give over,&amp;quot; said Mary, not caring at all for men and women in general, but full of anxiety for her brother. &amp;quot; Do you mean to say that,-that you can never love him?&amp;quot; It almost seemed, from her face, that she was determined utterly to quarrel with her new- found cousin,-to quarrel and to go at once away if she got an answer that would not please her. &amp;quot;Dear Mary, do not press me so hard.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I want to press you hard. It is not right that he should lose his life in longing and hoping.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ile will not lose his life, Mary.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I hope not;-not if I can help it. I trust that he will be strong enough to get rid of his trouble,-to put it down and trample it under his feet.&amp;quot; Clara, as she heard this, began to ask herself what it awas that was to be trampled under Will&amp;apos;s feet. &amp;quot; I think he will be man enough to overcome his passion; and then, perhaps, -you may regret what you have lost.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Now you arc unkind to me.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well; what would you havec me say? Do I not know. that he is offering you the best gift that he can give? Did I not begin by swearing to you that he loved you with a passion of love that cannot but be flattering to you? If it .is to be love in vain, this to him is a great misfortune. And, yet, when I say that I hope that he Aw-ill recover, you tell me that I am unkind.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No;-not for that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;May I tell him to come and plead for himself ?&amp;quot; Again Clara was silent, not knowing how to answer that last question. And wvhen she did answer it, she answered it thoughtlessly. &amp;quot; Of course he knows that he can do that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Ile says that he has been forbidden.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, Mary, what am I to say to you? You know it all, and I vwonder that you can continue to question me in this way.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Knew all what &amp;apos;P &amp;quot; &amp;quot;That I have been engaged to Captain Aylmer.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But you are not engaged to him now.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No-I am not.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And there can be no renewal there, I suppcse ?&amp;quot; Oh, no! &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Not even for my brother would I say a word if I thought-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No ;-there is nothing of that; but-. If you cannot understand, I do not think that I can explain it.&amp;quot; It seemed to Clara that her cousin, in her anxiety for her brother, did not conceive that a woman, even if she could suddenly transfer her affection from one man to another, could not bring herself to say that she had done so. &amp;quot;I must write to him to-day,&amp;quot; said Mary, &amp;quot;d and I must give him soine answer. Shall I tell him that he had better not come here till you are gone?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;That will perhaps be best,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;Then lie will never come at all.&amp;quot; Ican go;-can go at once. I will go at once. You shall never have to say that my presence prevented his coming to his own house. I ought not to be here. I know it now. I will go away, and you may tell him that I am gone.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;No, dear; you will not go.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;1 Yes ;-I must go. I fancied things might be otherwise, because he once told me that-he-would-be-a brother to me. And I said I would hold him to that ;-not only because I want a brother so badtly, but because I love him so dearly. But it cannot be like that.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You do not think that he will ever desert you ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I will go away, so that he may come to his own house. I ought not to be here. (Of course I ought not to be at Belton,-either in this house or in any other. Tell him that I will be gone before he can cbme, and tell himn also that I will not be too proud to accept from him what it may be fit that he should give me. I have no one but him;-no one but him;-no one but him.&amp;quot; Then she burst into tears, and, throwing back her head, covered her face with her hands. Miss Belton, upon this, rose slowly from the chair on which she vwas sitting, and making her way painfully across to Clara, stood leanincg on the weeping girl&amp;apos;s chair. &amp;quot;TYou shall not go wvhile I am here,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;Yes; I must go. Ile cannot come till I am gone.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Think of it all once again, Clara. May I not tell him to come, an&amp;apos; that while he is coming you will see if you cannot soften your heart towards him ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Soften my heart! Oh, if I could only harden it!&amp;quot; &amp;quot; He would wait. If you would only bid him wait, he would be so happy in waiting.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yes;-till to-morrow morning. I know him. Hold out your little finger to him, and he has your whole hand and arm in ; molnent.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I want you to say that you will try to love him.&amp;quot; But Clara was in truth trying not to love him. She was ashamed of herself because she did love the one man, when, but a few weeks since, she had confessed that she loved another. She had mistaken herself and her own feelings, not in reference to her cousin, but in supposing that she could really have sympathised with such a man as Captain Aylmer. It was necessary to her self-respect that she should be punished because of that mistake. She could not save herself from this condemnation,-she would not grant herself a respite,-because, by doing so, she would make another person happy. Had Captain Ayhnier never crossed her path, she would have given her whole heart to her cousin. Nay; she had so given it,-had done so, although Captain Aylmer had crossed her path and come in her way. But it was matter of shame to her to find that this had been possible, and she could not bring herself to confess her shame. The conversation at last ended, as such conversations always do end, without any positive decision. Mary wrote of course to her brother, but Clara was not told of the contents of the letter. We, however, may know them, and may understand their nature, without learning above two lines of the letter. &amp;quot;If you can be content to wait awhile, you will succeed,&amp;quot; said Mary; &amp;quot; but when were you ever content to wait for anything?&amp;quot; &amp;quot; If there is anything I hate, it is waiting,&amp;quot; said Will, when he received the letter; nevertheless the letter made him happy, and he went about his farm with a sanguine heart, as he arranged matters for another absence. &amp;quot; Awav long ?&amp;quot; he said, in answer to a question asked him by his head man; &amp;quot;how onl earth can I say how long I shall be away ? You can go on well eniou gh without me by this time, I should think. You will have to learn, for there is no knowing how often I may be away, or for how lolln.&amp;quot; When 3Mary said that the letter had been written, Clara again spoke about going. &amp;quot; And where will you go ?&amp;quot; said Mary. &amp;quot;I will take a lodging in Taunton.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;He would only follow you there, and there would be more trouble. That would be all. Ile must act as your guardian, and in that capacity, at any rate, you must submit to him.&amp;quot; Clara, therefore, consented to remain at Belton; but, before Will arrived, she returned from the house to the cottage. &amp;quot;O Of course I understand all about it,&amp;quot; said Mrs. Askerton; &amp;quot; and let me tell vou this,-that if it is not all settled within a week from his coming here, I shall think that you are without a heart. Ile is to be knocked about, and cuffed, and kept from his work, and made to run up and down between here and Norfolk, because you cannot bring yourself to confess that you have been a fool.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I have never said that I have not been a fool,&amp;quot; said Clara. &amp;quot;You have made a mistake,-as young women will do sometimes, even when they are as prudent and circumspect as you are,-and now you don&amp;apos;t quite like the task of putting it right.&amp;quot; It was all true, and Clara knew that it was true. The putting right of mistakes is never pleasant ; and in this case it was so unpleasant that she could not bring herself to acknowledge that it must be done. And yet, I think, that by.this time, she was aware of the necessity. ANTHONY TRIOLLOPE.</FullText></Record>