<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2464576</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130923</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>ON SOME DISPUTED POINTS IN MUSIC.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>115</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Jul 1876</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18760701</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Gurney</LastName><FirstName>Edmund</FirstName><PersonName>Edmund Gurney</PersonName><OriginalForm>GURNEY, EDMUND</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Gurney</LastName><FirstName>Edmund</FirstName><PersonName>Edmund Gurney</PersonName><OriginalForm>Gurney, Edmund</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>106</StartPage><EndPage>130</EndPage><Pagination>106-130</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2464576/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>ON SOME DISPUTED POINTS IN MUSIC.&amp;apos; FEW subjects in the present day are more widely discussed than music: no subject, if I may trust my own experience, less admits of profitable discussion. The fact that a musical work cannot well be talked about during its performance, and is not as a rule reproducible at pleasure, is one initial difficulty. Again, an ordinary person possessing a fair appreciation of both music and painting is generally more at home with the terms liqAt 8/ade and colotro than with synpcopatiou and moduldatioit; a knowledge of the simpler technicalities of music being for the most part confined to the small minority which forms the medium between the creative artist and his public. It follows that in general society musical talk almost always sinks into that most barren and wearisome region, the discussion of the merits or demerits of different executants and virtuosi. iBut even where it is easy to recall the exact points on which stress is to be laid, and where each person has command of the technical materials necessary for discussion and is anxious to appreciate the other&amp;apos;s ideas, I have too often found that differences of opinion on this subject are mutually irritating rather than mutually instructive: nor is the creative artist, who in his attempt to theorise suffers fiom2 &amp;quot; the sad conviction that he will after all probably be understood by those only who already share his own artistic views,&amp;quot; by any means the only person so troubled. I believe that this peculiarity of musical discussions is bound up with the very nature of the art. The other arts, however indescribable and incommunicable be their subtler beauties, yet having to do with external facts and ideas can be discussed from many external points of view and confronted with external realities. Music is peculiar in that, just as it is manifested through the individual organism in independence of external phenomena, so are its ideas (not indefinite or subjective but) isolated and independent; and its position in this respect may perhaps be made clearer by a brief examination of its origin and of the different ways in which it is applied and apprehended. Such an examination may have some interest for those who have no par/i pris on the subject: and though the very isolation I have mentioned is one of the points in dispute, and it will be clear from (1) I find here and there in this paper a curious correspondence with parts of an article on Wagner in the Edinaurgsh Reriew for January, 1876. As it is in favour of any view that it should have occurred independently to different people, I may mention that my paper was written last year, before I had seen the article in question. (2) I quote here and elsewhere Dannreuther&amp;apos;s translation of a most interesting letter of Wagner to 1. Villot. what I have said that I have no hope of convincing those who differ from me, there is at all events some advantage in recognising where differences become fundamental, if on such recognition a plea for toleration can be at all successfully founded. What is the origin of music? why does it affect us? to what uses can its different forms be put? what is its future? what is good and what is bad music :? and by what criterion are we to judge it ? all these are questions on which opinion is divided, and the answers to which are mutually interdependent. To begin then at the beginning, what is the origin of a sense of music ? M1r. Darwin gives many instance-s tending to prove that the vocal organs and means of producing sounds possessed by animals were primarily used and perfected ill relation to the propagation of the species; and considers that &amp;quot;musical notes and rhythm &amp;quot; (that is musical notes and the habit of using them in rhythm) &amp;quot;ewere first acquired by the male or femnale progenitors of mankind for the sake of charming the opposite sex.&amp;quot; We might still inquire why the opposite sex was charmed, and how far the pleasure in its early stages can be analysed. M1r. Herbert Spencer on the other hand has written an ingenious essay in which he derives the sense of music from the cadences of emotional speech: and as there are certain current musical opinions which might find some support in this view, it will be well briefly to examine it. Mr. Spencer founds his theory on the view that the vocal peculiarities which indicate excited feeling are those which especially distinguish song from ordinary speech, and sums them up under the heads of loudness, timbre or quality pitch, intervals, and rate of variation. He considers that song arose from emphasising and intensifying these peculiarities. On not one of these heads does he seem to me to succeed in making out his case. The first, loudness, is perhaps the most plausible; but loudness though a frequent is by no means a universal or essential element, either of song or of emo tional speech. Still less is musical resonance an essential element of the latter. Many of the tones of excited speech are even more removed from music than those of ordinary speech, as containing a greater number of the high harmonics which produce what we call harshness: and this must have been especially the case among our remote ancestors when the savage emotions were in the ascendant. Even if we take the residue of tones expressing pleasing emotions and having increased resonance of an agreeable kind, and if we accept Mlr. Spencer&amp;apos;s view of such emotional speech as being prior to music, the fact remains that agreeable sounds are only the material of music; and it is open to us to suppose that our human or semihuman ancestors, having been naturally moved by physiological causes to desert the re-ion of neutral tones in order to be pleasingly emphatic, may have utilised for independent musical purposes the material of increased resonance so discovered and developed, in accordance with the well-known fact that &amp;quot; organs originally adapted for one purpose have been utilised for some quite distinct purpose.&amp;quot; It is of course equally open to us, if we accept Mr. Darwin&amp;apos;s hypothesis that the power of making musical sounds was acquired for sexual purposes in the semi-human stage, to suppose that the more resonant sounds, first developed in this elementary love-music and rendered emphatic by the accompanying pleasure, were subsequently employed where emphasis was required for purposes of emotional speech. And, looked at in the light merely of musical material, I can hardly imagine that certain vocal tones are regarded by Mr. Spencer as oiling their agreeable quality simply to association with kindness and pleasing emotions. Yet he says, as though it were a rleductio a(d a(thou-rdu hi, that if the conclusiveness of his reasoning is not admitted, it must be supposed that vibrations causing soft sounds are intrinsically better than those causing harsh. Why of course they are intrinsically better as far as our ears are concerned, in precisely the same way as an octave is intrinsically a more agreeable chord than a sharp seventh, or a feather-bed a more agreeable couch than a heap of stones. The ear objects to the irregularities produced by the discordant harmonics present in harsh sounds just as the body objects to the contact of hard irregular surfaces. In dealing with the three remaining heads of what he considers common characteristics of emotional speech and song, Mr. Spencer seems to me to state as regards song the exact opposite of the truth. In the recitative which he himself considers naturally and historically a step between speech and song, the rapid variation of pitch is impossible, and such recitative is distinguished from the tones even of common speech precisely by being more monotonous. Mr. Spencer notices the monotony of savage dance-songs and ancient Eastern chants, and says that hence we may infer the divergence of vocal music from emotional speech to have been gradual and unobtrusive. Surely a theory of the unobtrusive divergence of one thing from another is somewhat bold, when they present in their earliest stages exactly opposite characteristics. Even in perfectly developed vocal melody large intervals and extremes and rapid variations of pitch are in a very small minority as compared with their opposites. If musical composers had begun by expressing their feelings in more extreme intervals than those of speech, and had gone on, as Mr. Spencer supposes, increasing this peculiarity, why is a semitone often the keytone of a melodic passage, and how is it that a vast number of the most emotional melodies proceed almost entirely by very small degrees ? I need only mention the allegretto in Beethoven&amp;apos;s seventh symphony. In modern music, which has the assistance of harmony, the most exciting melodic passage may even consist of mere monotone. There are few things in music more passionate than some bars in Schubert&amp;apos;s &amp;quot; Addio,&amp;quot; where the voice repeats the same note sixteen times, and the expression is given altogether by the rhythm and harmony. On the other hand any one may convince himself that not only are the intervals used in emotional speech very large, twelve diatonic notes being quite an ordinary skip, but that he uses extremes of both high and low pitch with his speaking voice, which, if he tries to dwell on them and make them resonant, will be found to lie beyond the compass of his singing voice. In saying &amp;quot;I never heard of such a thin-&amp;quot; in a tone of strong excitement, I find that I use the high tenor B for the word I, a note far above any that I can sing, and go down for never to something between G and E, which is the extreme of what I can sing in that direction. There are certain effects in emotional speech which do really play a very important part in a large number of musical effects, those namely which depend on pace and motion. But these must in both cases be referred back to an elementary sense of force or effort. Helmholtz derives the power of music to represent emotion from its resemblance to motion in space and its consequent power to adumbrate the forces which lie at the root of motion. He adds that he does not consider this explanation as opposed to the development (which he confines, however, to the very earliest stages) from the instinctive modulations of speech, because the rhythm of such modulations is often an expression of the corresponding psychical motive, and effort drives the voice up; but this is surely rather to find a common ground for the two phenomena in the one fundamental sense of force than to trace one from the other. When he goes on to give as another reason for considering the two derivations compatible that the desire to please causes the selection of a more agrecable timbre of voice, I cannot follow him, as I can trace no connection between quality of tone and force or motion. It may indeed be doubted whether mere timbre can express emotion of any kind. If we consider the cases where it seems to do so, we shall find that it is the pace or the manner of beginning the note, or something else beyond its mere quality, which gives it its emotional character. For instance, when we speak of the plaintive sounds of a violin, we are thinking of slow long-drawn-out notes, taken very gently without percussion or anything to give them a strongly-marked catch at the beginning. Nor would it occur to us to call sound of the same quality plaintive if instead of being divided into these long gentle notes it went on continuously, or if it were divided into short notes begun with more sharpness and suddenness. As regards pace and motion the converse of IHelmholtz&amp;apos;s explanation will equally hold; slow motion, if sufficiently regular to arrest the attention, will induce the opposite emotions to those connected with force and effort, and will give an impression of relaxation which will tend to be of a subdued and mournful character. It would lead us too far to consider the various esthetic effects of various motions or metres; but it will be convenient before proceeding farther with our examination of Mr. Spencer&amp;apos;s theory, to make some general remarks on rhythm, that all-important element of melody which distinguishes it alike from emotional and unemotional speech. Strict rhythm in its simplest form may be described as the production of a sound or movement, or of a small group of sounds or movements, at equal intervals of time. I say small group, because the most highly developed sense of rhythm that we know of can take in no more. If the group of sounds or movements to be repeated is too large, it will be impossible to grasp and retain it as a whole and to feel a vivid longing for its recurrence at a particular instant, and so the pleasure of rhythm, which must result from the satisfaction of an expectation, cannot exist. It follows that the mere repetition of a particular strain as in a bird&amp;apos;s song, even were it perfectly regular, might convey no strictly rhythmical impression to a human ear; as the interval of time before each recurrence might be too long for the memory accurately to measure, and an expectation can only be founded on accurate measurement. The length of the bars in a piece of music, being a constant standard, makes possible by the wide range of its subdivisions the immense variety of musical feet with their endless combinations.&amp;apos; Now no one can suppose that the sense of rhythm can be derived from emotional speech. Rhythm indeed of a kind may be found, as Mr. Spencer remarks, in the highest efforts of an orator; but he would allow that this rhythmical prose is the result of a late and very loose adaptation of the sense of balance and proportion found so pleasurable in the stricter rhythm of music and poetry, and that the utterances of our savage ancestors cannot have been delivered in prose of such a kind. Mr. Spencer himself admits that &amp;quot;&amp;apos; why the actions excited by strong feeling should tend to become rhythmical is not very obvious.&amp;quot; 2 It is equally difficult to decide where the sense of rhythm begins. Mr. Darwin remarks that &amp;quot;the perception, if not the enjoyment, of musical cadences and of rhythm, is probably common to all animals,&amp;quot; and mentions that in the case of insects and (1) It is worth noticing that in poetry, where the ear (as in rhythmical prose) accepts any sort of formal suppoit and assistance with gratitude, as being more than it is accustomed to when taking in the meaning of words, the lines or bars may be of various lengths, and may give a quite irregular or extremely complicated outline, while thefeet, owing to the nature of language, are comparatively few and simple. (2) He gives as instances the swaving of the body to and fro under pain or grief, and of the leg under impatience or agitation, both instances of rhythmical movement under some spiders the sounds made by the male to charm the female consist of one note repeated rhythmically. Now mammals, if they possess a sense of rhythm, still do not seem to have any special enjoyment of it, as we may conclude fromn their not voluntarily making rhythmical noises or accompanying movements; for it is only by adapting the music to horses and dancing-bears that they are made to seem even approximately to keep time. It is certainly extremely curious if insects and spiders possess a strong feeling for rhythm in common with man, of which his fellow-mammals are destitute. We perhaps find a solution of this difficulty in the fact that many noises miade by the lower animals are naturally rhythmical owing to the special way in which they are produced. Thus some insects make noises by rubbing the wing against the thigh, just as a boy runs a stick along a number of railings; when a movement of this kind has reached its termination, the wving is naturally withdrawn and begins again, and thus the sound will recur regularly. The same applies to sounds mnade by the regular process of inhaling and expelling air; just as with men the sound of moauing might become naturally rhythmical, being made when the air is expelled. We are not therefore compelled to suppose that the rhythm is the element in the spider&amp;apos;s performance which is.specially attractive to his mate: it may be the mere sound which is primarily agreeable, though the proof of this is certainly difficult. The extraordinary specialisation and development of the rhythmical sense in man (and we find it among the lowest savages, whose one instrument is often the drum) is a fact vecry hard to account for, but is doubtless connected with general development of the nervous system and of the intelligence, and may be supposed to have grown as memory and the power of expectation became stronger. There is however one fundamental characteristic of rhythm, especially marked in the superior musical development of man, which may I think be accounted for -the fact, namely, that it is formed by multiples of two. Whatever and however complicated be the arrangement of the small groups of notes which form the bars of a melody, the number of bars is two or a multiple of two.&amp;apos; To put it in another way, any complete musical sentence stops after two or four or six component groups or bars and so on, but not after one or three, or five. I am speaking of course of purely melodic painful emotion. I think, however, that here the movements are not excited by the emotion except indirectly; they may be accounted for on the supposition that they cause a slight pleasure and distraction, which acts as a relief to the mind. (1) Even apparent exceptions are rare. No one with an car will need to be told that a bar of silence (filled up as a rule with accompaniment) may occur at the beginning or end as well as in the middle of a melody. For instance the melody at the opening of Schubert&amp;apos;s sonata in B fiat apparently ends at the seventh bar; but the ear would resent the idea of concluding there, or even the starting of a new melody or phrase in passages, where the totally different interest caused by counterpoint repetition and sequence is absent or wholly subordinate; though even in the most elaborate passages of &amp;quot; carrying-out &amp;quot; and fugue, where these last elements are predominant, the dual basis will be found again and again re-asserting itself. Where there is a basis of symmetry at all, the basis is two: and this characteristic must I think have its roots in the simple fact of our being made symmetrically with two sides externally alike, which results in alternate motions with each side. A sense of rhythm is so essentially a sense of movement that even without the evidence which we have we could hardly have doubted the intimate connection of music and dancing in the early stages of art: and as the enjoyment of rhythm must arise to a great extent from its association with the agreeable sense of vitality caused by motion, and especially l)y locomotion, so I think will the fact that all regular external movement is alternate or double explain the characteristic of melody which I have mentioned. If we had three legs and arms, our melodies would be based on the number three. Of course an enormous majority of our conscious actions are irregular, but just on this account they make no impression on the attention or memory; while the experience of regular alternate movement which our ancestors have had, especially in walking and seeing others walk, is surely sufficiently large to account for the importance of the dual element in our sense of rhythm. The westhetic properties of rhythm are of course in no way confined to its alliance with sound, the eye being quite as competent a medium for its apprehension as the ear. The sense of it is bound up with the whole nervous organization; and whereas the arrangement of notes and intervals in the scale, and the faculty for apprehenidinig the relations of the notes of a melody in respect of pitch, admit of many varieties, the fundamental instinct of rhythm on the other hand seems one and universal. The history of music confirins this idea; for while such momentous chances as the invention of harmony and the development of tonality might seem to the eighth bar, whic h the refore belongs rbythmicallv to what prtc(des. There are cases where the baime bar actts as a second terrm with the one preceding and a first term with the one following, the ear fully comprehending and accepting the change of character. Again, Engel hai pointed out that in sonie national songs one bar or phrase is repeated for enai&amp;apos;lhaais, iii which case the extra bar may be regarded as a kind of pause, keeping the ear a xuonient in suspens-e. The curious eleven-bar Russian theme, taken up by each nistrunient in turn, in the trio to the scherzo of Beethoven&amp;apos;s quartett, Op. 59, No. 2, might be explained to the ear in this way by treating tho third bar (which could be omitted) as redundant, and a kind of repetition of the second. It is, however, perhaps more natural to consider the actual melody to begin in each ease with the second bar, and to treat the two notes in the first bar as a kind of As eW &amp;quot; or catch. It seems hardly necessary to notice such enes as where the dominant harnivnv is continued to the end of e.y. the eighth bar, of a melody, and the actually final note3 delaytd in order that it may coincide with the tc:&amp;amp;ic harmony on the first beat of the ninth bar. have revolutionised the very nature of the art, this one element of rhythm is as predominant with us as with the Greeks, and mucch of the most beautiful music in the world is written in rhythm as simple as that employed by the spider during courtship. Rhythm, while possessing independently only the most elemontalry irethetic qualities, seems essential to any complete and satistving sequence of single notes:1 for a formless succesCsion even of beautiful sounds is no more melody than a block of Parian marble is a statue. It is true that owing to the development of other elements of order, and especially of harmony, there is a sort of musical pleasure 1;or which strict rhythm is not indispensable: still the point :and importance of music, with its power of getting aIs it were into the blood and clinging to the memory are so dependent on at alny rate such strictness a;s will guide the car in its cardinal expectations, tbat the occasions on which this can be dispensed with will he comnparatively rare. Rhythm gives the framework for the most effectiv( application of the other elements of proportion and(l fior, which without it tend to sink into incoherence: and of the two fitetors in a melody, the rhythm may in a more special sense lie said to ford the sequence of notes, and the sequence of liotes to inform the rhythm. And this clement of form is wholly remote from anything we find in the nature of the material. Mr. Se1)(n1erIll says that &amp;quot;what we regard as the distinctive traits of song are simply the traits of emotional speech intensified and systematised.&amp;quot; If I am right in my objections to the word intensified, the expression loses all its point: what we regard as distinctive traits of a statue are simply traits of marble, e.g. whiteness and solidity, .sy.stemtif.scd, that is, put into artistic shape. One more consideration may be mentioned in respect of the material for music supplied by emotional speech. Music is distinguished from emotional speech in that it proceeds not only by fixed degrees in time but by fixed degrees in the scale. This is a constant quality through all the immense quantity of embryo and developed scale-systems that have been used: whereas the transitions of pitch which mark emotional affections of voice are, as Hlelmholtz has pointed out, of a gliding character. True, there are some instruments on which the performer glides from fixed degree to fixed degree. But the pleasure here is caused by the sound arriving at last at the fixed note after the car has been momentarily excited by watching its course towards it; in fact by the satisfaction of In (1) We cannot count as exceptions such relaxations as e.y. in the reciting note of a chant, for here the car, though held in suspense, never loses the exact sense of the satisfaction to follow. &amp;apos;T&amp;apos;he limit of such relaxation is fixed by the limit of the car&amp;apos;s grasp and retentiveness. Interludes of recitative sometimes seeni to me tobe striving as it were after rhythm, and just not attaining it at the accentsd noteH. These are but less mark-ed instances of suspense, which is relieved when the music settles .sgain into strict rhythmn. expectation depending on the presence of fixed degrees, not from any imitation of speech, which glides quite as much when used in the harsh accents of anger and complaint as in any other. The supposition that music preceded emotional speech need not preclude us from going so far with Mr. Spencer as to admit that some phrases of speech of a definite and non-gliding character may have been subsequently used for musical purposes, but used simply as material. Such phrases would be very few and simple, and must I think have been either short exclamnations or elosin- cadences. To me it is as impossible to imagine the development of the simplest musical melody from the general shifting mass of disordered tones used in emotional speech as to conceive that I shall find a panoramia of the world in the cluids. The only instinctive modulations of speech which could be selected and adapted to song would be those which readily admitted of recurrence, and so of the element of proportion and symmetry; t&amp;apos;r recurrence is obviously the stepping-stone to rhythm. The re-ular repetition of the same phrase or cry comes nearer music tlian the most excited utterances of fluent speech. A war-cry might be of such a nature, and here an aid to the development of rhythinical cadence might be given by the accompanying movements, such as the step or the swinging of a club. Some closing cadences of speech may perhaps have also recurred sufficiently often to fix the attention, and so to be consciously repeated in a way that would lead to recitative; which, so far from exaggerating the peculiarities of emotional speech, expressly avoided niost of them and was nearly monotonous. It was by passing through the interlude of monotone, but of rhythmical monotone, and so by discarding or limiting instead of exaggerating the characteristics of emotional speech, and introducing a totally new element, that recitation became a basis for music; and if we supposed with Mr. Spencer that the four-toeid recitative of early Greek poets was the slightly exaggerated emotional speech natural to themn, we should surely have a poor idea of their emotional speech. It is of course only natural that a person in chanting for sonme time continuously should confine himself to the very few tones which least tire his siniging voice; and the regular recurrence at the end of the Iihes of a cadence which may, as I say, have been adapted from a closing cadence of speech, would give the rhythmical eflect. If we go farther back in a sentence than the clusimig cadence, we are lost at once. Sentences have to begin as w sell a to end; amid according to the words employed the same idea or emotion may be expressed in a hundred different series of tones. EIven the sallie words may be excitedly uttered in diffrent ways with several different successions of notes: while it is possible to enIl)loy tle saume notes in expressing two opposite emotions, as in the excited delivery of the words &amp;quot;I lore you,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;&amp;apos; I hate vou.&amp;quot; The quality (as opposed to the psitch) of the tones will certainly be generally agreeable or the reverse according to the emotion cxp)rcssed: but music has never eml)hasised or exaggerated the harsher tones, and even WAagner has not re(1uired that Ortrud&amp;apos;s music shall bc sung by a woman with a cracked voice, or accompanied by a cat o1bligato. The princil)le of proportion is obviously at the root of the rhiyth,nieal element in music. No less is it at the root of the qualif&amp;apos;i of musical sound, as it is continued regularitv of vibrations ^-hich distinguishes musical sou01d frlm mere noise, and sweeter is distinguished from harsher timbre by the presence of a greater number of harmonic notes bearing to the fundamental note small and si~lple ratios. armio)1, again depenids directly on proportion. The samc principle must I think have roughly regulated the S1/Ccession of notes in very early stages; for the developmenit of clementarv seale-systemis couldl only be the result of its previou-s lidden operation. &amp;apos;We are now so enitirely depen(lenet on a feeling -for tonality, that is t(he relation of the tones heard to a key-note, that it is hard for uIS to imnagine ,the kind of musical sensatioll given by a succession of notes to ears which are otherwise constituted, or the manner in which melody would develop under such conlditions. We may conceive however that e.g. one phbraise would create a need to balance it with another, which would perhaps descend if the first had ascended. Proportion seems at first sight a somewhat abstract basis for the mysterious and l)owerfil emotiolis induced by music; but it is expressed in time, not space, and rhythm, to say nothing of its own peculiarly exciting effects, affords extraordinary scope for combinations of the other proportional elements. These can be translated into various elementary feelings of contrast and reciprocity, of support and dependence (as in architecture), and above all of expectation and satisfaction; 1 neutral-secming elements perhaps, but capable of osthetic expression, thanks to the groundwork of rhythm and of independently agrecable sound in which they are embodied; and the pleasure of rhythm and of musical sound (for (1) It is, of course, only in the alphabet of the developed language that we can at all consciously perform this translation; one step beyond, and the effect becomes infinitely too complex for analysis. But with regard to the alphabet, we can approach to some kinid of adumbration of an explanation. The semitoncs in the major and minor scales will afford an example. From thc nearness of the leading note to the key-note, the ear expects it to rise, and accepts the fulfilmnt of this expectation as a satisfactory close. Again, if wc ascend the scale of C and strike E natural, its nearness to F gives it a tendency to rise, and hence it seems as it were to stand on its own legs, to have a confident character and be able to nake an independent start; whereas if we strike E flat, which keeps nearer to D and stenms d.pendent on it and willing to return to it. this idea of dependence and tendency to fall will have a pathetic character; and the same applies to the A flat, which makes the interval of a minor sixth from C. these elements at any rate, as well I think as the others in embryo, may be reasonably referred to the semi-human stage) might on Mr. Darwin&amp;apos;s view be extraordinarily specialised and intensified. From its employment &amp;quot; during the season of courtship, when animals of all kinds are excited by the strongest passions,&amp;quot; what was primarily a simple ultimate pleasure which the organism was adapted to receive might well become in time capable of mighty emotional meanings, the apprehension of which is of a totally different kind from the sensuous pleasure in e.g. arrangements of tints. Few who realise the principle of inherited association, and the readiness with which music lends itself to association, will doubt the power of music to have become wholly differentiated, to have been sublimated as it were out of the coarse definite passions and excitements, love, hope, emulation, hostile ardour, triumph, present during its early stages, and so &amp;quot; to tell us of things we have not seen and shall not see.&amp;quot; I have as yet hardly touched on the startling developments of modern music, harmony, tonality, and modulation. In these three elements lies the power of making the simplest phrase eloquent, and the feeling for them seems to us so natural and spontaneous that we imagine with difficulty a musical sense from which it is absent. Surely the fact that these have been comparatively recently developed in obedience to artistic sensibilities, and in no way from sounds due to the physiology of speech or in imitation of instinctive vocal modulations, affords the strongest presumptive evidence that the production of rudimentary music was similarly ruled by rudimentary art-sensibilities. When we consider these things, Mr. Spencer&amp;apos;s theory of the function of music, that it is to facilitate the development of emotional speech, appears even more unsatisfactory than his account of its origin. He says that &amp;quot;&amp;amp;the complex Tn- Pal phrases by which composers have conveyed complex emotiu-,- influence us in making the involved cadences by which we convey our subtler thoughts and feelings.&amp;quot; Now the cadences of conversation are as regards tune infinite in number, and a new one is probably invented every time one of us says ten consecutive words. The phrases of musicians are practically also infinite, as the different values in time which can be given to notes multiply indefinitely their possible arrangements. Between units from these two infinites it would be a fruitless task to search for definite melodic resemblances. We are thrown back on such occasional and general characteristics as loudness and rapidity, which have been already discussed; and I cannot think that any of us will talk louder or quicker when excited, because we find these qualities in some exciting passages of music. It is of course impossible absolutely to prove this; but if it is not so, we are driven to conceive the Greeks, whose music was so much less elaborate and complex than ours, to have been also very inferior to ourselves in their powers of expressive utterance, and to have possessed much less developed vocal chords. The fact is that song, which moreover in our time is but a limited branch of music, is perpetually making conscious efforts; for instance, the most peaceful melody may be a considerable strain to a soprano voice, if sung in a very high register: while speech continues to obey in a natural way the physiological laws of emotion. It is curious to observe that Wagner, who like Mr. Spencer connects music with speech, and much of whose work might seem, from its efforts to portray ideas and emotions which are really out of the sphere of music and from the violent and extended intervals of its recitatives, to be an outcome of Mr. Spencer&amp;apos;s theory, yet owing to his metaphysical basis takes a view exactly opposite to M1r. Spencer&amp;apos;s of the history of the musical element in human speech. Regarding music as a direct representation of the nounlviown lie conceives the earliest efforts of speech to have come nearest it ill this respect; and in speaking of Beethoven&amp;apos;s symphonies he discovers the necessity for the invention in our own times of this completely novel means of expression in the more and more conventional development of modern speech. He says, &amp;quot;we findd in the so-called roots of words an origin which clearly shows that from the very first the conception of any object was formed in a manner coinciding almost entirely with the subjective feeling it called forth,&amp;quot; whence he suggests that probably the first language of human beings bore a great resemblance to singing. That is, it was the earliest speech which approached music, and in spite of the range of speech having since increased, which Wagner would hardly deny, he conceives speech to have become less and less musical. I feel that my apprehension of music must differ so totally from Mr. Spencer&amp;apos;s, that I perhaps fail fairly to catch his point of view. To me a melody has a certain musical meaning which is its real essence: it may be pitched high of low, played on a whistle or a double-bass, played within certain limits at different paces, and this essence will remain absolutely constant. On the other hand there are different modes of performance, each of which Mr. Spencer seems to regard as having an independent emotional meaning of its own; but each of which appears to me capable of being applied to melodies of the most diverse characters. For instance, Mr. Spencer describes staccato as essentially appropriate to the expression of exhilaration. resolution, and confidence. I need hardly point out how a vicew of this sort breaks down to any one who remembers the bass accompaniment of the wonderfully yearning and pathetic opening melody of the andante in Beethoven&amp;apos;s Pastoral Sonata. The difference of view already noticed naturally appears in another form in the various answers which are given to the question, *What does music express ? 3Mr. Spencer considers it an idealised language of passion and e(motion: Wagner holds its business to be the expression of preconceived l)oetical ideas. Now, though often a most emotional language, it would be altogether mislcading to call music a lan&amp;gt;guage *fbr t/h e(&amp;apos;motioiis. Its emotions, though often in harmonious correspondence with other emotions, are now so differentiated and ultimate that they can in no way be said to depend even on an imaginative realisation of these; and the analogies to which musical ideas often readily enough lend themselves are for the most part so vague anid remote as to add little to the interest. Not but that the connection between music and things external to itself may be in some ways tolerably definite: a special merry piece may have been inspired by a specially good dinnier or gay scene, and the rhythm in particular may be suggested by soluC external cause. But emotions (real or imagined) external to the music, though they may act indirectly by quickening -aund attuniing the mind to a sense of beautv, are fitr oftener wholly latent and lotential. A melody composed for an instrument in a neutral framie of mind might afterwards be set to religious words, of which it might then seem to breathe the very spirit; music written without a thought of death or any solemn subject might turn out to make a first-rate funeral march and be adopted as such; and a gifted child who had never personially realised the existence of such a feeling as mournfulness might appreciate and eveCI invent a deeply l)atlmetic melody. We can yearn, triumph, and so on in purely musical regions; the musical mood of a composer may bear no sort of discoverable relation to anything beyond the music;1 and even where we find in music a mood describable by some adjective drawn from the category of the emotions, to say the music was composed as an expression of the external emotion would as a rule be as true as to say that the interior of St. Mark&amp;apos;s was designed as an expression of a previous mood of gloom on the part of its architect. But, in fact, the attempt to analyse verbally the nIusical emotions of an important work would usually give a result Eo hleterogeneous and confused as to be a rcd~d/tio ad atlmurdwit of any supposed conscious embodiment of corresponding extenrial emotions, and d forfiori of more definite (1) It is of course quito ;notbler question holW ftr a mUsiCian&amp;apos;s permanient temperament, and character are connected with his artistic work. Different answers might probably be given in difflrent cases, and we might doubtless find instances where a predominant tone of struggle or sorrow or glaudtness seems to have bet-n at any rate emphasised in hlaritony with *xternal characteritstics. lIut I believe that Mendlessohn&amp;apos;s music would hay . remained agreeable and rtlau/y&amp;apos; through any amount of external or internal tumult; and that comfirt and happiness would not have htilled the sublime pathos of lie thoveuu; and that as a rulhu tho artistic and the general characteristics are more exturnal t&amp;apos; eachi other than is ustdliv itsluhitted. &amp;apos;The fashion of imagining and overstraining connuetious botw e n iinusic and lifi is due to a tendency, amniable but in music esp ecially ill-advised, to muia: beroes of artists. and concrete conceptions.&amp;apos; iEv;en thei idest deieriptive ad(Ijectiv-cssuch as joyful, tender, majestic, triumphant, pathetic-are of limited applieation, and music&amp;apos;s most ex(1iIisite effects lie contin111uily bcyon(l their range. Every bit of music that I care much about coive ys to me an impression peculiar to itself; and just IS only a, fev chor(ls -minor thirds and sixths for instance as compared with majorhave a definite emotional character, so not one in ten of these impressions can I (locket off under the most geiieral. heads. *We find as a pure matter of experience, without any (d p)riosi assulmptions about the miature of mnusic an(l in comI)lete accordalice with Mr. Darwin&amp;apos;s theory of its developiiellt, that just as we often caminot express the effect oil us of a lealitifill face or landscal)e ill terms of definite emotions, so musical wvorks nmay he througholut independent of any emotion now conceivable (Oiitside the musical sphere. This fact is absolutely igniored by those who, like Wagimcr, hold it to be thc great l)llsiness of melody &amp;quot; to express the mnotives of dramatic action; &amp;quot; asX a result of which, we continually find strained and barren analogies put forwvard as natural and true interpretations. llerr Illiffer for onle appears totally unconscious1 of any lofty beautty or meaning ill music except as expressingome emotion or idea definiable in other wavs. I cannot conceive whiait lie is to reply when I and thousands of others assure himi that the most exquisite and overpowering effects we have ever experieln(e have been through music which conveye(d to Us absolutely no such emotion or idea, and oftener perhaps in silence anld solitude thbai during an actual I)erformalce ; for lie treats such music as possessig mere &amp;quot;sonorous beauty,&amp;quot; that is, describcs it as I should d(sesribe a scale or a chord played on a, beautiful instrument. I am almost ashamed to insist at such lengtl on this point, but what is to be done when one often finds Beethoven&amp;apos;s legendary renmark labout the opening notes of the C niiior syuiphlony, &amp;quot; It is thus that Fate knocks at the gate,&amp;quot; (quoted as if it were a revelation ? Not thlat the words would lhave beeni lbolishl: stuch fanciful associations miay be amusing when thrown out in conversation, or useful asi; safetyvalves for excitement. But there seein to be those who believe that Beethoven conccive(l a desire to &amp;quot; express Fate,&amp;quot; and then struck three quavers and a minim. If this is not beyond a joke, the joke it is not beyond must be M1r. John Parry&amp;apos;s musical ropreseiitation of a boot-jack on the pianoforte. (1) In the attempt to dccribe music-an attemlpt as hopeless as to write English with the letters x y z-we are often driven from the recognised category of austhetic emotiotis to terns such as tantaliaing, capricious, uncoxnproimisiiig, persistoet, inaroeciatu , and even stranger expressiolis. It wotiuld 1) hard for instancee to describe except as a piece of divino folly tho &amp;quot; Jill c ame tumibiling after&amp;quot; effect of the scherzo of Beethoven&amp;apos;s sonata in F for piano and violin. WVas such niusic&amp;apos; written to express a preconceived idea of foolishness? This question as to the sense in which music expresses emotion, has of course an important bearing on its alliance with words, and especially on opera. The use of&amp;apos; music in this respect may be unduly extended and unduly circumscribed. The able writer of a recent article in the Coastenj)orary RterietB seemed to me to create a difficulty by confining it to alliance with words of high poetical merit, while at the samlle time requiring that the drama should be musically set throughout. I cannot but think the axiom laid down by this writer, that music begins where speech becomes inadequate, a dangerous one; for when thus stated it seems to imply the very sort of continuity and connection from which I dissent, as though speech and music were essentially means of graduated strength for expressing the saime things. The sphere of musical emotions certainly overlaps to a great extent the sphere of ordinary human emotions, and on this common ground music is of course adapted to dramatic interpretation: and as long as no sacrifice is made of complete musical beauty, association is always ready to extend the scope or this power by the gradual creation of genuinely-felt though inexplicable analogies. But in an opera where &amp;quot; the series of musical pieces would be unintelligible apart from the dramatic interpretation,&amp;quot; music loses its inherent rights even in this limited common region and is reduced to a kind of ideal emphasis. In such a case it would certainly be necessary that the drama should be throughout very well worth emphasising, and such a drama is very hard to imagine: for in every complete work of the kind there are necessarily passages destitute of high emotional expression which do not require to be dwelt on, nor will the mind stand the attempt to keep it perpetually omi the stretch by a system of musical underlining. There may be a dominant idea or emotion to the whole piece, and hence the excellence of the conception of recurring &amp;quot; leadingmotives &amp;quot; in the music; but many details of verbal expression will gain in nothing except wearisomeness from a forced alliance with notes and intervals with which they have no more connection than with geometrical curves. These considerations must not however lead us to padantic limitations. It must be noticed that, while many highly poetical words are quite unsuited to music, many words of comparatively ordinary quality are eminently suited to it. The use of words of some sort, over and above the beauty of the human voice as an instrument, has a peculiar value in the pleasure which results from the concurrence of the word-rhythm and the tunerhvthm. This pleasure from the perception of one governing element in different things-a pleasure of which in the purely musical region counterpoint affords a good instance-is an example of the natural love of tracing uniformity under multiformity, and may, if the music is good, be a most important element in the total result.&amp;apos; jI) The point and freshness of this charm (which has in every nation a charac ter of It is therefore no paradox to say that, while inferior music kills good words, rhythmical words of comparatively ordinary character may be a great adornment to good music, and even the meaning of them may get quite a new point and beauty from the alliance. Not to mention many volkslieds and popular songs, Auber&amp;apos;s operas afford numerous instances, though it must be admitted that his introduction of the music is often casual to a degree which it is perhaps hard to defend. The fact moreover that one and the same meaning can be conveyed in a hundred different ways by words makes it within certain limits an easy task to accommodate words to music; while every melody has its own distinct musical meaning inseparable from its form, and can only make compromises by giving up its very nature. Such form as verse and music have in common in the former v&amp;apos;ery generally belongs only to the framework and setting, in the latter always to the essence. It was of course to be expected that those who do not recognise an inherent and essential completeness in music should be the first to disregard in opera the two prime elements of melodv, strict rhythm and tonality: and the formless recitatives and restless transitions of key with which Wagner&amp;apos;s music abounds are in complete accordance with his theories. It is impossible not to feel strong admiration for this writer&amp;apos;s general ability and artistic earnestness: it is impossible, for me at all events, not to sympathize to the utmost with his contempt for moderii Italian opera, as well as with many of his other musical criticisms, and with his hatred of the mere displays of virtuosi. Though scarcely a poet he must be credited with very great genius as a musician; for that it is choice not necessity which has made him the Walt Whitman of music seems possible from his having shown valuable inventiveness precisely in the line he most despises and discredits-namely melody in marked rhythm, such as marches. But with all his ability I cannot but think that in his theory of opera he is embracing a cloud, and that too often the offspring, like Ixion&amp;apos;s broo4, is a double failure, neither music nor poetry. Let us briefly see what metaphysics do for music. Dr. Ilueffer, in an article in the Fortnightly Review, after mentioning that Wagner adopts with slight modifications Schopenhauer&amp;apos;s notions on the ideal basis of music, quotes Schopenbauer&amp;apos;s theory-to wit that music is &amp;quot; as immediate and direct an objectification or copy of the will of the world as the world itself is, as the ideas are of which the universe of things is the phenomenon. Music is not the copy of the ideas like the other arts, but a representation of the cosmical will its own) is very apt to vanish in translation. Excuse can be reAdily made for translations into the native language; but the spectaclo at Covent Garden of a French opera turned into Italian (with all the pretty sparkling dialogue represented by the most empty and conventioial recitative) is indeed pitiful. co-ordinate with the ideas themselves.&amp;quot; There may be truth in this view, though the expression of it seems somewhat fantastic: but what follows is a good specimen of id pTioi reasoning. Music, being of an entirely supernatural character, oygt to be likewise independent of space and time. Space is out of the question; and even time can to a certain extent be dispensed with &amp;quot; in that which is most musical in music-harmonv.&amp;quot; As if the commonest and most striking effects of harmony (those of discord and resolution, where a desire is created by one note and fulfilled by another,) did not depend precisely on the succession of notes in tie: for in the senso of&amp;apos; fitness with which we recognise the correspondence of things .simnultaneoutsly perceived (as by the eye) the peculiar excitement of exrpectation and .satisfiiction, the importance of wvhich in melody as well as harmony it is impossible to exaggerate, can have no part. Rhythm is naturally treated as &amp;quot; an intruder in the realm of absolute music,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot; the essentially rhythmical nature of Greek compositions could not be favourable to the flow of melody.&amp;quot; However much music ought to be independent of time, I am afraid my organism is such that I shall always prefer rhythmical phenomena to unrythmnical noumena. The writer goes on to say that &amp;quot;compositions which like dances are exclusively founded on rhythm must be of a lower order than where the melody grows out of harmonious relations.&amp;quot; Now what is meant here by harmonious relations? If r cXlations of harniony are intended, I reply that melodies which do not modulate or where the modulations are few and simple, (as is the case with the vast majority of the best tunes iii the world,) may be and naturally would be invented without any suggestion from or conscious reference to their natural harmonic accompaniment. If however the word harmonious is used non-technically, then any tonal melody with a meaning at all grows out of harmonious relations, dances as much as any other, for music founded exclusively on rhythm could only be written for the drum; and that the meaning is generally poor and conventional is the fault of the writers, not of the rhythm. To doubt this is surely too much to identify melody of simple form with the platitudes of Italian opera. Wagner often shows how little he recognises the deeply-seated nature and artistic place of the rhythmic impulse. For instance he ignores it altogether in attempting to make out the dramatic action to be as essentially a development of the original dance as the symphony is of the dance-melody. &amp;quot; The original people&amp;apos;s dance &amp;quot; he says &amp;quot; expresses an action, mostly the mutual wooing of lovers.&amp;quot; The original people&amp;apos;s dance has nothing to do with lovers, and is exemplified every time a child of three years old nods its head or stamps its foot to music. Again he considers the expressiveness of Beethoven&amp;apos;s symphonies lihited by their being in what he calls idealised dance-form. If by dance-form be meant phrases con- sisting of multiples of two, I have tried to showv reasons for recognising, as Beethoven did, the musical necessity of such elements. Blut eveI among those who .admit that for melodic coherence some continuous groundwork of satisfied cxpectation is a necessity, there are some who maintain1 that new kinds of rhythm can be based on new elemeints, which a subtler and more specialised sense will apprehend. I would only renark that the word sleci.ilieed must he used with caution: for any clique, who admired things not admitted as admirable by the great mass of those acquainted with the subject, might claim to be the afite in whom a peculiar exquisiteness of enjoyment had become differentiated. In art such terms are liarren, except wNhere the verdict of the tlite is in time endorsed by an ever-increasilig number, and the minority are as it were pioneers in sensation. Of course those who differ from mc have a perfect rigght to regard themselves in this light, and to prophesy that in time the human race, when rhythmically disposed, will forget that it has legs and arms and throw itself on the infinite. The requirements of rhythm being ignored, it is of course easy to go on .alnd say that the mclody lies implicitly in the poem. But the use made of Beethoven&amp;apos;s introduction of words in the ninth symphony is an unfortunate instance (if finding a text for a theory. Ile forsooth first felt &amp;quot; the demand of a previous poetic inspiration,&amp;quot; and was to &amp;quot; bow down before the eternal rights of poetry: &amp;quot; and henceforth every composer with high aspirations is &amp;quot;;to consider it his task to express a preconceived poetical idea by means of sound.&amp;quot; The beauty of the introduction of voices in this symphony is undeniable, and the words themselves are very fitting. But the melody, splendid as it is (and by the way most strictly rhythmical), has been equalled again and again by Bleethoven himself: and in the face of his other works this need for poetic inspiration seems to me to mean as much as if it were said that in the composition of the Pastoral Symphony, finding the inadequacy of his independent melodic resources, he was compelled to imitate the language of birds; or that Shakespeare proclaimed the insufficiency of men and women for dramatic purposes by the introduction of other beings into the Te)pi)est. But even had Beethoven felt what to the best of my knowledge he never once expressed, the inadequacy for his pumrpose of purely musical means, and even ere Wagner&amp;apos;s notion (of expressing preconceived poetical ideas as just as I believe it to be mistaken, what (1) I have even been as1;ed how music is to advance except, by a relaxation of the forms of melody ? Why should I or anybody else be. bound to say how music is to advance? Who knows if it is to advance at ll ? &amp;apos;That it will advance in tho sense of original and beautiful melodies and works constantly appearing, I see no reason to doubt, as long as there is no considerable intervAl of unpro(dnliveness. I lhad Sehubert and Schuniann. reached old age, they inight havo beems noIW livilq,, and iS not Brahms stiU with us? is to happen next? We have only to look round to see that poek are not musicians, nor musicians poets, even in the most untechnical sense, nor are the audiences they address coincident: the characteristics which thev necessarily possess in common may be reduced to a more or less emotional temperament and a sense of the formal element of rhvthm. Yet we must admit, supposing for a moment the close and detailed alliance between the two arts to be possible, that the poet who plans his poem so that it &amp;quot; can penetrate to the finest fibres of the musical tissue,&amp;quot; and who &amp;quot; has perfectly mastered the inexhaustible power of expression of the symphonic melody, so as to be induced to meet its finest and most delicate nuances,&amp;quot; will have at any rate a tolerable aptitude for music: and a cognate completeness and delicacy of perception of the other art would be required from the musician. The idea that poet and musician are to be one may seem a fascinating point in Wagner&amp;apos;s theory: and indeed the picture of the musician always sitting and waiting to be fertilised, and then inventing the music implicit in some one else&amp;apos;s poem, is grotesque and self-contradictory. But even Wagner would allow that, just as a total absence of ear for tune would prevent the greatest of poets from appreciating a melody, so some quite independent musical faculty is necessary to his ideal compound artist. Now assuming that the next hundred years, like the last, will produce a limited number of people endowed with certain independent musical aptitudes, how are the possession of an inventive dramatic genius and power of poetical expression to be assured to a single one of these? Nay, even if the connection of the two gifts were not most infrequent in individuals, still, unless we can suppose poetical and musical conceptions to have become more and more consciously united in the minds of the public addressed till now the craving for the blending of the two has grown quite definite, it is sterile to assert that the nature of music has changed. No development depends ultimately on isolated individuals- Nor, even if we confine ourselves to the specially gifted, can Wagner make out a connection between the two regions of ideas by asserting (what after all would be imere assertion) that poetical conceptions have existel, though in a latent or struggling condition, in the productions of Mozart and the other heroes of &amp;quot;absolute music:&amp;quot; for his contention is not that their works are imperfect (like so many early works in other arts) owing to a want of complete mastery which results in a failure worthily to realise and express the idea, but that they are perfect in a lower kind. While therefore he cannot dispense in &amp;quot;musicians of the future &amp;quot; with the special musical aptitudes possessed by those of the past, he in fact demands in addition a totally new set of aptitudes and ideas. Such a sudden change, implied no less in the requirements and appreciation of the public than in the moods and faculties of the artist, is at all events without precedent or analogy in the development of this or any other art. In his whole conception of &amp;quot; melody implicit in the poem,&amp;quot; or as I should call it recitative, Wagner seems to ignore the fact that lefiniteness of outline is necessary for the perception of melody as an organized whole, each part of which in its place is unalterably right and necessary. In recitative there mnust always be a tendency to lose this definiteness: where the chief object is to emphasise certain words, it will often be a matter of indifference whether we have treedledum or treedledee, in the same sense that it is a matter of indifference whether we have a word italicised or underlined. Knowvn and independent laws of form being abandoned, the very need of a true musical faculty tends to vanish iii a fog: it requires no great amount of genius for animal-painting to make a striking representation of a bandersnatch. The difference between &amp;quot;&amp;apos; melody implicit in the poem &amp;quot; and melody as I conceive it is markedly shown in a very striking passage, where Wagner compares hearing a dramaticmusical piece to a visit to a forest on a summer night, and describes the multitudinous voices as joining to produce the idea of one overpowering melody, which haunts the hearer though he can in no way repeat it. Now this is exactly what I should not call melody, however strong the overmastering charm. Wagner himself calls melody musical form, and he calls this forest-symphony infinite melody; but infinite form is a contradiction in terms. He makes the poet say to the musician &amp;quot; Spread your melody boldly, so that it may flow through the whole work like an uninterrupted stream: with it reveal all that I pass over in silence, because you only can reveal it.&amp;quot; Unfortunately notes, like words, when spread too boldly result in prose. &amp;quot; Melody &amp;quot; of such a character will certainly be about as impossible to recall as the noises of a forest; but this is a point very much against it as an artistic product, and as a means of happiness. Even supposing such an opera to give strong though indefinite enjoyment to numbers during its performance, a work only capable of being represented by exceptionally gifted artists in the few richest cities in the world, and the beauties of which cannot be recalled but lie as in a mine (so far as most people are concerned) between the occasional performances, will cause in the long run fewer moments of the highest pleasure than any single one of Schubert&amp;apos;s songs. In music as in everything else, memory depends on form. Such enhancement of the emotional effect intended by the poet as is possible at all is possible without deserting the recognised paths of .music. As an instance of how dramatically thrilling the very simplest purely musical effect may be, we may take the chord of E flat which accompanies the word &amp;quot;1 Tremblez,&amp;quot; in the three verses of the song in G, &amp;quot;Voyez sur cette roche,&amp;quot; in Auber&amp;apos;s Fra Diarolo. Such luck comes only to one who deserves it, for harmony waits on melody: and this effect, like a light in a picture, derives its whole point from occupying a particular place in a composition governed by laws of form to which our organism and associations compel obedience. Over and above the sense of proportion already so much insisted on, we find innate in us a love of recognising and discovering: and hence comes, as incidentally noticed above, a natural delight in perceiving uniformity under multiformity and symmetry under variety. Ears listening to melody are analogous to eyes which, while gazing at a beautiful statue, apprehend the unstudied and emotional character of the pose without ever losing sight of the perfect symmetry of the figure. I think that a great deal of the difference of opinion about Wagner is the result of variety of kbid in musical receptivity. The usual gradual progression from neutral non-comprehension to pleasurable comprehension is in music complicated in a very special and curious manner. There are a great many people who, without having what is called a musical ear or having one only imperfectly developed, derive extreme pleasure of a vague kind from fine sound, more especially when it rushes through the ear in large masses. They will be apt to find their own meanings in the music, which merely shows that the sound has a stimulating or a soothing effect on their nerves and acts as a congenial background for their subjective trains of thought and emotion. The use of music for religious purposes depends greatly on its power to act in this way: and the organ in particular, with its great waves of sound and varieties of timbre, is an invaluable instrument for the purpose. To a trained ear a rapid and loud fugue on the organ, if previously unknown, is apt to be &amp;quot; full of sound and fury, signifying nothing; &amp;quot; but to many who are capable of being strongly moved by music in a vague and mysterious manner it is a matter of indifference what is being played or sung, so long as the volume of tone is rich and full and the quality agreeable. The sense of moving and interlacing parts (especially in choral music) is often a large ingredient in this indefinite pleasure; and there are many contrapuntal compositions whose beauties few musicians would pretend to discover analyse or appreciate till after some little acquaintance, about which others who do not profess to be extremely musical will go into perfectly honest raptures at once. I have often wondered, if BMlow, instead of repeating the last movement of Beethoven&amp;apos;s B flat sonata, were to play something else equally long, fast, and elaborate, how many out of his London audiences would be the wiser. Now much of the effect of Wagner&amp;apos;s music is of this character. No one can pretend that the majority of an audience who receive a first performance of Loheiiyria with enthusiastic applause, would discover the difference, if on another night a great part of the music were altered, and if, the same words, situations, and kinds of instrumentation being retained, some other equally unusual progressions and transitions were introduced. Indeed I think that an experienced musician might hear the opera several times and still be sorry to have to bet on the next note in the vocal parts of much of the second act. If at a striking situation a fine soprano voice takes some unexpected intervals in a high register, accompanied by restless modulations in the orchestra, one is sure to hear it called dramatic. Diminished sevenths though a cheap are not a very wholesome luxury. Such effects in excess are about as dramatically expressive as the spasmodic movements of a marionette; but the word &amp;quot; dramatic &amp;quot; seems to be applied by many to music only to express violent or at least chromatic intervals. I cannot help thinking of that one chord of Auber&amp;apos;s, or of another equally fortunate in the table-music towards the end of Don Giobrani, which, while acting as the simple accompaniment of the simplest of melodies, seems to suggest with superb irony the whole impending doom. Let me not be thought to imply any such paradox as that music which is fully understood at once is better than music which requires time and study for intimate knowledge. At first much of a symphony of Beethoven or a fugue of Bach doubtless makes on many as undefined an impression as that produced by Wagner&amp;apos;s operas: but the final verdict on all bf these must rest not on any such result but on the conscious and definite perception of their beauties by those who obtain more complete knowledge of them. Wagner however expressly presents his work &amp;quot;not to the connoisseur but to the public,&amp;quot; and conceives that the &amp;quot;infinitely rich and ramified details of the large melody which comprises the whole dramaticmusical piece &amp;quot; are &amp;quot; to reveal themselves to the most naive layman as soon as he may be sufficiently collected to receive the impression: whereas I maintain that any wide popularity with &amp;quot; naive laymen&amp;quot; of such parts of Wagner&amp;apos;s work as are truly representative of his theories must depend on the broad and indefinite effect above described. Though it is common for the two to coexist in proportions which vary with different people, I fear that this uncritical pleasure seems to be in the inverse ratio of the musical perception and must recede as a more definite musical sense develops itself An car which has become accustomed to searching for coherent melodic and harmonic meanings cannot easily throw off this seeking attitude, or make itself sufficiently passive to derive satisfaction from beauty or mass of mere sound. It will be wearied rather than delighted by a poor composition played on a magnificent organ. Still, though in music often and most literally ignorance is bliss, it must be admitted that the pleasure resulting from a melody which is actually apprehended is higher than that arising from any series or combination of sounds whicb conveys no distinct musical lmleaning. For, to say nothing of the difference in value arising from the fact that the latter is transitory while the former is reproducible in imagination, the higher pleasure must be identified with the more specialised, that which will be appreciated by the keener or more developed sense. The universal, sensuous, and passive pleasure arising from mere broad effects of musical colouring or timbre1 will thus be lower than that arising from active apprehension of melodic form; nor is it intrinsically more intelligent (though far more powerfully felt) than a child&amp;apos;s admiration of the bright tints on a painter&amp;apos;s palette. I may be asked if I then consider this pleasure lower than that given by a bad and vulgar melody. But in opera there may of course be independent merit in the dramatic situations and emotions, which will be emphasised and nade more impressive to many by the musical background, so that the whole wsthetic result may be of considerable value: and the same may be said of purely subjective trains of thought or emotion. There are persons again with a strong and subtle feeling for colour, to whom the combination of gorgeous effects of colour presented to the eye with the musical colouring of splendid and varied timbre affords a new and exquisite pleasure, wholly differing like a chemical coinpound from each of its elements. With regard to Wagner however I cannot of course ignore the fact that there are cultivated musicians who find beauties where I find none; and it is here that I must urge the plea for mutual toleration which I may seem hitherto to have forgotten. When it comes to a simple question of liking, disliking, or regarding with indifference a succession of notes of which those who differ would seem each to have an equally definite and complete knowledge, there is no stand-point for argument. Dr. Seemann, quoted by Mr. Darwin, says it is to be doubted &amp;quot;whether even amongst the nations of western Europe, intimately connected as they are by close and frequent intercourse, the music of the one is interpreted in the same sense by the others. By travelling eastwards we find there is certainly a different language of music. Songs of joy and dance accompaniments are no longer as with us in the major keys, but always in the minor.&amp;quot; The same certainly holds with individuals; and the simpler and more obvious the melody, the stranger the less analysable and the more irritating the difference. To me a very large proportion of Rossini&amp;apos;s melodies appear either vulgarly pretentious or trivial and meaningless beyond all words. To many of course this will damn me at once as a critic of music: I would be more polite to them, and would joyfully admit that (1) The sense of gradations, combinations, and contrasts in the colouring may be highly educated and specialised; but the enjoyment of timbre, apart from the form it should clothe, is at the best too purely sensuous to lend itself to any sort of continuous after-meditation. It may be noticed that, like the palate in respect of food, the human ear has a very wide variety of taste as regards simple timbre or quality of sound, and as a rule preferences for particular voices or instruments seem to have little conncction with musical proficiency.: if they have received large masses of delightful and continuous emotion from such tune or tunes, they have a perception in this direction beyond mine, which, though I cannot understand it, I have no ground to call in question. Many other modern opera tunes, which to me are as disagreeable and cloying as over-ripe pears, are the daily bread of the Italians, and may be wholesome where indigenous. We may however certainly use the word bad of music which makes not a shadow of impression on any one, (like so much of the so-called popular music of the present day, of which no one would ever dream of recalling a bar,) and also in a comparative way when experience shows enjoyment of some music to be far less keen and lasting than (and at the same time often incompatible with) the enjoyment of other music; and broadly speaking the proof is not difficult. Many will be the readier to admit the expedience of toleration on the head of melody from a recollection of the different ways in which they themselves have been impressed by melodies at different times. It is not only that taste develops, and so music once dear becomes despised and music once incomprehensible becomes dear. There is I am afraid a necessity, arising from music&amp;apos;s independent position in our aesthetic life outside the intellectual sphere, that nothing in it will stand perpetual iteration. The frequent hearing of or continuous dwelling on a particular set of notes is too apt to sate the ear or dull the perception, so that we look in vain for the old message. Those are indeed fortunately constituted who escape this altogether. In one way the better the music the less the danger: in fact music that will last with him is the best subjective definition that any one can give of good music. But on the other hand the keener the first impression and the more haunting the first delight, the more chance is there of at all events partial or temporary failure. Most of us know the feeling of some particular music being at its acmei at the second or third time of hearing, when it is new enough still to surprise us, and old enough for us to feel the triumphant sense of possession which is given by recognition. Most of us know how for the moment composition after composition has appeared to eclipse all other music, and then has gradually receded to its proper place; and it would be absurd to condemn the pleasure whose only fault is to be transitory. The very different order of musical development in different cases affords another reason why the power of apprehension and appreciation of the same composition will form and culminate at different times with different people. The total impossibility of describing in words the impressions received from melodies makes it hopeless to give an intelligible account or justification of one&amp;apos;s musical taste: it will be best simply to recognise that the widest differences in the estimation of some compositions may co-exist with a common admiration of a vast number of others. It is worth remarking that it is extremely difficult to tell what amount of apprehension of a melody is possessed even by one who can hum or whistle it correctly: for parrots can whistle tunes composed by men without probably experiencing deep emotion. A test however is sometimes given by the amount of resemblance which different people find in tunes. Even musicians differ more than might be supposed in the power of differentiation. When one person thinks two tunes alike which, in spite of a few notes perhaps being identical in the two, give to another totally distinct impressions, the superiority in apprehension is almost certainly on the side of the latter. The first phrase of a tune may derive its whole point from the second, just as in a poem the first line may be a question which is answered in the second: and the mere external similarity of the opening phrase of one tune to the opening phrase of another, on which a charge of plagiarism is often founded, is in many cases absolutely beside the mark. Again, the difference of a single note may have to the keener sense as great an effect on the meaning as the insertion or omission of the small word tiot in a sentence. Differences of rhythm are especially often ignored in this way, and even correct ears may differ greatly in keenness of rhythmical sensibility: while on the other hand similarity in rhythm and nothing else frequently serves as a basis for a similar mistake. The isolation of music from other branches of culture makes one inclined sometimes to call it the highest and sometimes the lowest of the arts. There is really little meaning in calling it either: it is now beyond a doubt the most potent and universal engine of noble and exquisite emotion, while on the other hand (in its highlydeveloped and cosmopolitan stage) its results, like itself, are isolated, and can have little if any direct influence on the general intellectual and moral advancement.&amp;apos; But on this very isolation depends the wideness of its influence. In branches of art which are intimately connected with other and various elements of culture, education is necessary for appreciation, and it is only the specially gifted among the uneducated whose instincts can be relied on. Music, not being so connected, speaks intelligibly and truly to the masses; and with its immediately apprehended utterance, passing direct to the consciousness without fear of obscuration or distortion from vulgarity ignorance or prejudice, awakes in the minds of thousands who are inaccessible to any other form of high emotion a mighty sense of beauty order and perfection. EDMUND GURNEY. (1) The ethical effects of music on masses, either in inspiring and regulating common harmonious movements or in giving unanimity and intensity to the expression of religious or popular sentiments, do not belong to the essence of the art, but to the adaptation of certain forms of it.</FullText></Record>