<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2466539</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130300</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>DIANA OF THE CROSSWAYS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>210</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Jun 1884</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18840601</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Fiction</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Meredith</LastName><FirstName>George</FirstName><PersonName>George Meredith</PersonName><OriginalForm>Meredith, George</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Escott, Thomas Hay Sweet, 1844-1924</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>763</StartPage><EndPage>780</EndPage><Pagination>763-780</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2466539/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>DIANA OF THE OROSSWAY&amp;amp; CHArm L OF DMA3 AND DIA18R TOUCHIN TH HEMOINL AMONG the Diaries begning with the second quarter ofour century, there is frequent mention of a lady then becoming famous for her bet and her wit: &amp;apos;an unusual combition,&amp;apos; in the deliberate syllables of one of the writes, who is, however, not disposed to personal irony whe speaking of her. It is otherwise in his cae: and a general Sing at the sex we may deem able, for doing as little- harm to w as the stone of an urchin cast upon the bosom of moher Earth; though me mut look some day to have it returned to themu, which is a certainty ;-and indeed full surely will our idle-handed yougter too, in his riper season, be heard oumplaining of a strange assault of wanton missiles, coming on him he knows not whence; for we are all of us distinctly marked to get back what we give, even from the thing named inanimate nature..... A witty woman is a treasure; a witty beauty is a power. Has she actual beauty, actual wit P-not simply a tidal material beauty that passes current any pretty ippancy or saggerin nto ne P Grant the co nion she will appear a veritable queen of her period, fit for homage; at least meriting a diition to believe the beat of her, in the teeth of foul rumour; beamuse the well of true wit is truth itself, the gathering of the precious drops of right reason, wisdom&amp;apos;s lightning; and no soul g and dp g it can justly be a target for the world, however well-armed the world acnfronting her. Our temporar ld, that Old Credulity and stone-huring urchin in oe, upos it possible for a woman to be mzentally active up to the point of spiritual clarity and also fleshly vile; a guide to life and a biter at the fruits of death; both open mind and hypocrite. It has noyet bee taught to apreciae a quality certifying to sound citi hip a autho tivy as ace of lan in fe simpe, or coffers of bonds, sares and stocks, and a mo imperishable guarantee. 1inur Wilmr, in his Diary, i not content to quote the beaut Xm Warwick, he attempts a portrait. Mrs. Warwick is &amp;apos;quite Grecma&amp;apos; She migt &amp;apos;pPose for a stat&amp;apos; He presents her in crpenter&amp;apos;s li, with a dab of school-box colours, effctive to those whm the Keepsake fashion cn stir. She has a straight ose, red 1Wl, raven, hai, blac eyes, rich ioa remakblyfLabust, and she walks we and has 4a agreeble voice; likewise I&amp;apos;deliate extremities.&amp;apos; The write wa created for p ithad he Chosen to bring his art into our literary market. Perry Wilkinson is not so eaborate: he desrie hw in his IBc lc Ios as a splendi brans, eclipsing all. the blomdes coming near her: and &amp;apos; what is more, the besatiful creature can tal&amp;apos; He wondered, for she was young, now to society. 8ubIq._Ly he is rathe ashamed of his wonderMt, and accounts for it by &amp;apos;not having known she was Irish&amp;apos; She turns out to be Dan Merimn&amp;apos;s daugter.&amp;apos; Her sounding of the letter R a trifle y i noticed by Lady Pennon: &amp;apos;and last, not lest, the lovely Xrs Warwic, twenty minutes behind the dinner-hour, rr-reuy feing she was late.&amp;apos; After alluding to the soft inluence of hr bet and ingenumince on the vexed hostes, the kindly old c e adds, that it was no wonder she was late, &amp;apos; for jut before string from home she had brokien loose from her husband for good, and she entered the room absolutely houseless I &amp;apos; She was not the less i brilliant.&amp;apos; Her obrins re often &amp;apos;so drol I lauged till I cried&amp;apos; Lady Pennon became in coansquence one of the sdunh supporters of Mrs Warwick. We have it from Perry Wilkinsa that the union. of the divergent couple was lilkned to another union always in a Court of law. There was a d ction; most analogies will furish one; and here we see England and elwad their part, until later, after the brec, when the Englishman and Iishwoman resumed a cetain resemblance to the yoked isands. Henry Wilmers, I have said, deals exclusivly with the wit and charm of the woman. He treats the sandal as we might do in like manner if her story had not to be told. But these are not reporting columns; very little of it shall trouble them He is too copious in recording the lady&amp;apos;s tt s he h ,s quoting an obscure g, says of thm lapidary sentences, that they have merly &amp;apos;the value of chalk-eg which lure the th to sit,&amp;apos; and tempt the v os to rain for the lke, oe might add; besides flattering the wodd to imagine itself rier than it is in es that are golden. Henry Wilirs noles a multitude of then &amp;apos; The talk fell upon our being creatures of Habit, and how far it was good;&amp;apos; she id, &amp;apos;It is the tat we s ourslve cruthed between love grow old and indeiee aging to love.&amp;apos; Crific ears not present at the conr ston catch an eeo d and aphoriams over-chanad, notwsd i thrill in the irony of &amp;apos;aging to v&amp;apos; The quotation ranks rather among th test e to her charm. is freshe when speaking of the war of the sexes. For oe sentence out of my, though we find it to be but the cleve literary Clothing of a comon accustion:&amp;apos;menasy hae roundd Sewg Point: ey he nm yt doubld Cap Tern&amp;apos; It in war, and on the mal ide, Ottoman war: her reduced hl r to tik so postively. Her ma wa of the soial clas which in p ely venatorial still, canine wnder its polsh. She hold a brief for her beloved Ireland. She close a discussion upon Irish agitation by saying rather neatly:Yos; hm tah tm it is Angs a gel as comaon h#% natr to feel en intred in the deg that hAm bten yos&amp;apos; The dog eio ay puts on madness to win attention; we gather then that Englnd, in an angry tremour, tries him with watr-gruel to prove him sane. Her saying that &amp;apos;A woman in the pillory restores the original bark of brotherhood to mankind,&amp;apos; is no more than a cry of personal anguish She has golden apples in her apron. She says of Life: &amp;apos; Wen I fail to heris it in erecy fire the fire win are rwning,&amp;apos; and that drives like rain to the roots. She says of the world, generosly, if with tapering idea: From. the point of vison of the angel this ugly monster, only hall out of dime, must appear our one constant hero!&amp;apos; It can be reed ma y, but abstain. She says of Romance: &amp;apos; The young who avoid that region ecape the title of Fool at the cost of a celesial crown.&amp;apos; Of Poetry: &amp;apos;Those that have souls modt their fellows there&amp;apos; Touches inward are not absent: &amp;apos; To have the sense of the eternal in life is a short 1ight for the soul. To have had it, is the or&amp;apos; vitality.&amp;apos; You we entreated to repress alarm. She was by preference lighthanded; and her saying of Oratory, that &amp;apos;It is always the more impressive for the spice of temper which renders it untr ty,&amp;apos; is ligHt enoug. On Politics, she is rhetorical and swings: she wrote to spur a junior politician: &amp;apos;It is the first business of men, the school to Mediocrity, to the covetosly ambitiu a sty, to the dullard his amphithere, arms of Titnstothedeperately enteping, Olympus to the ge s&amp;apos; The instances of her drollery are rather hinted by the Diarists for the benefit of those who had met her and coud inhale the a e at a wrd. Diarists of aming passages are under an obligation to paint us a realistic reival of the time, or we mis the relish. The odour of the reet, and more, a slice of it is required, unless the humorus thing be n lly spirited to walk the eth as one immortal among a number les numerous than the mythic Gods. &amp;quot;He givwe good dinners,&amp;quot; a candid old critic said, when asked how it wasthat he ooold praie a certain poet In an isand of chills and fogs, cdlum crebris imbribus a nebulis fidum, the comic and other perceptions are dependent an the stirring of the gastric juices. And such arevival by any of us would be impolitic, were it a possible attempt CHAPTER H. AN I AL. IN the Asembly Rso fthe capitl yof the Sister sland there was a public ball, to celebrate the return to E1 of a British hero of Irish blood, after his victorious Indian campaign; a mighty stru e didly ended; and truly could it be sid that all Erin danced to meet him; but this was the pick of the dancing, past dispute the pick of the supping. Outside those halls the supping was done in Lazarus fashion mainly through an excessive straining of the organ of hearing and vision, which imparted the readiness for mr declared by physans to be the date inducing to sound digestion. nSoe one spied the figure of the hero at the window and was fed; some only to hear the tale chewed the ed of it; some told of having ee him mount the steps; and re itwas that at an hour of the night, no matter when, and never mind a drop or two of cloud, he would comne down them again, and have an Irish chee to freshen his pillow. For &amp;apos;tin Ireland gives England her soldier, her generals too. Farther away, over field and bogland, the whiskies did their xcellent ancient service of watering the dry and drying the damp, to the toast of &amp;quot;Lord Iorrian, God l him I hs an honour to the old eountry !&amp;quot; and a bit of sigh to follow, hints of a stoy, and loud laughter, a drink, a deeper sigh, settling ietO cnvation upon the brave Lord Larrian&amp;apos;s deeds, and an Irish regiment he favoured-had no taste for the enemy without the backing of his&amp;apos; boys&amp;apos; Not he. Why, h&amp;apos;d never march to battle and they not handy; because when he struck he struk hard, he said. And he has a wound on the right hip and two fingers of his Wit hand; has bled for England, to show her what Irishmen are when there well Umeted. The fine old warrior standing at the upper end of the long saloon, tall, straight, grey-haired, martial in his aspect and d tim, was worthy to be the dag-pole for tha His large grey eyes lightened froe time to time as he ranged them over the loai couples, and dropped a wowrd of iquiry to his aide, Captai Sir [akin Danstane, a good model of a cavalry offic, thoug omewhat a giant equly happy with his chief in passing the troops of animated ladies undr review. He named as many as were known, to him. Reviewing women quitel attired for inspection, al variously and charmingly smiling, is a relief after the monotonous regiments of men Ireland had done her best to present the hero of her blood an agreeable change; and he too expressed a patriotic satisfactoon hearing that the fices most admired by him were of the native ise He loeked upon one that came whirling up to him on a young officers arm, and wept off into the crowd of tops, for a while before he put his customary quest she was returning on the spin when he sa, &amp;quot;Who is she?&amp;quot; Sir Lin did not know. &amp;quot; She&amp;apos;s a new bird; she nodded to my wife; I&amp;apos;ll ak&amp;quot; He manwuvred a few steps cleverly to where his wife reposed. The informati he gathered for the behoof of his chief was, that the handsome creature answered to the name of Miss Xerion; Irish; aged somewhre between eighteen and nineteen; a dear friend of his wife&amp;apos;s, and he ought to have remembered her; but she was a child whe he saw her last &amp;quot; Dan eron died, I remember, about the day of my siling for Indis,&amp;quot; mid the General. &amp;quot; She may be his daughter.&amp;quot; The bright cynosure rounded up to him in the web of the waltz, with her dark eyes for Lady Dunsae, and vanished again among the twisting columns. He made his way, hand y bumped by an apologetic pair, to lady Dunsane beside whom a seat was vacated for him; and he trusted shead not overatigued herselE &amp;quot; Coes,&amp;quot; she replied; &amp;quot;yu are perishing to ]know more than Lulin has been able to tell you. Let me hear that you admire her: it pleases me; and you sha hear what will plese you as much I promise you, General&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I do. Who wouldn&amp;apos;t?&amp;quot; said he frany. &amp;quot;She ed the Channel expressly to dance here to-night at the pubie ball in honour of you.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Where she apear, the first person fials to sesond rank, and act it humbly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; That is grandly spoken. &amp;quot;She make everhinginn the room dut round a blaing jeweL&amp;quot; &amp;quot; She makes a poet of a soldier. Well, that you may understand how pleased I am, ke is mhy dearest friend, though she is younger than as may be ; she is the only friend I have. I nursed her when she was an infant, my father and Mr. Dan Menion were chums. We were parted by my marriage and the voyage to India. We hav not yet e and a sy&amp;amp;ae: she wsuappe up, of cosurs, the moot she entered the room. I knew she woold be a tukiug girl: how lovly, I did not gums. You e right, she i the others She used to be the spihlet. living areatsres and to judge by k her lett isht has not faded. NWe&amp;apos; in the mawket Lrd Lanian nodded to everyhg he heard, din mock ddlf shake of the heaL . My pooest b I&amp;quot; mighed, in the theatrical but cordially of gee age Viewing Cythress arket. Hi po aes t sbern was ch m t he in thew~ee itabid for sochkrms &amp;quot; What is her name in addition to MPriam &amp;quot; &amp;quot;Diana Antonia Xeron. Tony to me, Dian to the worLd &amp;quot;She lives over there?&amp;quot; In IEnland or anywhere; wherever she is taken in. Ne wi live, I hope, chiy with ime &amp;quot; And honest Irish?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Oh, she Irih&amp;quot; &amp;quot;AM!&amp;quot; the General was Irish to the heels tlat night. Before furthe could be sid, the fair object of the dialogue e darting oa a trip of little runs, both hads out, all her fe one tender sparkle of a mile; and her cry proved the quality ad her blood: &amp;quot; Emy! Emy! my heart! &amp;quot; &amp;quot; My dea Tony! I should not have com but for the hap of g you hee&amp;quot; Lord Larrian rose and received a hurried aowldgnt of his courtey.from the usurper of his place. &amp;quot;E y!wemight kiand hug; w&amp;apos;reinlrelnd. Ibantol But yore not still idear? Sayno! That I1i fever nust have gam You do look a dash pale, my o ; youre tired.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;One dance s tired m. Why were you so late P &amp;quot;To give the othr a chance P To produce -a rester p by suspense? No and an I wrote yo I was with the Petmgrews. We ught the coah we caught the boa, we were only two hor late fo the Ball; sowedidwonders. And good Mrs. Wett is Pinning sOMAmewherto comlether a IW in the crsilh, ying for Emmy, whn Mr. Mayor; inf d me it was At dut of eoery IrI to daoe her toe oC if sed be known fwr what sheis. And twilaah meby thewamst, and I dying to find OL&amp;quot;&amp;apos;Who VW the aP&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Not to save these limb from the lighted tae could I tel &amp;quot;You are to perform a c _ex bow to Lord Laria&amp;quot; COhtter firt I a little I &amp;quot; Th&amp;amp; plea for chatter di It was visble that the hero of the night hung listening and il exPectAtion. He and the Beauty were named to one another, and they chatted through a quadrill Sir Lukn introduced a fellow Harrovian of old days, Mr. Thomas Redwarth, to his wife. se Our weat err ,ie _ , &amp;quot;- h&amp;amp;tole rmked, to nt te going; &amp;quot; you reme nmber, in India, my pointing to you his name in a er-ler an the subject. He was generally asae fr the crieting days.&amp;quot; IAdy Duntane kindy appeared to call it to mind, and she led upon the theme, queried at times by an abrupt E A P? &amp;quot; and I beg par,&amp;quot; for manifestly his ge and one of his ears, if not the pair, were gipT to the young lady di g with Lord Larian. Beauty is rare; luckily is it rare, or, judging from its dect on men, and the very stoutest of them, our world would be nt ally a more dietracted planet than we see, to the perverso of business, courtey, rights of propert; and the res. She perceived an incipient victim, of the hundreds she anticipted, and she very tolerantly tlked on: &amp;quot;The weather and women have some lthey sy. Is it true that he who reads the one can read the other P &amp;apos; Lord Larrian here burst into a brave old laugh, excibiming, &amp;quot;Oh! good!&amp;quot; Mr. Rtedworth knitted his tk brows. -I beg pardon P Ah! women ! Weather and womenP No; the one point more variable in women makes all the difference&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-Cn you tell me what the General laughed at P&amp;quot; The honet Englishman entered the trap with promptitue. &amp;apos; She sid:-who is she, may I ask youP&amp;quot; Lady Dunsa mentid her name. Daughter of the famous Dan Xemion P The young lady meited examination for her far&amp;apos;s sae. But when reminded of her laughter-moving peech, Mr. Redworth bungled it; he owned he spoilt it, and candidly stated his inability to see the fun. &amp;quot;She said, St. George&amp;apos;s Channel in a gale ought to be called St. Patricks I something- I mised se point. That quadille-tone, the Pturelle or something.. She had of the Channel lat night,&amp;quot; Iml Dunstane pursued, and they bot, whi in seeming conves, caught satches from their during a pause of the dance. The k Dina said to Lord Larrian, &amp;quot;You really decline to make any of us prid women by dancing to-nightP &amp;quot; The General aswered: I might do it n two stilts; Icant en one ]He touched his veteran leg. &amp;quot;But swry,&amp;quot; said she, &amp;quot; thes always an a o to it fre its partner in motion, if me of them ths the H. signified a woeful negative. &amp;quot; My dear young lady, you may dark things to grey hairs !&amp;quot; Men rejoine: - If we were over in nlanmd, and yeo fixed on mu the stiga, of saying dark things, I should never speak without being thought obscur&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;apos;It&amp;apos;s because you lash too brightly for them&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I think it is rather the r n c of the tooth that once recived a atone when it expected candy.&amp;quot; Again the General laughed; he looked pleased and warmed. &amp;quot;Yes, that&amp;apos; teir way, thts their way! &amp;quot; and he repeated the words to himself, diminishin their importance as he stamped them on his esmury, but so heatiy admiring the lovely speaker, that he maidered her wit an honour to the old country, and told her so Irish prevailed up to boilingpoint. Lady Dunatae, not ls gratified, glanced up at Mr. Redwoeth, whoa. brows bore the knot of pelexit over a strong stare He, too, samped the words on his _mmory, to see beq tly whether they had a vestige of ng. Terrf y r he tout her. Idy DUnt in her quick mpay with her fiend, read the adver mind in his lace. And her reading of the mind was .right, wrog altogether hdeducin of th coesponding etiment. Musk was remumed to confuse the hearin of the eavsdrr They beheld a quaint spectacle: a gentle , obviously all lisan, a oed, with the evident intention of reminding the Beauty of e night of he engagement to him, and claiming her, as it were, in the lons jaws He advanced a foot, withdrew it, advnd, withdrew; eager for his prize, not over ; in a of te Illustrious General she enLmim r Wy quite unaware of the pretender&amp;apos;s presence; wheepo voice was oeard: deOh ! if it was minuetting you meant before the lady, I&amp;apos;d never have disputed your right to peorinr, air.&amp;quot; For it eemed that three wre two claimants in the field, an Irishman and an Englis ; and the fimer, having a livelier seose of the eituatin, hung aloof in waiting for her eye; the latter directed imelf to strike blunly at his prey; and he continued m ttg, now rapidly blinkin, flibed, an , consco of awka e and a tangle, incapbe of exWricatio He began to blink rlily under the riley of his rival. The General observed him, but as an olject remote and miute, a fly or gat. The face of the brilliant Diana was entirely devoted to him she amused. Way Du _sa hald the faint line of a decorous lugh on lar lips, as ue said : &amp;quot; How odd it is that our me showto moh na in a BI.-nos I baveose them in daer, ad ereth si first of any, and one is proud of tho. ?lTey should always be acing the elements or in action.&amp;quot; he glanced at the minuet, which had become a petrified figure, till p ting, bent forward, an interrogaive reminder. Mr. Redworth reserved hIs asent to the of any English disadvantage. A whif of Cdtic hosilit in the atmospiee put him on his mettle. &amp;quot; Wherever the usm is tried,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot; My lady! &amp;quot; the Irish gentleman bowed to lady Dundsn &amp;quot;I had the r ... uivan Smith . . . at the a l. . .&amp;quot; 8he responded to the salute, and Mr. Sullivan Smith proceeded to tell her, hall in speech, half in dotb most luminous, of a civil contention between the English tleman and himself, as to the poesso of the loveliest of partners for this particular ensuI dance, and that they d imultneoudy made a rush from the Tower Courts, namely, their car, to the Upper, being the lady; and Mr. Sullivan Smith partly founded his preferable claim on her Irish descent, and on his uaintance with her eminent defunct father-one of the over-radiating sAr of his qo i counfry Lady Dunstae sympathized with him for his not intruding his claim whe the young lady stood pro-engaged, as well as in humorous areciation of h inve logic &amp;quot; There will be dancing enough afer supper,&amp;quot; she sid. &amp;quot; If I could soore one dance with her, Id go home supperless and fad,&amp;quot; aid he. &amp;quot; And thats not saying muc among the hordes of hungry troopers tip-toe for the signal to the buffet. See, my lady, the gentleman, as we call him; tere he is working his gamut perpetally up to dacap. Oh! butiti a heep trying to be wolf; be sheep-eyed and he&amp;apos;s wolf-fanged, pathetic and larcenous! Oh, now! whod bel it !-the man ha dared... Id as soon think of t sacrilege in a cathedral! &amp;quot; The man was actually, to quote his idnt rival, &amp;apos; breaching the fortress,&amp;apos; and pointing out to Diana Merion &amp;apos;her name on his dirty scrap of pper&amp;apos;: a shocking sight, when the ladys recollection was the ade point to be aimed at, and the lyumpure &amp;quot; s if all of us coudnt have written that, and hadn&amp;apos;t dme it I &amp;quot; Mr. ivan Smait groaned disgusted. He hat bad ma , partl rlyin casesinvolving ladies; and the bad manners of a Saxo fired his aagM to the race; individual members of which he boased of hbirpvig and embracing&amp;amp; ho. the individual b nd to rce for him, and the race was excused in the But his hatred of bad manners was vehement andl have exended to a iflw-countryman. Hie wee of the ateednt ty, Dimaa turned from her purser with a iwou liftiug of the Iws at her fried, Lady Dunane, otionea her fan, and Diana - banding he1 -Are you bound in honour P&amp;quot; - I doi&amp;apos;t thlklIam. And I do want to gon takin with the General. He is so delightful and my a of a trwe soldie !-telling me of his last big battle, bit by bit, to my Siung.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Putof the man for a square dane down the list, and take out Mr. Rledworth-Mis Diana Xeron, Mr. Redworth :-he will bring you back to the General, who mus not totally absorb you, or he Wi f-it hispo Diana instantly struck a trt with the PAcI advocate of his claims, to whom, on his uishing hr, Mr. Sullivan Smith remarked: &amp;quot;Oh! sir, the law of it, where a lady&amp;apos;s comerlnd! Youere one for evictima, I should gues, and the anti-huma pros..a It&amp;apos;s that letter of the lw that stands between you and me and mine and yora But you&amp;apos;ve got your congee, and my bl_ snon ye!n &amp;quot;It was a positive t,&amp;quot; said the eawey. Mr. Sullivan Smith derided him. &amp;quot;And a pretty parter you&amp;apos;ve pickled for yourself when she keep her positive engagement!&amp;quot; Iady Dunstane expressed her opinion that her couple danced exclletlytogether. &amp;quot;It&amp;apos;d be a bitter thing to see, if the fellow couldnt dance, after ladg her out!&amp;quot; sighed Mr. Sullivan Smith. &amp;quot;I heard of her over there They call her the Black Pearl, and the Irish lalybeue she dark. They rack their poor brains to get the laugh of us&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And I lisen to you,&amp;quot; saud Lady Dunstane. &amp;quot;Ah I if all England, hl?a quarter, the _sllest piece of the lad were like you, my lady, rd be loyal to the finger-nailsL Now, is she engaged -when I get a word with her P&amp;quot; &amp;quot; She is nineteen, or neay, and she ouh to have fiye good years of fedomi, I think.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And five good years of srm Id serve to win her!&amp;quot; Up he sprang. Diana was on Mr. Eedwort&amp;apos; arm. &amp;quot; No refrehmes&amp;quot; she aid; and &amp;quot;this is my r hm taking the seat of Mr. Sullivan Smith, who culated, &amp;quot;I must go and have that gt &amp;apos;s nane He wanted a Joe. &amp;quot;Yo know you ae ready to coqUe with the General at any nomt, Tony,&amp;quot; sid her friend. &amp;quot;Yes, with the General &amp;quot; &amp;quot;He is a noble old man&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-uprbA And dont my &amp;apos; old man With his unifm and his height and his grey head, he is like a glorious October day just tbeforthe brow leaves fill.&amp;quot; Diana hummed a little of the air of Planxty Kelly, the favourite of her childhood, as Lady Dundane well remembered, and they smiled together at the scnes and times it recalled. Do you still write verses, Tony? &amp;quot; &amp;quot;I could about him. At one part of the fight he thought he would be beaten. He was overmatched in artillery, and it was a cavalry charge he thundered on them, riding across the field to give the word of command to the couple of reients, riddled to threads, that gained the day. That is life-when we dare death to live! I wonder at men, who are men, being anything but soldiers! I told you, madre, my own Emmy, I forgave you for marrying, because it was a soldier.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Perhaps a soldier is to be the happy man. But you have not told me a word of yourself. What has been done with the old Crossways?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The house, you know, is mine. And it&amp;apos;s all I have: ten acres and the house, furnished, and let for less than two hundred a year. Oh! how I long to evict the tenants! They can&amp;apos;t have my feeling for the place where I was born. They&amp;apos;re people of tolerably good connections, middling wealthy I supoe, of the name of Warwick, and, as far as I can understand, they stick there to be near the Sussex Downs, for a nephew, who likes to ride on them. I&amp;apos;ve a half engagement, barely legible, to visit them on an indefinite day, and can&amp;apos;t bear the idea of straners masters in the old house. I must be driven there for shelter, for a roof, some month. And I could make a pilgrimage in rain or snow just to dote on the outside of it. Thates your Tony.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;She&amp;apos;s my darling.&amp;quot; ,,I hear myself speak! But your voice or mine, madre, it&amp;apos;s one oul. Be sure I am giving up the ghost when I cease to be one soul with you, dear and dearest! No secrets, never a shadow of a deception, or. else I shall feel I am not fit to live. Was I a bad correspondent when you were in India?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pretty well Copious letters when you did write.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; I was shy. I knew I sould be writing to Emmy and sonoter, and only when I came to the flow could I forget him. He is very finely built; and I dare may he ho a head. I read of his deeds in India and quivrd But he was just a bit in the way. Men are the barriers to p ect ss; at least, with gi, I think You wte to me in the Gmoe tone as ever, and at first I had a struggle to rely. And I, who have such pride in being always myself !&amp;quot; Two staring mi lehad formnd, one to front the Hero, the other the Beauty. The half moons iMpNckpty ai to repimish, and bme a fied bsdruction. &amp;quot;Yes, they look,&amp;quot; Diana made answer to Iady Dundane&amp;apos;s con- meat on the curous p mo She was geting usd to it, and her friend had a graifatiou in seeing how little this afeoted hw perfect &amp;quot;You are often in the world-dinners, dances P&amp;quot; she sidL 4 People are kind.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;A ny proposals ?t &amp;quot;Nibblesa&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Quite heart-free ?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Absolutely.&amp;quot; Diana&amp;apos;s bright face defied all menace of an eclipse. The block of sturdy garers began to melt. The General had dispersed his gp of satellites by a movement with the Xayoress on his arm, conestud as the signal for procession to the sapper-table CHA~rER MI. TE ITRIO OF ML DWOT AND TUE EXTERIOR OF NL SULLIVAN SMUB. &amp;quot;IT may be as well to take Xr. tedworth&amp;apos;s arm; you will escape the crush for you,&amp;quot; said lady Dunstane to Diana. -I don&amp;apos;t sup. Yes! go! You must eat, and he is handies to conduct you.&amp;quot; Diana thought of her chaperne and the lateness of the hor. S mumured, to soften her c &amp;quot;Poor Mr Pettigrew!&amp;quot; And once more Mr. Redworth, outwardly imper ble was i the m iltn of a hawi resembling tep He tlked and knew not what he uttered. To give this matchless girl the bes to eat and drink was his busines, and he performed it. Oddly, for a man who had no loaded design, marshalling the troops in his active and capacious cranium, he fell upon lulai of his income, present and prospective, while she at at the table and he stood behind her. Other were wrangling for place, chairs, plates, glasses, gam-_pie, pe: had them; the lady under Is chuage to a oertainty would have then; so far good; and he had ewvn hundred pouds per annum-seven hundred and fifty, in a favourab aspect, at a stretch . . . &amp;quot;Yes, the plesntt thing to me after working all day is an opera of Cari&amp;apos;s,&amp;quot; he said, in full accord with her tast, &amp;quot;and Tellio for tenor, certainly.&amp;quot; -A fair enoug sum for a bacelor: four hundred personal. income, and a prospect of highor dividends to increase it; three hundred odd from his o&amp;amp;oe, and no immediate ppect of an increase there; no cue died there, no dedly martyr for the advanceent of his juor could be persuaded to die; they were too toug to think of reiring. Say, sve hundred and fift .... eigt hundred, if the commerce of the country fortified the bank his pro. perty was embarked in; or eight-ffty: or nine, m .. . I could cull him my poet also,&amp;quot; Mr. Redworth agreed with her tate in poets I His letters are among the best evewr wIa r ever published: the raciest English I know. Frank, staht out: cpital des The best English letter-writers are a good n the French-You don&amp;apos;t think so P-in their way, of couuras I dae my we don&amp;apos;t epffciently cultivate the art We require the supple tongue a closer iter of society give&amp;quot; -Eight or ten hundred. Comfortable enough for a mn in chambers To dream of entering as a h o c that urn, in these days, would be tark nonsense: and a man two removes from a baronetcy has no right to set his reckoning on deaths :-if he does, he becomes a sort of meditative assassin. But what were the Fate about when they planted a n of the ability of Tom Redworth in a Government office! Clearly they intended him to remain a bachelor for life. And they snt him over to Ireland on inspection duty for a month to have eight of an Irish Beauty.... &amp;quot; Think war the finest subject for poetsP&amp;quot; he exclaimed. &amp;quot;Flatly no: I don&amp;apos;t think it. I think exactly the reverse. It brings out the noblest traits in human character P I wont own that even. It brings out some: but under ecitement, when you have not always the real man.-Pray don&amp;apos;t sneer at domestic life. Well, tire was a suspicion of disdain -Yes, I can respect the hero, military or civil; with this distinction, that the military hero aime at persoual reward__&amp;quot; &amp;quot;He braves wounds and death,&amp;quot; interposed Diana. &amp;quot;Whereas the civilian-hero-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pardon me, let me deny that the soldier-hero aim at a personal rewd,&amp;quot; she again interposed. &amp;quot;He gets it.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;If he is not beaten.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;And then he is no longer a hero.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;He is to me.&amp;quot; She had a woman&amp;apos;s inveterate miration of the profession of arms Mr. Bedworth endeavoured to render prti e an opening in her mind to reason. He admitted the grandeur of the poetry of Homer. We are a few centuries in advance of Homer. We do not day damsels for a sacrifice to propitiae cedletial wrath; pa dowe revel in details of slauhter. He reasoned with her; he repeated stories known to him bf civilian heroes, and won her asent to the heroical title for their deeds, but it was languid, or not so bright as the deeds desrved-or as the young lady could look; and he insisted on the civilian heo, impelled by some c ai motive to make her ase tIe thing he thought, also the thin he _wa-hi plain mind md matter-of-lmt natur Pomably she caught a glimpse of that. After a tun of fencing, in which he was impressed by the vibrion of her tones when speaking of military heroes, she quitted the tasble ying: &amp;quot;An argument between one at supper and another &amp;amp;anding ple, is rahe unequal if e e is needed. As Pat said to the conStable when his hands weried, 6You beat me with fists, but my spirit is towering and kicks fredy.&amp;quot; -Eight hundred P a thousand * year, two thousand, areas nothing in the of a her who means that the mistrs of the house shall have th choicest of the fruits and flowers of the Four Quarters; and Thoms Redworth had vowed at his first outlook on the world of womn, that never should one of the sisterhood o under his charge complain of not having them in profusion. O ently he was a settled bachelor. In the character of diWggd and p , pl ial bachelor, he reviewed the r ao f her character betrayed by the beatiful virgin devoted to the sanguine coaSt. The thrill of her voice in speaking of soldier-heroes shot him to the yonder side of a gulL Not knowing why, for he had no she, desperate or other, in his head, the least adited of men was frited by her taste, and by her aplomb, her in iv m freedem of maer and self-sufficiency-sign of purest breeding: and by he easy, peerless vivacity, her proofs of descent frm the blood of DanY Xenon-a wildish blood. The candour of the look of her eyes in speaking, her power of looking forthrot at men, and loolig the thing she spok, and the play of her volube lips, the significant repose of her lips in silence, her weighing of the words ho uttered, for a moment before the prompt apposite rply, down to her simple quotation of Pat, alarmed hIm; he did not ask himself why. A war would offer her the decorated soldier she wanted. A war! Such are women of this kind! The thought revolted him, and pricked his appetite for supper. He did sevie by M Petigew, to which lady Mis Xerion, as she said, promoted him, at the tabl, and then began to refresh in person, stading. &amp;quot;alkin ! that&amp;apos;s the follow&amp;apos;s name;&amp;quot; he heard close at his ear. Xr. Suivan Smith had drained a c gl , bottle in hand, and was priming the successo to it. Be cooked hIs eye at Mr. Bedwrh&amp;apos;s quick stare. Xalkiu! And now We&amp;apos;ll re whether the interior of him is gr, or black, or tabby, or tortoise-shell, or any other coloudrof the Malkin brd&amp;quot; He eqpained to Mr. Rtedworth tha hehd sum- m Xr. Malin to mwe to him As a tl for callin Miss Xenon a jilt. &amp;quot;The m an, sir, said in my heaing se jilted bi, and that&amp;apos;s to call the lady a jilt. T es not a point of di a a I overwhrd him. I happened, by the ble g of Prosiaence, to be by e he named her publicly jilt. And its enough that shes a lady to have for her champion. The same if she had been an Es~juiAUX uw. rll nevr live to hear a lady insulted.&amp;quot; You don&amp;apos;t mean to sy you&amp;apos;re the donkey to provoke a duel! &amp;quot; Mr. ledworth burst out gruffly, through turkey and sdffing. &amp;quot;And an Irish lady, the ymng Beauty of Erin!&amp;quot; Mr. Sullivan Smith was lowing on. He became frigid; he politely bowed: &amp;quot;Two, sir, if you haven&amp;apos;t the grace to withdraw the offensive term before it cools and can&amp;apos;t he obliterated.&amp;quot; Fiddle ! and go to the deuce!&amp;quot; Mr. Redworth cried. Would a soft dsap o&amp;apos;the cheek persude you, ir P&amp;quot; Try it outside, and don&amp;apos;t bother me with nonense of that sort at my supr. If I&amp;apos;m struc*, I strike back I keep my pistols for bandits and law-breakers. Here,&amp;quot; said Mr. Redworth, better inspired a to the way of treating an ultra of the isle; &amp;quot;touch glases: you&amp;apos;re a enman, and won&amp;apos;t disturb good company. By-and-by.&amp;quot; The pleasing prospect of by-and-by renewed in Mr. Sullivan Smith his composure They touched the foming glasse: upon which, in a friendly manner, Mr. Sullivan Smith proposed that they should go outside as soon as Mr. Redworth had finished supperfaie finished Wper: for the reason that the term &amp;apos;donkey&amp;apos; affixed to him was like a milster cap of achooldays, ringing bells on his top-knot, and also that it suck in his giza Mr. Bedworth declared the term to be simply hypothetical &amp;quot;If you fight, youre a donkey for doing it. But you won&amp;apos;t fight.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But I will fight.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;He won&amp;apos;t fight.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Then for the honour of your country you must. But rd rather have him first, for I haven&amp;apos;t drunk with him, and it should be a case of necessity to put a bullet or a couple of inches of steel into the a You&amp;apos;ve drunk with. And what&amp;apos;s in your favour, she danced with ye. She seemed to take to ye, and the man she has the smallest sg rmlting for is sacred if he&amp;apos;s not sweet to me. If he retracts! &amp;quot; thelicaly, No.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;But itiousl P&amp;quot; 4&amp;quot;Oertainly.&amp;quot; Then we g hands on it. It&amp;apos;s Malkin or nothing!&amp;quot; said Mr. Sullivan Smith swinging his heel moodily to wander in search of the foe How one ne man could name another a donkey for fighting to clear an innocent young ly reputation pased his rain a Sir Lukn hastened to Xr. Bedworth to have a talk over old &amp;quot;a Oldays&amp;apos;and. fellowa. I&amp;apos;l- tell you what,&amp;quot; said the civilian, &amp;quot; there we Irishmen and rish n rve met cool heds and.lng hes among them, and you and I knw Jack Derry, who was good at most things. But the burlesque Irishman_ an&amp;apos;t be carcaured. Nature strained herself in a fit of absurdity to produce him, and a11 that art can do is to cow.&amp;quot; This was his prelude to an account of Mr. Sullivan Smith, whom, as a specimen, he rejoiced to have met. &amp;quot;IThers a chance of mischie;&amp;quot; aid Sir Lukin. -I know nothing of the ma he calls Makin. I&amp;apos;ll inquire presently.&amp;quot; He talked of his prospect, and of the women. Fair ones, in his opinion, besides Miss Merion wo parading; he sketched two or three of his partners with a broad brush of epithets. &amp;quot; It won&amp;apos;t do for Mis Merion&amp;apos;s name to be mixed up in a duld,&amp;quot; said Bedworth. &amp;quot;sNot if she&amp;apos;s to make her fortune in Engld,&amp;quot; said Sir Lukin. &amp;quot;eIts probhbly all smoke.&amp;quot; The remark had hardly escaped him when a wreath of metaphorical smke, and fire, and no mean report, startled the company of supping . At the pitch of his voice, Mr. Sullivan Smith d Mr. alkin in presence for a cur ming as CaLct &amp;quot;And that is not the scoundrel&amp;apos; prime offene. For what d&amp;apos;ye thin ? He trumps up an beatifi lady, and beue she can&amp;apos;t rember, binds her to an oath for a dance to come, and then, holding her prisoner Wim, he sulks, the dirty dog-at goes and sulks, and he wonet dance and won&amp;apos;t do anything but screech up in orners that hes jilted. He sad the word. Dozens of getb heard the word. And I demand an apology of Mierr Malkin-or . . ! And none of your guerner nodding and bravado, Misterr Mallin, at me, if you please. The case is fwr settlement between gentln&amp;quot; The harassed gtl of the name of Milin, driven to extremity by the worrying, stood in braced e for the English attitude of defence. His tormentor drew c to him. &amp;quot;Mind, Igi you wa ing, if you lay afnger on me, I&amp;apos; knock you down,&amp;quot; sid he. Most joyfully Mr. Sullivan Smith uttered a low melodious crow. &amp;quot;For a specimen of manners, in an assembly of ladies and gentlemen . . . Iaskye ! &amp;quot; he addressd the ngabout him, to put his adversary entirely in the wrong before provoking the act of war. And then, as one intending gently to remonstrae, he Wsu on the point of stretching out his finger to the shoulder of Xr. Malin when Redworth seied his arm, saying, &amp;quot;I &amp;apos;m your man: firt: you&amp;apos;re due to Le.&amp;quot;, Xr. Sullivan Smith beheld the vanishing of his foe in a cloud of faces Now was he wroth on patently reas onle grounds. He thetnd aodm Man up, ma down, he llngethe r of short-legged, thickset, woodon-pated ce: and let it be pagilim if their white livers shivered at the notion of powder and balL Redworth, in the staggle to haul him away, received a blow from him. &amp;quot; And you&amp;apos;ve got it! you would have it! &amp;quot; roared the d9t. &amp;quot;E cuse yourself to the company for a misected effort&amp;quot; Redworth aidd; and he observed generally, &amp;quot;.No Irish gelm astikes a blow in good company.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; But thts true as Writ! And I offer excuses-if you&amp;apos;ll come along with me and a couple of friends. The thing has been done before by torchlight-and neadly.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;, Come along, and come alone,&amp;quot; said Redworth. A way was cleared for them. Sir Lukin hurried up to tedworth, who had no doubt of his ability to manage Mr. Sullivan Smith. He managed that fine-hearted but purely sensational fellow so well that Lady Dunstane and Diana, after hearing in some anxiety of the hubbub below, beheld them entering the long saloon amicably, with the nods and looks of gentlemen quietly accordant. A little later, Lady Dunsane questioned Redworth, and he smoothed her apprehension, deliverig himaclf, much to her comfort, thus: &amp;quot; In no case would any lady&amp;apos;s name have been raised. The whole affair was nonsensial He&amp;apos;s a capital fellow of a kind, capable of behaving like a man of the world and a gentleman. Only he has, or thin he has, like lots of his ountrymen, a raw woundsomething that itches to be grazed. Champagne on that I . .. Irishmen, as far as I have seen of them, are, like horses, bundles of nerves; and you must manage them, as you do with all nervous crtus with firmness but good temper. You must never get into a fury of the nervs yourself with them Spur and whip they don&amp;apos;t want; they&amp;apos;ll be off with you in a jiffy if yo try it. They want the bridle-rein. That eams to me the secret of Irish character. We Finglish are not bad hornen. It&amp;apos;s a wonder we blunder so in our management of Such a people.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I wish you were in a position to put your method to the proof,&amp;quot; sid she. He shrugged. &amp;quot; There&amp;apos;s little chance of it!&amp;quot; To reward him for his practical discretion, she contrived that Diana should give him a final dance; and the beautiful girl smiled quickly resosve to his appeal. He was, moreover, seniable in her look and speech that he had aldaned in her consder to be no Loger the mere inning stick, a young lady&amp;apos;s partner. By which he humbly understood that her friend approved him. A gentle delirium enfolded his brain. A householder&amp;apos;s life is often begun on eight hundred a year-on less, on much le :-sometimes on nothing but resolution to make a fitting income, carving out a fortune. Eight hundred may stand as a supior basi s . . &amp;quot;4 Yes,&amp;quot; he replied to her, &amp;quot; I like my experience of Ireland and the Irish; and better than I thought I should. St. Ge&amp;apos;s Channel ought to be c a oner by both of us.&amp;quot; -r always glad of th. sgnLal sid Dia. He allowed her int to remain perona, for te sake of a creeping that it carried through his blood. &amp;quot; Shall you soon be retuning to EnglandP&amp;quot; be vetured to ask &amp;quot; I an Lady Dunstane&amp;apos;s guest for som months&amp;quot; &amp;quot; The you wilL Sir LuIn has an estate in Surrey. He talks of quitting the Service.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I can&amp;apos;t believ it!&amp;quot; Hu thrilled blood was chilled. She entertained a sentiment amonting to adoration for the profession of arm! Gallntly had the veteran General and Hero held on into the night, that the festivity might not be dashed by his depare; perhaps, to a certain degree, to prolong his ejoment of a ftteng scene. At last Sir Lukin had the word fron, him, and ce to his wife. Diana slipped across the loor to her acco datingern whom, for the sake of another five minutes with her beloved Emma, she very agreeably persuaded to walk in the train . Lord larrian; and forth they trooped down a pathway of nodding heads and curtsies, resembling oak and birch-trees under a tempered gale, even to the shedding of leaves, for here a turban was picked up by Sir IuDin, there a jewelled ear-ring by the self-constituted attendant, lr. Thoma Redworth. At the portico rang a wakening cheer, realy worth hearing. The rain it rained, and hats were formless, as in the first eon of the edifice, backs were damp, boots liquidly musical, the pipe of consolation smoked with difficulty, with much palling at the stem; but the cheer aro m nificetly, and multiplied itself, touching at the same moment the heavens and Dianas heart-at least, drawing them together; for she fet exalted, enraptured, as pd of her country as of their hero. &amp;quot;6Thats the natural shamrock, after the artificial I&amp;quot; she heard Mr. Redworth say, behind her. She turned and sent ne of her brillint glances dying mee him, in gratitude for a timely word well said. And she never forgot the remark, nor he the look.</FullText></Record>