<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2467308</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130801</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>HOME AND FOREIGN AFFAIRS.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>178</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Oct 1881</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18811001</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Stead</LastName><MiddleName>T</MiddleName><FirstName>W</FirstName><PersonName>W T Stead</PersonName><OriginalForm>Stead, W. T.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>527</StartPage><EndPage>536</EndPage><Pagination>527-536</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2467308/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>HO&amp;quot; AND FOREIGN APFAiR ArIM lingering eleven weeks in protracted agony, sffering many things of many physicians, but nursed through the whole of that dreary time by his devoted wife, President Garfield died on the 19th of September, from the effects of the shot fired by Guiteau on July 2nd. The postmortem mination showed that from the first recovery was imposble, but until the last it was hoped and believed that he would recover. The many vicissitudes of his illness, the hope enca gd by his frequent rallies, the innumerable inciAents of the sick-room, reproduced in every newspaper in the Union, had concentrated to an unprecedented degree the interest of the English-speaking world on the sorely wounded man who carried on for so many weeks such an indomitable struggle with death. People had began to count upon his recovery as a certainty, when a change ensued for the worse, and during the last two days of his illness it is no exaggeration to say that the eyes of two nations were fixed upon the sick-chamber at Longbranch. When at last his death was announced the news was the signal for the most spontaneous and general mourning that ever united two nations in a common emotion. From the Queen to the vestry of Clerkenwell every one in this country joined in the transmission of sympathetic merges to America For the first time in our history there was absolute unanimity in the sentiments of the old country and the new, and in this universal outburst of a genuine sorrow among all English-speaking men may be seen a happy augury of the future union of the race. General Arthur took the presidential oath within three hours of his predecessor&amp;apos;s decease, and the executive power of the Government of fifty millions of men changed hands almost unnoticed amid the general grief. President Arthur, although belonging to the Grant-Conkling faction of the Republican party, is too shrewd as wefl as too patriotic a statesman to break roughly with the Cabinet on the policy of his predecessor. Without attempting to forecast the influence which the change is likely to have on the ediate future of American politics, it may safely be said that the tragic death of the chosen chief of the American Republic has done more to consolidate the union than anything that he could have effected by his life, and at the same time it has strengthened the ever-incesing ties of sympathy and affection which bind together the crowned and uncrowned democracies which speak the English tongue. After the death of the President the weather has been the most important factor in the history of the month. It has rained the harvest in England by excessive damp, while in the United States as excessive a heat has filled the American press with narratives of lamin forests and vast districts desolated by drought. The heat has suspended military operations in Algeria, and in Tanis the army of occption, fser-smitten, has been unable to make headway against the Arabs, on whose side fought the torrid rays of an African sun. The trace of the heat will soo be over, but the rain will leave more permanent marks on the political development of Great Britain. Three bad harvests in scion brought the Irish peasantry to despair, and compelled the imperial legilature to postpone all other work in order to effect a great economic and social revolution in the tenure of land in Ireland. It seems by no means improbable that the bad harvest which has cruelly dspointed the expectations of the English iulturist. may have results not less important than those which followed the failure of the crops in Ireland. A succession of bad years had brought many a British farmer to the verge of bankruptcy, from which he had indeed only eseaped by repeated but tempora remissions of rent. The fine promise of the opening year, and the brilliant sunshine of July, encouraged the agriculturist to hope that at last a bountiful harvest was to rewardhis labours, and enablehimoncemoreto feelsureof his position. When the time for the in-gathering arrived his hopes were blighted by a continued downpour of rain. Through the clondcovered Asy the sun shone, if at all, with a watery gleam portending further showers, and the promise was fulfilled. The cut corn sprouted in the stooks, and as day followed day with no intemission of the rain hope died in the farmer&amp;apos;s breast. The harvest which was to have put everything to rights had been spoiled. His last chance seemed to have disappeared, and it was with a heart heavy with despair he availed himself of the few belated days of suniine to gather in the damaged grain. The first immediate result of the unseasonable weather was the loss of a Liberal seat in North Lincolnshire For some time the Conservatives seemed to be unable to find a candidate, and Colonel Tomline had the field to himself. At last Sir. James Lowther, the original patentee of the art of political obstruction, who had the further distinction of having been one of the worst Irish Secretaries on record, volunteered to lead the forlorn hope. Appealing to the suffering farmers of North Lincoln, the sons of men who had been the staunch supporters of the Corn Laws, he boldly raised the standard of Protection. It was evident to the crowd whom he addressed in the pouring rain that the Liberals had not brought fine weather; and although Sir. Lowther did not venture to promise them sunshine in exchange for their suffrages, he did not hesitate to promise them an import duty on foreign corn. So far as his ability to keep his pledges was concerned he might as well have promised them sunshine; but whereas the veriest dolt can see that politicians have no control over the weather, distressed agriculturist may fail to see the reasons which place a corn law as far beyond the reach of our Chancellor of the Exchequer as the sun itselL The bait, however, took. Thefarmers rallied round the man who promised to tax the bread of the people to enable them to pay their rents to their landlords, and M1r. Lowther was returned by a majority of 471. The election in North Lincolonshire, followed as it was the next day by a second victory in North Durham, where Sir George Elliot won back his old seat by an alliance with Mr. Parneli, came as manna from on high to the disconsolate Conservatives. The &amp;quot; Fair Traders,&amp;quot; as the Protectionists style themselves, were elated. Every Conservative candidate-Colonel Knox in Tyrone, Mr. Bulwer in Cambridge, and Mr. Trotter in Berwick-hoisted the Protectionist flag; and even Sir Stafford Northcote so far forgot what was due to the keeper of the economical conscience of the Conservative party as to adopt at a political banquet at Sheffield the shibboleth of the new Protectionists, and make an equivocal declaration in favour of &amp;quot; fair trade.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I am a free-trader,&amp;quot; said the ex-Chancellor of the Exchequer, &amp;quot;but I desire to see free trade universal and fair.&amp;quot; His words were eagerly seized upon by his most energetic supporters to justify their adhesion to the &amp;quot; fair trade &amp;quot; propaganda, and the movement in favour of making trade brisk by making bread dear took larger proportions. The effect oi the Liberals was not less great. The manifestation of discontent on the part of the farmers drewattention to the necessity for redressing the grievances of the agriculturist. The fact that the Opposition were off on a false scent offered the Minis an opportunity of which they were not slow to avail themselves. The farmers of Aberdeenshire were the first to indicate the direction in which improvement was possible. After a series of meetings asking for a reduction of rent, the demand for a Land Bill on the lines of the Irish Land Act took formal shape. The demand was immediately endorsed by the Farmers&amp;apos; Alliance and the Trades Union Congress. The farmers&amp;apos; agitation spread to other Scotch counties, and during the contest in North Durham it was found that the northern farmers entertained the strongest opinions as to the necessity for effective legislative protection agaist the confiscation of their improvements. Tyrone election, where in spite of the vehement opposition of the Land League and the Orange lodges Mr. Dickson was returned at the head of the poll, seems to show that in Ulster the farmers are inclined to accept the Land Act with gratitude, and loyally co-operate with the English Liberals in theremoval of the other grievances of Ireland. But the victory in Tyrone was won under a restricted franchise. If the non-electors had voted, Mr. Dickson would hardly have been returned as the re ttive of a county more than one-half of whose population we Romn Catholics. The Land League Convention, which met in, Dublin on the 5th indant, displayed but little disposition to endse the verdict of Tyrone. It did not counsel the rejection of the Act tight out, which was so much gained, but it accepted it conditionally upon the understanding that if it did not reduce rents at leat one-half-Mr. Parnell asserted the only fair reduction was one of 88 per cent.-it could not be regarded as even a temporary settle,nent of the Land question. Too much importance, however, should not be attached to the cut and dried resolutionsubmitted to the Con-vention by men whose first anxiety was to continue to earn &amp;quot; the American money&amp;quot;-that is to say, the weekly subsidy of ?1,000 remitted to the treasurer of the Land Iea by the organ of American socialim, avowedly in order that the agrarian movement -in Ireland may be fostered for the benefit of the communistic propganda in the United States. The Land Act has not yet got into -operation, and some months must pass before it can be seen how far it is likely to remove the discontent of the Irish people. The negotiations for the renewal of the commercial treaty with France have been resumed with some prospect of a successfule AL Gambetta reaffirmed his belief in free trade principles in a speech at a banquet at Honfleur, and it is believed that the now Ministry, of which he is to be the head, will prove more amenable to common sense than the Cabinet of B. Ferry. England, excepting on political grounds, regards with comparative indiffernce the renewal of a treaty which, in appearance at least, is a concesion to an unsound economical principle- On political grounds, however, there is sufficient reason to rejoice at the resumption of negotiations which tend to bind more closely together the two great nations of the West. Of the need for strengthening the ties of friendship between England and France, the present month has afforded a striking example. In Egypt, the two Powers have entered into curious and anomalous ,partnership for the control of the government of the Khedive, which dt is much more easy to condemn than it is to explain how it can be terminated. Egypt is an integral part of the Ottoman Empire. Its affairs are therefore, from the point of view of international law, subject to the provision of the treaties of Berlin and Paria. All the powers are bound to abstain from isolated intervention in its afirs, as in those of any other province of the Turkish Empirem All of them ,are bound to deal with questions arising in the Nile valley in concert, as a matter of European concern. The whole tendency of English and French policy for many years has been to minims the control exercised by the Sultan over his vassal on the Nile, and under Ismael the tie which bound Cairo to Constantinople was of the slightest. The Khedive, excepting the performance of some formalities and the payment of a fixed tribute, was an independent sovereign in all but in name. Yet within the last two years all this has heas been re-versed. To secure the removal of Ismel, the Sultan was encouraged -to asert his right to depose at will the ruler of Egypt, and at the same time that Egypt was thrust back under the influence of Turkey-, Engand and France undertook an extraordinary and ill-defined function of control over the new Khedive. The inconsistency of their position was emphasised by the means which brought it about. If Egypt had been independent of Turkey, its control would not have concerned- the rest of Europe. But the control was assumed or ooliidated simultaneously with the assertion by the Sultan of a sovereignty which brought Egypt within the region from which all but the concerted action of all the powers was expressly excluded. The control was financial, not administrative. The controllers were paidr by the Khedive, and although they had a right to attend all councils of the Ministry, they had no voice in its decisions. The arrangement was malo to the last degree, but as the other Powers did not protest, and the joint control exercised by Mr. Colvin and M1. de Blignieres at Cairo, produced indistable benefits to the dwellers in the Nile valley, to say nothing of the subsidiary advantage to Europe of Maintaining order and tranquillity in Egypt, it came to be regarded as both natural and expedient. It rested, however, on a very precarionu basis. The good-will or the impotence of the Khedive, the acquiescence of the Sultan, the absence of any opposition on thepart of the others powers, the- cordial co-operation of the repre-s sentatives of England and Egypt, and the submission of the army, were all esstial to its success. It was endangered by the intrigues of the French Consul-General de Ring. He was recalled, and the danger of a rapture was averted. A more formidable peril disclosed itself in the insbordination of the army. Biaz Pasha, in many respects an excellent minister, was too weak to keep the army under control. Repeated displays of aspirit of insbordiation wre left pishd, and more than once it seemed as if the colonels were becoming the supreme power in the State. This mutinous siWrit culminated on &amp;apos;the 10th of Sepitember, when Ourabi Bey surrounded the Abdin Palace with 4,000 soldiers and demanded the dimnissal of ia Pasha on threat of deposition. &amp;quot;oWe have your successor ready,&amp;quot; said Ourabi to the Khedive; and the Khedive, instead of taking Mr. Colvin&amp;apos;s advice and boldly arresting the insolent although timorous mutineer, condescended to treat with him. Ourabi insisted on the dismissal of Riaz, but consented that his other demands, viz. the increase of thearmy to 18,000 men and the concession of a constitution, should be referred to Constantinople. Cherif Pasha, after some hesitation, and a period of suspense, when something like a panic reignedamong the European residents, consented to take office. His conditions having been conceded, the colonels declared their submission, and for the moment the crisis was averted. It had lasted long* enough to excite serious alarm in London and Paris, and to display in a very striking light the perils of the system of joint control. It was- admitted by both Governments that it was impoible to allow Egypt to fail into the hands cf a mob of mutinous soldiery, but beyond this preliminary agreement it seemed hopeless to come to an understanding. A section of the French press loudly accused England of having brought about the pronunciamento immediately after the departure of If. de Blignieres, and all the Parisian papers were unanimou in declaring that on no account whatever should the Sultan be allowed to send troops to disperse the mutineers. On this side the Channel protestations as vigorous were made against the landing of a single French soldier in Egypt, and inferentially against the Anglo-French expedition which was believed to be in favour with the French Ministry. If the Khedive appealed to the Sultan for assistance, England and France, it was contended, ought not to take the responsibility of vetoing the despatch of such forces as might be requisite to restore the authority of the Khedive. Their influence might be more legitimately employed in providing stringent guarantees against the abuses which usually follow in the train of an Ottoman o o These views were vigorously combated in Paris, and fortunately the timely arrangement of a compromise obviated the necessity for calling in force of any kind. The crisis, however, lasted long enough to show that there was an irreconcilable difference of opinion between the Powers which exercise the control as to the means to be adopted for reducing the colonels to submon, and that there was an evident desire on the part of at least one of the other Powers to aail itself of any deadlock at Cairo to insist upon sharing the position now occupied exclusively by England and France. The situation is dangerous, and no one as yet seems willing to propose the only real solution of the difficulty, the conversion of Egypt from a Turkish pachalic into an Oriental Belgium, whose and neutrality is guaranteed by all the Powers. If another Leopold could be secured for the throne of the Pharouls, such a solution would sastorily ve the problem which might at any moment involve this country in serious difficulties if not in actual war. The state of Europe is not exactly that in which England can afford to leave open a question of such vital interest to her imperial position as the sovereignty of the Nile Valley. The day before Ourabi Bey made his pronunciamento at the Abdin Palace the triple alliance of the military empires was reconstituted at Dantzic, where the Czar and the Kaiser met for the purpose of proclaiming the renewal of the Kaiserbund. Pince Bismarck was present at the interview; General Ignatief was not. The significance of the accident is variously interpreted, but it is believed that the Czar&amp;apos;s lchief object was to declare his adhesion to the old maxim which has governed the policy of Russia-&amp;quot; Nearest neighbours, fastest friends&amp;quot; -and to secure the support of his imperial neighbous in the projected raffia of revolutionists throughout the Continent. If the Nihlsts were but denied shelter by the civilised world the emperors imagine they would be safe, but the chances are all the other way. Sophie Peroffkid and her accomplices never quitted Russia till they were hanged. Vera Savsulitch shot General Trepoff before she went abroad, and Solvieff shot at the Czar without having crossed the Russian frontier. A few more assassins might be hanged, but as *ss tins are almost invariably attempted by those over whom the power of the Czar is already absolute, the sug ed international crusade against the Nihilists will not effect much beyond malking Nihilists more desperate. They are less dangerous outside Russia than within. If the whole of Europe were to be converted into a Russian gaol it would not in the least remove the temptation to strike at the chief gaoler. The attempt, however, is likely to be made, and it is to be regretted that England&amp;apos;s position vi8-d-vis any such attempt to limit the freedom of asylum has been seriously weakened by the incredible folly of the speeches of the Home Secretary concerning the threats of O&amp;apos;Donovan Roes. It is doubtful whether England can rely upon any ally in Europe in mintaining the right of asylum. Switzerland has already expelled Prince Krapotkin, whom Mr. Cowen has engaged to deliver a series of lecture in this country upon the internal state of Russia. Italy and Austria will probably follow the lead of the Northern Courts. France, uponwhom we oughtto have beenable torely, isinnoposition to render effective. assistanc The stock-jobbing speculation which plunged her into war with Tunis has practically deprived her of that freedom of action which shehad but recently regained sce the ls of Alsace and Lorraine. Every month that has passed since she dictated the treatyto the unfortunate Beyhas increased her difficulties inAfrica. Southern Algeria has to be reconquered, and in Tunis the work of conquest has to be begun. She has sent 50,000 men to Africa since hostilities began, and she could not prevent the Arabs from cutting off the water supply of the capital. Nor can she exercise authority over a foot of Tunisian territory not covered by the range of her guns She has occupied with or without bombardment various forts on the sea-coas, but inland the Arabs are masters of the situation. A march upon Kairouan, ordered weeks ago, has not been carried out, General Sabatier&amp;apos;s column not having been able to get beyond at Zaghouan. The young soldiers, unaccustomed to ckmpaigning under an African sun, have sickened and died. The hospitals are crowded, and every day fever sweeps off its ill-fated victims It is no longer the uirs or Bou Amema with whom France has to cope. She is face to face with Arab Africa in arms The tribes are in motion from Morocco to Tripoli, and for months to come she will find ample occupation for her energies in asserting her authority over insurgent Idam. To conciiiate Spain she has promised to pay, with a view to action in Morocco, two million francs indemnity to the ruined colonists of Oran, and all her protests have failed to peent the heavy reinfement of the Ottoman garrison in Tripoli IL Roustan&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;war for business&amp;quot; is not turning out to be such a good speuat as he anticipated, and the whole of the West suffers from the baleful a ndenc which stockjobbers have been able to secre in the politics of France. The result of the French elections was definitely ascertined after the ballotage of the 4th September. The new Chambers will consist of 457 Republicans of various shades, 47 Baparti, and 43 rist. On the whole the Repblicans have gained 71 seats from the reactionary parties, whose grow poll fell from 3,577,882 in 1877 to 1,789,767, or almost exactly one-halt There we 2,997,902 abstentions an increase of 1,136,776 on the numbers who did not vote in 1877. The aggregate R blican vote, which rose from 4,028,153 to 4,367,202 in 1877, amounted to 5,128,442 in 1881. The collapse of the Monarchical parties is vr remarkable, and there is the customary quantum of su g among the reactionists as to the cause of their defeat. It may be attributed largey to the fact they had nothing to offer France but a baen pr e of revolution in the interest of detested dynasties. What is much more able is the collapse of the Catholicoposition to the anticlaical crusaders. It says but little for the practical sincerity of the Catholics of France that they should have made so poor a protest against the domination of the party which has declared war against the religious orders and demands the separation of Church and state. The Tabkt is disgusted at what it terms &amp;quot; the cowardly submision of reckless negligence &amp;quot; dispayed by the French Conservatives. There is much force in the bitter taunt of the Englis organ of the Roman Church that&amp;quot; A party which practipally mn the rpeinmntatio of rance only ten yea ago, and which could have done anything it liked if it had known how to be united, tolerant, and bnsi, but which has allowed every advantage to be snatched out of its nervels hands, can hardly be expected to exhibit amidst the ie t of dehat virile virtues which even the consciousnes of power and the sense of duty could not develop. The copious use of pious xresons, doubtless sincere, and the systematic refunal, doubtle conscientious, evn to stir out of doors to give a vote against a repesentativeof irreligion, appear to be the confirmed tactics by which a large section of the Conservatives of Prance imagine that they are heroically defending the threatened interests of religion, morality, and society.&amp;quot; R us conviction that is not sufficiently strong to make its possessor walk to the polling-booth can hardly be regarded as worthy the nane, and of all the evidence that is accm ulating to prove how little hold the Church retains on the French people the most conclwive is supplied by the clericals themselves. It is very ictive to note the geographical distribution of party strength in France as revealed by the general elections. Fify out of the ninety de nt of France are entirely Rpblican. The republicanism of nineteen others is marred in each case by the return of one &amp;quot;Irectionary.&amp;quot; There are only eight deprtent in which the Mona and Imperialists possess a majority of the representatives, and there is not one depent even inLa Vend&amp;amp; where the Republia have not succeeded in returning at least one member. The whole of the easter deprtments are exclusively Republican The strength of the Monarchists lies in the west. Roughly seking, the north-west is Royalist, the south-west Bonapartist, while there is a strong Monarchical element along the northern coast. At least half of the maritime de ts in the north and west return Conservatives; but the departments on the inland frontiers and the Mediterranean are almost without exception Republican. Much more important than the geographical distribution of parties is the distribution of party strength in the new Chamber. A warm discussion has raged ever since the elections as to the constitution of the new majority. At first every one assumed that the majority was Gambettist and revisionist, or, as we would say, advanced Liberal. Even M. Ferry seemed to take this view of the situation until he discovered in the electoral reverses sustained by M. Gambetta&amp;apos;s henchmen reasons for believing that the new Chamber would tolerate the old Ministry. - Broadly speaking, the Republican deputies may be divided into three groups: (1) the Extreme Lefts, small in number, but energetic and strong in the support of the great cities; (2) the Republican Union, which is Gambettist and revisionist, and numbers above 200 members; and (3) the Republican Left, representing the Ministerial majority in the late Chamber, which numbers 145 members. At first sight the Republican Union has obviously the best claim to be considered as the nucleus of the future majority. But it was discovered by ingenious supporters of the Ferry Ministry that 88 members of the Republican Union might fairly be classed with the Extreme Left. By adding these 88 names to the Extr s and deducting them from the Republican Union, the Republican Left becomes the most numerous group, and may on that account claim to be regarded as the centre of the new majority. IL Ferry, and it is believed ML Grivy, favour this pretension, which is vehemently den ed by the Gambettists, who insist that the majority of the new Chamber belongs to the Republican Union, and that it is pledged to take in hand at once the revision of the Senate. &amp;amp;rutts de lute is dropped until the next general election draws near; but M. Gambetta seems disposed to insist upon the revision of the Constitution if only to distgish his followers from those of 3L Ferry. There is no doubt that ML. (mbetta received a severe personal check at the late elections, which to some extent impaired the effect of his political triumph. But it is equally indisthlile that the new majority is more advanced than the old, and also that ML Gambetta is beyond comparion the most powerfid as well as the most skilu of all the statesmen of France. His recent rever will have done him good service if they teach him the necessity of exerting himself as the actual leader, inset-d of posing as the veiled dictator, of the French Republic. The neighbours of France display no indication of any intention to take advantage of the di i on of her army consequent upon the war in Northern Africa. Prince Bismarck, preoccupied with financial anxieties, and desring of being able to secure the establishment of the tobacco monopoly by any other means, has gone hafway to Canossa by sanctionmig the appointment of Dr. Korum as Bishop of Treves. The COulture-Kampf is thus tacitly abandoned, a native of Alsace-Lorraine is raised to the Episcopal throne, and at a moment when the French Republic is entering with a light heart upon a fresh campaign against Clericalism, the German Chancellor comes to term with the Pope. The change is momentous If it succeeds, Prince Bismarck, who never does things by halves, and patronises as energetically as he persecutes, may yet be regarded as the Defensor Fdei of the nineteenth century, and if not the eldest yet the stoutest son of the Church. Such a r6l would stand him in good stead on both his frontiers with the Catholics of Poland and of the French provinces. But before the transformation is complete the Prince will probably wait to see how the Clerical vote will go at the coming elections, which are now fixed for the 27th of October. The senatorial elections in Spain have resulted in the return of a large Ministerial majority. it is expected that &amp;quot;ehor sagasta will avail himself of the support of an obedient Cortes to decree civil marriage, not so much for the sake of would-be brides and bidegoms who object to the religious cerenony, as to assert the supr of the State over the Church. In Italy the Ministry have sueslly combatted an attempt by the intriguers, who are bent upon baffling the more idberal instincts of the Pope to manufacture an international difficulty out of the distances which were provoked by the Vaticanists on the occasion of the removal of the body of the late Pope to its find resting-place. The race rivalry Which otitutes the great domestic difficulty of the heterogeneous Empire of the Hapsburg continues to disturb the peace of the ljds where Tcheques and Germans contend for the mastery, and itensifies the hostility with which the Magyar press declaims against every manifestation of Russian activity in Eastern Europe. Greece has succeeded in occupying, without bloodshed, the province of Thessaly-an achievement of European diplomacy almost uprecedented in history. But according to close observers at Athens the completion of the occupation may mark the beginning of the end of King George&amp;apos;s reign, ad, as a sequel to the libeation of their kins6Ak the Greeks may eaipate their race from the yoke of the Monarchy. Byrdh I269I, l -UL</FullText></Record>