<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2467210</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130318</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>A JOKE OR A JOB?</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>223</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Jul 1885</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18850701</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><OriginalForm>A MEMBER OF CONVOCATION.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Escott, Thomas Hay Sweet, 1844-1924</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>102</StartPage><EndPage>107</EndPage><Pagination>102-107</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2467210/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>A JOKE OR A JOB? Taaaz eminent personages in the University of Oxford, aisted by two colleagues less eminent in person than by office, have lately indulged themselves in what the censorious desmibe as a job, and the charitable prefer to regard as a joke. The present writer, who under an urgent but very smmse of duty takes up his pen to review this performane is himelf extremely reluctant to adopt the former description of it, and will be only too glad if his readers find it in their power to satisfy themselves with the latter. He proposes to hold his own judgment in complete suspense on the question. He cannot, it is true, afford to ignore the existence and the weight of one consideration which makes for the less charitable view, and which is, that whereas most persons-and indeed nearly all acdemical persons entrusted with patronage-are capable of the perpetration of a job, it is certain as anything not mathematically proved can be, that the three principal actors concerned in this incident are quite incapable of a joke. The writer, however, has no desire to pres this argument in a vindictive spirit It must have occuned already to everyone competent to pronounce an opinion upon the election, and the electors, to that new Chair of English literature which Mr. Napier, of Gottingen, has been recently chosen to fill. Let it be admitted too, on the other hand, that there are many things connectedwith the aHir which tend to favour the theory of a joke. There is, first, the very title of the new Chair, the &amp;quot;M 3erton Professorship of English Language and Literature.&amp;quot; Now to be a professor of English literature is admittedly to bear an honourable title; but to talk or write of a man as a &amp;quot;Professor of English language,&amp;quot; is not to talk or write English,-except perhaps in the sense in which, according to a well-known story, Burton, of the Anatom y of fauhely, may be aid to have found &amp;quot;professors of nglish language&amp;quot; in the barges under Folly Bridge. The new professor could hardly fail to be on terms of some constraint with, for instance, the Ad Corpus Professor of the Latin Language and Literature&amp;quot; But intending candidates generously consented as a rule to waive this critical objection, the more so as the Commissioners under the Universities Act, 1877, if dealing too parsimoniously with the new Chair in respect to the definite article, had in the matter of emolumentb been liberal to it indeed. The new professor was to receive a stipend of ?700 a year, and to hold during his tenure of offioe a fellowship at Merton worth ?200 a year more. This undoubtedly is a very handsome salary, and the ap t of its amount had the natural effect of conlirming many gentlemen in a conviction of their complete fitness for the post. Intending straigltway divided themselves into two parties, the one hastening to inquire into the precise nature and amount of the new professor&amp;apos;s duties; the other, and the more worldly-wise, proceeding to inform themselves of the constitution of the Board of Electors. The result of this latter inquiry was to send manyof theinquirers in amused amaement to the &amp;quot; Universities of Oxford and Cambridge Act, 1877,&amp;quot; to rresh their memory as to the names of the Commissioners by whom the board of election to this professorship was devised Which was the humourist among them ? For the composition of the board was a maserpiece of humour. Lord Redesdale and Dean Bradley are grave persons; and since the gigantic practical joke which he helped to play off upon his country in the year 1872 at Washington, the Right Hon. Mountague Bernard is not known to have perpetrated any other. The President of St. John&amp;apos;s has a dry humour, and so, in greater abundance, had the late Professor Henry Smith; but one can hardly suppose that it would readily take the peculiar form of drollery which is here exhibited. &amp;quot;Subject,&amp;quot; say the Commissioners, &amp;quot;to any exercise of the power of the University to regulate or varyfrom time to time the constitution of the board, in other respects the board shall consist of (1) The Regius Professor of Moder History; (2) the Corpus Christi Professor of Comparative Philology; (3) the principal librarian of the British Museum; (4) Bodley&amp;apos;s librarian; (5) a member of Merton College, appointed by the College on the occasion of eawh election to act as an elector on that occason.&amp;quot; There is a simplicity about these selections-a simplicity suggestive not so much of their learned and right honourable authors as of an equal number of honest country gentlemen summoned to the performace of an honourable but unfamiliar duty-which the most artistic comedian might envy. We picture to ourselves one of the worthy squires suggsting that a professor of modem history was sure to know something about English literature, and a professor of comparative philology something about &amp;quot; English language; &amp;quot; another observing that there was &amp;quot;a power of books, they did tell him,&amp;quot; in the British Museum; and a third that there was quite as many of them in the Bodleian as would serve to give any man who was always looking after them a taste for literature. Like many a good joke, however, it owed its sharpest point to a pure piece of luck. For, though the Commisioners could select the fficees which should make their holders ex oemo electors to the professorsip, they could not, of course, know by whom and what manner of men these particular offices would at any given moment be filled. They could decree the delegation of a member of Merton, of the Corpus Professor of Comparative Philology, and of the Regius Professors of History to places on the board; but in two out of these cases they could not have foreseen that it was not axy professor among professors, not a o ViNuv among Merton dons, whom they were appointing, but that with the comparatively philological Mr. Max Muller would be joined suck a Merton don as Mr. Brodrick, and above all suc/s a professor as Mr. Edward Augustus Freeman. Could they have known that, between the date of their deliberations and the first election to the new Chair, the erudite Dr. Stubbs would, in the inscrutable counsels of the Prime Minister, have been called to the Episcopate, and that Mr. Freeman, long his disinterested admirer, would have become his successor? No; it was not they, but Fortune, Fortune lAdum inolstem ludere perttiyax, who had decreed that Professor Freeman should be commissioned to adjudicate upon the contending claims of a body of candidates, many of whom would belong to a clas Which he loves and by which he is beloved, and to some of whom he would perhaps have endeared himself by his modest d o in newspaper controversies, or by the recollections of his chivalrous courtesy as examiner in the Schools. Of the qualifications of the Board of Electors to decide between the purely literary claims of the various candidates there was, fortunately, no doubt. Professor Freeman&amp;apos;s English style is as rmrkable for its grace as his demeanour, and pos all the subtlety and flexibility of his mind. Professor Max Muller writes &amp;quot;English language &amp;quot; like a born German, and with all the ease and freedom which belong to that birthright. Of the Warden of Merton, cidered as a critic of competing critics, it is only necessary to recall the fact that he was once a diinguied contnbutor to the Times. This is not to say, of course, that he used to write all, or even any, of those masterly criticisms of contemporary English literature with which each successive editor of the Times, from Barnes to Buckle, has so tastefuly adorned its outer sheet in the occasional absence of any superior kind of padding. But Mr. Brodri*c, if not a reviewer, wasa leader-writer, and the leaders of the Tims have many of the literary merits of its reviews. Of the critical attainments of Mr. Bond and Mr. Nicholmn nothing definite is known, but they are both believed to have an extensive acquntance with books. I imagins, however, that few even among the most simple-minded of the candidates believed that either Mr. Nicholson or Mr. Bond would have much to say to the appointment. The belief was that Mr. Bond would say ditto to Mr. Nicholson, and that Mr. Nicholson would say ditto to the three eminent persoages. And by way of more precisely se ing the votes of these two estimable nonentities, some people went so far as to say that there were not three eminent personages, but one eminent personage, to wit, Professor Freeman. Considering, further, that the humourists of the Universities Commission had, of their drollery, thought fit to provide that the Professorship of English and Literature might at the will of the University be united to the Professorship of Anglo-Saxon, there was not much doubt how the interests of unfortunate English literature would fare in the competition with &amp;quot; English language.&amp;quot; Professor Freeman would find in the alleged necessity of eecting an AngloSaxon scholar an additional excuse for dissembling his love of literary person These persons, however, are notoriously sanguine and imaginative, and it was actually believed among them that though the board might lean somewhat too much perhaps to the interests of philology, they would not go quite so far as to ignore the interests of criticism altogether. If &amp;quot; English language &amp;quot; got a little advantage over English literature, it would not, they thought, be quite allowed to monopolise the attention of the electors But those who believed this did not know their men or rather their man. They did not know what Professor Freeman could do when he had before him the double opportunity of administeinag a rebuff to a whole class of persons whom he detests, and of demonstrating his high-approval of that order of intelligence and that line of studies which most resemble his own. The electors or the grand elector, resolved to treat the Chair as simply a Chair of ,English language,&amp;quot; and to fill it as such; and their success in their search for its proper occupant so far exceeded all expectations as to recall the well-known descriptive account of the elections to the AU Souls&amp;apos; fellowships The Warden and Fellows of that college were wont, it was said, to enter the college chapel and there to pray that it might be granted to them to elect a &amp;quot; Christian gentleman ;&amp;quot; and so efficacious were their prayers that they were in many instances guided by Divine Providence to the election of a Christian nobleman. So Mr. Freeman and his coadjutors, praying that their choice might light upon a &amp;quot; sound scholar,&amp;quot; were actually permitted to catch an &amp;quot;&amp;apos; extraordinary professor at a German university.&amp;quot; Of Mr. Arthur S. Napier&amp;apos;s philological qualifications-the only qualications which, to do him justice, he professes to poess-I raise no question at alL Evidently he ha been an enthusiastic student of &amp;quot;English language,&amp;quot; since its attractions were able, after a short conflict, to vanquish those of the study of German &amp;quot; scientific works.&amp;quot; Nor do I make it a serious ground of objection to Mr. Napier that he did not apparently find out that he had a mother tongue until, not content with having obtained a first class in natural science, he pursued his choen abject into the receses of &amp;quot;modern German,&amp;quot; whence he was guided, by way of the &amp;quot; older Germa dialects and Anglo-Saxon,&amp;quot; to the discovery aforesaid. But really we must ask why, if the electors required a Professor of Anglo-Saxon, they did not elect Mr. Earle, the present excellent professor of that language in the University, and by uniting his Chair with this newly founded one -a they have power to do under the Statute-thus secure their Prolessor of English Language and Literature, without creating the gratuitous anomaly involved in the co-existence of two professorships of Angl-Saxon. With every desire to take the most charitable view of Mr. Napier&amp;apos;s selection, one is really compelled to repeat the question with which I started, &amp;quot;s Was it a joke or a job ? &amp;quot; To elect a student of Anglo-Saxon (for such Mr. Napier is, so far as Oxford is concerned), to a chair of literature at Oxford, seems more like a joke than a job; but then, on the other hand, to elect a student of AngloSaxon to a chair of literature for which a Professor of Anglo-Saxon was a candidate, seens more like a job than a joke. Let me, however, in justice to myself, though I fear at the risk of irreparably damaging the case of the electors, recall what has been sad on their behalf. What has been mid on their behalf is in effect that whoever has ventured to say anything against them is simply a presumptuous ignoramus. That is the acute and elegant rejoinder. A writer signing himself -,,M. A.&amp;quot; protested against the tone which the Pal aMa Gaztte and other journals were &amp;quot; taking against the accomplished scholar and trained professor who has just been appointed to the new Chair. A set of smart article-writers make a plunge at the tempting prize of ?900 a year for a professorship of the English language and literature, and because one of their set has not won the prize they are all yelping directly, or indirectly [what is an indirect yelp?] at the sound scholar who has won it. They put the words of the statute founding the profe ip at defiance; ignored the first subject, the English language, of the history and development of which most of them were profndl ignorant, and resolved that the new professorship should be one of literature as they conceive it. That i, that the lucky man should be able to write forty-two showy critical papers on English authors, or the sources of their books, and sell as many of them as he could to any journal that would buy them. The ignorance of their own languge&amp;apos;s history which these journalisic people show, is naturally matched by a like ignorance of the writers of that history. Of course they have not been watching the rising men in England and abroad. Of course they do not know how good a man Professor Napier is. Let them, then, hold their spiteful and arrogant tmgues till they have found out.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Spiteful and arrogant,&amp;quot; quotha! This is the devil rebuking sin indeed. But surely it is impossibae not to recognise the sweet urbanity of this style; surely that phrase, &amp;quot;oof the history and development of which most of them are profoundly ignorant,&amp;quot; unmistakbly accuses its author. He signs himself a graduate of two letters only, instead of three; but surely there can be but one Lord Peter in Oxford, who, &amp;quot;to convince us what a parcel of blind, positive, ignorant, wilful puppies &amp;quot; we are, &amp;quot;d would use but this one plain argument,&amp;quot; that a Professor of Anglo-Saxon is a &amp;quot;s true, good, natural Professor of English Language and Literature &amp;quot; as any to be found in England, and &amp;quot;may we be eternally confounded if ever we offer to believe otherwise !&amp;quot; In the argument, too, there is all the dialectical dexterity which we have been taught to expect from the Regius Professor of Modern History. The critics of this appointment are accused of &amp;quot;ignoring the first subject of the professorip-the English language,&amp;quot; when the electors have quietly ignored not only its second subject, but, it may fairly be argued, both of them, since, whatever &amp;quot;English language,&amp;quot; as distinct from &amp;quot; the English language,&amp;quot; may be, it is presumably not Anglo-Saxon. And it to be necessary that one or other of the two subjects, language or literature, should be comparatively ignored, it is matter of common knowledge to all: outside the narrow clique to which the insolent pedant whom I have quoted belongs, that among the foremost critics of the day there are many men far more competent to deal philologically with our language than any pure philologist-and Mr. Napier honestly admits that he is no more-could ever be to deal critically with our literature. When, lastly, I add that this professorship is, by the conditions of its tenure, essentially a teaching professorship, and not one founded for the encouragement of original research, I hope I shall have done enough to show that, whether the election of Mr. Napier to the Merton Chair of English Language and Literature be a joke or a job, it is most assuredly a scandaL The chief responsibility for this scandal is easily apportioned. Whoever &amp;quot; M. A.&amp;quot; may be, there can be no doubt in the mind of anybody- acquainted even by reputation with the gentleman whom I have ventured to call the &amp;quot; grand elector,&amp;quot; that the letter to which these two initials are subscribed, is a perfectly faithful reflection of the state of that gentleman&amp;apos;s mind with reference to the comparative claims of &amp;quot; language &amp;quot;-as he conceives of language-end literature as he would scorn to conceive of it. To him language, whether &amp;quot;&amp;apos;English&amp;quot; or other, means not a breathing organism, but the chemical constituents either of an unquickened embryo, or of a dead body. It means this to him,. just as English history meaw to him a conscientious &amp;quot; restoration &amp;quot; of the theatre of our ancient institutions, with every plank and joist religiously re-fitted in its place, but without the semblance of a living actor on the stage. How should such a man be expected to care any more for &amp;quot; literature,&amp;quot; than a professor of organic chemistry cares as such for the outlines of the &amp;quot; Meleager,&amp;quot; or a stage-arpenter for the poetry of ? A NImR OF CoNvocAnoN.</FullText></Record>