<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2468093</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127131002</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>THE STAGE IN RELATION TO LITERATURE.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>199</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Jul 1883</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18830701</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Review</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Lytton</LastName><PersonName>Lytton</PersonName><OriginalForm>LYTTON</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Lytton</LastName><FirstName>Robert</FirstName><PersonName>Robert Lytton</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lytton, Robert</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><OriginalForm>Escott, Thomas Hay Sweet, 1844-1924</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>12</StartPage><EndPage>26</EndPage><Pagination>12-26</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2468093/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>THE STAGE IN RELATION TO LTERATURE. IN the last April number of the Quarterly Rertew the writer of a very interesting paper on the English stage has observed that &amp;quot; it is to the existence of a yearning for something more worthy &amp;quot; (than such pieces as Our Boys, The Colonel, et id genns orne) &amp;quot; of the traditional glories of the English stage, that Mr. Irving largely owes the immense success which has attended his management at the Lyceum.&amp;quot; This appears to be the conclusion of a competent and impartial observer; for which reason it must be welcomed by all who have at heart the dignity and prosperity of that great department of our national literature now unoccupied by any writer of literary eminence. But the condition and prospects of the literary drama in England suggest questions more easily asked than answered; and the following desultory remarks upon the subject of them are offered in an interrogative rather than an affirmative spirit. These remarks I wish to prefiace by a proposition which is perhaps a truism; but which, if not disputed, has apparently been disregarded, by those whom it most concerns. The social civilisation of a people is signifi y indicated by the incharacter of its popular amusements, and of such amuement the stage is one of the most important Experience has repeatedly proved the power of the stage as an educational agency for the diffusion, not only of popula refinement, but also of those ideas and sentiments which strengthen and elevate national character. When Count Stephen Szechenyi, the Great Magyar, as his countrymen still call him, began to devote himself to the regeneration of their national life, his first efforts were directed to the creation of a national stage; and he spared no pa to attract to it all the literary talent of his country. The revival of the Maryar language, which inaugurated the reassertion of the Magyar nationality, had been accomplised on the stage before it was extended to the Diet; and if a true and full history is ever written of the great constitutional movement began by Hungary in 1848, some of its most instructive pages must be devoted to the part played by the national stage in the resuscitation of the national spirit. From their national stage the spirit of the German people received a similar stimulus during a period of great national depression, and the grateful affection with which they still cherish the memory of Schiller attests the national influence of his genius; which is, I think, underrated by his English critices. Goethe excels every poet since Shakespeare in breadth of intellect and subtlety of insight, but Shiller far surpasses him in that moral elevation which is the primary requisite of the poetic drama. It was, I think, a saying of Roger Ascham&amp;apos;s, that man, in order to live up to his level, must keep constantly before him an ideal of excellence above and beyond it. But uneducated sentiment is continually running into vulgar types; and to counteract this tendency, the stage (if it fulfilled its literary and truly national function) would keep the heroic type permanently and plainly before the imagination of the people. &amp;quot;The great movements of the soul,&amp;quot; says Talma, &amp;quot;elevate man to an ideal nature in whatever ranik fate may have placed him.&amp;quot; To portray the great movements of the soul in such a manner. as shall have the effect of elevating whole masses of human beings into a perception of this &amp;quot;ideal nature,&amp;quot; and a sympathetic contact with it, is the purpose of the poetic drama and the function of the great actor. Authors and actors who have themselves no perception of an ideal nature not visible on the surface of society, and to whom the movements of the soul appear exaggerated or artificial when they cease to be commonplace, do well, no doubt, to leave the poetic drama alone. But a literature and a stage which cannot, between them, produce any school or specimen of poetic drama, have no place in the first order of the intellectual departments to which they belong. In the days of Chatham, when the national life of England was throbbing with a vigorous pulse, when parliamentary eloquence had attained its noblest standard, and the tendency of the national action was instinctively towards the heroic, the intellectual influence of the great actor was not inferior to that of the great orator, and the stage co-operated with the Senate in the maintenance of a lofty national type. I do not know whether any historian of the French Revolution has yet tried to trace the influence of the French classical drama upon the formation of those types of social and personal character which seem to have represented the revolutionary ideals of republican excellence. But this influence is perceptible and noteworthy. Read, for instance, such a play as the Horaces of Corneille; wherein the ideal presence which pervades the whole action, shapes the whole character, and inspires the whole language of the drama, powerfully impressin its influence at every point upon the imaginto of the audience, is that of Rome herself; a supreme semi-supernatural but very real political entity, majestic and inexorable, s but sublime; the sacrificial unflinching, uncomplaining worship of whose power constitutes the whole duty of the virtuous citizen. And then tum to the language and action of the first French republicans. Were they not animated by the spirit which the genius of Corneille has breathed into this great play? To me it seems that all that part of the political vocabulary of the first French Republic which was not directly borrowed from Rousseau teems with involuntary echoes from the French classical drama. And perhaps it would not be altogether ntastical to assert that, whils Richelieu and Louis XIV. were unconsciously preparing for the Republic the material conditions of its a tie despot, the great dramatists of their time were no less uncoioy providing for it some of the sources of its political sentiment and animating spirit. The sanguina despotism of the iepublic, in its turn, prepared the conditions of that brilliant and bellicose autocracy which rapidly rose upon its ruins. And, again, the thoroughly practical intellect of Napoleon, rejecting no imaginative agency, recognised at once in the national stage, and the genius of Talma, potent inestruents for the promotion or ideas conducive to the grandeur and conquering spirit of his Empire. But it is needless to multiply instances of the influence which a literary stage is capable of exciting, for good or evil over national charatebr. I say advisedly, a literary stage. For if the stage be illiterate it can have no influence at al. And, although unintellectual influnce, when they take of those popular amusements which (unlike field-sports and athletic games) are to be clased amongst intellectual recreations, may stunt or pervert the popular taste, it is not conceivable that a stage destitute of ideas should have any efct, good or bad, on the ideals of national character. Loooking, however, at the stage in relation to its minor function, as ainstrument for the diffusion of social refinement, I may mention here, by the way, a curious il of its power in that capacity, which happens to have fallen under my own observation. Many years ago, it was one of my official duties, as Secretary of Embassy at Vienna, to study the social cnition of the Austrian working classes. - With this object I attended their political clubs and pLae of public amusent, v ed them in their homes, and became at last fairly intimate with the leading meambers of their principal unions. I do not thin they are naturally so igent as our own working classes; but what most struck me in my intercourse with them was their superior social renement, and their apparet literary culture. This I aftewrds1 discovered to be the result of their amiliar with the m ofa nao stage which includes auongst its most poplar dramatists many of the greatest poets and thinkers of Germany. In the absence of any perceptible alliance between her contemporary literature and her contemporary stg, England, at the present moment, stands alone amongst the civilised nations of Europe. In all other European countries po g a national literature, the acting drama still contributes to the continuation of that literature as fully and worthily as any other department of it. You cannot enumerate the authors of the best plays produced during the last fifty years upon the French stage without naming many of the greatest imaginative writers and teachers of France. The same may be said, relatively, of the German, Italian, Spanish, and Danish stages. I mention these as the only ones of which I have any personal knowledge. The dramatic literature of France has added, and is adding, treasures to the rich store of genuine plays bequeathed it by the genius of Corneille and Racine and Molihre. The dramatic literature of Germany has not ceased to be productive since the death of Goethe, and Schiller, and Lessing. That of Italy has not stopped short with Alfieri. Calderon is not the last word of the Spanish national drama, nor Oehlenschlager of the Danish. How does the dramatic literature of our own country happen to be so impoverished that the succesul revival of plays written in the reign of Elizabeth is regarded by us as the most important effort which our stage is capable of making for the perpetuation in the popular mind of the noble traditions of the literary drama ? At the beginning of the Victorian age the English stage could boast, at least, of having assoiated with itself in this laudable endeavour some writers of literary eminence; but since then, English authors and actors appear to have grown mutually satisfied with the complete dissolution of that old and honourable paterhip between them to which our literature owes the comedies of Sheridan and our stage its &amp;quot;traditional glories.&amp;quot; And thus, between playwrights who are not poets or thinkers, and thinkers and poets who cannot write actable plays, the British stage derives from our contemporary literature no intellect nutrment, and our literary genius receives from the stage no dramatic inspiration. What is the caufe of this ? Several years ago I had occasion to quote, in the pages of this Review, the following epigram by Grillparzer, a dramatic poet of rare genius: &amp;quot;Danach schaut euch vor Allem um, Schauspieler, dichter, und publicum,&amp;quot; which, for present purpose, may be thus loosely paraphrased &amp;quot;The play&amp;apos;s succes depends on you, rlyer, and poet, and public too.&amp;quot; Grillparzer&amp;apos;s plays would probably be thought unactable by English actors, for they are conceived and c ted in a region of dramatic art unfamiliar to our metropoin ma and theatrical star But on the national stage of his own country they are exeedingly, and deseredly, popular. He was, I think, eighty years old when he wrote this epigram, and it expresses the result of a long practical experience of the essential requisites of the higher order of acting drama, under the most favourable stage conditions. According to Grillparzer, the production of a genuine play requires the combined effort of a competent author, competent actors, and a competent public. No one of these three factors, taken alone, is more indispensable than any other to that triumph of art and genius which can only be achieved by their harmonious co-operation. Nor is this all. To render possible such harmonious co-operation there must also be some standard of intelligence and intellectual culture common to all three. And that standard must be a high one. If all this be true, the present unsatisfactory relations between the stage and literature would appear to be attributable to some defect in one or other, or possibly even in all three, of these equally indispensable conditions. But where does the fault lie ? With our authors, our actors, or our public ? And if it lies, in a less or greater degree, with all three of them, what is the direction in which we may most reasonably expect or attempt the correction of it? As already avowed, I approach these questions in no dogmatic or positive spirit. I have stated them as they arise in my own mind, and I shall not attempt to suggest any definite or conclusive answer to them. But at least they may serve to guide us in a somewhat closer examination of the matter. I need hardly repeat that it is only from a literary point of view I am here discusig the present prospects of the English stage; but, regarded from this point of view in relation to authors, actors and audiences, they present I think under each aspect at least some encouraging feature. The interest taken in the stage by the representatives of social refinement and intellectual life is said to be incraing. The metropolitan stage generally exhibits a marked improvement in many of the essential conditions of good acting; and, although the younger race of dramatists, whose aspirations are worthily represented by such writers as Mr. Herman M1erivale and Mr. Buchanan, complain, I believe, of the depressing conditions to which their art is subjected by a low standard of theatrical taste, it may be hoped that they themselves are gradually improving that standard by their prais worthy impatience of it. So far, the present conditions of dramatic art and literature seem fairly favourable. But the aspect of them does not improve under closer examination. Tle refined portion of the public take an increasing interest in the stage ? Yes, but what are the features and aspects of the stage by which it is attracted? Do the professors of aesthetic principles, the persons who set the taste of the public in art, thoroughly understand what they are talking about when their talk is of theatrical maters P Do they know the difference between a good play and a bad one? Between true and false acting ? between what is artistically natal and what is artificially realistic, in dramatic or histrionic art P Are they training and guiding the public and the theatrical profession to sound principles and a right dis inatn in such matters ? And if not, is the increased attention besowed by them upon the tage of any real benefit to it ? Broadly s k our theatril public is divisible into upper and middle-clan audiences. Mr. Archer, in his work upon the RZVI Dru of to-Doy, describes the English upper-clas audience as &amp;quot; utterly frivolous&amp;quot; He observes that the true representatives of &amp;quot;intellect and culture,&amp;quot; so far from being habitual frequetes $of the playhouse, visit it but very rarely ; and, what is woras when they do visit it, they are, he says, &amp;quot;perfectly in the dark as to what is really good and bad.&amp;quot; Doubtless becau their intellects and culture have not been directed by the infilence of an inteetually cultivated stage to any serious study of the prnciples of dramatic art. &amp;quot;Ple re,&amp;quot; he says, &amp;quot;and that of the last elevating sort, is all that the public expects or will accept at even our best theatres,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot; a drama which opens the slightest intellecal, moral, or political question is certain to fail&amp;quot; This is a sere judgment on that portion of the theatrical public whe increased interest in the stage is hailed as an e symptom by so many of its well-wishers. Still, there i one decidedly iprovWd feature in the general physiognomy of our present s4ge, the deveLAt of which may, I think, be fairly credited to the influc ?of the upper-clas audiences. They are no doubt, in a dramatic s , gin ve and indised to intellel elrt; but it costs than no intellectual effort to perceive the coae and palpable absurdity of actors and actresses who, in the impers tion of gentlemen and gentleomn of the common type, neither talk, nor walk, nr otherwiss conduct themselv &amp;quot;as suh&amp;quot; Theirtste, therefore, is justly intolerant of the conventional ge pronu ti, twang, and strut. And in all probability it is their influence Which has so largely purged our modern stage of tho old-fashioned offence against good taste In this respect the average level of English acting ev at the minor theatres has been greatly improved during the last twenty years. But I must own to a doubt whether the improvement has not been somewhat dey pu sed It appears to me that the influence, whatever it be, which ha freed the ste from revolting exagerations, has also bnished from it all genuine dramatic strength and intensity, all aspiration beyond the superficial and above the om npe So long as the actor will only pitch his voice in a na key, and walk and talk as people who are not actors are in the habit of waking and talking; so longas the dialogue of the play rechoes with a fidelity ealy recognised the most vapid conversation of clubs and mess-rooms and second rate drawingrooms, or the slang of the street and the racecour; so long as the dramatist is content to leave to the scene-painters, machinidst and carpenters those emotional effects which his predecessors in dramatic art endeavoured to produce by their treatment of human character and pasion-bo long will our upper-els audience be to all appearance perfectly satisfied with the kind of dramatic eninmet provided for them. Mr. Robertson&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;d Society pieces,&amp;quot; as they are called, -were the natural dramatic product of this state of things. Neither in the c tion, nor the performance, nor the enjoyment of them can the author, the actors, or the audience have caught for one solitary moment the faintest glimpse of that &amp;quot; ideal nature - to which, acording to Talma, human beings of all classes and conditions are capable of being exalted by &amp;quot; the great emotions of the soul.&amp;quot; But great emotions, it may be said, are proper only to Tragedy; and Comedy, whose natural province is peopled by the follies, the vices, and the varying humours of society, has nothing to do with the revelation of any sort of ideal nature. Surely, however, that is not a true statement of the case. The comedy, not only of Sha re, but of Moliere, Goldsmith, and Sheridan, abounds in ideal types of human nature. What are Benedick and Jaques, what are Alceste and Don Juan, what is Tony Lunpkin, what are the Teazles and the Surface, but so many ideal types ? Comedy, at least, no les than tragedy, demands from its authors, its actors, and its-auditors a high action of the mind. Its emotions no doubt are intelll rather than moral, but they are not deprived of the element of greatness Wit, the main instrument of comedy, is, in its origin and its effect, a great emotion of the intellect. Mr. Archer charaterizes the bulk of our middle-clas audience as &amp;quot;Philistine.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; But how can they help being Philistines if the plays written for their edification artPhilistian P My own impres Is tha4, on the whole, the middleclass portion of our playgoing public brings to the theare a more responsive distion, a more co-operative intelligence, eater intellectual e sness, and more heart than the purely fahi portion of it. Looking at it as a whole, however, I am reluctant to believe that our theatrical public is untehable. We are unable to analyse the miqed impressions of those great audiences which, night after night, for month after month, have been Rocking to theShakp i revivals at the Lyceum. But it cannot, I thin}, be e ay doubted that this re ble series of perfomnesI has done more than anything else to attract the attention of &amp;quot;people of intellect and culture &amp;quot; to the present condition and prospects of the stage ; or that in the conspicuous success and immense popularity of them there are grounds of encouragement to any dramatic poet (if such a one there be amongst us) who is capable of bringing to the practical construction of the acting poetic drama that combia of high intellectual aim and minute attention to technical detail which Mr. Irving has devoted to the interpretation of it. It is impossible to take even the most cursory review of the pre- sent literary capacities and prospects of our English stage without special reference to what has been done for their -mpro t by this dis ed artist in his threefold capacity as actor, manager, and critic. It is long since there has been in our theatrical world any such noticabe or national event as the im on of his trig indidulity upon the attention of the public, and the activity with which that imprion is now operating as an intellectual force beyond the immediate precincts of the stage. The satisfactory impersonation of the great rebs i ned by great writers demands a rare combination not only of intelll powers but also of physical gifts, not often united all together, and very seldom united with a complete equivalence of effect by any single actor. In critiing, therefore, the genius or the art of an actor who possess any appreciable number of them we must remember that every great actor carries into the parts he plays a strong individuality of his own, and that every strong individuality has &amp;quot; the defects of its qualities &amp;quot; in a degree pronounced and emphasd by the strength of it. The warmest admirers of Mr. Irvings acting would probably admit that it abounds in pernal p uities ih, to those who disie them, furnish fair matter for r blecriticism; whilst, on the other hand, its most mpromising detractors would not, I thinkr-deny that it exhibits a distinct inte q Wlit which renders his a interpreter of the poetic drama by far the most important and interesting event of the British sage since the retirement from it of Mr. lacready. The mention of these two eminent actor suggests a pasing oompa of the results achieved by each of them in the same high cause. Although no two actors could be more unlike in pers and in manner, there are etinc common to them both. They must be claed amongst those actors who produce their effect and enforce their influence rather by intelectual su peroity and an elaborate study of their art than trough inspiration or the magic of physical beauty and animal power. Their genius is not to be aociated with their Lineriuna, which have rather obscured the rea merits of their acting than aided its dict, but with qualities of a purely int order. They will not be remembered for the uendous impr s they have made in this or that particular pasge of a part, but for the c paum and originality of their concetion of the part as intwhole. That conception may be open to dissuasion, but not the cr with which it has been formed, or the intellectual power employed in its formation. These, moreover, will be best appreciated by the who study the actor&amp;apos;s perrmance an he himself has studied what he performs, with a desire to penetrate the leading ides of it. Neither Mr. Xacready nor Mr. Irving have achieved those magnifie outbursts with which Edmund Kean is sid to have elerifid his audience even when he was under the infruence of stimulants by no means intellectua; but they have done more to elevate the stage and themselv amongst the intellectual forces of their time by a higher sense of the dignity of their vocation, a wider incultur, and a nobler asiation. There are, however, two things which Mr. Macready succeeded, and which Mr. Irving has not yet succeeded, in doing for the literary character of the stage. He succeeded in gathering around him a group, on the one hand, of acton capable of placing on the sme stage all the varieties of the drama enumrated by Polonius, and, on the other hand, of writers more or les eminent in literature-men amongst whose names may be entioned those of Serjeant Talfourd, Sheridan Knowles, Robert Browning, and Edward Bulwer Lytton. A manager commanding the zealous assistance of such writers as thes, aid such actors as Phelp, Anderson, Webster, Harley, Keeley, Buxton, Farren, Frank Matthews, Mrs. Glover, Mrs. Stirling, Mm Nisbet, and Miss Hellen Faucit, was placed in an exceptionally fivourable position for keeping the literary drama alive upon the stage. But such a position is no longer possible. The extinction of the monopoly of the two great theatre has irrevobly dispkeed that coctration of histrionic talent they were able to comand; and between the dis e of William Macready and the appearance of Henry Irving the condition of the stage has been such as to offer to no writer of any literary eminence the smallest inducuet to write for it. The principles which regulute the composition of an acting drama are as inexorable as those which regulate the composition of a snet, and they are infinitely more complex. Faculties never employed are eventually lest; and, in relation to the art of dramatic ompoiti, our present poets resemble the bees described by Mr. Darwin, who lost their wings by never using them But if Mr. Irving has not yet seeded in gathering around him a of literary drmatists he has had, at. least, the signal honour of inspiring our greatest living poet with the wish to write for the stae he has created, and of a ciang with himself the first dramatic darts of Alfred Tennyson. Those efforts have not hitherto been successul. But one cause of their ill-success may fairly be attributed to the conditions under which they were made; for it is difficult to believe that any poet, whatever his genius, can ccessfully write for the sage withot a careful study of its reqements No poet can produce a genuine play by solitary incubation, unless indeed the incation has been preceded by active personal contact with the stage. He must have studied not only the capabilitiesof the agment and actors to whom he confides his play, but also (what is probably better known to them than to him) the c its of the star which is to be the vehicle, and the public which is to be the recipient, of the effets he wishes to produe And this tree- fold study is specially requisite to the case in which it is most commonly disregarded, of authors whose dramatic purpose demands for its fulfiment a more than ordinary intellectual effort on the part of the actors and the audience. The author must be content to learn, and even eager to learn, much from those who may possibly be his intellectual inferiors It is the only chance of their learning anything from him. The process of producing a play upon the stage is one of give and take upon the part of all concerned in it. A play, properly so called, is not an exclusively individual production, any more than a foreign policy or a military campaign is the work of one man only. It is in some of its essentials a collective production, and co-operation is a primary condition of its success. From Sh e to Sheridan no sucessul dramatist has disregarded the importance of this condition. The dramatist who does disregard it is like a general who saould expect to win a battle without having personally studied the character of the country in which and the trops by whom it is to be fought. His strategic conceptions may be excelent, but uness he is constantly moding their details to meet unforesen contingencie as they arise, and unless he himself looks osely after his transport and nmiat, he cannot reoi upon victory. The sort of ugru o-option betwe author and actor which r comidered to be so important a condition of their joint acems in the production of a genuine play is, I think, sugesively Mustrated in some letters written by my father to Mr. Macready during the poduction of Rihele, one of the few literary plays of the last geneaion which still hold the stage1 Mr. Archer, in hisEsgliA Dwmmtb of To-ay, advocates &amp;quot;the priniple of ollboration&amp;quot; in the compoition of dramatic works, and attlrbtes to the rarity of its adoption by nlish dramatists much of the weakness of the modem English drama. Into the discussion of this opinion I cannot enter here. I do not think that joint auhrsi to the extent desidrated- by Mr. Archer is ompatible with the conditions necessary to the prdcti of any ima ae work belonging to the highest order; for genius is the most depotic, of m ois. But we must distinguish betwem geniu which nnot be acquired or communicated nd art which ca The fault comn_ to our dramatic poets is an ignoance of dramatic art Yet there is no kind of iaginWie ork in Which genius without art is so indectual as it is in the drama. Mr. Archer&amp;apos;s remaron this sbject, though I do not quite subscribe to all of them, are very suggestive; and they appear to me inspired by a sound appreciation of the practical conditions of dramatic com tion(1) Mu0 to So IX ru and appmd As1mm of Mr. ArIw, who lwu tho trn od h ready toughtf ad mugeie knto by borowing firm ujoma, of ither auth sf Wu very ,woue achomu, a hxamssis u UWe., waty, a t hoed, for to vimiom OZwumAM of impuAinos_ to th y aft guet dBod th &amp;quot;I&amp;apos; the drama,&amp;quot; he says, -it is fiequently the case that two heads ae better than one. mhe re verbal discussion of a them, often sugests possibilities and t which would never have occurred to a single thinker. Every one has his little asies blending him to fault. of style or errors af taste in his ownwo When two peole e at ork on a play it is subjested to a continuous, careul, and often toleably unbiasled eriticiun in the very os of its 1rt... If sincerity and compete could be insured in the find towhm the play is read, he would be in the best sense of the werd a c batr. oire had one vale o r cook; but he and hsae ad other earlier dramatist (Spanish, French, or English), wvhos plays they rewrote.&amp;quot; Al this is perfectly true, and the substantial truth of it is contamed in the maxim which Grillparnes epigram was written to illustra and enforce, that a perfect play is in all its parts and at every dage of its development, from the stirring of the earliest germ in the in of one man to the refecton of its complete effect in the imaginao of many, not an individual but a colective production. For such a pr n, however, the best posible collboration is that which insensibly results from the uAleserved nteange of ide and knowledge between a great author and a great actor. If both actor and author are me of literary culture and lofty aim, with a common standard of excellence and a common aspiration to attain it, this is the best combination fr the successful production of the literary drama; but the relatios represented by it must be based on mutual condence and inlul respect. The author has much to learn from the actor, but he has also much. to teach him; he must be able to fed that he has in the actor not merely a technical adviser who has studied the stge, but also a and fiirly competent stdent of the literary codition and purpose of his wor In that case he canno too copiously consult or unrervdy defer to the actors sugetins on thoe points in regard to which the ators e ence is ne ily superior to his own. This combination is rre, at least in our own country, because few English authors have studied the stage sufficiently to appreiate the importace of confrming their work to its o conditions; and not many Englih actors have sudficienliy stdied literare to appeeia&amp;quot; the obligation of coufoa - ing their o art to the standard which the literary drama impo on the pe of it. But such a ombinatin did, I t , exit in the production of Richei; and I have therefore slected the genesis of tha ply to illustrat my previous remarks upon the condit of a it r g R&amp;quot;eee, it mut here be observed, was not written merly for the sake of writing a ply, but expresy for the purpe of aiding Mr. Macready in an enterprise which enlisted the warn and sympathy of itb author. The fist idea of the play grew out of a onversation, or rathe several con s, with Mr. Macready on the prospects of that enterprise, which lad ended in a promise on my father&amp;apos;s part of some further effort, more elaborate than The Lady of Lyons, in support of Macready&amp;apos;s admirable endeavour to enlarge the acting rt~proire of our modem literary drama. In the first conception of the play the chief part appears to have been alotted to a character whose name (Marillac) does not even appear in its final list of dramati# perow, but whose relation to the other characters is more or les represented by that of De Mauprat. It was in the gradual evolution of this germ that the character of Richelieu himself, little by little, assumed its present proportions, and dictated a complete reconstruction of the original sketch. An outline of the plo, as at first imagined, was submitted to lacready ith the following rearks on it. &amp;quot; Now, lookwell at this story. You will see that incident and position are good. But then, there is one great objection. Who is to do Richelieu ? Marflac has the principal part, and requires you. But a bad Richelien would spoil alL On the other hand, if you took Richelien there would be two acts without you, which will never do; and the main interest of the plot would not fifl on you. Tell me what you propose. Must we give up this idea P The incidents e all historical. Don&amp;apos;t let me begin the g if you don&amp;apos;t think it will do, and decide about M1ariliae and Richelieu. Send me back the Papers. You am consult Forster, of course.&amp;quot; In the result of the conference thus opeed between author and actor, M c di e the depotism of RiCheliews tb ed, and the play ttativelyfinished on those lines, but with ebe hesitation, as appears from the following letter:&amp;quot;MY DI3 X uhry,-I nd you thplaycomplete ActsIandTlmay require a little shortening;, but you are a master at that. The rest average the length of the acts in Tk Lady of Ly.. I hope the stoeryis clear. The domestic intees is not o strong as in the Lady, but I think the acting of Bicheic&amp;apos;spart my tbalance this defecL For the rest, I sy of th, as of the Lady, if at all hazardou or uncertain it must not be acted, and I mut try aga;i&amp;apos;&amp;quot; The actor was, at this stage of the matter, more sanguine than the author, who, after the first reading of the play, wrote to Macredy.1 &amp;quot;One thing struck and surprised me more than anything else, viu the prosaic and almost bold cas of the general diction. This I say surpriuad me, becaue I knew I had w a poem; and yet, by sme alemy, all the poetry has beez subtracted ftam it. On consideration I fid it is to be accounted_ for thus The i part wa purposely left plain and simple in order to throw the whole ividnese of contrast and light upon these Paes s w e thought or pmon, as in real li, burst sot ly into poetry. The of th adherence to the of nature has become a melancdhy defect upon the stage (owing of ou to some eror in treatment), for almost every one of those paages is struck out as not essential to the busines, and the raa that rezain will undergo the - process, further condsao being requisit. So that at last nothing will rumain but a dipped and gat skeleton of prose robbed of the pwpum 1m whic gave any bloom to its apparition in my own mind; and the play, as I wrote and you firt read it, will not appear upon the stage. This bareness of dialogu is much more destructive to the effect than you would imagine. And, indeed, I observed that the parts most efftive in reading were thors which the mutilation has not yet reached. Now to obviate thi when the play is once condened, the dialoge of the retaied parts must be re-writtam, and the business part rendered more artificial. A ferful vice in compoition (acordiugto myconceptioofart), but whichne appears tobei sines I now see why more edramatists (Knowles, for instance, and Talburd) have&amp;apos;studiousy practised it. When a door is to be shut, I sy&amp;apos; Shut the door Knowles; would say. as I think he Us said soewhere, &amp;apos; Let the rom be airless.&amp;apos; Prmbably he is right But this clange of style will be tediouswork ZiwiM iaed, and I doubt if I cando it at all At the sam tie, far m ompining of the omission, I see the necessity of still e ruthless and I begin to despair of the play and of myself Unless therefore upon onsideration you see clearly what at presmat seems doubul, the triumphant effect of the portraiture and action of Bichelie himselt you had better re me the play; and if I can form myself an a now ahool of art, and unlearn all that tact and thought have hitherto taught me, I will attempt another. But for this year you mut do witut me&amp;quot; This letter illustrates the eteal source of dit between the actor, whore instinc is to bordinate everyt!ig to &amp;quot;stage busiDees,&amp;quot; and to regard the author&amp;apos;s work as a mere vehicle fir stag busies, and the author, whose tedency is to underrate the pactical, requirsnnts and conventions of stage buiness, and resent the torenting conditions which his art as a dramatist impoes on his giaus as poet. Thus, in another letter, on another suject, my father, repying to a request for collaborati of the kind common in Prance, and o ended by Mr. Archer, wrote to Mr. Macready:&amp;quot;Isend you bash your play. I ca make nothing of it. It seemsto that so mprovement could give the outine stuff and voue enough for afiveact play, thoug it would make a very pretty three-ac piece. It is no _s beginning with a plot which does not catch my f1ncy, as wel as yew notion of what you want; and I warn you that the former object will not be efiude unless the plot be grounded on some conception that calls ir me as an Gnwr as well as a drsmatt.&amp;quot; No original writer will question the propriety of this condition. But the rival claims of the poet an the ne hand and the tage on the other are not i able Neither of them can with inpunity be entirely sacrificed to the other in the production of a good play; and if the actor or manager is a mni of literaq tste, and the author free from self-conceit, they ought between thei to find the right point of adjument. ilM eously objected to Tarious lines assigned to her by Victor Hug, on the retention of which he no less strongly inisted; but er objections had reference to canons of literary taste about which the author was obviousy the best judge. On matters of stage business her judgment was probly better than his; and if the author of Erma had never entered a gB -rooe n or listened to the practical criticism of actors and actresses it may be bly doubted whether his powefl draemtic genius wOld ewr haw e found adequat exp on the stage. Meanwhile the composition of Richeu proceeded with undiminished consultation between author and actor. BULWZ TO XACKEADY. &amp;quot;I send the play as you wished, and make the following s ugetons:Act L The effect of Bichelien&amp;apos;s grave kindness to Mauprat and Julie will I think be heightened by the contrast of a comic touch-characteristic-as thusRc. (to Tmsq). Go. When you I have a feast for you: The last great act of my great play. JOar (going out hadily). The scourge! Rhe. (takiwg tip the play). These verses. ... Gone? Poor man! Ifeamt himef, withis play. Sublime! EnAtr AurRAT AxD JuLI, &amp;amp;:.&amp;quot; The e thus. inserted is improved in the final arrangement of the dialogue. Joseph mutters as he goes out &amp;quot;1Strange that so great a statesman 9ould be so bd a post! &amp;quot; R1ca. What dest thou say ? Jos. That it is strange so great a statesman should Be so sublime a poet. RIc. Ah, you rogue; Laws die, books never. Of my ministy lam not vain; but of my muse I own it.&amp;quot; Ta SA To TU SAM &amp;quot;Act III. In the soe afte Hugnet is sent to the BEstile I have put some lines istl the mouth of De Beringhen as an excuse forhim togs out He mut n a Franos otherwise he would recognis m at the Bae. I _mentim this becase the lion are nogreat things, and you might othervise at themoat as uioperfuou Act IL You have cut out the alluion to the Pigies a Hercles,1 but yo had better retain the lines&amp;apos;Balh! in policy We foil gigantic danger, not by giants, But dwar&amp;apos;BecM these lines give point and purpose to the _met of Nazion Uad Frn 2 Act V. WhEn Pranois and Do Beringhen go out struggling for the packet, De Berighen must not cry out, let it uheuld seem oddthat they ar not overheard. Th struggle must be rapid, intense, but not noisy. If any bla used, daggers not swords, as more coovenwat fo close strggle Act M. Still ends wekly. The act for its effect, if rd, needs a m- elborte analyis of the characters of Richelienand Louis. And thi I shall probably add (not in the acting oW), to remove all ground for the criticisms I refrd to lat night But I doubt if it would do for the stage; whre if Biebi stands out too amiably it will be se that he does so fom the _iion of touhes too minute and subtle, or scenes too long fr the action of a ply. I dab low to learn ho it turns out in theg renroom. I eevery swr of Act V., and think whole much bttered by our lii 1.wr.&amp;quot; nd here foflow a few words of touching reference to a now almost fgoW9tten tagedy of rel life &amp;quot; Fortunately I had dae my connectons to-day b the news of poor L I. L&amp;apos;s deth, Which I have just seen in the paper. It has quit overcame me, and I cnnot now write many little things which had occurred to me. So (1) It wsu nt redred ad does ni appear in the ply. (2) They are rained in the play. young, so gifted! And yesteday I received a letter from her written in high spirits. I have not beeu, so shocked for years.&amp;quot; THE SAME TO TH SAME. &amp;quot;It occurs to me that, if you adopt my suggestion in Act m., and show the bed, &amp;amp;c., you will add to the suspense and surprise of the situation by omitting ichelieus words, &amp;apos;You, have slain me, I am dead, &amp;amp;c.&amp;apos; Leave the audience in expectaion, till Nauprat&amp;apos;s return, as to what L&amp;apos;s devise really is. There are nf eyso 8 may papers used, by way of writ, despatches, &amp;amp;c., that we must distinguis broadly between them. The writs of l sbnmt and deat should be short scraps of parchment, and lheieus conditions of power, which the king sgns, should be in a small portl, or pocket book with clasps. If I righ rememaber the history, the document containing these and other articles of Richlies power was actually found (after his death) in a red and gold morocco book. The despatch must be from the writs, but I hardly know bow. I should add, about dress, that I think in the pictures of Richulieu he wears the cola and order of the Saint Esprit; that Louis never were any colou but blck and orange ribbons; tat Xauprat&amp;apos; first dres must be black as Julie alludes to that colour; and his general costume very like Bragelone&amp;apos;s&amp;apos; trousers to the knee-bows, a mantle, &amp;amp;c. You will see that in Act V. I have made the King say he had promised to hold the life of Baradas sacred. 1st, because that will account for the vindictive and rales Cardinal not killing him; 2nd, because Richelieu, having said at the beginning that he had aother bride, the grave, for Baradas; unless some such obstacle arses at the close, there would be no reason in the subsequent conduct of Baradas for the adinal&amp;apos;s chang of mind. By the way, Rielieu lived more splendidly than the King. The scenery should convey thi idea If De Beringhe must have another jes, I can think of no better a one than this-&amp;apos; St Deais traveled without his hei. rm luckier than 8t. Denis.&amp;apos; Act IL-When Nauprat for the first tim, says, in the gardens, &amp;apos;I loathe the face of man,&amp;apos; &amp;amp;c., Baradas exclaims, &amp;apos; I have him&amp;apos; This must be altered, as Richelieu uses the expreson in the next scene. Let Baradas say&amp;apos;Go where thou w the heUll-hounds of Rnge Pant in thy track, and dog thee down.&amp;apos; Baradas, in the expression of his exaltation, ougt to be longer and more florid than Bichelieu, whose simpicity of phrase comes fiom the ease of superior power and unirm success. To him, in fat, what raies all the devils in Baradas breast is mere ehild play. Warde will I trust, understand tt the charabteristIcs of Baradas are prodiious eneg a restlessne; with yout loe, jelousy, ha put in contrast the vast and dark movement of the old _&amp;apos;8eemas intellect and X uch will depend on his rcing ot this contr&amp;quot;2 The details of this and other portions of the hitherto published corespondnc e frm which I macke these extrats illus te the tenaity with which the author of Ric n kept the visin of the stae beore his mind though t the compositi of the play. But I mnut reserve fbr a b eqent number the continuaton of this co podene, and some further commente upon it. LYTUOX. (X) In h wea el ragi. (2) Te migial em&amp;amp; of Zdeh is given as fellows by Sir Frederick Paliock in his note to Macremdy&amp;apos;s ksiu:in.:-Lois XIm., Mr. Elto; Gaston, Mr. Didiur; Riheba, Mr. Maready; Baradas, Mr. Wards; Mapjat., Mr. Andin; De Bermma, Mr. V hing; Jose, Mr. Pheps; Hognek Mr. Geoe Bme#t; Fmagoas, M. Howe; Julie, m Helm Faucit; Manes de Irue, Wm Cavde. (To be maUmd.)</FullText></Record>