<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>2468821</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20160127130852</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>CARDINAL NEWMAN.</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>14004</PublicationID><Title>Fortnightly review, May 1865-June 1934</Title><Qualifier>London</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>Chapman and Hall.</Publisher><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>151</Issue><AlphaPubDate>Jul 1879</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>18790701</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Periodicals</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Lilly</LastName><MiddleName>S</MiddleName><FirstName>W</FirstName><PersonName>W S Lilly</PersonName><OriginalForm>LILLY, W S</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>WellesleyAttribution</ContribRole><LastName>Lilly</LastName><MiddleName>S</MiddleName><FirstName>W</FirstName><PersonName>W S Lilly</PersonName><OriginalForm>Lilly, W. S.</OriginalForm></Contributor><Contributor><ContribRole>Editor</ContribRole><LastName>Morley</LastName><FirstName>John</FirstName><PersonName>John Morley</PersonName><OriginalForm>Morley, John, 1838-1923</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><ISSN>2043-2887</ISSN><ISSN>0950-5679</ISSN><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>23</EndPage><Pagination>1-23</Pagination><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/2468821/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007573</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009130</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000001</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Terms><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>BOOKS - REVIEWS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>GREAT BRITAIN - Politics and Government - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH ESSAYS</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 19th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm><FlexTerm><FlexTermName>DerivedSubject</FlexTermName>         <FlexTermValue>ENGLISH LITERATURE - 20th Century</FlexTermValue>       </FlexTerm></Terms><FullText>CARDINAL NEWMAN. THz new and uniform edition of Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s works is now, with one exception,1 complete: thirty-four volumes, given originally to the world at various intervals, and upon occasions very widely differing, from the year 1828 to the year 1875; the record of the thought, the action, the sufferings, the joys, the fiailures, the successes of a long and eventful life. These volumes entitle their author to no mean place among the classics of our country. There is no living writer who has attained to such supreme mastery over the English tongue. It is to him an instmentof which he knows all the mys- terious capabilities, all the hidden sweetness, all the latent power; and it responds with marvellous precision to his every touch, the boldest or the slightest. Persuasive winningness, scathing denunciation, vivid irony, closest logic, soul-subduing pathos, graceful fancies-all are at his command, and come forth to do his bidding. His is a high creative faculty united to great ratiocinative power, and matured and chastened by that supreme art which leaves no trace of workmanship. Where in the whole range of our literature shall we find passages of loftier eloquence and purer religious feeling than in his sermons? Where an exacter apprehension and a clearer statement of gravest philosophical problems-whatever our view as to his solution of them-than in the Gnamar of Anent, the Essay on Derelokpme, the Lcdrew on tie Ideal of a Univrdty ? Where sweeter and more delicate flowers of poesy than in such verses as &amp;quot;Lead, kindly Light,&amp;quot; or the &amp;quot;Dream of Gerontius&amp;quot;? Who has displayed greater descriptive force, or more cons te power of word-painting, than he who has made ancient Athens live before us Whose holy enchantment has walled up in the midst of the nineteenth century, with its fevri strivings and incessant movement and restless endeavour, the venerable shades of St. Benedict (1) The annoatd k anshdiou of St. Athauasans remain to be added to this edition i ords to eompete it. It is to this th my references are made throughout this aatel. and his companions, in the unbroken calm and untroubled peace of the early monastic institute? Who has &amp;quot;sorted and nmmbered the weapons of controversy &amp;quot; with such scientific precision, and employed them with such consummate skill, as the author of the Treatise on the Propheti Qjiee, the Tract on Creed and Canmon, the Lectures on Anglican Difficulties, and the Letter to the Duke of Horfol ? While, still higher glory, in a life full of polemical strife, he has never taken an unfair advantage or won a dishonest victory. These are some of the titles upon which Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s claim rests to a high place in the literature of his country. It is not, however, my present purpose to consider him from a merely literary stand-point. Cardinal Newman has played a notable part in a most importantperhaps the most important-department of the annals of our century. He is the especial representative of a great spiritual ad intellectual movement, and a conspicuous leader of religious thought. It is in this character that I propose now to regard him. My object is to sketch the mainoutlinesof his life, and in such rough way as maybe possble to form an estimate of his work. And in executing this task my chief materials will be derived from his books, one special note of which is their strong individuality. They are instinct with that egotism which, to use a happy expression of his own, is, in some provinces, the truest modesty. Each in its different way and its varying degree has for us its revelation about the writer. Thus the Grammar of Assent does for us objectively what the Apologa does subjectively. The Essay on Derelopnment is confessedly a chapter-the last-in the workings of the author&amp;apos;s mind which issued in his submission to Rome. There is perhaps not one of his Ozford Sernons which, as he has told us of the famous discours on Wisdom and Innocence, was not written with a secret reference to hi=sef His verses are the expressions of personal feelings, the greater part of them, to give his own account, growing out of that religious movement which he followed so faithfully from first to last.&amp;apos; And, further, we have his present criticism upon his former self, his ultimate judgments upon his early views, in the prefaces and notes with which he has enriched the new editions of his old works Then we posess in his volumes not only the story of his life, but, in some degree, his comment thereon. 4 ile velut fidis arey sodalibus olfm Oredebat libris, neque male oesmerat unquam Decurews alio, nyque si bene, quo fit ut omma Votiva pteat veluti desip ta efla ViA senis.&amp;quot; (1) Dedication to Mr. Bsdoey of Vera upom vwwm Oceasdo, p. yL Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s life runs with the century. It is to the age of Pitt and Fox, of Napoleon and Pius VII., of Scott and Byron, of Coleridge and Kant, that we must go back to survey the moral, political, and religious surroundings of his early y - which largely influence every man, and the more largel in proportion to the receptivity and retentiveness of his intellectual constitution. To form some apprehension of the spiritual element in which Cardinal Newman lived and moved during the time when bis character was matured and his first principles were formed, is a necessary condition precedent to any true understanding of what he is and of what he has wrought. Let us therefore glance at the condition of English religious thought at that period. Perhaps it is not too much to say that never, during its course of well-nigh two thousand years in the world, has Christianity presented less of the character of a spiritual religion than during the last half of the eighteenth century. Not in England only, but throughout Europe, the general aim of its accredited teachers seems to have been to explain away its mysteries, to extenuate its supernatural character, to reduce it to a system of morality little differing from that of IEpictetus or Marcus Aurelius. The dogmas of Christianity were almost openly admitted to be nonsense. Religious emotion was stigmatized as enthusiasm. Theology, from being &amp;quot;I the science of things divine,&amp;quot; had sunk into apologies, opposing weak answers to strong objections, and into evidences, endeavouring with the smallest result to establish the existence of a vague possible deity. Even the sanctions of morality were sought in the lowest instincts of human nature, the reason for doing good assigned in the received text books of philosophy being in effect, as Mr. Mill puts it, &amp;quot;d that God is stronger than we are, and able to damn us if we do not.&amp;quot; The prevailing religion of the day may be accurately judged of from the most widely popular of its homiletic works, those thrice-famous sermons of Blair&amp;apos;s, which were at one time to be found in well-nigh every family of the upper and middle classes of this country, and which probably may still be discovered in the remoter shelves of the libraries in most country houses. No one can look into these discourses without admitting the truth of Mr. Stephen&amp;apos;s trenchant criticism that &amp;quot;s they represent the last stage of theological decay.&amp;quot;1 For unction there is mere mouthing; for the solid common amHe of earlier writers, an infinite capacity for repeating the feeblest platitudes; the morality ca scarcely be dignified by the name of prudential, unless all prudence be summed up in the conmand, !&amp;apos;Be respectable; &amp;quot; the pages are full of solemn trifling-prosings about adversity and prosperity, (1) SipHA Tlint isthe O ighte Cextmg vol. ii p. 346. The rma.im in my oing we - an abridgment of an admirae pag-tbe next-of Mr. tPWhenooL b*&amp;apos; eulogies upon the most excellent of virtues, Moderation, and proofs that religion is upon the whole productive of pleasure. As Mr. Mill accurately sums the matter up&amp;quot; The age seemed smitten with an incapacity of producing deep or stong feeling, such at least as could ally itself with meditative habits. There were few poets, and none of a high order; and philsophy had fallen into the hands of men of a dry prosaic nature, who had not enough of the materials of human feeling in them to imagine any of its more complex and mysterious manifestations; all of which they either left out of their theories, or intoduced them with suh explanations as no one who had experienced the feelings could receive as adequate.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; Such was the dominant tone of English thought about the time when Cardinal Newman was bon. But beside it there was another school which exercised a strong influence over a not incoderble number of adherents, and which potently affected the growth of his character and the formation of his opinions. Among the figures conspicuous in the history of England in the last century, there is perhaps none more worthy of careful study than that of John Wesley. Make all deductions you please for his narrowness, his self-conceit, his extravagance, and still it remains that no one so nearly approaches the fulness of stature of the great heroes of Christian spiritualism in the early and middle ages. He had more in common with St. Boniface and St. Bernardine of Sienna, with St. Vincent Ferrer, and Savonarola, than any religious teacher whom Protestantism has ever produced. Nor is the rise of the sect which has adopted his namethe &amp;quot;people called Methodists&amp;quot; was his way of designating his followers-by any means the most important of the results of his life and labours. It is not too much to sy that he, and those whom he formed and influenced, chiefly kept alive in England the idea of supernatural order during the dull materialism and selfish coldness of the eighteenth century. To him is undoubtedly due the Evangelical party. Romaine and Newton, Venn and Jowett, Milner and -Simeon, differing as they did from him on particular doctrines, derived from him that fundamental tenet of religious conversion which they termed &amp;quot;d the new birth.&amp;quot; It is easy now, as it ever was, to ridicule the grotesque phraseology of the Evangelical school, to make merry over their sour superstitions, their ignorant fanaticism, to detect and pillory their intellectual littleness It is not easy to estimate adequately the work which they did by reviving the idea of grace in the Established Church. They were not theologians, they were not philosophers, they were not scholars. Possibly only two of them, Cecil and Scott, can be said to rise above a very low level of mental mediocrity. But they were men who felt the powers of the world to come in an age when that world had become to most little (1) Di;u-iew Di eta , WL i,np 5. more than an nmeaning phrase; who spoke of a God to pray to, in a generation which knew chiefly of one to swear by; who made full proof of their ministry by signs and wonders parallel to those of the prophetic vision. It wasin truth a valley of dry bones in which the Evangelical clergyman of the opening nineteenth century was set; and as he prophesied there was a noise, and behold, a shaking, and the breath came into them, and they lived and stood upon their feet, an exceeding great army. In this army John Henry Newman was led to enrol himsef in early youth. He has himself told us how, in the autumn of 1816, he fell under the influence of a definite creed, and received into his intellect impressions of dogma which have never been effaed or obscured: how Ad the conversations and sermons of that excellent man, long dead, the Rev. Walter Mayers, of Pembroke College, Oxford,&amp;quot; were &amp;quot; the human means of the beginning of this divine faith&amp;quot; in him; how he is &amp;quot; sill more certain of the inward conversion of which he was then conscious, than that hehas hands orfeet.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s earliest religious reading was of authors such as Romaine, Thomas Scott, Joseph Milner, whose works were then the text books of the Evangelical school. But he also studied attentively two writers of very different characters, both of whom made a deep impresipon his mind: William Law, the non-juror, whose Serions Call, it will be remembered, was such a powerful agent in John Wesley&amp;apos;s spiritual history, and Bishop Newton, whose work upon the Prophecies is the very fount and source of an &amp;quot;expository &amp;quot; literature still dearly cherished by Exeter Hall, and of which the great light in our own days is Dr. Cumming. In 1819 he was entered at Trinity College, Oxford, and during the whole of his undergraduate course he adhered rigidly to the straitest sect of the Evangelicals. It was not until 1822 that his spiritual horizon began to widen. In that year he came under the influence of Dr. Whately, who, he tells us, &amp;quot;emphatically opened my mind and taught me to think, and to use myreason.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; It is curious tofind him particularly specifyingamong his obligatos to Dr. Whately, this:&amp;quot;What he did for me in point of relious opinion was to teach me the existie of the Church as a substantive body or corporation; next to fix in me those anti-Erastian views of Church polity, which were one of the most prominent features of the Tractarian movement.&amp;quot; At the same time he formed a friendship with a worthy representative of the classic High Church school of Anglicanism, Dr. Hawkins, then Vicar of St. Mary&amp;apos;s, who was the means of great additions to hi belief. From him he derived directly the doctrine of Tradition, (1) Apiqa pro Vitesp.p4 ( (2) Ibid pp. 11, IL and indirectly the doctrine of Baptismal Reg ti; while Mr. James of Oriel taught him the dogma of Apostolical Suessio, and Mr. Blanco White led him &amp;quot;to have freer views on the subject of spir than were usual in the Church of England at that time&amp;quot; 1 Still more important were his obligations to Butler, whom he began to read about the year 1823. He regards the study of the Analogy as an era in his religious opinions, and refers to it the underlying principles of a great portion of his teahing: S - talim and Probability.&amp;apos; It is manfes that while acquiring thes new views he was widely diverging from the sand of orthodoxy of his Evangelical friends Amang the many legds which have grown up about him is one attrbuting his fina separation firom the to the rejection in 1826 of two hundred and fifty n mens aid to have been moved by him to the draft of the annual report of the Oxford Bible Society, of which body, according to the stoy, he was &amp;quot; third secretary: &amp;quot; directed to the purgation of that document frm the strange verbiage which was the outward and visible sign of the Low Church spirit. Unfortunately a word from Cardinal Newman has dispelled this amusing myth. &amp;quot; I never was any kind of sary to the Bible Society,&amp;quot; he tells me, &amp;quot;and I neve moved MYany t mes at aLl. There is, however, one grain of truth in the story. It was, indeed, about the year 1826 that John Henry Newman&amp;apos;s ties with the Evgelical party were finaUy severed. But though no longer of them as a professed adherent, he retained much that he had learnt from them. In particular their fndamental doctrine of Grace, that is, of a sensible, aspern and direct divine influence upon the soul of man, remaind, and hs remained up to this day, with him as a prime and vital verity. For some little time from 1826 he continued unattached to any theological section or schooL The old high and dry party, the two-bottle orthodox, then pr inant in the university, were little to his taste, although he y i vehemently with their political opinions, and for the first few years of his reidence as a fellow at Oriel-he had been elected in 18 e lived very much alone. In 1826 he began a close and tender friendihip with Richard Hurrell Fronde, never dimmed nor interrupted during the short career of that many-sided and highy gift man. Robert Iaac WVberforee, who, like Froude, was then a Probationer Fellow of Oriel, was also among his most intimate om and there were others-their names need not be enumeratd re-who (1) 4ptiwPM re- p, . 8, 9. (2) By the mummaWal sya, a the l1rgense of the wod, Caiod New-in-me &amp;quot; the doebine that natuiml jlemonuaa are boeh the typ a=A the haskmenu of redfatn u18z.&amp;quot;-Apoegie P. I BDutls teahing&amp;quot; tagt pimsbaly is the guide o lIf&amp;quot; he eaides to have origina led 1.him to &amp;quot;the queu of the logial egmeyefai,&amp;quot; an which he h1s &amp;apos;Ain we e&amp;quot;-Idi p. 11. were drawn to him by the strong ties of kindred minds, like aspirations, and the many inexpressible influences engendered by community of academical life. One thing which especially bound together the little knot of men who constituted the original nucleus of the future Tractarian party was an rrep ible disatisfction with the religious schools of the day; an eager looking out for deeper and more definite teaching. It may be truly said-the phrase I think is Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s-that this feeling was in the air of the epoch. The French Revolution, shattering the framework of society throughout Europe, was but the manifestation in the public order of great intellectual and spiritual changes. England, indeed, shut off from the Continent by her insular position, and by the policy of the great minister whose strong hand guided her destinies for so many perilous years, was exempt, to a great extent, from the influence of the general movement of European thought. Still, in England too there arose the longing-vague, half expressed, not half understood-for some better thing, truer and higher, and more profound than the ideas of the outward world could yield: a longing which found quite other manifestations than the Evangelical. Striking evidence of this feeling is afforded by the reception given to the delineation of the fuller life of a simpler agoe, which was attempted in the poetry and prose fictions of Sir Walter Scott. &amp;quot; The general need of something more attractive than had offered itself elsewhere,&amp;quot; as Cardinal Newman remarks&amp;quot; led to his popularity, and by means of this popularity he reacted on his readers, stimulating their mental thirst, feeding their hopes, setting before them visons which when once seen are not easily forgotten, and silently ind ing them with nobler ideas, which might afterwards be appealed to on firs princples.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; Byron and Shelley too bear witnes in a different way to the working in the English mind of the ferment with which the Eurepemn intellect was leavened. But of the actual movement of contempo thought and feeling upon the Continent, little was definitely udertood in England. The great reaction in France against the eighteenth century, the initiation of which will be in the event, and, indeed, even now is, Chateaubriand&amp;apos;s best title to fame, was very faintly apr-ctd among us, and the masters of the new literature in Germany were scarcely even heard of For long years Goethe was known in this country only by Sir Walter Scott&amp;apos;s ts ti of one of his earliest and least significant works; and of Lesing, Schifler, TSeck, Richter, Novalis, the two Schlegels, it might be said, with almost literal truth, that they were not known at all. Kantism (1) &amp;quot; Emy an the PeQoecta of the Anglican Church,&amp;quot; repriat in Ap; Cruifa aid 1uatwiw viL L p. 267. was an epithet significant of &amp;quot;absurdity, wickedness, and horror,&amp;quot; and was freely used to label any fiantic exaggeration in &amp;quot; sentiment,&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;crude fever dream in opinion,&amp;quot; which might anywhere break forth. 1 Slowly, however, but surely, did the new critical philosophy infiltrate itself into this country, through the most metaphiysical head which the country has ever produced. Samuel Taylor Coleridge was the first among English thinkers to study and understand Kant, to assimilate his teaching, and to reproduce it. Rejecting with disgust the physical method which he found predominant in English speculation, he discerned in the Critique of Pure Reason a higher and nobler system than the materialism of Locke or the utilitarianism of Paley. Coleridge, indeed, was no blind disciple of his Teutonic master. It may be truly said of him that he was &amp;quot;KulJius addictus jurre in verba magistri.&amp;quot; His mind was too original to allow him to be a mere echo of other men&amp;apos;s thoughts; his reading was too vast to suffer him to be blind to the deficiencies of the sage of Kinigsberg. It is, however, undoubtedly to Kant that he owes, with much else, that distinction between the Understanding and the Reason-Verstand and Vernunft -which is one of his fundamental positions; which, indeed, he considered essential to any profitable study of psychology. But the philosophy of Coleridge is too great a subject to be dealt with here. I can only observe that its influence upon the mind of his age was far more potent than is generally understood. In my judgment he stands in the same position with regard to English thought of the nineteenth century, as is occupiedby Locke with regard tothat of the eighteenth. I am, however, immediatelyconcernedwith hisefect upon that particular intellectual and spiritual phase which is represented by the Tractarian movement. Cardinal Newman, in a paper published in the British Critic in 1839, reckons him one of its precursors, as &amp;quot; providing a philosophical basis for it, as instilling a higher philosophy into inquiring minds than they had hitherto been accustomed to accept.&amp;quot; The action of this great thinker&amp;apos;s doctrine was, indeed, to a large extent, indirect. It is through the poetry of his friend and disciple Wordsworth, that his philosophy, stripped of its technicalities, and presented in a popular form, has won the widest acceptanze and exercised its deepest influence. &amp;quot; I wish to be considered a teacher or nothing,&amp;quot; Wordsworth wrote to his friend, Sir George Beaumont. His age had need of his teaching, bewitched as it was by the Circean strains of Byron&amp;apos;s morbid egotiun, and the iitble charm of the splendid verse in which Sheley clothed. his pasionte dreams, soaring like his own skylark away frmw this (1) CuYsMs ZiMA E &amp;amp; L i p. K working-day world until he is lost in the clouds of his ecstatic idealiations. How many felt in Wordsworth&amp;apos;s own generation, how many more have felt since, the healing influence of his poetry, as of Nature herself ! &amp;quot;As snow those inward pleadings fall, As soft, as bright, as pure, as cool, With gentle weight and gradual, And sink into the feverish soul.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; &amp;quot;I have not written for superficial observers and unthinking minds,&amp;quot; the poet explained to his friend. But from the first he drew to him the more thoughtful and true-hearted of his age: &amp;quot;Non solum dulcissimm poeseos, verum etiam divine veritatis, atistes,&amp;quot; 2 and among those who were most deeply influenced by him was John Keble The Christian Year appeared in 1827. Cardinal Newman, writing of it nineteen years later, after his secession, and looking back upon it and the work it did, from an external point of view, observes&amp;quot; Much certainly came of the CArisian YCerT........Coming from one who had such claims on his readers, from the weight of his name, the depth of his devotional and ethical tone, and the special gift of consolation of which his poems were the evidence, it wrought a great work in the Establishment. It kindled hearts towards his Church; it gave something for the gentle and forlorn to cling to; it raised up advocates for it among those who, if God and their good angel had suffered it, might have wandered away into some sort of philosophy and acknowledged no Church at alL.&amp;apos; 3 It did all this, certainly, and there can be no question that it acted as a powerful instrument in drawing together those who subsequently constituted the Tractarian party. It is, however, very difficult for men of the present generation to understand the sort of influence exrcised by this -volume of devotional poetry, when it first appeared more than half a century ago. It is not hard to account for its popularity; but it is hard to conceive now how it could have been an important factor in a great movement of religious thought. Judged coldly, and by the ordinary canons of citicism, the book may be justly praised for delicacy and refinement of style, for smoothness and harmony of numbers, for correctness of taste, for a sweet and gentle mysticism. But there is no trac of the fine frenzy which, according to the Aristotelian dictum, is the chief note of high poetic inspiration. Nor do we find (1) I brut Cardinal Newmaa will pardon the application here node of these lines fre hi. inagnileut religious poem, &amp;quot;St. rhilip in hids God.&amp;quot; (2) Dediatis to WM= Wordsworth-&amp;quot; vao vero philosopho et vati sacro&amp;quot;-of KebW&amp;apos; 1&amp;apos; iWuM. ecdemiw. (3) E1sa Critical aid Histonri4 vol. iL p. 245. in it the keenness of vision, the intensity of feeling, the passion for appeal by which the souls of men are wont to be kindled, and which we are led to look for in compositions playing an important part in a religious revivaL If we compare M1r. Keble with the poets of the previous century, whose hymns were such a living power, it must be allowed that though he never sinks to their lowest level, he certainly never attains to their highest. There is nothing in the Chrisan Year which for grandeur of conception, splendour anid fire of diction, natural freedom, easy grace, and strong upwelling of religious emotion, can be ranked with some of Charles Wesley&amp;apos;s best verses: verses which perhaps have more in common with the masterpieces of Adam of St. Victor, and St. Bernard, than any other in our language. Indeed John Keble&amp;apos;s professed purpose was to exhibit the soothing tendency of the Prayer Book, and that this purpose was accomplished with rare skill and beauty, who can doubt? The curious phenomenon is that the volume achieved so much beyond what its author aimed at; and that this was so, is an emphatic testimony to the needs of the age in which he wrote. The high and dry school had little to offer in satisfaction of spiritual aspiatios. In place of living bread-panis vivus et vitalis-it had nothing to set before the hungry soul but the stone of theological petrifictions. Erangelicalism was in its decadences It was perishing of intellectual inanition. Beginning, in Apostolic wise, with &amp;quot; the foolishness of preaching,&amp;quot; it had ended unapostolically in the preaching of foolishness. Its divinity was confined to a few isodated dogmas, which, torn from their place in systematic theology, had no enduring principle of life. For scholarship it had unctuous pulpit platitudes; for philosophy, the delrwaenta of apocalyptic tea-tables. From art, it turned away with mnator references to &amp;quot; texts&amp;quot; in Exodus and Leviticus. To those who like John Henry Newman had made trial of it, and had found it wanting, and to those who like Hurrell Froude had never been drawn by it from conventional orthodoxy, the Christian Year came as &amp;quot;a new music, the music of a school long unknown in England, where the general tone of religious literature was so nerveless and impotent.&amp;quot; Cardinal Newman judges that the two main telltual truths which it brought home to him were the principle of s tali and the doctrine as to certitude, which he had aleady learned from Butler. S&amp;amp;ch was the influence of the Chrisgi Year. Cardinal Newman reckons it the original bond of those who were to become the leaders of the Oxford movement, the formal start of which he dates firom Mr. Keble&amp;apos;s once famous discure on National Apostacy, preached in St Mary&amp;apos;s in 1833. It was in that year that Cardinal Newman began, &amp;quot; out of his own head,&amp;quot; the series of papers from which the (1) 4ph~u, p. 18. MOTement received its truest and most characteristic name of Tractarian. There can be no room for doubt that its chief springs of action are to be found in the Tracn for the Time, and in those Oxfrd &amp;amp;rmeog, which, as their recent editor says, produced &amp;quot;a living effect &amp;quot; upon their hearers. The importance of the part played in the movement by Cardinal Newman admits of an easy tesL Is it possible to conceive of it without him? We can conceive of it without the two Kebles, without Isaac Williams, without Dr. Pusey, who did not join it until 1836. They are, if we may so speak, of its accidents; Cardinal Newman is of its essence. It grew, indeed, out of the occult sympathies of kindred minds, and was the issue of manifold causes, long working according to their own laws. But the objective form which it assumed was due principally to Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s supreme confidence, irresistible earnestness, absolute fearlessness, and to the unique personal influence which accompanied and in part sprang from these endowments. The specific danger, as it was judged, which supplied the occasion for its initiation was the Bill for the suppression of certain Irish Bishoprics. But this measure was an occasion merely. To Cardinal Newman, since at the age of fourteen he first looked into Voltaire and Hume, the primary fact of the age had been what he denominates iberali. And by this term he means not merely the democratic pinciple in politics, bat the general movement of thought, of which that principle is merely one manifestation-a movement which men call anti-dogmatic or enlightened, revolutionary or emancipatory, sceptical or pr iv i alistic or rational, as the point of view from which they regard it suggests, and their individul judgments and personal predilections determine. To this he sought to oppose the principle of dogma-from the first until now the basis of his religion. He endeavoured to meet the new spirit with a definite religious teaching as to a visible Church, the kingdom in this world of a present though invisible king, a great supernatural fact among men, rePrsnted in this country by the An E ishment, and speaking through its fo aries and the living voice of its eiscopa- and to hium, as to each man in particular, through his own bishop, to whom he looked up as &amp;quot; the successor of the a es, the Vicar of Christ.&amp;quot;L And so he tells us&amp;quot; Tbe [Oxford] nmvement started on the gound of maintaining eccesiastical authowity, as opposed to the ainism of the Stt It e dthe Church as the one etlmy object of io s loyalty and veration, te some of all spiitual power and jurisd on, and the chane of all grac It represented it to be the interest, as well as the duty, of Churmen, the bond of peace and the eseret of strength to submittheir judgmt in al t toherdecision. Andit taut that this divinely founded Church was realised and brught into (1) 4 -kgis, p. f1. effect in our country in the Nation Establiment, which W the outward form or development of a continuous dynasty and hereditary power which descended from the Apostles. It gave, then, to tlat h Eatln in its offiers, its laws, its usage, and its worship, that devotion and obedience which are correlative to the very idea of the Church. It set up on high the bench of Bishops and the Book of Common Prayer as the authority to which it was itself to bow, with which it was to cow and overpower an Frastian Stat.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; This, according to Cardinal Newman, was the &amp;quot;clear, unvarying line of thought &amp;quot; upon which the movement of 1833 proceeded, and a careful studyof the documents in which itshistoryis to be traced amplyconfirms, if confirmation is wanted, the correctness of this view. The progress of Tractariani, from Tract I. to Tract XC., was the natural growth, the logical development, of this idea. It was a progress leading ever farther from the historical position, the first principles of the Church of England as by law established. The enterprise in which the Tractarians were engaged was, unconsciously to themselves, an attempt to transform the character of the Anglican Communion, to undo the work of the Reformation, to reverse the traditions of three centuries. Unconsciously to themselves,&amp;quot; indeed. Nor need we wonder at their unconsciousness. It is, as Clough A-sks&amp;quot;What do we see? Each an a space Of some few yards before his face.&amp;quot; No man may see more. &amp;quot; If we would ascertain the real course of a principle, we must look at it at a certain distance and as history represents it to us.&amp;quot;2 But who can project himself into times to come, and survEy the present from the stand-point of the future? The Tractarians were as men who had launched upon unknown seas, full of strange tides and secret currents, which swifty and imperceptibly bore them away, baffling their vain attempts at steerage. Others, however, could see more clearly than was possible to them the direction in which they were drifting. Even at the beginning of the movement Cardinal Newman says : cry was heard on all sides of us that the Tracts and the writings of the Fathers would lead us to become Catholics before we were aware of it.&amp;quot;3 It was then that he set about a defence of the movement and its principles, and produced his work upon O7we Proplietical Oilce of tAe Church, newed relatiely to Ronaeien and Popular Proetanxti This work appeared in 1837. Its subject was the Via Media, a designation &amp;quot;which had already been applied to the Angcan system by writers of repute. Its main object was to furish an pproximation in one or two points towards a correct theory of the (1) *dwi&amp;amp; Dijkaftin, vo L pa 1l. (2) Apsege, P. 263. (3) -Aplegi, p. 63. duties and office of the Church Catholic.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; If we deny that the Roman view of the Church is true,&amp;quot; the author says, &amp;quot; we are bound in very shame to state what we hold ourselves.&amp;quot; The Lectures on the Prophetical Office attempted to put forward such a statement. There was, however, an initial objection which he felt keenly and stated with his habitual candour and peculiar power:&amp;quot;When we profess our Via Media as the very truth of the Apostles, we sem to bystanders to be mere an iquans or pedants amusing ourselves with illuuso or learned subtleties, and unable to grapple with things as they are. Pantiund Popery are real religions. No one can doubt about them. They have frnished the mould to which nations have been cast, but the Via Mfedia, viewed as an integral system, has never had an existence, except on paper.&amp;quot; He grants the objection, although he endeavours to lessen it &amp;quot; It stil remains to be seen whether what is called Anglo-Catholicism, the religion of Andrews, Laud, Hammond, Butler, and Wilson, is capable of being pfeed acted on, and maintained on a large sphere of action and through a sufficient period, or whether it be a new modification and transition state of Bomanism or of popular Protestantism.&amp;quot; The trial was made, and we know with what results. In these Lectures on the Prophetical Office, the case stated is put with marvellous dialectic skill and great persuasive power; but the logic of facts is stronger than the strongest logic of words And facts were against the No Media, the facts both of antiquity and modern times Its author had taken the historical foundation for granted.&amp;apos; It was an unfortunate assumption. The national feeling did but assert, with whatever passion and prejudice, the testimony of the national history-of which, indeed, that feeling is to a large extent the outcome-against the tjOor of the movement as alien from the blished religion. It was nothing to the purpose to show that the views put forward in that famous pamphlet might be paralleled, one from this Anglican authority, another from that. It was not pretended that any accredited writer of the Establishment had ever ventured to hold such a body of doctrine as Tract XC. set forth. The essentially Protestant mind of the country was shocked at the attribution of a theology practically indisguishable from the Tridentine, to a Church whose time-honoured boast was (as South had declared) that &amp;quot; it alone made Protestantism considerable in Europe.&amp;quot; Such was the ultimate resolution of the idea, dogmatic, sacerdotal, hierarchical, of the movement of 1833. To this goal had it conducted its authors. (1) reface to the thi editon p. xxii Ia the.ApdeIia, pp. 114-120 and p. 130, Cardial Newma teDs of his diay when ancient eeccsiasical hiy dilosed to him vitable examples of a Via Xedia in the Mophysite and Arian hereses ee aom the Twdftk LeStic enAx Alica DuFcvltts. &amp;quot;From beginnings so small, from elements of thought so fortuitous, with prospects so uncompromig,&amp;quot; it had proceeded, &amp;quot; getting stronger year after year, until it cme into collision with the nation and with the Church of the nation, which it began by prfessing epciay to serve.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; Tract XC. was received throughout the country with a storm of indignation, and the living rulers of the Establishment began to move. &amp;quot;&amp;apos; These are they,&amp;quot; Cardinal Newman says, &amp;quot; who reverse the Roman&amp;apos;s maxim, and are wont to shrink from the contumacious and to be valiant towards the submissive.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; This little touch of bitterness is not unnatural, but, pawe taats irt, I venture to say that Anglican bishops seem to have acted towards Tractarianism with much long-suffering, and in the event to have condemned it only when the primary obligation of fidelity to themselves compelled them to do so. Excellent men, but not heroic; respectable, but not sacerdotal; solidly adhering to things settled, and, in Mtr. Carlyle&amp;apos;s phrase, mainly occupied in burning their own smoke-what sympathy could they have had with such a movement ? Indeed Tract L, in which the author declared that he &amp;quot; could not wish them a more blessed termination of their course than the spoiling of their goods and martyrdom,&amp;quot; might reasonably have distressed and alarmed them. But for years they bore and forbore; it was difficult to be hard upon men who assured them that they were &amp;quot;Apostles true.&amp;quot; And when at length they acted, in obedience to strong popular pressure, surely no action could have been milder. Contrast it with any conceivable action upon the part of Catholic bishops in respect of a Protestantising movement within the communion of Rome. Still, in the event they did. undoubtedly pronounce against Tract XC. in a series of charges lasting through three years. &amp;quot;It was a formal, determinate condemnation.&amp;quot; Cardinal Newman says, &amp;quot; I recognised it as a condemnation. It was the only one in their power.&amp;quot;s3 It was the beginning of the end. To the adverse verdict of public opinion, to the censure of academical Boards, he might have been comparatively indifferent. He had not entered upon his course to be turned aside from it arbitrio oppsari8 aure, or to quail before the ardor eiiurn prarajibentm. But the condemnation of the episcopate was a fatal blow to the Tractarian party. Its leaders felt, Cardinal Newman tells us, that &amp;quot;their occupation was gone. Their initial principle, their basis, external authority, was cut away from under their feet. They had set their fortunes on a cas, and they had lost&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Hewceforward there was nothing left for them but to shut up their school and retire into the country, ... unless, indeed, the took up sme other theory, unless they changed their ground, unles they srangely forgot their own luminous and most keen convictions,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;9eased to be (1) Kpoeki p. 76. (2) &amp;apos;4Pembjetietdebelke rubos. -An. Dif. vol. Lp. 131. (3) Apexyi, p. 76. what they were, and became what they were not,&amp;quot; or, &amp;quot; looked out for truth and peace elsewhere.&amp;quot;1 These were indeed the three courses open to the adherents of the movement, and some followed one of them, some another. There were those who withdrew from a world not moving to their mind, to the seclusion of rural parishes, to reap the reward of toil unsevered from tranquillity, from the beneficent activity of an English clergyman&amp;apos;s life and the sothing inkluencesof hishome. Many &amp;quot;vindicated therightof private judgment,&amp;quot; modified their views, and cast in their lot with other sections of religious thought. No inconsiderable number, after more or fewer years of anxiety and suspense, determined that the Church of Rome was the true home of the theological idea which they could not surrender. Of these was John Henry Newman. It is unnecesy to dwell here upon the workings of his mind which led him to this conclusion. They may be followed, step by step, in the Apologia and the Esay on Development. It was on September the 25th, 1845, that his last words as an Anglican clergyman were spoken to the little knot of friends assembled in the chapel of his house at Littlemore to keep with him the anniversary of its consecration. There were few dry eyes there save the preacher&amp;apos;s, as from the text which had been that of his first sermon nineteen years before, he spoke to them of &amp;quot;sthe parting of friends.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Man goeth forth to his work and his labour until the evening.&amp;quot; His &amp;quot; sun was set, and even had come.&amp;quot; They knew well what he meant when, in the sacred lange which &amp;quot;nveils our feelings while it gives expression to them,&amp;quot; he bade them keep the feast, &amp;quot; even though in haste and with bitter herbs, and with loins girded and with staff in hand, as they who have no continuing city, but seek one to come.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; It is now more than thirty years ago that Cardinal Newman seceded from the Church of England. Since then, he tells us, &amp;quot;&amp;apos; I have no further history of my religious opinions to narrate.&amp;quot; And he adds, in explanation, &amp;quot;In saying this I do not mean that my mind has been idle, or that I have given up thinking on theological subjects, but that I have had no variations to record, and have had no anxiety of heart whatever.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I have never had one doubt.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It was like coming into port after a rough sea&amp;quot; 3 Although, however, there is no further history of Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s religious opinions to be added to the Apoogia, there is a memorable chapter of his religious activity to be writte The Tractarian movement has certainly been of much imporance to the Church of Rome, even as regards its direct and visible results, which are those of the least moment. I do not think it is too much to say that to it, in large measure, is due all that most signaly diinguses the present position of Catholics from. (1) Ayglic k ni% voL i p.134. (2 &amp;amp;reme - &amp;amp;Weta f 9k Dy, p. 39. (3) Adpelei, p. 238. that which they occupied half a century ago. No doubt the Act of Emancipation rendered possible the change whic has come about. But as the Catholic body then was in England, its condition was hardly such as to enable it to profit to any large extent by that great measure of justice. Far be it frma me to write one word sounding in di g Irt of men for whom I entertain a reverential dmition which no words can adequately expreuss Who indeed can but revere and admire the indefectle fidelity of that heroic band of hereditary confessorsP No Englishman, surely, can fail to be touched by it. Still I suppose it is an unquet filet of history that the political d tional and social disbities of centuries had told disastrously upon the Catholics of England. How could it have been otherwise? For generations they had dwelt in -darkness and in the shadow of death, and the iron had entered into their souls. S&amp;amp;ae adjutorio, inuer tnortuoa lilr, ict vlonerati dormientes in upatchris, is the true description of the state in which they found themselves when they were once more admitted to their constitutional rights. It was opportune, then, that the fresher zeal, the wider cultivation, the uncramped energies of the band of proselytes whom Cardinal Newman headed, were placed when they were at the service of Catholicism in England. The new blood brought into the Catholic Communion is certainly a very important result of the Oxford movement; and its importance is not restricted either to the geographical limits of this country, or to the chronological limits of this age. Still I do not think I am hazarding a doubtful prediction in saying that in the long ran the most considerable product of Tractarianism, so far as the Catholic Church is concerned, will be found to be her gain of John Henry Newman, her aquisition of this one mind-a mind upon a level with that of Pascal or Bossuet, and uniting to much which was highest and best in both, great endowments that were given to neither. It is very difficult, however, to set down in writing anything that will convey a just impresion of the work which Cardinal Newman has done and is doing for the Church with which he cast in his lot more than three decades ago. The writings which he has published, great as their effict has already been, represent only a small portion of it. From his retreat at Birmingham has gone forth through the Catholic world the same subtle influence which once went forth from Oriel and Littlemore, an influence profoundly affecting events, not in their more vulgar manifestations which meet the eye, but in their secret springs and prime sources. To others he has left conspicuous positions and &amp;quot;d The load applause and ayes vehement,&amp;quot; which have greeted their achievements there, himself takin unquestioningly that lowest place which his e a l superiors assigned him, going forth, as of old, to hi work and to his labour in his appointed sphere; and now, in the &amp;quot;c alm sunset of his various day&amp;quot; as u eoingly obeying the voice of authority bidding him go up higher, and setting him among the princes of his people. And it is his singular happiness that he has lived to see the cloud of oneptions which so long hung over him pass quite away. The good opinion of his countrymen has always been dear to him, and he has regained it. Comparatively few Englishmen hare his religious opinions There ae fewer still who do not respect the motives which led him to embrace them, the spirit in which he has held them, the tone in which he has advocated them; who do not disoen in him a shining example of the qualities which are the especial boast of the English name; who do not venerate in him a great intelligence devoted to the noblest ends and guided by the purest affections. Let me now turn from the man, and endeavour to give some account of some of the more prominent features of his work. And first I would note that throughout his long career the deep underlying convictions which have guided him have been unca Not only is it true of him that &amp;quot; his wandering step&amp;quot; was ever &amp;quot; obedient to high thoughts,&amp;quot; but it is also true that the thoughts have always been, in substance, the same. As an Anglican his battle wa on behalf of the dogmatic principle. As a Catholic he has carried on the sme battle, under different conditions He quitted the Church of England when he became convinced that it was in no true nse dogmatic, but, as he has recently expressed it, merely &amp;quot; a civil Esablishment daubed with doctrine.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; And he says in another place:&amp;quot;There came upon me an extreme shment that I had ever imagined it to be a portion of the Catholi Cu .... Forthwith I could not get myself to see in it anything else t .... a mere national insttutio As if my eves wer suddenly opened, so I saw it-sp aneously, apart frEm any denite *a of reason or any argumet; and so I have se it ever since. I gd at [the Caholic Curch] amost passivy-asagreat objecive hfL I lookedat her; ather ites, her sandherprecepts; and I said, this u a religion: and then when I looked bak upon the poor Anglican Church, for which I had laboured so hard, and upon al that appertained to it, and thought of our various attempts to dra it up doctinally and estheticaly, it seemed to me the veriest of nonentites&amp;quot;&amp;apos; 2 This is the main thesis of Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s earlier Catholic sermons and of those Lectures on Anglican Dijfculties, which are perhap the most powerful work of religious controversy in the English language;--that the Church of England is not an oracle of religious truth, that Catholicisn is the natural, logical, and true home of the idea of Tractarianim. It is not that he is innsible to (I) ris di, L L p. 339, Dote of 18,7. (2) Ajohrix, p. 340- much that is winning and excellent in the national worship; its &amp;quot;decency and order,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;the pure and beautiful English of its prayer.,&amp;quot; &amp;quot; the piety found among its m ber&amp;quot;!&amp;apos; &amp;quot;There is al this,&amp;quot; as he ungrudgingly nies, and much more, to attract the mind to it. But he adds: &amp;quot; Attachment is not ust, nor is to obey the sme as to lok up to and to rely upon; nor do I think that any thoughtful and educated ma c smply beieve or confe in the wod of the E blished Church. I nevermen any such person who did, or said he did, and I do not think tht such a person hs posM&amp;amp;le Its defendes would believe if they could; but their hiet confidenc is qualified by a misgiving.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; And the course of events in the Anglican communion has been such as to add point to his argument. The defeat of Tractaianismn was the victory of i lism, and i ralim has reaped the full fruits of its triumph. One judgment after another of the Supreme Appellate Court of the E bed Church has deprived it of any semblance of dogmatic char which it may once have po-sessed, and reduced it to the position of an exponent of the most conflicting opinions on theological subjects. If Bishop Watson has rightly defined Protestantism to be &amp;quot;s the right of saying what you think, and of thinking what you please,&amp;quot; the Church of England is the most Protestant of ecclail communities The Tracr movement has done much for Anglicanism as a sentiment. It has been fatal to it as an eclistical ystem. And to John Heny Newman-the great leader of that movement-is due the most crushing demonstration that the National Churc cannot claim to be, &amp;quot;in however narrow a sense, the guardian of orthodoxy.&amp;quot; 2 So much may suffice with regard to Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s action in the Anglican controversy. It is, as I have observed, a continution of that championhip of the dogmatic principle which distinged him as a Protestant. And the same may be said of his coue with regard to the controversies as to Catholicism While he has streuouldy combated, on the one hand, the Liberalim, which strikes at the root of the dogmatic principle, he has, on the other, been an equally ucprmising opponent of those who, as he judged, sought to overlay the Catholic creed with private inte on, and to impose their unauthorised shibboleths an teahorithive ta ng. A &amp;quot;jealou vindication against tyannous didil., of the range of truths and the mm of propositions, of which the absolute reception may be required,&amp;quot; is among the most maked char of his (X) Dsw is ira 2, p. 2. so Mr. Edo: &amp;quot;The CaUs&amp;amp; at t nMO&amp;quot;bt in MUd to be S hs Noig I&amp;amp; but pon.--. If a BSAp noo kn isaelligmt gemAin, and reads faa-l in is ey he haso MR - i -at to take wine ih hin.&amp;quot;-EkOA rrit p. 15. (2) Haii DAwfksi, v. L p. 7. later writings, and nowhere, perhaps, has he more strongly displayed it than in dealing with a document so much and so ignorantly talked of both by Catholics and Protestants, the Syllabns Errorw, issued by command of the late Pope in 1864. Before proceeding to his argument, that this catalogue of errors has in itself no dogmatic force, that it is a mere index raironni, the value of which lies in its references; that the aversion of educated Europe towards it arises mainly from misinterpretation of the theses condemned, from ignorance of the language of scientific theology, and from the reading of the propositions apart from the context, occasion and drift of each, he interposes words of indignant protest against &amp;quot;athose who wish and try to carry measures, and declare they have carried, when they have not carried them;&amp;quot; and adds the caution, that utterances which &amp;quot;lare really dogmatic must be read by definite rules and by traditional principles of interpretation, which are as cogent and unchangeable as the Pope&amp;apos;s own decisions themselves.&amp;quot; 1 It is not necessary, however, for me to pursue this subject, and I gladly leave unstirred theological dust now happily fallen, to glance, in concl this article, at Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s treatment of another question of far profounder and more general interest. It is, indeed, the great question of the day, lying as it does at the root of all philosohy. Is any knowledge of God possible --any knowledge of His existence as a fact ?-any knowledge of Him as a person --and, if so, how? I need hardly say that to present with any fulness Cardinal Newman&amp;apos;s mind upon this matter would be an ung very far beyond my present limits, involving as it would, with much else, an exposition of his whole doctrine as to certitude and the logical cogency of faith. AU I can pretend to do here is to indicate as briefly as may be consistent with clearness the outlines of one important branch of his argument; and I shall endeavour to do this, as far as postible, in his own words His main principle is that which he originally learnt fromButler-that probability is the guide of life. &amp;quot; Formal logical sequence,&amp;quot; he observes&amp;quot; is not, in fact, the method by which we are enabled to become certin of what is concrete, and it is equally plain what the real and necessry method is It is the cumulation of probailii, inde-tof eac other, arising out of the nature and - of the particular case whic is - review, proballitis too fine to avail separately, too sbtle andcGrcuitousto be eonvetile into syllogisms, too numerous and various for such conversion, ev were they convertble&amp;quot;2 &amp;quot;This,&amp;quot; he says&amp;quot;is the mode in which we ordinarily reason, de with tgs dectly and as they stand, one by one, in the concrete, with an intrinsic and pesonal (1) Ldter to 9k Dab of Nerfoa, we. 7. M Gremmir of Aswxt, p. 281. power, not a conseious adoption of an artificial instrment or expedient.&amp;quot; &amp;apos; &amp;quot; rom the nature of the cae, and from the constitution of the human mind, certitude is the result of arguments b whc taken in the letter, and not in their full impicit sem, are but pro ities&amp;quot; 2 And so, in religious inquiries he holds informal inference to be the real and necesary method. By religion he means the knowledge of God, of His will, and of our duties towards Him; and he finds three main channels which Nature furnishes for acquiring this knowledge, viz our own minds, the voice of manknd, and the course of the world, the most authoritative of these, a specially our own, being our own mind. To Cardinal Newman our great internal teacher of religion is conscience, a personal guide, which he must use because he must use himself, and nearer to him than any other means of knowledge.3 He puts away abstract questions; he does not conder &amp;quot;how far external existenes are in all cases necessary to the action of the mind, because, in fat man does not live in isolation, but is everywhere found as a member of society.&amp;quot; He deals with no individuem gWoo, but with mn as the experence of life presents him, and with the man he is best acquantdwith-himself, because he knows what has satisfied and satisfies himself; if it satisfies him it is likely to satisf others; if, as he believes and is sure, it is true, it will approve itself to others also, for there is bat one truth4 Conscience, then, to him is the voice of God within, .&amp;quot; teaching not only that He is, but what He is,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;the serial Attribute under which it brings Him before us, and to which it subordinates all other Attributes,&amp;quot; being &amp;quot;that of justie-retributive justice.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;H nce its effec is to burden andsadden the religious mind, and is in motratwith the enjoyment duiable from the exorse of the affections, andfrom the pereptionof beauty, whetOr in the material universeorinthe creations of the inteleoL .Thu is that fearflantagoismn brought out with inch soul-pierg reality by Lucretius, when he speaks so disof whathe coiders he heavy yoke of religion, and the &amp;apos;a ternas pwm in mowte timendum;I and, on the ther hand, rejoices in his Alma Venu, &amp;apos; Qua mum naturam ida g-bbers He looks within, then, and he finds, as he believes, that the existence of a God of Judgment is as certain to him as his own exidsene, however difficult it may be to put into logical shape the grounds of .that certainty. He looks into the world, and there he sees a sight 4 which seems to give the lie to this great truth, of which his whole being is fIl.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; To consider the world,&amp;quot; he writes&amp;quot;in its 1mgth and breadth, its vwioUs hiTo, the many roes of man, (1) Grow of Awft, p. 324. (4) UAL p. 3M (3) Ibid. p. 38. (2) IAL p. 286. (a) ULpa 386. their starts, their fortunes, their mutual alienation, their conflicts; and thou their ways, habit go ts, forms of worship, their enterprises theiraimlees courses, their random achievements and aiements, the impotent conclusion of long-standing facts, the tokens so faint and broken of ape nt design, the blind evolution of what turn out to be great powers or truths, the progress of things, as if frm reasoning element, not towards final causes, the greatness and littleness of man, his far-reaching aims, his shedt duration, the curtain hung over his futurity, the disppointments of life, the defat of good, the success of evil, physicl pain, mental anguish, the prevalence and intensity of sin, the pervading idolatries, the corruptions, the dreary.hopeless irreligion; that condition of the whole race, so fearfully yet exactly described in the Apostles words, &amp;apos; Having no hope, and without God in the world,&amp;apos;-all this is a vision to dizy and appal; and inflicts upon the mind the sense of a profound mystery, which is absolutely beyond human solution.&amp;quot; &amp;quot; Were it not for the voice speaking so clearly in my conscience and my heart, I should be an atheist, or a pantheist, or a polytheist, when I looked into the worL&amp;quot;&amp;apos; Thus does human life present itself to him. Such is the &amp;quot; heartpiercing, reason-bewildering fiact &amp;quot; which he has to faos Is there any e tion of it? &amp;quot;I see only a choice of alternatives,&amp;quot; he aners. &amp;quot; Either there is no Creator, or He has disowned His creaturel Are, then, the dim shadows of His presence in the affairs of men but a fancy of our own, or, on the other hand, has He hid His fac and the ligt of His c nce because we have in same special way disonore Him ? My true inlrmant, my burdened conscience, gives me at once the true answer to each of these a questions: it pronounces without any misgiving that God exists; it powunces too quite as surely, that I sin alimated from Him; that &amp;apos; His hand is not dsortened, but that our iniquities have divided between us and our God.&amp;apos; Thus it solves the world&amp;apos; mystery, and se in it only a Of its own original teaching.&amp;quot; 2 This, then, is his first step. The presence of God in the conscience, and the sen of sin, are to him the main truths of natural religion-the notorious facts of the case inthe medium of his priary mental experiences. And here, before I pas on, I should remark, that irreistibly as Cardinal Newman finds the doctrine of the existence of God borne in upon him, he must not be spposed to be without a keen I of the number and weight of the objections which may be raised against it-of the insouble questons, the nc abls, inxpie mysteries which attend it-of the imperfection and incomple of the body of proof adducible for it-of the plable excuses which may be urged for doubting it.3 (1) 4p1y* p. 241. (2) Gra ar of , t, p. 3t2 (3) Om sermon on &amp;quot;Mysteries of Nature and Grace&amp;quot; in Diwowwg Xind Curegtina, p. 263. go in OxIord University Sermon, p. 194, he rearks, &amp;quot; It us a great question whether Atheism isnt as u com sat wik the phimia of the paieL world, take-, by as the doctrine of a ereative and sovereign power.&amp;quot; But see the note in the lat edition upon the words in alics It must not be qfpoued that Caidinal Newman denies the validity of the u tom design in its plece. He rocognises that &amp;quot;&amp;apos; the main difficulty to an inquirer is firmly to hold that there is a Living God, the Creator, Witness, and Judge of men.&amp;quot; And he thinks that, when once the mind is broken in &amp;quot;to the belief of a Power above it, when once it understands that it is not itself the memreof all things in heaven and earth, it will have Little difficulty in going forward,&amp;quot; not, indeed, that it necessarily must, but that it has passed a line-that &amp;quot;the great obstacle to finith is taken away.&amp;quot;&amp;apos; &amp;quot;1 The very difficulties of nature,&amp;quot; he judges, make it likely. that a revelation should be made. &amp;quot; That earnest desire which religious minds cherish, leads the way to the expectation of it. Those who know nothing of the wounds of the soul are not led to deal with the question or consider its circumstances But when our attention is roused, then the more steadilv we dwell upon it, the more probable does it seem that a reve ation has been, or will be given to us. This presentiment is founded on our sense, on the one hand, of the infinite goodness of God, and on the other, from our extreme misery and need.&amp;quot; 2 &amp;quot; You know there is a God, yet you know your own ignorance of Him, of His will, of your duties, of your prospects. A revelation would be the greatest of possible boons which could be vouchsafed to you After all, you do not know, you only conclude that there is a God; you see Him not, you do but hear of Him. He acts under a vel; He is on the point of manifesting Himself to you at every turn, yet He does not. He has impressed on your heart anticipations of His majesty; in every part of creation has He left traces of His presence and given glimpses of His glory; you come up to the spot, He has been there, but He is gone...... The news, then, of a revelation, far from suspicious, is borne in upon our hearts by the strongest presumptions of reasons in its behalf. It is hard to believe that it is not given, as, indeed, the conduct of mannkind has ever shown. You cannot help expecting it from the hands of the A11merciful, unworthy as you feel yourselves of it. It is not that you can claim it, but that He inspires hope of it; it is not you that are worthy of the gift, but it is the gift which is worthy of your Creator. It is so urgently probable that little evidence is required for it, even though but little were givn. Evidence that God has spoken you must have, else were you a prey to impostares; but its extreme likelihood allows you, were it necessary, to dispense with all proof that is not barely sufficient for your purpose. The very fUa, I say, that there is a Creator, and a hidden one. powerfully bears you on and sets you down at the very threshold of revelation, and leaves you there looking up earnestly for divine tokens that a revelation has been made.&amp;quot; 3 This is the second stage of his argument. His third point is, If there is a revelation, where is it ? Chrisianity he considers to be the only complement which natural religion can have.4 But which of its innumerable varieties is the true form of Christianity ? And here comes in the testimony of history. Christianity is a great fact in the world. Its founders set it up as a Church, a Visible Society, (1) Di--a to Mired CJieatis, p. 276. (2) Gewaxnr of Ast, p. 41. (3) Durs to Xined CGrwfitia, p. -29. (4) Grsswr of Anut, p. 419. a Kingdom. This was their work, not to write a book, or to put together a collection of documents, the Bible being, in hicks the creation of the Church, and deriving from her sanction an authority, the actual extent of which she has never defined. But where is this kingdom which Christ set up, if, indeed, it is still on earth ? As If,&amp;quot; he argues&amp;quot; all that can be found of it is what can be discerned at Constantinople or Canterbury; it has disappeared. .... We must either give up the belief in the Church as a divine institution altogether, or we must recognise it in that ommnion of which the Pope is the head. .... We mut take things as they are; to believe in the Church is to believe in the Pope.&amp;apos; The question lies between the [Catholic] Church and no divine messenger at all; there is no revelation given us, unless she is the organ of it; for where else is there a prophet to be found ? Your anticipation, which I have been speaking o, has ailed, your probability has been falsified, if she be not that prophet of God. Not that this conclusion is an absurdity, for you cannot take it for granted that your hope of a revelation will be fulfilled; but in whatever degree it is probable that it will be fulfilled, in that degree it is probable that the Church, and nothing else, is the means of fulfilling it ...... Turn away from the Cathli Church, and to whom will you go ?9.. .. There is nothing between it and septicism, when men exert their reason freely. Private creeds, fincy religions. may be showy and imposing to the many in their day; national rligions may be huge and lifeless, and cumber the ground for centuries, and distract the attention or confsen the judgment of the learned; but in the long run it will be found that either the Catholi religion is verily and indeed the coming in of the unseen woEd into this, or that there is nothing positive, nothing dogmatic, nothing real in any of our notions as to whence we come and whither we ar going. 2 Such is, in substance, the solution of the great religious question of the day which commends itself to Cardinal Newma Of those who are faithest from accepting it, there are, perhaps, not a few who will recognise that he has done much to clear the ground, and to present to the world the true issue. W. S. LiLLY. (I) Letter to the Dske of Korfoa, msc. 3. (2) Discourset 1. Mired Chrvpfute, p. 283.</FullText></Record>